<document id="10.1.1.1.1543"><clusterid>915</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Coordination Variables and Consensus Building in Multiple Vehicle Systems</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Much of the research focus in the cooperative control community has been on formation control problems [1, 3, 7, 10, 19]. This focus may be due to the fact that the group control problem can be reduced to well-established single-agent control problems by employing a leader-follower type control strategy. For example, single-agent path planning and trajectory generation techniques can be employed for the leader, and conventional trajectory tracking strategies can be employed for the followers. Indeed, formation control problems are much like linear systems theory: we search where the light is the brightest. It can be argued that formation control problems are the simplest type of coordination problems and that even if they were to be completely solved, the solution would be of limited usefulness since the formation concept is of limited utility. This last comment is supported by the observation that humans cooperate to perform a wide variety of tasks, yet we rarely maintain formation with each other. The usefulness of cooperative control technologies will be greatly enhanced</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2003</year><venue src="INFERENCE">Proceedings of the Block Island Workshop on Cooperative Control</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><publisher src="INFERENCE">Springer Verlag</publisher><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="1859494"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Wei Ren</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Brigham Young University, Provo</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Utah 84602</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">{weiren</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="1859495"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Al W. Beard</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Brigham Young University, Provo</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Utah 84602</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">beard}@ee.byu.edu</email><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="1859496"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Timothy W. Mclain</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Brigham Young University, Provo</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Utah 84602</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">mclain@byu.edu</email><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28911"><clusterid>916</clusterid><authors>Tucker Balch,Ronald C Arkin</authors><title>Behavior-based formation control for multirobot teams</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><volume>14</volume><raw>Tucker Balch and Ronald C. Arkin. Behavior-based formation control for multirobot teams. IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation, 14(6):926–939, December 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28912"><clusterid>917</clusterid><authors>Tucker Balch,Lynne E Parker</authors><title>editors. Robot Teams: From Diversity to Polymorphism</title><year>2002</year><editors>A. K. Peters, Ltd</editors><pubAddress>Natick, Massachusetts</pubAddress><raw>Tucker Balch and Lynne E. Parker, editors. Robot Teams: From Diversity to Polymorphism. A. K. Peters, Ltd., Natick, Massachusetts, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28913"><clusterid>918</clusterid><authors>Randal W Beard,Jonathan Lawton,Fred Y Hadaegh</authors><title>A feedback architecture for formation control</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><volume>9</volume><raw>Randal W. Beard, Jonathan Lawton, and Fred Y. Hadaegh. A feedback architecture for formation control. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 9(6):777–790, November 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28914"><clusterid>919</clusterid><authors>Randal W Beard,Timothy W McLain</authors><title>Multiple UAV cooperative search under collision avoidance and limited range communication constraints</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, 2003. To appear.  Variables and Consensus 17</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Randal W. Beard and Timothy W. McLain. Multiple UAV cooperative search under collision avoidance and limited range communication constraints. In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, 2003. To appear. Coordination Variables and Consensus 17</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28915"><clusterid>920</clusterid><authors>Randal W Beard</authors><title>and Vahram Stepanyan. Synchronization of information in distributed multiple vehicle coordinated control</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>Randal W. Beard and Vahram Stepanyan. Synchronization of information in distributed multiple vehicle coordinated control. In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, 2003. To appear.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28916"><clusterid>921</clusterid><authors>John Bellingham,Michael Tillerson,Arthur Richards,Johnathan P How</authors><title>Multi-task allocation and path planning for cooperating UAVs</title><venue>In Cooperative Control: Models, Applications and Algorithms</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>1--19</pages><raw>John Bellingham, Michael Tillerson, Arthur Richards, and Johnathan P. How. Multi-task allocation and path planning for cooperating UAVs. In Cooperative Control: Models, Applications and Algorithms, pages 1–19. Conference on Coordination, Control and Optimization, November 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28917"><clusterid>922</clusterid><authors>Calin Belta,Vijay Kumar</authors><title>Trajectory design for formations of robots by kinetic energy shaping</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>2593--2598</pages><pubAddress>Washington DC</pubAddress><raw>Calin Belta and Vijay Kumar. Trajectory design for formations of robots by kinetic energy shaping. In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, pages 2593–2598, Washington DC, May 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28918"><clusterid>923</clusterid><authors>J Russell Carpenter</authors><title>Decentralized control of satellite formations</title><venue>International journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--2</pages><volume>12</volume><raw>J. Russell Carpenter. Decentralized control of satellite formations. International journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control, 12:141–161, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28919"><clusterid>924</clusterid><authors>Gustavo Ayres de Castro,Fernando Paganini</authors><title>Convex synthesis of controllers for consensus over a network of agents</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>Gustavo Ayres de Castro and Fernando Paganini. Convex synthesis of controllers for consensus over a network of agents. In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, 2003. To appear.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28920"><clusterid>925</clusterid><authors>Magnus</authors><title>Egerstedt and Xiaoming Hu. Formation constrained multi-agent control</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><volume>17</volume><raw>Magnus Egerstedt and Xiaoming Hu. Formation constrained multi-agent control. IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation, 17(6):947–951, December</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28921"><clusterid>926</clusterid><authors>Rosemary Emery,Kevin Sikorski,Tucker Balch</authors><title>Protocols for collaboration, coordination and dynamic role assignment in a robot team</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>3008--3015</pages><pubAddress>Washington DC</pubAddress><raw>Rosemary Emery, Kevin Sikorski, and Tucker Balch. Protocols for collaboration, coordination and dynamic role assignment in a robot team. In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, pages 3008–3015, Washington DC, May 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28922"><clusterid>927</clusterid><authors>J Alexander Fax,Richard M Murray</authors><title>Graph laplacians and stabilization of vehicle formations</title><venue>In IFAC World Congress</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pubAddress>Barcelona, Spain</pubAddress><raw>J. Alexander Fax and Richard M. Murray. Graph laplacians and stabilization of vehicle formations. In IFAC World Congress, Barcelona, Spain, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28923"><clusterid>928</clusterid><authors>C Godsil,G Royle</authors><title>Algebraic Graph Theory, volume 207 of Graduate Text in Mathematics</title><year>2001</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>C. Godsil and G. Royle. Algebraic Graph Theory, volume 207 of Graduate Text in Mathematics. Springer, New York, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28924"><clusterid>929</clusterid><authors>Ali Jadbabaie,Jie Lin,A Stephen Morse</authors><title>Coordination of groups of mobile autonomous agents using nearest neighbor rules</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><volume>48</volume><raw>Ali Jadbabaie, Jie Lin, and A. Stephen Morse. Coordination of groups of mobile autonomous agents using nearest neighbor rules. IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, 48(6):988–1001, June 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28925"><clusterid>930</clusterid><authors>W Kang,N Xi,Andy Sparks</authors><title>Formation control of autonomous agents in 3D workspace</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>1755--1760</pages><pubAddress>San Francisco, CA</pubAddress><raw>W. Kang, N. Xi, and Andy Sparks. Formation control of autonomous agents in 3D workspace. In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, pages 1755–1760, San Francisco, CA, April 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28926"><clusterid>931</clusterid><authors>Wei Kang,Hsi-Han Yeh</authors><title>Coordinated attitude control of mulit-satellite systems</title><venue>International Journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><volume>12</volume><raw>Wei Kang and Hsi-Han Yeh. Coordinated attitude control of mulit-satellite systems. International Journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control, 12:185–205,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28927"><clusterid>932</clusterid><authors>Jonathan Lawton,Randal Beard</authors><title>A projection approach to spacecraft formation attitude control</title><venue>In 23rd Annual AAS Guidance and Control Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>00--011</pages><publisher>AAS</publisher><pubAddress>Breckenridge, Colorado</pubAddress><raw>Jonathan Lawton and Randal Beard. A projection approach to spacecraft formation attitude control. In 23rd Annual AAS Guidance and Control Conference, Breckenridge, Colorado, February 2000. Paper no. AAS 00-011.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28928"><clusterid>933</clusterid><authors>Naomi Ehrich Leonard,Edward Fiorelli</authors><title>Virtual leaders, artificial potentials and coordinated control of groups</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>2968--2973</pages><pubAddress>Orlando, Florida</pubAddress><raw>Naomi Ehrich Leonard and Edward Fiorelli. Virtual leaders, artificial potentials and coordinated control of groups. In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, pages 2968–2973, Orlando, Florida, December 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28929"><clusterid>934</clusterid><authors>T McLain,P Chandler,S Rasmussen,M Pachter</authors><title>Cooperative control of UAV rendezvous</title><venue>In Proc. of the ACC</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>2309--2314</pages><raw>T. McLain, P. Chandler, S. Rasmussen, and M. Pachter. Cooperative control of UAV rendezvous. In Proc. of the ACC, pages 2309–2314, June 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28930"><clusterid>935</clusterid><authors>Timothy W McLain,Randal W Beard</authors><title>Coordination variables, coordination functions, and cooperative timing missions</title><venue>In Proceedings of the American Control Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>296--301</pages><publisher>McLain</publisher><pubAddress>Denver, CO</pubAddress><raw>Timothy W. McLain and Randal W. Beard. Coordination variables, coordination functions, and cooperative timing missions. In Proceedings of the American Control Conference, pages 296–301, Denver, CO, June 2003. 18 W. Ren, R. W. Beard, T. W. McLain</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28931"><clusterid>936</clusterid><authors>Wei Ren,Randal W Beard</authors><title>A decentralized scheme for spacecraft formation flying via the virtual structure approach</title><venue>In Proceedings of the American Control Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>1746--1751</pages><pubAddress>Denver, CO</pubAddress><raw>Wei Ren and Randal W. Beard. A decentralized scheme for spacecraft formation flying via the virtual structure approach. In Proceedings of the American Control Conference, pages 1746–1751, Denver, CO, June 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28932"><clusterid>937</clusterid><authors>A Richards,J Bellingham,M Tillerson,J How</authors><title>Coordination and control of UAVs</title><venue>In Proceedings of the AIAA Guidance, Navigation, and Control Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>2002--4588</pages><pubAddress>Monterey, CA</pubAddress><raw>A. Richards, J. Bellingham, M. Tillerson, and J. How. Coordination and control of UAVs. In Proceedings of the AIAA Guidance, Navigation, and Control Conference, pages AIAA–2002–4588, Monterey, CA, August 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28933"><clusterid>938</clusterid><authors>Wilson J Rugh</authors><title>Linear System Theory</title><year>1996</year><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><pubAddress>Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Wilson J. Rugh. Linear System Theory. Prentice Hall, Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey, 2nd edition, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28934"><clusterid>939</clusterid><authors>Reza Olfati Saber,Richard M Murray</authors><title>Agreement problems in networks with directed graphs and switching topology</title><venue>In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>Reza Olfati Saber and Richard M. Murray. Agreement problems in networks with directed graphs and switching topology. In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, 2003. (to appear).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28935"><clusterid>940</clusterid><authors>Shahab Sheikholeslam,Charles A Desoer</authors><title>Control of interconnected nonlinear dynamical systems: The platoon problem</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1992</year><volume>37</volume><raw>Shahab Sheikholeslam and Charles A. Desoer. Control of interconnected nonlinear dynamical systems: The platoon problem. IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, 37(6):806–810, June 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28936"><clusterid>941</clusterid><authors>Daniel J Stilwell,Bradley E Bishop</authors><title>Platoons of underwater vehicles</title><venue>IEEE Control Systems Magazine</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><volume>20</volume><raw>Daniel J. Stilwell and Bradley E. Bishop. Platoons of underwater vehicles. IEEE Control Systems Magazine, 20(6):45–52, December 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation><citation id="28937"><clusterid>942</clusterid><authors>P K C Wang,F Y Hadaegh</authors><title>Coordination and control of multiple microspacecraft moving in formation</title><venue>The Journal of the Astronautical Sciences</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><volume>44</volume><raw>P. K. C. Wang and F. Y. Hadaegh. Coordination and control of multiple microspacecraft moving in formation. The Journal of the Astronautical Sciences, 44(3):315–355, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1543</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.et.byu.edu/~wr25/./papers/preprints/bookchapters/RenBeardMcLain03.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>b19651b86d103046e04894fce7b936198e828683</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>