<document id="10.1.1.1.1557"><clusterid>1245</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">WordNet Exploitation through a Distributed Network of Servers</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract. The architecture of a lexical database in which multilingual semantic networks would be stored requires the incorporation of flexible mechanisms and services, which would enable the efficient navigation within and across lexical data. We report on WordNet Management System (WMS), a system that functions as the interconnection and communication link between a user and a number of interlinked WordNets. Semantic information is being accessed through a distributed network of servers, forming a large-scale multilingual semantic network. 1</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1270">tagging</keyword><keyword id="1271">the annotation of each content word with a semantic category. WordNet</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4338"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">I. D. Koutsoubos</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">2 Research Academic Computer Technology Institute,; 61 Riga Feraiou, 26221</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patras, Greece</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">koutsoub@cti.gr</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4339"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Vassilis Andrikopoulos</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">1 Computer Engineering and Informatics Department, Patras University,; 26500</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patras, Greece</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">andrikop@ceid.upatras.gr</email><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4340"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Dimitris Christodoulakis</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">2 Research Academic Computer Technology Institute,; 61 Riga Feraiou, 26221</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patras, Greece</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">dxri@cti.gr</email><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29254"><clusterid>1246</clusterid><authors></authors><title>WordNet: An Electronic Lexical Database</title><year>1998</year><editors>Fellbaum Ch. (ed</editors><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, M.A</pubAddress><raw>Fellbaum Ch. (ed.) (1998) WordNet: An Electronic Lexical Database, Cambridge, M.A: MIT Press.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29255"><clusterid>1247</clusterid><authors>S Stamou,K Oflazer,K Pala,D Christodoulakis,D Cristea,D Tufis,S Koeva,G Totkov,D Dutoit,M Grigoriadou</authors><title>BALKANET: A Multilingual Semantic Network for Balkan Languages</title><venue>In Proceedings of the GWA 1 st International WordNet Conference, Mysore</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pubAddress>India</pubAddress><raw>Stamou S., Oflazer K., Pala K., Christodoulakis D., Cristea D., Tufis D., Koeva S., Totkov G., Dutoit D., Grigoriadou M. (2002) “BALKANET: A Multilingual Semantic Network for Balkan Languages”. In Proceedings of the GWA 1 st International WordNet Conference, Mysore, India, Jan. 21–25, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29256"><clusterid>1248</clusterid><authors></authors><title>EuroWordNet: A Multilingual Database with Lexical Semantic Networks</title><year>1998</year><editors>Vossen P. (ed</editors><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><pubAddress>Dordrecht</pubAddress><raw>Vossen P. (ed.) (1998) EuroWordNet: A Multilingual Database with Lexical Semantic Networks, Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29257"><clusterid>1249</clusterid><authors>T Pavelek,K Pala</authors><title>WordNet standardization from a practical point of view</title><venue>In Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on WordNet Structures and Standardisation, and How These Affect WordNet Applications and Evaluation, Las Palmas, Gran Canaria. 30–34</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Pavelek, T. and Pala K. (2002) “WordNet standardization from a practical point of view”. In Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on WordNet Structures and Standardisation, and How These Affect WordNet Applications and Evaluation, Las Palmas, Gran Canaria. 30–34, May 28th, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29258"><clusterid>1250</clusterid><authors>M Panti,L Penserini,L Spalazzi</authors><title>A pure P2P approach to information integration</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2002</year><tech>Tec. Report 2002-02-19</tech><raw>Panti M., Penserini L., Spalazzi L. (2002) “A pure P2P approach to information integration”. Tec. Report 2002-02-19, Istituto di Informatica, University of Ancona, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29259"><clusterid>1251</clusterid><authors>R J Bayardo,W Bohrer</authors><title>InfoSleuth: Agent-Based Semantic Integration of Information in Open and Dynamic Environments</title><venue>In Proceedings of the ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><volume>26</volume><raw>R. J. Bayardo, W. Bohrer, et al. (1997) “InfoSleuth: Agent-Based Semantic Integration of Information in Open and Dynamic Environments”. In Proceedings of the ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data, vol. 26, No. 2, June 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29260"><clusterid>1252</clusterid><authors>H Garcia-Molina,Y Papakonstantinou</authors><title>The TSIMMIS approach to mediation: data models and languages</title><venue>In Journals of Intelligent Information Systems, 8:117–132</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>H. Garcia-Molina, Y. Papakonstantinou, et al. (1997) “The TSIMMIS approach to mediation: data models and languages”. In Journals of Intelligent Information Systems, 8:117–132, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29261"><clusterid>1253</clusterid><authors>A Levy,A Rajaraman,J Ordille</authors><title>Querying Heterogeneous Information Sources Using Source Descriptions</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 22 nd VLDB Confernece</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><raw>A. Levy, A. Rajaraman, J. Ordille (1996) “Querying Heterogeneous Information Sources Using Source Descriptions”. In Proceedings of the 22 nd VLDB Confernece, September, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29262"><clusterid>1254</clusterid><authors>M Nodine,W Bohrer,A H</authors><title>Hiong Ngu (1999) “Semantic Brokering over Dynamic Heterogeneous Data Sources in InfoSleuth</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 15þ International Conference on Data Engineering</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>M. Nodine, W. Bohrer, A. H. Hiong Ngu (1999) “Semantic Brokering over Dynamic Heterogeneous Data Sources in InfoSleuth”. In Proceedings of the 15þ International Conference on Data Engineering, March 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29263"><clusterid>1238</clusterid><authors>A Sheth,J Larson</authors><title>Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed, Heterogeneous and Anonymous Databases</title><venue>In ACM Transaction on Database Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><volume>22</volume><raw>A. Sheth and J. Larson (1990) “Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed, Heterogeneous and Anonymous Databases”. In ACM Transaction on Database Systems, 22(3), 1990.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation><citation id="29264"><clusterid>1255</clusterid><authors>G Wiedehold</authors><title>Mediators in the Architecture of Future Information Systems</title><venue>In IEEE Computer Magazine</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>25--38</pages><raw>G. Wiedehold (1992) “Mediators in the Architecture of Future Information Systems”. In IEEE Computer Magazine, 25:38–49, March 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1557</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.fi.muni.cz/gwc2004/proc/104.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>d852ee7dcbdf19015ee1415cd1f9f6ab77c01e0f</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>