<document id="10.1.1.1.1518"><clusterid>575</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Peer-to-Peer Human-Robot Interaction for Space Exploration</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">NASA has embarked on a long-term program to develop human-robot systems for sustained, affordable space exploration. To support this mission, we are working to improve human-robot interaction and performance on planetary surfaces. Rather than building robots that function as glorified tools, our focus is to enable humans and robots to work as partners and peers. In this paper, we describe our approach, which includes contextual dialogue, cognitive modeling, and metrics-based field testing.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4209"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Terrence Fong</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Computational Sciences Division; NASA Ames Research Center</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Moffett Field, CA 94035 USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">terry @.arc.nasa.gov</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4210"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Illah Nourbakhsh</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Computational Sciences Division; NASA Ames Research Center</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Moffett Field, CA 94035 USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">illah   @.arc.nasa.gov</email><order src="null">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28555"><clusterid>576</clusterid><authors>N Cabrol</authors><title>Proceedings of the Astronaut-Rover interaction post Silver Lake field test debriefing: results, lessons learned, and directions for future human exploration of planetary surfaces</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1999</year><tech>Technical Report NP-2004-01-334HQ</tech><raw>Cabrol, N. 1999. Proceedings of the Astronaut-Rover interaction post Silver Lake field test debriefing: results, lessons learned, and directions for future human exploration of planetary surfaces. Technical Report NP-2004-01-334HQ, NASA Ames Research Center, Moffett Field, CA.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28556"><clusterid>577</clusterid><authors>T Fong,D Kaber,M Lewis,J Scholtz,A Schultz,A Steinfeld</authors><title>Common metrics for human-robot interaction. in submission</title><year>2004</year><raw>Fong, T., Kaber, D., Lewis, M., Scholtz, J., Schultz, A., and Steinfeld, A. 2004. Common metrics for human-robot interaction. in submission.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28557"><clusterid>578</clusterid><authors>T Fong,C Thorpe,C Baur</authors><title>Multi-robot remote driving with collaborative control</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><volume>50</volume><raw>Fong, T., Thorpe, C., and Baur, C. 2003. Multi-robot remote driving with collaborative control. IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics 50(4).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28558"><clusterid>579</clusterid><authors>T Fong</authors><title>Collaborative control: a robot-centric model for vehicle teleoperation</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><pages>01--34</pages><pubAddress>Pittsburgh, PA</pubAddress><tech>Ph.D. Dissertation</tech><raw>Fong, T. 2001. Collaborative control: a robot-centric model for vehicle teleoperation. Ph.D. Dissertation, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA. CMU-RI-TR-01-34.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28559"><clusterid>580</clusterid><authors>M Goodrich,D Olsen</authors><title>Seven principles of efficient human robot interaction</title><venue>In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man and Cybernetics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>3943--3948</pages><raw>Goodrich, M., and Olsen, D. 2003. Seven principles of efficient human robot interaction. In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man and Cybernetics, 3943–3948.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28560"><clusterid>581</clusterid><authors>R Hansen,K Ford</authors><title>A human centered vision of Mars exploration</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2004</year><tech>Technical Report NAG9-1386</tech><raw>Hansen, R., and Ford, K. 2004. A human centered vision of Mars exploration. Technical Report NAG9-1386, Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, University of West Florida.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28561"><clusterid>582</clusterid><authors>S Hart,L Staveland</authors><title>Development of NASATLX (Task Load Index): results of empirical and theoretical research</title><year>1988</year><editors>In Hancock, P., and Meshkati, N., eds., Human Mental Workload</editors><publisher>North-Holland Elsevier Science</publisher><raw>Hart, S., and Staveland, L. 1988. Development of NASATLX (Task Load Index): results of empirical and theoretical research. In Hancock, P., and Meshkati, N., eds., Human Mental Workload. North-Holland Elsevier Science.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28562"><clusterid>583</clusterid><authors>T Huntsberger,G Rodriguez,P Schenker</authors><title>Robotics challenges for robotic and human Mars exploration</title><venue>In Proc. Robotics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>Huntsberger, T., Rodriguez, G., and Schenker, P. 2000. Robotics challenges for robotic and human Mars exploration. In Proc. Robotics.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28563"><clusterid>584</clusterid><authors>H Jones,S Rock</authors><title>Dialogue-based human-robot interaction for space construction teams</title><venue>In Proc. IEEE Aerospace Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Jones, H., and Rock, S. 2002. Dialogue-based human-robot interaction for space construction teams. In Proc. IEEE Aerospace Conference.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28564"><clusterid>585</clusterid><authors>D McFarlane</authors><title>Coordinating the interruption of people in human-computer interaction</title><venue>In Proc. HCI Interact</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>McFarlane, D. 1990. Coordinating the interruption of people in human-computer interaction. In Proc. HCI Interact.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28565"><clusterid>586</clusterid><authors></authors><title>The vision for space exploration</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><pubAddress>NASA, Washington, DC</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report NP-2004-01-334-HQ</tech><raw>NASA. 2004. The vision for space exploration. Technical Report NP-2004-01-334-HQ, NASA, Washington, DC.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28566"><clusterid>587</clusterid><authors>R Proud,J Hard,R Mrozinski</authors><title>Methods for determining the level of autonomy to design into a human spaceflight vehicle: a function specific approach</title><venue>In Proc. NIST Performance Metrics for Intelligent Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Proud, R., Hard, J., and Mrozinski, R. 2003. Methods for determining the level of autonomy to design into a human spaceflight vehicle: a function specific approach. In Proc. NIST Performance Metrics for Intelligent Systems.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28567"><clusterid>588</clusterid><authors>G Rodriguez,C Weisbin</authors><title>A new method to evaluate human-robot system performance. Autonomous Robots 14(2):165–178</title><year>2003</year><raw>Rodriguez, G., and Weisbin, C. 2003. A new method to evaluate human-robot system performance. Autonomous Robots 14(2):165–178.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28568"><clusterid>589</clusterid><authors>J Scholtz,J Young,J Drury,H Yanco</authors><title>Evaluation of human-robot interaction awareness in search and rescue</title><venue>In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><raw>Scholtz, J., Young, J., Drury, J., and Yanco, H. 2004. Evaluation of human-robot interaction awareness in search and rescue. In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28569"><clusterid>590</clusterid><authors>J Scholtz</authors><title>Theory and evaluation of human robot interactions</title><venue>In Proc. Hawaii International Conference on System Science 36</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Scholtz, J. 2003. Theory and evaluation of human robot interactions. In Proc. Hawaii International Conference on System Science 36.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28570"><clusterid>591</clusterid><authors>B Smith,S Tyler</authors><title>The design and application of MIDAS: a constructive simulation for human-system analysis</title><venue>In Proc. Simulation Technology and Training (SIMTECT</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Smith, B., and Tyler, S. 1997. The design and application of MIDAS: a constructive simulation for human-system analysis. In Proc. Simulation Technology and Training (SIMTECT).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation><citation id="28571"><clusterid>227</clusterid><authors>D Sofge,D Perzanowski,M Skubic,M Bugajska,J Trafton,N Cassimatis,D Brock,W Adams,A Schultz</authors><title>Cognitive tools for humanoid robots in space</title><venue>In Proc. IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><raw>Sofge, D., Perzanowski, D., Skubic, M., Bugajska, M., Trafton, J., Cassimatis, N., Brock, D., Adams, W., and Schultz, A. 2004. Cognitive tools for humanoid robots in space. In Proc. IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1518</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.ri.cmu.edu/pub_files/pub4/fong_terrence_w_2004_1/fong_terrence_w_2004_1.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>bb44bfce19166763a0c858e32ca405b54761a879</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>