<document id="10.1.1.1.1535"><clusterid>781</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">A Sub-Quadratic Algorithm for Conjunctive and Disjunctive BESs</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">We present an algorithm for conjunctive and disjunctive Boolean equation systems (BESs), which arise frequently in the verification and analysis of finite state concurrent systems. In contrast to the previously best known O(e&amp;sup2;) time solutions, our algorithm computes the solution of such a fixpoint equation system with size e and alternation depth d in O(e log d) time.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2004</year><venType src="INFERENCE">TECHREPORT</venType><tech src="INFERENCE">CS-Report 04-13</tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4313210"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Jan Friso Groote</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">1 Department of Mathematics and Computer Science, Eindhoven University</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">of Technology, P.O. Box 513, 5600 MB Eindhoven, The Netherlands</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J.F.Groote@tue.nl</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4313211"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Misa Keinänen</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">1 Department of Mathematics and Computer Science, Eindhoven University</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">of Technology, P.O. Box 513, 5600 MB Eindhoven, The Netherlands</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Misa.Keinanen@hut.fi</email><order src="null">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28786"><clusterid>782</clusterid><authors>H R Andersen</authors><title>Model checking and boolean graphs</title><venue>Theoretical Computer Science</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>3--30</pages><volume>126</volume><raw>H.R. Andersen. Model checking and boolean graphs. Theoretical Computer Science, 126 (1994) 3-30.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28787"><clusterid>783</clusterid><authors>J F Groote,M K Keinänen</authors><title>Solving Disjunctive/Conjunctive Boolean Equation Systems with Alternating Fixed Points</title><venue>Proc. 10th International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems (TACAS’2004), volume 2988 of Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><pages>436--450</pages><editors>In K. Jensen and A. Podelski, editors</editors><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>J.F. Groote and M.K. Keinänen. Solving Disjunctive/Conjunctive Boolean Equation Systems with Alternating Fixed Points. In K. Jensen and A. Podelski, editors, Proc. 10th International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems (TACAS’2004), volume 2988 of Lecture Notes in Computer Science, pages 436-450. Springer, 2004.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28788"><clusterid>784</clusterid><authors>V King,O Kupferman,M Y Vardi</authors><title>On the complexity of parity word automata</title><venue>Proc. of 4th International Conference on Foundations of Software Science and Computation Structures, volume 2030 of Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>276--286</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>V. King, O. Kupferman and M.Y. Vardi. On the complexity of parity word automata. Proc. of 4th International Conference on Foundations of Software Science and Computation Structures, volume 2030 of Lecture Notes in Computer Science, pages 276–286. Springer, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28789"><clusterid>785</clusterid><authors>D Kozen</authors><title>Results on the propositional µ-calculus. Theoretical computer Science 27</title><year>1983</year><pages>333--354</pages><raw>D. Kozen. Results on the propositional µ-calculus. Theoretical computer Science 27 (1983) 333-354.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28790"><clusterid>786</clusterid><authors>A Mader</authors><title>Verification of Modal Properties using Boolean Equation Systems</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1997</year><tech>PhD thesis, Technical</tech><raw>A. Mader. Verification of Modal Properties using Boolean Equation Systems. PhD thesis, Technical University of Munich, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28791"><clusterid>787</clusterid><authors>R Mateescu</authors><title>A Generic On-the-Fly Solver for Alternation-Free Boolean Equation Systems</title><venue>In Proceedings of Conf. on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems, Lecture Notes in Computer Science 2619</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>81--96</pages><publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher><raw>R. Mateescu. A Generic On-the-Fly Solver for Alternation-Free Boolean Equation Systems. In Proceedings of Conf. on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems, Lecture Notes in Computer Science 2619 (Springer Verlag, 2003) 81-96.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28792"><clusterid>788</clusterid><authors>M Sharir</authors><title>A strong-connectivity algorithm and its application in data flow analysis</title><venue>Computers and Mathematics with Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1981</year><pages>7--1</pages><raw>M. Sharir. A strong-connectivity algorithm and its application in data flow analysis. Computers and Mathematics with Applications 7(1):67-72, 1981.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28793"><clusterid>789</clusterid><authors>R E Tarjan</authors><title>Depth first search and linear graph algorithms</title><venue>SIAM Journal of Computing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1972</year><pages>1--2</pages><raw>R.E. Tarjan. Depth first search and linear graph algorithms. SIAM Journal of Computing. 1(2):146-160, 1972.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation><citation id="28794"><clusterid>790</clusterid><authors>R E Tarjan</authors><title>A hierarchical clustering algorithm using strong components</title><venue>Information Processing Letters</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1982</year><pages>14--1</pages><raw>R.E. Tarjan. A hierarchical clustering algorithm using strong components. Information Processing Letters, 14(1):26-29, 1982.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1535</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.win.tue.nl/~jfg/articles/CSR-04-13.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>