<document id="10.1.1.1.1553"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract 1 Language Policy and Localization in Pakistan: Proposal for a Paradigmatic Shift</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper examines the present language policy of Pakistan and its consequences for the indigenous languages of the country. It then relates this to efforts at localization--creating computer software in the languages of the country---and argues that all such efforts have been power-oriented. This means that only those languages have been selected for localization which are used in the domains of power---government, bureaucracy, judiciary, military, commerce, media, education, research etc---thus further strengthening them vis a vis the marginalized languages of the people. It is therefore argued that the efforts at localization should be rights-based i.e. all language communities should be considered equal and their languages should be localized not because of their present use in the domains of power but because they too should be strengthened by being put to such use. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4329"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Tariq Rahman</name><order>1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29173"><authors>Syed Abdullah</authors><title>Pakistan Mein Urdu ka Mas ala [Urdu: The problem</title><venue>of Urdu in Pakistan] Lahore: Maktaba Khayaban-e-Adab</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1976</year><raw>Abdullah, Syed. 1976. Pakistan Mein Urdu ka Mas ala [Urdu: The problem of Urdu in Pakistan] Lahore: Maktaba Khayaban-e-Adab.</raw><contexts><context> the Centre. The story of this patronization is given in detail in several books (see Rahman 1996) but it always fell short of what the more ardent supporters of Urdu demanded (for their position see Abdullah 1976). In the beginning, since a very powerful section of the bureaucracy spoke Urdu as a mother-tongue (being Mohajirs), there was an element of cultural hegemony about the privileging of Urdu. The Mohaj</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29174"><title>Urdu Zabita Sufha Ki Mayar Bandi: Loh ba Loh Ahwal</title><venue>In Muqtadra 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>25--32</pages><raw>Afzal, Mohammad. 2002. ‘Urdu Zabita Sufha Ki Mayar Bandi: Loh ba Loh Ahwal’. In Muqtadra 2002: 25-32.</raw></citation><citation id="29175"><authors>Rafiuddin Ahmad</authors><title>The Bengali Muslims 1871-1906: A Quest for Identity Delhi</title><year>1981</year><editors>ed</editors><publisher>Oxford University Press. This</publisher><raw>Ahmad, Rafiuddin. 1981. The Bengali Muslims 1871-1906: A Quest for Identity Delhi: Oxford University Press. This ed. 1988.</raw></citation><citation id="29176"><authors>Feroze Ahmed</authors><title>The Language Question in Sindh</title><venue>In Zaidi Akbar S. 1992. Regional Imbalances and the National Question in Pakistan Lahore: Vanguard</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><publisher>Books</publisher><raw>Ahmed, Feroze. 1992. ‘The Language Question in Sindh’. In Zaidi Akbar S. 1992. Regional Imbalances and the National Question in Pakistan Lahore: Vanguard Books.</raw><contexts><context> through these languages made them powerful ethnic symbols (Rahman 1996). However, Urdu was not resented or opposed much except in Sindh where there were language riots in January 1971 and July 1972 (Ahmed 1992). But even in Sindh the crucial issue was of power. The Mohajirs were dominant in the urban areas and the rising Sindhi salariat resented this. The most evocative symbol to mobilize the community was</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29177"><title>Urdu Machini Mutarajam ke Mojid Tafsir Ahmed’. Interview by Aleem Ahmad</title><venue>In Muqtadra 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>42--46</pages><raw>Ahmed, Tafsir. 2002. ‘Urdu Machini Mutarajam ke Mojid Tafsir Ahmed’. Interview by Aleem Ahmad. In Muqtadra 2002: 42-46.</raw></citation><citation id="29178"><authors>Hamza Alavi</authors><title>Politics of Ethnicity</title><venue>in India and Pakistan’, Pakistan Progressive 9: 1 (Summer</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1987</year><raw>Alavi, Hamza. 1987. ‘Politics of Ethnicity in India and Pakistan’, Pakistan Progressive 9: 1 (Summer).</raw><contexts><context>ts opposition by the Bengali intelligentsia or what the Pakistani sociologist Hamza Alavi calls the ‘salariat’ ---people who draw salaries from the state (or other employers) and who aspire for jobs (Alavi 1987). One explanation is that the Bengali salariat would have been at a great disadvantage if Urdu, rather than Bengali, would have been used in the lower domains of power (administration, judiciary, edu</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29179"><authors>Benedict Anderson</authors><title>Imagined Communities: Reflections on the Origin and Spread of Nationalism</title><year>1983</year><pubAddress>London</pubAddress><raw>Anderson, Benedict 1983. Imagined Communities: Reflections on the Origin and Spread of Nationalism. London: Verso (revised edition) 19991.</raw><contexts><context>i identity. This symbol was used to ‘imagine’, or construct, a unified Bengali community as communities, such as nations, were constructed through print language and other unifying devices in Europe (Anderson 1983). In Sindh, Balochistan, the N.W.F.P and South Western Punjab the languages used as identity symbols were Sindhi, Balochi and Brahvi, Pashto and Siraiki. The mobilization of people, especially the in</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29180"><authors>Joan Baart,Khwaja A Rehman</authors><title>The Language of the Kandal Shahi Qureshis in Azad Kashmir’, Unpublished manuscript [I am grateful to the authors for showing it to me</title><raw>Baart, Joan and Rehman, Khwaja A. 2003. ‘The Language of the Kandal Shahi Qureshis in Azad Kashmir’, Unpublished manuscript [I am grateful to the authors for showing it to me].</raw></citation><citation id="29181"><authors>Benjamin Barber</authors><title>Jihad Versus Mc World</title><year>1995</year><publisher>Times Books</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Barber, Benjamin. 1995. Jihad Versus Mc World New York: Times Books.</raw></citation><citation id="29182"><authors>Pierre Bourdieu</authors><venue>Language and Symbolic Power</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1991</year><publisher>Polity Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge</pubAddress><raw>Bourdieu, Pierre. 1991. Language and Symbolic Power Cambridge: Polity Press.</raw><contexts><context>s (Nettle and Romaine 2000: 94-97). What happens is that market conditions are such that one’s language becomes deficit on what Bierre Bourdieu, the French Sociologist, would call cultural ‘capital’ (Bourdieu 1991: 230-231). Instead of being an asset it becomes a liability. It prevents one from rising in society. In short, it is ghettoizing. Then, people become ashamed of it as the Punjabis, otherwise a powerf</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29183"><title>World English: A</title><venue>Study of Its Development Clevedon: Multilingual Matters Ltd</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Brutt-Griffler, Janina. 2002. World English: A Study of Its Development Clevedon: Multilingual Matters Ltd.</raw></citation><citation id="29184"><authors>Roland J L Breton</authors><venue>Atlas of the Languages and Ethnic Communities of South Asia. New Delhi</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><publisher>Sage Publications</publisher><pubAddress>London</pubAddress><raw>Breton, Roland J. L. 1997. Atlas of the Languages and Ethnic Communities of South Asia. New Delhi &amp; London: Sage Publications.</raw><contexts><context>i Dhati Tharparkar, Sanghar (Sindh) 3700-5100 SSNP-5: 134 30,000 (in 1992) 700 (in 1998) 55,000-60,000 (in 1981) 2000-3000 (in 1992) 2000-5000 (in 1992) 10,000-13,000 (in 1998) 200,000 plus (in 1987) Breton 1997: 200; Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 SSNP-2: 37 Grimes 2000 Breton 1997: 200 &amp; Grimes 2000 SSNP-5: 11 Breton 1997: 200 &amp; Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Dogri Punjabi, Pahari Azad Kashmir 1 million? Breton 1997: 20</context><context>oma Mominabad (Hunza &amp; Nagar) Gawar-Bati Narsati, Nurisati, Gowari, Aranduiwar, Southern Chitral, Arandu, Kunar river 300 plus (in 2002) SSNP 2: 79; Grimes 2000; personal observation 1500 SSNP-5: 156 Breton 1997: 200s15 Satr, Gowar-bati along PakistanAfghanistan border (in 1992) Ghera Sindhi Ghera, Bara Hyderabad Sindh 10,000 (in 1998) Goaria Cities of Sindh 25,000 Gowro Gabaro, Gabar Khel (different from Ga</context><context>xical similarity to Ghera) Hazargi Hazara, Hezareh, Hezare’i (similar to Persian) Karachi, cities of Sindh (in 1998) 200 (in 1990) 300,000-700,000 plus (in 1992) &amp; Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Breton 1997: 200 &amp; Grimes 2000 SSNP-3: 96 &amp; Grimes 2000 100,000 Grimes 2000 35,000 (in 1998) Quetta 220,000 Jadgali Jatgali, Jatki, Jat Southern Balochistan and Southwest Sindh Jandavra Jhandoria Southern Sindh </context><context>of Bashgal Valley) (in 1998) 60,000-70,000 (in 1995) 2900-5700 (in 1992) 6000 (in 2002) 2000 (in 1992) Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Baart 1999: 4 SSNP-5: 11 Breton 1997: 200; Zaman 2002 SSNP-5: 143; Grimes 2000sKashmiri Keshuri Kashmir &amp; diaspora 105,000 Kati Bashgali, Kativiri, Nuristani 16 (Chitral) Gobar Linkah Valleys (in 1993) 3700-5100 (in 1992) Khetrani None </context><context>esert Nagar Parkar Kundal Shahi Neelam Valley, Azad Kashmir Lasi Lassi Las Bela District (south east Balochistan) (in 1987) 250,000 plus (in 1993) 220,000 (in 1993) 170,000 (in 1998) 30,000 (in 1980) Breton 1997: 200; Grimes: 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 SSNP-5: 11 Breton 1997: 200; Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 Grimes 2000 500 (in 2003) Baart and Rehman 2003 15,000 (in 1998) Loarki Sindh---various pla</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29185"><authors>Erran Carmel</authors><title>American Hegemony in Packaged software trade and the</title><venue>Culture of Software”, The Information Society</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><pages>4</pages><volume>12</volume><raw>Carmel, Erran. 1996. ‘American Hegemony in Packaged software trade and the “Culture of Software”, The Information Society 12: 4.</raw></citation><citation id="29186"><authors>Stephen P Cohen</authors><title>The Pakistan Army Karachi</title><year>1994</year><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><raw>Cohen, Stephen P. 1994. The Pakistan Army Karachi: Oxford University Press.</raw><contexts><context> tradition of the British. The officer corps of the armed forces, as Stephen P. Cohen suggests, was also Anglicized. It was, in his words, the ‘British generation’ which dominated the army till 1971 (Cohen 1994: 162-163). This generation and its values have been described by many army officers and one of the best descriptions comes from Major General A. O. Mitha who says that there were both Westernized and</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29187"><authors>Robert L Cooper</authors><title>Language Planning and Social Change</title><year>1989</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge: Cambridge</pubAddress><raw>Cooper, Robert L. 1989. Language Planning and Social Change. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</raw><contexts><context>us planning (writing books, dictionaries, grammars, orthographies etc) and acquisition planning (teaching languages, pressurizing the state to each them, using them in the media) (for these terms see Cooper 1989). But second, it has jeopardized additive multilingualism recommended by UNESCO (2003) and, of course, by many eminent linguists and educationists (Edwards 1994) as Urdu spreads through schooling, me</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29188"><authors>David Crystal</authors><title>Language Death</title><year>2000</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge: Cambridge</pubAddress><raw>Crystal, David. 2000. Language Death Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</raw><contexts><context>ith which we are familiar through the works of linguists who oppose the arrogance of monolingual English speakers (see the following authors for such arrogance in other contexts Skutnabb-Kangas 2000; Crystal 2000: 84-88; Nettle and Romaine 2000) created much resentment against Urdu and, indeed, may be said to have infused the element of personal reaction to or antagonism against the speakers of Urdu in the fi</context><context>ucational system. 5. An endangered language will progress if its speakers can write their language down. 6. An endangered language will progress if its speakers can make use of electronic technology (Crystal 2000: Chapter 5). The last is especially relevant in the context of localization which we have been describing. Although the candidates for localization, after Urdu, should be the major languages of Pakis</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29189"><authors>2003b</authors><title>Pakistani Urdu: Mazeed Mubahise [Pakistani Urdu: More Debates] Islamabad: Muqtadra Qaumi Zaban</title><raw>Durrani, Atash. 2003b. Pakistani Urdu: Mazeed Mubahise [Pakistani Urdu: More Debates] Islamabad: Muqtadra Qaumi Zaban.</raw><contexts><context>instance, Sahibzada Abdul Qayyum Khan (1864-1937) reported in 1932 that the Pashtuns wanted their children to be instructed in Urdu rather than Pashto (LAD-F 12 October 1932: 132). And even this year (2003), the MMA government has chosen Urdu, not Pashto, as the language of the domains of power, including education, in the N.W.F.P. In Baluchistan too the same phenomenon was noticed. Balochi, Brahvi and </context><context>ing (teaching languages, pressurizing the state to each them, using them in the media) (for these terms see Cooper 1989). But second, it has jeopardized additive multilingualism recommended by UNESCO (2003) and, of course, by many eminent linguists and educationists (Edwards 1994) as Urdu spreads through schooling, media and urbanization, pragmatic pressures make the other Pakistani languages retreat. I</context><context>of Microsoft Dubai office, in software competition (ITCN Asia 2000 Exhibition) in March 2000 in Karachi (Also see Muqtadra 2002: 90-92). He persuaded Abdullah to include changes for Urdu in Unicode-4 (2003). The Unicode is basically for the Arabic script naskh which, according to Durrani, needs less positions than the nastaliq script in which Urdu is written. A completely new letter-based, user-friendly</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29190"><authors>Int</authors><title>Interview of Dr. Atash Durrani with Tariq Rahman [the writer</title><venue>14 Nov 2003, Muqtadra, Islamabad</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Durrani, Atash. Int. 2003. ‘Interview of Dr. Atash Durrani with Tariq Rahman [the writer]’, 14 Nov 2003, Muqtadra, Islamabad.</raw></citation><citation id="29191"><authors>John Edwards</authors><year>1994</year><publisher>Multilingualism</publisher><pubAddress>London: Routledge</pubAddress><raw>Edwards, John. 1994. Multilingualism London: Routledge.</raw><contexts><context>them in the media) (for these terms see Cooper 1989). But second, it has jeopardized additive multilingualism recommended by UNESCO (2003) and, of course, by many eminent linguists and educationists (Edwards 1994) as Urdu spreads through schooling, media and urbanization, pragmatic pressures make the other Pakistani languages retreat. In short, thes5 consequence of privileging Urdu strengthens ethnicity while</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29192"><authors>GOP</authors><title>Report of the Commission on Student’s Problems and Welfare and Problems Islamabad : Ministry of Education</title><venue>Government of Pakistan Grimes, Barbara F</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1966</year><pages>588--598</pages><pubAddress>Pakistan</pubAddress><raw>GOP. 1966. Report of the Commission on Student’s Problems and Welfare and Problems Islamabad : Ministry of Education, Government of Pakistan Grimes, Barbara F (ed). 2000. ‘Pakistan’. In Ethnologue: Languages of the World. 14 th Edition Dallas, Texas; Summer Institute of Linguistics. pp, 588-598.</raw><contexts><context>ion). However, the Commission was also convinced that these schools would produce suitable candidates for filling elitist positions in the military and the civilian sectors of the country’s services (GOP 1966: 18). This meant that the concern for equality was merely a legal nicety. And this, indeed, was what happened. Today the public schools are as well-entrenched in the educational system of the country</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29193"><authors>Jacqueline Hall</authors><title>Convivencia In Catalonia: Languages Living together Barcelona: Fundcio Jaume Bofill</title><year>2001</year><raw>Hall, Jacqueline. 2001. Convivencia In Catalonia: Languages Living together Barcelona: Fundcio Jaume Bofill.</raw></citation><citation id="29194"><authors>HBWI</authors><year>1982</year><raw>HBWI. 1982. History of Bangladesh War of Independence. Dhaka: Government of Bangladesh, Ministry of Information.</raw></citation><citation id="29195"><authors>Arif Hisam</authors><title>Urdu Mahir: EK Ta’aruf</title><venue>In Muqtadra 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>47--49</pages><raw>Hisam, Arif. 2002. ‘Urdu Mahir: EK Ta’aruf’. In Muqtadra 2002: 47-49.</raw><contexts><context>ion specifically meant for promoting the use of Urdu in Pakistan---in 1995. The PDMS has also created Mahir software which works with the latest version of Windows and processes both Urdu and Sindhi (Hisam 2002). The second wave of development came in 1998 when FAST, a private university excelling in computer studies in Lahore, organized the National Urdu Computer Seminar on 12 September 1998 in which it wa</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29196"><authors>Aqeel Abbas Jafri</authors><title>Urdu Web Sites Ki Dunya</title><venue>In Muqtadra 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>71--74</pages><raw>Jafri, Aqeel Abbas. 2002. ‘Urdu Web Sites Ki Dunya’. In Muqtadra 2002: 71-74.</raw><contexts><context>now being developed (Durrani. Int. 2003). Also, Atash Durani is translating and standardizing computer terms which are presently available in Arabic (Durrani. Int. 2003). Urdu websites are available (Jafri 2002), though the official website of Pakistan is in English. Softwares to process Sindhi are being used but there is little development in Punjabi, Pashto, Balochi and other languages. This, however, is </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29197"><authors>Rounaq Jahan</authors><title>Pakistan: Failure in National Integration</title><year>1972</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York and London: Columbia</pubAddress><raw>Jahan, Rounaq. 1972. Pakistan: Failure in National Integration. New York and London: Columbia University Press.</raw><contexts><context>f jute and other products, was predominantly financing the development of West Pakistan or the army which, in turn, was West Pakistani- (or,s4 rather, Punjabi-) dominated (HBWI: 1982: Vol 6: 810-811; Jahan 1972). The language, Bengali, was a symbol of a consolidated Bengali identity in opposition to the West Pakistani identity. This symbol was used to ‘imagine’, or construct, a unified Bengali community as </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29198"><authors>Ahmad Mirza Jameel</authors><title>Nuri Nastaleeq ki Kahani Ahmad Mirza Jameel ki zubani</title><venue>Interview by Khan, Raziuddin and Siddiqui, Wajih Ahmed. In Muqtadra 2002: 4-13. Originally published in Science Digest [Karachi</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Jameel, Ahmad Mirza. 2002. ‘Nuri Nastaleeq ki Kahani Ahmad Mirza Jameel ki zubani’, Interview by Khan, Raziuddin and Siddiqui, Wajih Ahmed. In Muqtadra 2002: 4-13. Originally published in Science Digest [Karachi] 1983.</raw><contexts><context>It was adopted by the Jang Group of newspapers which started publishing their newspapers in it. It was also enthusiastically welcomed by Dr Ishtiaq Hussian Qureshi, Chairman of the Muqtadra, in 1980 (Jameel 2002: 8). Later a number of softwares---Shahkar, Surkhab, Nastaliq, Nizami were created. The last mentioned was created by the Pakistan Data Management Services (PDMS) Karachi, established in Karachi in 1</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29199"><authors>Kenneth Keniston</authors><title>Software Localization: Notes on Technology and Culture’. Working paper 26, program</title><venue>in Science, Technology, and Society</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pubAddress>MIT, Cambridge, Massachusetts</pubAddress><raw>Keniston, Kenneth. 1997. ‘Software Localization: Notes on Technology and Culture’. Working paper 26, program in Science, Technology, and Society, MIT, Cambridge, Massachusetts.</raw><contexts><context>one who has written on localization and its relation to language and culture, calls ‘cultural localization’. In this ‘software written in one culture is adopted to the needs and outlooks of another’ (Keniston 1997: 1). This is important because some assumptions and values do always go in the creation of computer programmes. Erran Carmel, a writer on software development, argues that most of those who work on s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29200"><title>Politics, Culture and Software’, Economic and Political Weekly [Mumbai] 17 January. LAD-Bal. Legislative Assimbly Debates of Baluchistan (dates and other details follow in the text) LAD-F: Legislative Assembly Debates of the North-West Frontier Province (dates and other details follow in the text</title><year>1998</year><raw>---------. 1998. ‘Politics, Culture and Software’, Economic and Political Weekly [Mumbai] 17 January. LAD-Bal. Legislative Assimbly Debates of Baluchistan (dates and other details follow in the text) LAD-F: Legislative Assembly Debates of the North-West Frontier Province (dates and other details follow in the text).</raw></citation><citation id="29201"><authors>Wayne A Lunsford</authors><title>An Overview of Linguistic Structures in Torwali: A Language of Northern Pakistan’, unpublished M.A</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><pubAddress>Arlington</pubAddress><tech>Thesis</tech><raw>Lunsford, Wayne A. 2001. ‘An Overview of Linguistic Structures in Torwali: A Language of Northern Pakistan’, unpublished M.A. Thesis, The University of Texas, Arlington.</raw></citation><citation id="29202"><authors>Sabiha Mansoor</authors><venue>Punjabi, Urdu, English in Pakistan: A Sociolinguistic Study. Lahore: Vanguard</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><raw>Mansoor, Sabiha. 1993. Punjabi, Urdu, English in Pakistan: A Sociolinguistic Study. Lahore: Vanguard.</raw><contexts><context>amed of it as the Punjabis, otherwise a powerful majority in Pakistan, are observed to be by the present author and others (for a survey of the attitude of Punjabi students towards their language see Mansoor 1993: 49-54). Or, even if language movements and ethnic pride does not make them ashamed of their languages, they do not want to teach them to their children because that would be overburdening the childr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29203"><authors>A O Mitha</authors><title>Unlikely Beginnings: A Soldier’s Life Karachi</title><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><raw>Mitha, A. O. 2003. Unlikely Beginnings: A Soldier’s Life Karachi: Oxford University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="29204"><title>Akhbar-e-Urdu: Urdu Software Number (Jan-Feb 2002) Islamabad: Muqtadra Qaumi Zaban</title><raw>Muqtadra. 2002. Akhbar-e-Urdu: Urdu Software Number (Jan-Feb 2002) Islamabad: Muqtadra Qaumi Zaban.</raw></citation><citation id="29205"><authors>2002a Akhbar-e-Urdu</authors><raw>Muqtadra. 2002a. Akhbar-e-Urdu (June).</raw></citation><citation id="29206"><authors>Akhbar-e-Urdu</authors><raw>Muqtadra. 2003. Akhbar-e-Urdu (June).</raw></citation><citation id="29207"><authors>Daniel Nettle,Suzanne Romaine</authors><title>Vanishing Voices: the Extinction</title><venue>of the World’s Languages</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>Nettle, Daniel and Romaine, Suzanne. 2000. Vanishing Voices: the Extinction of the World’s Languages New York: Oxford University Press.</raw><contexts><context>liar through the works of linguists who oppose the arrogance of monolingual English speakers (see the following authors for such arrogance in other contexts Skutnabb-Kangas 2000; Crystal 2000: 84-88; Nettle and Romaine 2000) created much resentment against Urdu and, indeed, may be said to have infused the element of personal reaction to or antagonism against the speakers of Urdu in the first twenty years of Pakistan’s e</context><context> and are learning Urdu. This phenomenon, sometimes called ‘voluntary shift’, is not really ‘voluntary’ as the case of the native Hawaiians, narrated by Daniel Nettle and Suzanne Romaine, illustrates (Nettle and Romaine 2000: 94-97). What happens is that market conditions are such that one’s language becomes deficit on what Bierre Bourdieu, the French Sociologist, would call cultural ‘capital’ (Bourdieu 1991: 230-231). I</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29208"><authors>Robert Phillipson</authors><title>Linguistic Imperialism</title><year>1992</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>London: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>Phillipson, Robert. 1992. Linguistic Imperialism London: Oxford University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="29209"><authors>Tariq Rahman</authors><venue>Language and Polities in Pakistan Karachi</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><raw>Rahman, Tariq. 1996. Language and Polities in Pakistan Karachi: Oxford University Press.</raw><contexts><context>and settled down in large numbers in Pakistani, especially Sindhi, cities. Although it was used by educated people in Punjab, the North West Frontier Province and Kashmir because of British policies (Rahman 1996: Chapter 3), it was not considered a threat for the indigenous languages of the area. It was because of the linguistic and educational policies of the Pakistani political decision-makers that there i</context><context>s. However, it has been resisted because it has been patronized, often in insensitive ways, by the ruling elite of the Centre. The story of this patronization is given in detail in several books (see Rahman 1996) but it always fell short of what the more ardent supporters of Urdu demanded (for their position see Abdullah 1976). In the beginning, since a very powerful section of the bureaucracy spoke Urdu as </context><context>Balochi and Brahvi, Pashto and Siraiki. The mobilization of people, especially the intelligentsia, as a pressure group which became possible through these languages made them powerful ethnic symbols (Rahman 1996). However, Urdu was not resented or opposed much except in Sindh where there were language riots in January 1971 and July 1972 (Ahmed 1992). But even in Sindh the crucial issue was of power. The Moha</context><context>D-Bal 21 June and 15 April 1990). The language activists enthusiastically prepared instructional material but on 8 November 1992, these languages were made optional and parents switched back to Urdu (Rahman 1996: 169). Such decisions amount to endangering the survival of minor languages and they devalue even major ones but they are precisely the kind of policies which have created what is often called ‘Urdu </context><context> and judiciary is Sindhi. Sindhi was used in Sindh ever since the British conquest and its use, as its supporters complain, is now less in the cities (especially Karachi) than it was in British days (Rahman 1996: Chapter 7). The only other language used by some schools upto class-5 and in the madrassas is Pashto. Except for these language, and in these restricted domains, Pakistan’s indigenous languages are </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29210"><title>Language, Education and Culture Karachi</title><year>1999</year><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><raw>-------- 1999. Language, Education and Culture Karachi: Oxford University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="29211"><title>Ideology and Power, Language Learning Among the Muslims of Pakistan and North India Karachi</title><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><raw>--------. 2002 Language, Ideology and Power, Language Learning Among the Muslims of Pakistan and North India Karachi: Oxford University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="29212"><authors>Tove Skutnabb-Kangas</authors><title>Linguistic Genocide</title><venue>In Education or Worldwide Diversity and Human Rights</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><publisher>Erlbaum</publisher><pubAddress>London: Lawrence</pubAddress><raw>Skutnabb-Kangas; Tove, 2000. Linguistic Genocide In Education or Worldwide Diversity and Human Rights London: Lawrence Erlbaum.</raw><contexts><context>ages. This position, with which we are familiar through the works of linguists who oppose the arrogance of monolingual English speakers (see the following authors for such arrogance in other contexts Skutnabb-Kangas 2000; Crystal 2000: 84-88; Nettle and Romaine 2000) created much resentment against Urdu and, indeed, may be said to have infused the element of personal reaction to or antagonism against the speakers of </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29213"><authors>SSNP</authors><title>Sociolinguistic Survey of Northern Pakistan 5 vols</title><venue>Islamabad: National Institute of Pakistan Studies and Summer Institute of Linguistics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><raw>SSNP. 1992. Sociolinguistic Survey of Northern Pakistan 5 vols. Islamabad: National Institute of Pakistan Studies and Summer Institute of Linguistics.</raw></citation><citation id="29214"><title>Education in a Multilingual World</title><pubAddress>Paris: UNESCO</pubAddress><raw>UNESCO. 2003. Education in a Multilingual World Paris: UNESCO.</raw></citation><citation id="29215"><title>Report on a Language Survey Trip to the Bishigram Valley [http://www.geocities.com/kcs_kalam/ushoji.html</title><raw>Zaman, Muhammad. 2002. Report on a Language Survey Trip to the Bishigram Valley [http://www.geocities.com/kcs_kalam/ushoji.html].</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.elda.fr/en/proj/scalla/SCALLA2004/rahman.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>6f7fc1d0d12fc0898abfc7304179b942b4d66533</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>