<document id="10.1.1.1.1554"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Research article A quantitative analysis of qualitative studies in clinical journals for the 2000 publishing year</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4330"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Biomed Central</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4331"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Kathleen Ann Mckibbon</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Canada L8S 1V8</address><order>2</order></author><author id="4332"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Cynthia S Gadd Open Access</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Canada L8S 1V8</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">csg@cbmi.pitt.edu</email><order>3</order></author><author id="4333"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Kathleen Ann Mckibbon</name><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">mckib@mcmaster.ca</email><order>4</order></author><author id="4334"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Cynthia S Gadd</name><order>5</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29216"><authors>Miller WL</authors><title>Crabtree BF: Clinical research. Handbook of Qualitative Research 2nd edition. Edited by</title><venue>Denzin N K and Lincoln Y S. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>2001--607</pages><raw>Miller WL, Crabtree BF: Clinical research. Handbook of Qualitative Research 2nd edition. Edited by: Denzin N K and Lincoln Y S. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2001:607-631.</raw><contexts><context>exts, and experiences of individuals or groups, can be best addressed using qualitative methods. Other issues benefit from interleaving or integration of both research traditions. Miller and Crabtree [1], describe their Page 1 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes)sBMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making 2004, 4:11 http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11 experiences working in family me</context><context>hodology Studies (n = 37), and Studies from Nursing Journals (n = 211) Category All studies % All studies # Mixed Methods mixed methods or multipardigmatic studies as described by Miller and Crabtree [1] and Creswell [18] is encouraging for those who espouse harnessing methodologies appropriate for exploring, explaining, and interpreting the complexities and ranges of issues in health care practice a</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29217"><authors>Creswell JW</authors><title>Fetters MD, Ivankova NY: Designing a mixed methods study in primary care</title><venue>Annals of Family Medicine</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>2--7</pages><volume>2004</volume><raw>Creswell JW, Fetters MD, Ivankova NY: Designing a mixed methods study in primary care. Annals of Family Medicine 2004, 2:7-12.</raw><contexts><context>th care. Creswell and colleagues expand on this theme by stating that &amp;quot;When used in combination, both quantitative and qualitative data yield a more complete analysis, and they complement each other&amp;quot; [2]. Most studies in the major clinical journals have been quantitative studies. Very few qualitative studies and even fewer that combine both qualitative and quantitative approaches are published. An ex</context><context> in the United Kingdom. Many other examples exist; Creswell and colleagues describe 5 additional mixed methods studies in primary care as well as provide criteria for evaluating mixed methods studies [2]. We postulate that qualitative studies, either stand-alone reports or studies with mixed methods, are occurring more frequently in health care. This paper was done to describe the publishing of quali</context><context>ersons studied, setting, and disease or health condition considered. In addition, studies with mixed methods were further analyzed although we did not use stringent criteria for assessing the quality [2] of the combination of methods. We identified mixed methods articles using a loose criterion of &amp;quot;some numerical or statistical analysis of quantitative data or qualitative data that had been turned in</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29218"><authors>K Jolly,F Bradley,S Sharp,H Smith</authors><title>Mant D: Follow-up care in general practice of patients with myocardial infarction or angina pectoris: initial results of the SHIP trial. Southampton Heart Integrated Care Project. Fam Pract</title><year>1998</year><pages>15--548</pages><raw>Jolly K, Bradley F, Sharp S, Smith H, Mant D: Follow-up care in general practice of patients with myocardial infarction or angina pectoris: initial results of the SHIP trial. Southampton Heart Integrated Care Project. Fam Pract 1998, 15:548-555.</raw><contexts><context>oth qualitative and quantitative approaches are published. An example of the breadth of qualitative studies and how findings and results can be combined across paradigms is a study by Jolly and Wiles [3,4] who used mixed methods to study a nurse-led intervention for 422 adults after myocardial infarction and 175 adults with new-onset angina in 67 general practices in the United Kingdom. Their study sho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29219"><authors>R Wiles</authors><title>Patients' perceptions of their heart attack and recovery: the influence of epidemiological &amp;quot;evidence&amp;quot; and personal experience. Soc Sci Med</title><year>1998</year><pages>46--1477</pages><raw>Wiles R: Patients' perceptions of their heart attack and recovery: the influence of epidemiological &amp;quot;evidence&amp;quot; and personal experience. Soc Sci Med 1998, 46:1477-1486.</raw><contexts><context>oth qualitative and quantitative approaches are published. An example of the breadth of qualitative studies and how findings and results can be combined across paradigms is a study by Jolly and Wiles [3,4] who used mixed methods to study a nurse-led intervention for 422 adults after myocardial infarction and 175 adults with new-onset angina in 67 general practices in the United Kingdom. Their study sho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29220"><authors>Willms</authors><title>DG: A new stage, a new life: individual success in quitting smoking. Soc Sci Med</title><year>1991</year><pages>33--1365</pages><raw>Willms DG: A new stage, a new life: individual success in quitting smoking. Soc Sci Med 1991, 33:1365-1371.</raw></citation><citation id="29221"><authors>Gilbert JR,Wilson DM,Best JA,Taylor DW,Lindsay EA,J Singer,Willms</authors><title>DG: Smoking cessation in primary care. A randomized controlled trial of nicotine-bearing chewing gum. J Fam Pract</title><year>1989</year><pages>28--49</pages><raw>Gilbert JR, Wilson DM, Best JA, Taylor DW, Lindsay EA, Singer J, Willms DG: Smoking cessation in primary care. A randomized controlled trial of nicotine-bearing chewing gum. J Fam Pract 1989, 28:49-55.</raw></citation><citation id="29222"><authors>Willms GG,Best JA,W Taylor</authors><title>D: A systematic approach for using qualitative methods in primary prevention research. Medical Anthropology Quarterly</title><year>1990</year><pages>4--391</pages><raw>Willms GG, Best JA, W Taylor D: A systematic approach for using qualitative methods in primary prevention research. Medical Anthropology Quarterly 1990, 4:391-409.</raw></citation><citation id="29223"><authors>Borkan JM,M Quirk,Sullivan</authors><title>M: Finding meaning after the fall: injury narratives from elderly hip fracture patients. Soc Sci Med</title><year>1991</year><pages>33--947</pages><raw>Borkan JM, Quirk M, Sullivan M: Finding meaning after the fall: injury narratives from elderly hip fracture patients. Soc Sci Med 1991, 33:947-957.</raw><contexts><context>ir attitudes towards smoking and thus stop smoking. Another effective example of integrated qualitative (ethnography) and quantitative (epidemiology) methods was a study done by Borkan and colleagues [8] to determine predictors of recovery after hip fracture in elderly patients. Traditional predictors such as age, type of break, and comorbidity, were collected by using standard questionnaires. In-dep</context><context>l or statistical analysis of quantitative data or qualitative data that had been turned into quantitative data&amp;quot;. (An example of quantifying qualitative data is the study done by Borkan and colleagues [8] on hip fracture.) The analysis had to be fairly substantial– for example, a simple descriptive analysis of baseline demographics of the participants was not sufficient to be included as a mixed metho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29224"><authors>J Donovan,N Mills,M Smith,L Brindle,A Jacoby,T Peters,S Frankel,D Neal</authors><title>Hamdy F: Quality improvement report: Improving design and conduct of randomised trials by embedding them in qualitative research: ProtecT (prostate testing for cancer and treatment) study. Commentary: presenting unbiased Page 7 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes)  Medical Informatics and Decision Making 2004, 4:11 http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11 information to patients can be difficult.[see comment</title><venue>BMJ</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>325--766</pages><volume>2002</volume><raw>Donovan J, Mills N, Smith M, Brindle L, Jacoby A, Peters T, Frankel S, Neal D, Hamdy F: Quality improvement report: Improving design and conduct of randomised trials by embedding them in qualitative research: ProtecT (prostate testing for cancer and treatment) study. Commentary: presenting unbiased Page 7 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes) BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making 2004, 4:11 http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11 information to patients can be difficult.[see comment]. BMJ 2002, 325:766-770.</raw><contexts><context>onnection with the outside world also showed better ambulation at 3 and 6 months than persons with a more narrow and confined view of the fracture and its resulting disability. Donovan and colleagues [9] used mixed methods to study prostate cancer screening and treatment choices to determine why study recruitment was lower than expected. Rousseau and Eccles and their colleagues [10,11] used qualitati</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29225"><authors>N Rousseau,E McColl,J Newton,J Grimshaw,Eccles</authors><title>M: Practice based, longitudinal, qualitative interview study of computerised evidence based guidelines in primary care.[see comment</title><venue>BMJ</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>326--314</pages><volume>2003</volume><raw>Rousseau N, McColl E, Newton J, Grimshaw J, Eccles M: Practice based, longitudinal, qualitative interview study of computerised evidence based guidelines in primary care.[see comment]. BMJ 2003, 326:314.</raw><contexts><context>van and colleagues [9] used mixed methods to study prostate cancer screening and treatment choices to determine why study recruitment was lower than expected. Rousseau and Eccles and their colleagues [10,11] used qualitative methods (case interviews) to explain the limited use of computerized guidelines for asthma and angina in a primary care study done in the United Kingdom. Many other examples exist; C</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29226"><authors>M Eccles,E McColl,N Steen,N Rousseau,J Grimshaw,D Parkin</authors><title>Purves I: Effect of computerised evidence based guidelines on management of asthma and angina in adults in primary care: cluster randomised controlled trial.[see comment</title><venue>BMJ</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>325--941</pages><volume>2002</volume><raw>Eccles M, McColl E, Steen N, Rousseau N, Grimshaw J, Parkin D, Purves I: Effect of computerised evidence based guidelines on management of asthma and angina in adults in primary care: cluster randomised controlled trial.[see comment]. BMJ 2002, 325:941.</raw><contexts><context>van and colleagues [9] used mixed methods to study prostate cancer screening and treatment choices to determine why study recruitment was lower than expected. Rousseau and Eccles and their colleagues [10,11] used qualitative methods (case interviews) to explain the limited use of computerized guidelines for asthma and angina in a primary care study done in the United Kingdom. Many other examples exist; C</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29227"><authors>Haynes</authors><title>RB: ACP Journal Club: Purpose and procedure. [http:/ /www/acpjc.org/shared/purpose_and_procedure.htm</title><raw>Haynes RB: ACP Journal Club: Purpose and procedure. [http:/ /www/acpjc.org/shared/purpose_and_procedure.htm].</raw><contexts><context>erapy, diagnosis, prognosis, etiology, economics, clinical prediction guides, differential diagnosis, and qualitative studies and if so, did each meet predefined methodology criteria for study quality[12]. For 2000 we intensified our data collection to provide data to update and develop new clinical retrieval searching hedges for MEDLINE, PsycINFO, CINAHL, and EMBASE using methods described by Haynes </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29228"><authors>Haynes RB,N Wilczynski,McKibbon KA,Walker CJ,Sinclair</authors><title>JC: Developing optimal search strategies for detecting clinically sound studies</title><venue>in MEDLINE. J Am Med Inform Assoc</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>1--447</pages><raw>Haynes RB, Wilczynski N, McKibbon KA, Walker CJ, Sinclair JC: Developing optimal search strategies for detecting clinically sound studies in MEDLINE. J Am Med Inform Assoc 1994, 1:447-458.</raw><contexts><context>intensified our data collection to provide data to update and develop new clinical retrieval searching hedges for MEDLINE, PsycINFO, CINAHL, and EMBASE using methods described by Haynes and colleagues[13]. One hundred and seventy journals provided data for this article. The staff of the Health Information Research Unit has established quality criteria for the 8 categories of clinical literature that m</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29229"><authors>Giacomini MK,Cook</authors><title>DJ: Users' guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care B. What are the results and how do they help me care for my patients? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group</title><venue>JAMA</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>284--478</pages><volume>2000</volume><raw>Giacomini MK, Cook DJ: Users' guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care B. What are the results and how do they help me care for my patients? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group. JAMA 2000, 284:478-482.</raw><contexts><context>irly substantial– for example, a simple descriptive analysis of baseline demographics of the participants was not sufficient to be included as a mixed methods article. In addition, Giacomini and Cook [14,15], as part of the Evidence-Based Working Group in the Users' Guides to the Medical Literature, describe attributes that they have identified as belonging to high-quality qualitative studies: participan</context><context>h BMJ publishing 12. The highest-ranking journal with qualitative studies was Annals of Internal Medicine, ranked number 6. JAMA, ranked number 2, published articles about qualitative studies in 2000 [14,15] but did not publish any qualitative studies. Mixed qualitative and quantitative studies 37 qualitative studies (11%) included qualitative and quantitative methods and analyses. These were published i</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29230"><authors>Giacomini MK,Cook</authors><title>DJ: Users' guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care A. Are the results of the study valid? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group</title><venue>JAMA</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>284--357</pages><volume>2000</volume><raw>Giacomini MK, Cook DJ: Users' guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care A. Are the results of the study valid? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group. JAMA 2000, 284:357-362.</raw><contexts><context>irly substantial– for example, a simple descriptive analysis of baseline demographics of the participants was not sufficient to be included as a mixed methods article. In addition, Giacomini and Cook [14,15], as part of the Evidence-Based Working Group in the Users' Guides to the Medical Literature, describe attributes that they have identified as belonging to high-quality qualitative studies: participan</context><context>h BMJ publishing 12. The highest-ranking journal with qualitative studies was Annals of Internal Medicine, ranked number 6. JAMA, ranked number 2, published articles about qualitative studies in 2000 [14,15] but did not publish any qualitative studies. Mixed qualitative and quantitative studies 37 qualitative studies (11%) included qualitative and quantitative methods and analyses. These were published i</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29231"><authors>Denzin NK,Lincoln</authors><title>YS: Handbook of Qualitative Research. 2nd edition</title><venue>Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><raw>Denzin NK, Lincoln YS: Handbook of Qualitative Research. 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2001.</raw><contexts><context>were used and if an additional methodology was found it was added to the list of types using definitions and descriptions from the Handbook of Qualitative Analysis, 2 nd edition by Denzin and Lincoln [16]. Data collection and sampling procedures were also extracted. Multiple designations were allowed. To assess the reproducibility a random 10% (n = 35) sample of citations was reviewed using predefined</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29232"><title>Tongprateep T: The essential elements of spirituality among rural Thai elders</title><venue>J Adv Nurs</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>31--197</pages><volume>2000</volume><raw>Tongprateep T: The essential elements of spirituality among rural Thai elders. J Adv Nurs 2000, 31:197-203.</raw><contexts><context>%), general issues such as vaccinations or Internet use, and nonspecific spectrum of diseases (e.g., all patients in a clinic) (12%). Many uncommon issues were also assessed. For example, Tongprateep [17] reports a phenomenology study designed to help nurses better understand essential elements of spirituality and health among rural Thai elders. Analysis of the 37 articles with mixed methods showed si</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29233"><authors>Creswell JW</authors><title>Research Design: Qualitative, Quantative and Mixed Methods Approaches. 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2003. Pre-publication history The pre-publication history for this paper can be accessed here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11/prepub Publish with BioMed Central and every scientist can read your work free of charge &amp;quot;BioMed Central will be the most significant development for disseminating the results of biomedical research in our lifetime.&amp;quot; Sir Paul Nurse, Cancer Research UK Your research papers will be: available free of charge to the entire biomedical community peer reviewed and published immediately upon acceptance cited in PubMed and archived on PubMed Central yours — you keep the copyright BioMedcentral Submit your manuscript here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/info/publishing_adv.asp Page 8 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes</title><raw>Creswell JW: Research Design: Qualitative, Quantative and Mixed Methods Approaches. 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2003. Pre-publication history The pre-publication history for this paper can be accessed here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11/prepub Publish with BioMed Central and every scientist can read your work free of charge &amp;quot;BioMed Central will be the most significant development for disseminating the results of biomedical research in our lifetime.&amp;quot; Sir Paul Nurse, Cancer Research UK Your research papers will be: available free of charge to the entire biomedical community peer reviewed and published immediately upon acceptance cited in PubMed and archived on PubMed Central yours — you keep the copyright BioMedcentral Submit your manuscript here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/info/publishing_adv.asp Page 8 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes)</raw><contexts><context>(n = 37), and Studies from Nursing Journals (n = 211) Category All studies % All studies # Mixed Methods mixed methods or multipardigmatic studies as described by Miller and Crabtree [1] and Creswell [18] is encouraging for those who espouse harnessing methodologies appropriate for exploring, explaining, and interpreting the complexities and ranges of issues in health care practice and research. It is</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.biomedcentral.com/content/pdf/1472-6947-4-11.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>fb8e2f2523a604c645e672faab00c5974eec18b9</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>