<document id="10.1.1.1.1557"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">WordNet Exploitation through a Distributed Network of Servers</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract. The architecture of a lexical database in which multilingual semantic networks would be stored requires the incorporation of flexible mechanisms and services, which would enable the efficient navigation within and across lexical data. We report on WordNet Management System (WMS), a system that functions as the interconnection and communication link between a user and a number of interlinked WordNets. Semantic information is being accessed through a distributed network of servers, forming a large-scale multilingual semantic network. 1</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1270">tagging</keyword><keyword id="1271">the annotation of each content word with a semantic category. WordNet</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4338"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">I. D. Koutsoubos</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patras, Greece</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">koutsoub@cti.gr</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4339"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Vassilis Andrikopoulos</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patras, Greece</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">andrikop@ceid.upatras.gr</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4340"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Dimitris Christodoulakis</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patras, Greece</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">dxri@cti.gr</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29254"><title>WordNet: An Electronic Lexical Database</title><year>1998</year><editors>Fellbaum Ch. (ed</editors><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, M.A</pubAddress><raw>Fellbaum Ch. (ed.) (1998) WordNet: An Electronic Lexical Database, Cambridge, M.A: MIT Press.</raw></citation><citation id="29255"><authors>S Stamou,K Oflazer,K Pala,D Christodoulakis,D Cristea,D Tufis,S Koeva,G Totkov,D Dutoit,M Grigoriadou</authors><title>BALKANET: A Multilingual Semantic Network for Balkan Languages</title><venue>In Proceedings of the GWA 1 st International WordNet Conference, Mysore</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pubAddress>India</pubAddress><raw>Stamou S., Oflazer K., Pala K., Christodoulakis D., Cristea D., Tufis D., Koeva S., Totkov G., Dutoit D., Grigoriadou M. (2002) “BALKANET: A Multilingual Semantic Network for Balkan Languages”. In Proceedings of the GWA 1 st International WordNet Conference, Mysore, India, Jan. 21–25, 2002.</raw></citation><citation id="29256"><title>EuroWordNet: A Multilingual Database with Lexical Semantic Networks</title><year>1998</year><editors>Vossen P. (ed</editors><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><pubAddress>Dordrecht</pubAddress><raw>Vossen P. (ed.) (1998) EuroWordNet: A Multilingual Database with Lexical Semantic Networks, Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht.</raw><contexts><context>to them. The architecture of WMS is summarized in the following figures. 3.1 Network of Servers Each WMS server hosts one (or more) wordnet data sources which are interconnected via the ILI structure [3]. WordNet data sources are identified by language and version (creating a unique pair). A WMS server is considered a node in the P2P network and is treated equally by its peers. For each peer to acqui</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29257"><authors>T Pavelek,K Pala</authors><title>WordNet standardization from a practical point of view</title><venue>In Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on WordNet Structures and Standardisation, and How These Affect WordNet Applications and Evaluation, Las Palmas, Gran Canaria. 30–34</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Pavelek, T. and Pala K. (2002) “WordNet standardization from a practical point of view”. In Proceedings of the LREC Workshop on WordNet Structures and Standardisation, and How These Affect WordNet Applications and Evaluation, Las Palmas, Gran Canaria. 30–34, May 28th, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>c medium has to implement. Currently, WMS provides by default mechanisms for access to the majority of commercial Relational Database Management Systems and to XML files that use the VisDic formalism [5]. 4 Discussion and Future Enhancements We have presented the architecture of WordNet Management System, a distributed network of servers that provides facilities for WordNet exploitation. In the futur</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29258"><authors>M Panti,L Penserini,L Spalazzi</authors><title>A pure P2P approach to information integration</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2002</year><tech>Tec. Report 2002-02-19</tech><raw>Panti M., Penserini L., Spalazzi L. (2002) “A pure P2P approach to information integration”. Tec. Report 2002-02-19, Istituto di Informatica, University of Ancona, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>t mediator do not deal with decentralized systems with participants andsWordNet Exploitation through a Distributed Network of Servers 267 information sources location upredictability. As mentioned in [6] a P2P approach would be a more appropriate solution, since it lacks a centralized structure and promotes the equality among peers and their collaboration only for the time necessary to fulfill a requ</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29259"><authors>R J Bayardo,W Bohrer</authors><title>InfoSleuth: Agent-Based Semantic Integration of Information in Open and Dynamic Environments</title><venue>In Proceedings of the ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><volume>26</volume><raw>R. J. Bayardo, W. Bohrer, et al. (1997) “InfoSleuth: Agent-Based Semantic Integration of Information in Open and Dynamic Environments”. In Proceedings of the ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data, vol. 26, No. 2, June 1997.</raw><contexts><context> environment where no a priori knowledge of the location of specific data is possible, the traditional mediator and federated databases approaches are not appropriate. Furthermore, approaches such as [7,9,10] that provide a source- and query-independent mediator do not deal with decentralized systems with participants andsWordNet Exploitation through a Distributed Network of Servers 267 information source</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29260"><authors>H Garcia-Molina,Y Papakonstantinou</authors><title>The TSIMMIS approach to mediation: data models and languages</title><venue>In Journals of Intelligent Information Systems, 8:117–132</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>H. Garcia-Molina, Y. Papakonstantinou, et al. (1997) “The TSIMMIS approach to mediation: data models and languages”. In Journals of Intelligent Information Systems, 8:117–132, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>d through the WMS. From its definition, WMS falls into the Data Integration framework, being able to manage a distributed, dynamic network of homogeneous data. Previous systems built for this purpose [8,11,12] are often characterized by a centralized system that controls and manages interactions among distributed information sources in order to serve requests for data. As a consequence, in a distributed en</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29261"><authors>A Levy,A Rajaraman,J Ordille</authors><title>Querying Heterogeneous Information Sources Using Source Descriptions</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 22 nd VLDB Confernece</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><raw>A. Levy, A. Rajaraman, J. Ordille (1996) “Querying Heterogeneous Information Sources Using Source Descriptions”. In Proceedings of the 22 nd VLDB Confernece, September, 1996.</raw><contexts><context> environment where no a priori knowledge of the location of specific data is possible, the traditional mediator and federated databases approaches are not appropriate. Furthermore, approaches such as [7,9,10] that provide a source- and query-independent mediator do not deal with decentralized systems with participants andsWordNet Exploitation through a Distributed Network of Servers 267 information source</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29262"><authors>M Nodine,W Bohrer,A H</authors><title>Hiong Ngu (1999) “Semantic Brokering over Dynamic Heterogeneous Data Sources in InfoSleuth</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 15þ International Conference on Data Engineering</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>M. Nodine, W. Bohrer, A. H. Hiong Ngu (1999) “Semantic Brokering over Dynamic Heterogeneous Data Sources in InfoSleuth”. In Proceedings of the 15þ International Conference on Data Engineering, March 1999.</raw><contexts><context> environment where no a priori knowledge of the location of specific data is possible, the traditional mediator and federated databases approaches are not appropriate. Furthermore, approaches such as [7,9,10] that provide a source- and query-independent mediator do not deal with decentralized systems with participants andsWordNet Exploitation through a Distributed Network of Servers 267 information source</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29263"><authors>A Sheth,J Larson</authors><title>Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed, Heterogeneous and Anonymous Databases</title><venue>In ACM Transaction on Database Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><volume>22</volume><raw>A. Sheth and J. Larson (1990) “Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed, Heterogeneous and Anonymous Databases”. In ACM Transaction on Database Systems, 22(3), 1990.</raw><contexts><context>d through the WMS. From its definition, WMS falls into the Data Integration framework, being able to manage a distributed, dynamic network of homogeneous data. Previous systems built for this purpose [8,11,12] are often characterized by a centralized system that controls and manages interactions among distributed information sources in order to serve requests for data. As a consequence, in a distributed en</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29264"><authors>G Wiedehold</authors><title>Mediators in the Architecture of Future Information Systems</title><venue>In IEEE Computer Magazine</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>25--38</pages><raw>G. Wiedehold (1992) “Mediators in the Architecture of Future Information Systems”. In IEEE Computer Magazine, 25:38–49, March 1992.</raw><contexts><context>d through the WMS. From its definition, WMS falls into the Data Integration framework, being able to manage a distributed, dynamic network of homogeneous data. Previous systems built for this purpose [8,11,12] are often characterized by a centralized system that controls and manages interactions among distributed information sources in order to serve requests for data. As a consequence, in a distributed en</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.fi.muni.cz/gwc2004/proc/104.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>d852ee7dcbdf19015ee1415cd1f9f6ab77c01e0f</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>