<document id="10.1.1.1.1555"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Object-Relational Management of Multiply Represented Geographic Entities</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">©2003 IEEE. Personal use of this material is permitted. However, permission to reprint/republish this material for advertising or promotional purposes or for creating new collective works for resale or redistribution to servers or lists, or to reuse any copyrighted component of this work in other works must be obtained from the IEEE. This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work. Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author's copyright. In most cases, these works may not be reposted without the explicit permission of the copyright holder.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4335"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Anders Friis-christensen</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Denmark</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">afc@kms.dk</email><order>1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29234"><authors>G Booch,J Rumbaugh,I Jacobson</authors><title>The Unified Modeling Language User Guide</title><year>1999</year><publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher><raw>G. Booch, J. Rumbaugh, and I. Jacobson. The Unified Modeling Language User Guide. Addison-Wesley, 1999.</raw><contexts><context> restoring consistency, but specify also the conditions that should trigger an update action. The MRSL has a graphical and a lexical syntax. The former is based on the Unified Modeling Language (UML) [1], and we use the Object Constraint Language (OCL) [17] to specify constraints. A more thorough description of the MRSL is given elsewhere [6, 7]. An MRSL specification, termed an MRSchema, is used to </context><context>in the two databases is that aerial photo interpretation needs not be duplicated. Simplified building schemas in UML are seen on Figure 2. (We assume that the reader is familiar with the UML notation [1].) Only representative attributes are given—e.g., Technical map (1:5,000) TM_Building id : Local_id shape : Polygon Topographic map (1:10,000) T10_Building id : Local_id shape : Polygon usage : UseCod</context><context>s Building Attributes: id : Global_id, shape : Polygon, usage : BR_useCode, numOfFloors : Integer Operations: checkInside(Point) : Boolean, placeInside(Point) Object Correspondence: o1: &lt;&lt;master&gt;&gt; tm [1] : TM_Building, o2: br [1] : BR_Building Value Correspondence: m1: shape = &lt;&lt;master-attribute&gt;&gt; tm.shape, m2: usage = &lt;&lt;master-attribute&gt;&gt; br.usage, m3: numOfFloors = &lt;&lt;master&gt;&gt; br.numOfFloors, v1: sh</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29235"><authors>Circular</authors><title>About the Establishment of the Buildings and Dwellings Register</title><venue>Ministry of Housing, January</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1977</year><volume>6</volume><raw>BR. Circular About the Establishment of the Buildings and Dwellings Register. Ministry of Housing, January 6, 1977 (in Danish).</raw><contexts><context>ding varies across the three databases, which complicates the process of creating an MRSchema. The definitions are seen in Table 1. The definitions given here are simplifications of the official ones [2, 12, 16]. An example of the building representations is seen in Figure 3. It is seen that several inconsistencies occur between the shapes of TM and T10 buildings (see the dashed and solid polygons). The shap</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29236"><authors>B P Buttenfield,J S DeLotto</authors><title>Multiple Representations – Scientific Report for the Specialist Meeting</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1989</year><pubAddress>Buffalo, USA</pubAddress><tech>Report 89-3, NCGIA</tech><raw>B. P. Buttenfield and J. S. DeLotto. Multiple Representations – Scientific Report for the Specialist Meeting. Report 89-3, NCGIA, Department of Geography, SUNY Buffalo, USA, 1989.</raw><contexts><context>hich support different applications. This phenomenon, termed multiple representation, invariably leads to inconsistencies, which has been recognized as a key problem in geographic database management [3, 11]. Ensuring consistency among databases describing the same entities (termed representation databases) improves the quality and applicability of data. In this paper, we focus on the case where multiple</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29237"><authors>S Ceri,J Widom</authors><title>Managing Semantic Heterogeneity with Production Rules and Persistent Queries</title><venue>In VLDB</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>108--119</pages><raw>S. Ceri and J. Widom. Managing Semantic Heterogeneity with Production Rules and Persistent Queries. In VLDB, pp. 108– 119, 1993.</raw><contexts><context>class and r-classes and are described at two levels: the object correspondence (OC) level and the value correspondence (VC) level. These mirror the general notions of existence and value dependencies [4, 13]. Finally, the restoration rules specify which actions to be taken if inconsistency occurs. They specify not only the actions needed for restoring consistency, but specify also the conditions that sho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29238"><authors>T Devogele,J Trevisan,L Raynal</authors><title>Building a Multiscale Database with Scale-transition Relationships</title><venue>In International Symposium on Spatial Data Handling</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>337--351</pages><raw>T. Devogele, J. Trevisan, and L. Raynal. Building a Multiscale Database with Scale-transition Relationships. In International Symposium on Spatial Data Handling, pp. 337–351, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>ke into account heterogeneous and independent databases. Another line of study has resulted in a multi-scale database that maintains scale-transition relationships between objects at different scales [5]. This work centers on integration and considers only relationships between pairs of objects. In summary, we are not aware of any work that considers modeling multiple representations with matching, c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29239"><authors>A Friis-Christensen,C S Jensen,J P Nytun</authors><title>A Conceptual Schema Language to Manage Multiple Representation of Geographic Entities</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2003</year><tech>Technical report</tech><raw>A. Friis-Christensen, C. S. Jensen, and J. P. Nytun. A Conceptual Schema Language to Manage Multiple Representation of Geographic Entities. Technical report, Aalborg University, Awaiting submission, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>presentation management. The MRMS maintains consistency based on a specification, a multiple representation schema (MRSchema), formulated in a so-called multiple representation schema language (MRSL) [6, 7]. The MRSchema specifies matching, consistency, and restoration rules. The MRSL is based on the assumption that objects representing the same entity exhibit semantic similarities that enable us to mod</context><context>The former is based on the Unified Modeling Language (UML) [1], and we use the Object Constraint Language (OCL) [17] to specify constraints. A more thorough description of the MRSL is given elsewhere [6, 7]. An MRSL specification, termed an MRSchema, is used to configure the MRMS. The process is depicted in Figure 1, which shows MRSchema specified in MRSL Translation ObjectRelational MRSchema Proceeding</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29240"><authors>A Friis-Christensen,D Skogan,C S Jensen,G Skagestein,N Tryfona</authors><title>Management of Multiply Represented Geographic Entities</title><venue>In IDEAS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>150--159</pages><raw>A. Friis-Christensen, D. Skogan, C. S. Jensen, G. Skagestein, and N. Tryfona. Management of Multiply Represented Geographic Entities. In IDEAS, pp. 150–159, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>presentation management. The MRMS maintains consistency based on a specification, a multiple representation schema (MRSchema), formulated in a so-called multiple representation schema language (MRSL) [6, 7]. The MRSchema specifies matching, consistency, and restoration rules. The MRSL is based on the assumption that objects representing the same entity exhibit semantic similarities that enable us to mod</context><context>The former is based on the Unified Modeling Language (UML) [1], and we use the Object Constraint Language (OCL) [17] to specify constraints. A more thorough description of the MRSL is given elsewhere [6, 7]. An MRSL specification, termed an MRSchema, is used to configure the MRMS. The process is depicted in Figure 1, which shows MRSchema specified in MRSL Translation ObjectRelational MRSchema Proceeding</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29241"><authors>P W P J Grefen,J Widom</authors><title>Protocols for Integrity Constraint Checking</title><venue>in Federated Databases. Distributed and Parallel Databases</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><volume>5</volume><raw>P. W. P. J. Grefen and J. Widom. Protocols for Integrity Constraint Checking in Federated Databases. Distributed and Parallel Databases, 5(4):327–355, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>nderlying autonomous databases. In contrast, the main purpose of an MRMS is to maintain consistency. At a more general level, related work can be found in distributed integrity constraint maintenance [8, 10]. The paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes the overall approach to integrating multiple representations. Section 3 presents the real-world case used in the paper. Section 4 demonstrates </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29242"><authors>C Jones,D Kidner,L Luo,G Bundy,J Ware</authors><title>Database Design for a Multi-scale Spatial Information System</title><venue>International Journal of Geographic Information Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><volume>10</volume><raw>C. Jones, D. Kidner, L. Luo, G. Bundy, and J. Ware. Database Design for a Multi-scale Spatial Information System. International Journal of Geographic Information Systems, 10(8):901–920, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>hereas we consider multiple representations from a more general viewpoint. A single multi-scale database that is capable of storing geographic objects with multiple geometries has also been proposed [9]. This approach assumes an integrated database and does not take into account heterogeneous and independent databases. Another line of study has resulted in a multi-scale database that maintains scale</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29243"><authors>G Karabatis,M Rusinkiewicz,A Sheth</authors><title>Interdependent Database Systems, Chapter 8</title><venue>Management of Heterogeneous and Autonomous Database Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>217--252</pages><editors>in A. Elmagarmid et al., editors</editors><publisher>Morgan Kaufman</publisher><raw>G. Karabatis, M. Rusinkiewicz, and A. Sheth. Interdependent Database Systems, Chapter 8, pp. 217–252. in A. Elmagarmid et al., editors, Management of Heterogeneous and Autonomous Database Systems. Morgan Kaufman, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>nderlying autonomous databases. In contrast, the main purpose of an MRMS is to maintain consistency. At a more general level, related work can be found in distributed integrity constraint maintenance [8, 10]. The paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes the overall approach to integrating multiple representations. Section 3 presents the real-world case used in the paper. Section 4 demonstrates </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29244"><authors>T Kilpeläinen</authors><title>Multiple Representation and Generalization of Geo-databases for Topographic Maps</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1997</year><tech>PhD thesis</tech><raw>T. Kilpeläinen. Multiple Representation and Generalization of Geo-databases for Topographic Maps. PhD thesis, Finnish Geodetic Institute, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>hich support different applications. This phenomenon, termed multiple representation, invariably leads to inconsistencies, which has been recognized as a key problem in geographic database management [3, 11]. Ensuring consistency among databases describing the same entities (termed representation databases) improves the quality and applicability of data. In this paper, we focus on the case where multiple</context><context>rcial data management software (DBMS or GIS) to support multiple representation, which is similar to our goal. However, they focus on aspects other than matching and restoration rules. Other research [11] has focused on the generalization of map features where there is an exact dependency among representation objects, whereas we consider multiple representations from a more general viewpoint. A singl</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29245"><authors>Top10DK Specification</authors><title>National Survey and Cadastre</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Copenhagen</pubAddress><raw>KMS. Top10DK Specification. National Survey and Cadastre, Copenhagen, 1999. Version 3.1.0 (in Danish).</raw><contexts><context>ding varies across the three databases, which complicates the process of creating an MRSchema. The definitions are seen in Table 1. The definitions given here are simplifications of the official ones [2, 12, 16]. An example of the building representations is seen in Figure 3. It is seen that several inconsistencies occur between the shapes of TM and T10 buildings (see the dashed and solid polygons). The shap</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29246"><authors>Q Li,D McLeod</authors><title>Managing Interdependencies among Objects in Federated Databases</title><venue>In IFIP Database Semantics Conference on Interoperable Database Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>331--347</pages><raw>Q. Li and D. McLeod. Managing Interdependencies among Objects in Federated Databases. In IFIP Database Semantics Conference on Interoperable Database Systems, pp. 331–347, 1992.</raw><contexts><context>class and r-classes and are described at two levels: the object correspondence (OC) level and the value correspondence (VC) level. These mirror the general notions of existence and value dependencies [4, 13]. Finally, the restoration rules specify which actions to be taken if inconsistency occurs. They specify not only the actions needed for restoring consistency, but specify also the conditions that sho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29247"><authors>A P Sheth,J A Larson</authors><title>Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed</title><venue>Heterogeneous, and Autonomous Databases. ACM Computing Surveys</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><volume>22</volume><raw>A. P. Sheth and J. A. Larson. Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed, Heterogeneous, and Autonomous Databases. ACM Computing Surveys, 22(3):183–236, 1990.</raw><contexts><context>ng multiple representations with matching, consistency, and restoration rules. Finally, it should be noted that multiple representation databases relate in a more general sense to federated databases [14]. A federated schema usually provides an integrated view of the underlying autonomous databases. In contrast, the main purpose of an MRMS is to maintain consistency. At a more general level, related w</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29248"><authors>S Spaccapietra,C Vangenot,C Parent,E Zimanyi</authors><title>MurMur: A Research Agenda on Multiple Representations</title><venue>In International Symposium on Database Applications in NonTraditional Environments</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>373--384</pages><raw>S. Spaccapietra, C. Vangenot, C. Parent, and E. Zimanyi. MurMur: A Research Agenda on Multiple Representations. In International Symposium on Database Applications in NonTraditional Environments, pp. 373–384, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>onal model. It thus demonstrates that it is possible to design and implement an MRMS in a cost-efficient manner. Multiple geographic representation has been studied for some years. The MurMur project [15] aims at extending commercial data management software (DBMS or GIS) to support multiple representation, which is similar to our goal. However, they focus on aspects other than matching and restoratio</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29249"><authors>TK99 Specifications</authors><title>for Techinal Maps TK99. Committee under the Organization of Municipalities in</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Denmark</pubAddress><raw>TK99. Specifications for Techinal Maps TK99. Committee under the Organization of Municipalities in Denmark, 1999 (in Danish).</raw><contexts><context>ding varies across the three databases, which complicates the process of creating an MRSchema. The definitions are seen in Table 1. The definitions given here are simplifications of the official ones [2, 12, 16]. An example of the building representations is seen in Figure 3. It is seen that several inconsistencies occur between the shapes of TM and T10 buildings (see the dashed and solid polygons). The shap</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29250"><authors>J B Warmer,A G Kleppe</authors><title>The Object Constraint Language: Precise Modeling with UML</title><year>1999</year><publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher><raw>J. B. Warmer and A. G. Kleppe. The Object Constraint Language: Precise Modeling with UML. Addison-Wesley, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>ns that should trigger an update action. The MRSL has a graphical and a lexical syntax. The former is based on the Unified Modeling Language (UML) [1], and we use the Object Constraint Language (OCL) [17] to specify constraints. A more thorough description of the MRSL is given elsewhere [6, 7]. An MRSL specification, termed an MRSchema, is used to configure the MRMS. The process is depicted in Figure </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29251"><authors>R Weibel,G H Dutton</authors><title>Generalising Spatial Data and Dealing with Multiple Representations</title><venue>Rhind (eds), Geographic Information Systems - Principles and Technical Issues</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>R. Weibel and G. H. Dutton. Generalising Spatial Data and Dealing with Multiple Representations, in P. Longley, M. Goodchild, D. Maguire, and D. Rhind (eds), Geographic Information Systems - Principles and Technical Issues, 1999.</raw><contexts><context> with this method is that it is only possible to specify dependencies between pairs of source and target classes. This may be sufficient in the field of data warehousing and geographic generalization [18], where the target representation classes are controlled by derivation rules. The main problem, however, is when the r-classes constitute a multiply represented entity that depends on more than one cl</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.cs.auc.dk/~csj/Papers/Files/2003_friis-christensenSSDM.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>ea32216b4330650c497ff4e2327545bf7e9b138b</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>