<document id="10.1.1.1.1602"><clusterid>2052</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">FCND DP No. 80 1 FCND DISCUSSION PAPER NO. 80 NONTRADITIONAL CROPS AND LAND ACCUMULATION AMONG GUATEMALAN SMALLHOLDERS: IS THE IMPACT SUSTAINABLE?</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">FCND Discussion Papers contain preliminary material and research results, and are circulated prior to a full peer review in order to stimulate discussion and critical comment. It is expected that most Discussion Papers will eventually be published in some other form, and that their content may also be revised. ii Since the late 1970s dramatic economic changes have taken place in the agricultural sector in the highlands of Guatemala. The introduction of new export crops, such as snow peas, broccoli, and miniature vegetables, has led to yet another agro-export boom. Unlike earlier booms, however, this one has included all but the smallest farmers. The high rate of smallholder participation in the boom, and the initial high profitability of nontraditional exports (NTXs), fueled initial optimism that NTX production could increase smallholders ’ ability to accumulate land and so decrease the highly skewed distribution of land in Guatemala, a country with one of the most unequal landholding patterns in all of Latin America. The picture that emerges from the analysis in this paper raises serious questions</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4448"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Calogero Carletto</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Food Consumption and Nutrition Division; International Food Policy Research Institute</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2033 K Street, N.W.; Washington, D.C. 20006 U.S.A.</address><order src="null">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30053"><clusterid>2053</clusterid><authors>Bradford Barham,Michael R Carter,Wayne Sigelko</authors><title>Agro-Export Production and Peasant Land Access: Examining the Dynamic Between Adoption and Accumulation</title><venue>Journal of Development Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><pages>85--107</pages><volume>46</volume><raw>Barham, Bradford, Michael R. Carter, and Wayne Sigelko (1995) Agro-Export Production and Peasant Land Access: Examining the Dynamic Between Adoption and Accumulation. Journal of Development Economics 46: 85-107.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30054"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>Bradford Barham,Mary Clark,Elizabeth Katz,Rachel Schurman</authors><venue>Nontraditional Agricultural Exports in Latin America. Latin American Research Review</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>43--82</pages><volume>28</volume><raw>Barham, Bradford, Mary Clark, Elizabeth Katz, and Rachel Schurman (1992) Nontraditional Agricultural Exports in Latin America. Latin American Research Review 28 (2): 43-82.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30055"><clusterid>2054</clusterid><authors>Michael Conroy,Douglas Murray,Peter Rossett</authors><title>A Cautionary Tale</title><venue>Failed U.S. Development Policy in Central America</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><publisher>Lynne Rienner Publishers</publisher><pubAddress>Boulder, Colorado</pubAddress><raw>Conroy, Michael, Douglas Murray, and Peter Rossett (1996) A Cautionary Tale: Failed U.S. Development Policy in Central America. Boulder, Colorado: Lynne Rienner Publishers.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30056"><clusterid>982</clusterid><authors>William H Greene</authors><title>Econometric Analysis</title><year>1993</year><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><pubAddress>Englewood Cliffs, N.J</pubAddress><raw>Greene, William H. (1993) Econometric Analysis. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice Hall.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30057"><clusterid>2055</clusterid><authors>Maarten Immink,Eileen Kennedy,Herwig Hahn,Ellen Payongayong</authors><title>Nontraditional Export Crops Among Smallholder Farmers and Production, Income, Nutrition, and Quality of Life Effects: A Comparative Analysis 19851991</title><venue>International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pubAddress>Washington, D.C</pubAddress><raw>Immink, Maarten, Eileen Kennedy, Herwig Hahn, and Ellen Payongayong (1993) Nontraditional Export Crops Among Smallholder Farmers and Production, Income, Nutrition, and Quality of Life Effects: A Comparative Analysis 19851991. Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30058"><clusterid>2056</clusterid><authors>Elizabeth G Katz</authors><title>Intrahousehold Resource Allocation in the Guatemalan Central Highlands: The Impact of Nontraditional Agricultural Exports</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1992</year><tech>Ph.D</tech><raw>Katz, Elizabeth G. (1992) Intrahousehold Resource Allocation in the Guatemalan Central Highlands: The Impact of Nontraditional Agricultural Exports. Ph.D.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30059"><clusterid>2057</clusterid><authors>G S Maddala</authors><title>Limited-Dependent and Qualitative Variables in Econometrics</title><year>1983</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge: Cambridge</pubAddress><raw>dissertation, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin. Maddala, G. S. (1983) Limited-Dependent and Qualitative Variables in Econometrics. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30060"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>Simon Maxwell,Adrian Fernando</authors><venue>Cash Crops in Developing Countries: The Issues, the Facts, the Policies. World Development</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1989</year><pages>1677--1708</pages><volume>17</volume><raw>Maxwell, Simon, and Adrian Fernando (1989) Cash Crops in Developing Countries: The Issues, the Facts, the Policies. World Development 17 (11): 1677-1708.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30061"><clusterid>2058</clusterid><authors>Peter M Rossett</authors><title>Sustainability, Economies of Scale</title><venue>and Social Instability: Achilles Heel of Nontraditional Export Agriculture? Agriculture and Human Values 8 (3</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1991</year><raw>Rossett, Peter M. (1991) Sustainability, Economies of Scale, and Social Instability: Achilles Heel of Nontraditional Export Agriculture? Agriculture and Human Values 8 (3).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30062"><clusterid>2059</clusterid><authors>Lori Ann Thrupp,with Gilles Bergeron,William F Waters</authors><title>Bittersweet Harvests for Global Supermarkets</title><venue>Challenges in Latin America’s Agricultural Export</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><publisher>World Resources Institute</publisher><pubAddress>Boom. Washington, D.C</pubAddress><raw>Thrupp, Lori Ann, with Gilles Bergeron and William F. Waters (1995) Bittersweet Harvests for Global Supermarkets: Challenges in Latin America’s Agricultural Export Boom. Washington, D.C.: World Resources Institute.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30063"><clusterid>2060</clusterid><authors>Joachim von Braun,David Hotchkiss</authors><title>Maarten Immink (1989) Nontraditional Export Crops</title><venue>in Guatemala: Effects on Production, Income, and Nutrition. Research Report 73. Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>von Braun, Joachim, David Hotchkiss, and Maarten Immink (1989) Nontraditional Export Crops in Guatemala: Effects on Production, Income, and Nutrition. Research Report 73. Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30064"><clusterid>2061</clusterid><authors>Manfred Zeller Madagascar</authors><title>Technology and Food Policy to Combat Iron Deficiency in Developing Countries, Howarth E. Bouis, August 1994 02 Determinants of Credit Rationing: A Study of Informal Lenders and Formal Credit Groups in</title><venue>FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 01 Agricultural</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 01 Agricultural Technology and Food Policy to Combat Iron Deficiency in Developing Countries, Howarth E. Bouis, August 1994 02 Determinants of Credit Rationing: A Study of Informal Lenders and Formal Credit Groups in Madagascar, Manfred Zeller, October 1994 03 The Extended Family and Intrahousehold Allocation: Inheritance and Investments in Children in the Rural Philippines, Agnes R. Quisumbing, March 1995 04 Market Development and Food Demand in Rural China, Jikun Huang and Scott Rozelle, June 1995 05 Gender Differences in Agricultural Productivity: A Survey of Empirical Evidence, Agnes R.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30065"><clusterid>2062</clusterid><authors>Quisumbing</authors><title>06 Gender Differentials in Farm Productivity: Implications for Household Efficiency and Agricultural</title><venue>Christine Peña, Chizuru Nishida, Agnes Quisumbing, and Alison Slack, September 1996 FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 20 Macroeconomic</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pubAddress>Hanan Jacoby</pubAddress><raw>Quisumbing, July 1995 06 Gender Differentials in Farm Productivity: Implications for Household Efficiency and Agricultural Policy, Harold Alderman, John Hoddinott, Lawrence Haddad, and Christopher Udry, August 1995 07 A Food Demand System Based on Demand for Characteristics: If There Is &amp;quot;Curvature&amp;quot; in the Slutsky Matrix, What Do the Curves Look Like and Why?, Howarth E. Bouis, December 1995 08 Measuring Food Insecurity: The Frequency and Severity of &amp;quot;Coping Strategies,&amp;quot; Daniel G. Maxwell, December 1995 09 Gender and Poverty: New Evidence from 10 Developing Countries, Agnes R. Quisumbing, Lawrence Haddad, and Christine Peña, December 1995 10 Women's Economic Advancement Through Agricultural Change: A Review of Donor Experience, Christine Peña, Patrick Webb, and Lawrence Haddad, February 1996 11 Rural Financial Policies for Food Security of the Poor: Methodologies for a Multicountry Research Project, Manfred Zeller, Akhter Ahmed, Suresh Babu, Sumiter Broca, Aliou Diagne, and Manohar Sharma, April 1996 12 Child Development: Vulnerability and Resilience, Patrice L. Engle, Sarah Castle, and Purnima Menon, April 1996 13 Determinants of Repayment Performance in Credit Groups: The Role of Program Design, Intra-Group Risk Pooling, and Social Cohesion in Madagascar, Manfred Zeller, May 1996 14 Demand for High-Value Secondary Crops in Developing Countries: The Case of Potatoes in Bangladesh and Pakistan, Howarth E. Bouis and Gregory Scott, May 1996 15 Repayment Performance in Group-Based credit Programs in Bangladesh: An Empirical Analysis, Manohar Sharma and Manfred Zeller, July 1996 16 How Can Safety Nets Do More with Less? General Issues with Some Evidence from Southern Africa, Lawrence Haddad and Manfred Zeller, July 1996 17 Remittances, Income Distribution, and Rural Asset Accumulation, Richard H. Adams, Jr., August 1996 18 Care and Nutrition: Concepts and Measurement, Patrice L. Engle, Purnima Menon, and Lawrence Haddad, August 1996 19 Food Security and Nutrition Implications of Intrahousehold Bias: A Review of Literature, Lawrence Haddad, Christine Peña, Chizuru Nishida, Agnes Quisumbing, and Alison Slack, September 1996 FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 20 Macroeconomic Crises and Poverty Monitoring: A Case Study for India, Gaurav Datt and Martin Ravallion, November 1996 21 Livestock Income, Male/Female Animals, and Inequality in Rural Pakistan, Richard H. Adams, Jr., November 1996 22 Alternative Approaches to Locating the Food Insecure: Qualitative and Quantitative Evidence from South India, Kimberly Chung, Lawrence Haddad, Jayashree Ramakrishna, and Frank Riely, January 23 Better Rich, or Better There? Grandparent Wealth, Coresidence, and Intrahousehold Allocation, Agnes R. Quisumbing, January 1997 24 Child Care Practices Associated with Positive and Negative Nutritional Outcomes for Children in Bangladesh: A Descriptive Analysis, Shubh K. Kumar Range, Ruchira Naved, and Saroj Bhattarai, February 1997 25 Water, Health, and Income: A Review, John Hoddinott, February 1997 26 Why Have Some Indian States Performed Better Than Others at Reducing Rural Poverty?, Gaurav Datt and Martin Ravallion, March 1997 27 &amp;quot;Bargaining&amp;quot; and Gender Relations: Within and Beyond the Household, Bina Agarwal, March 1997 28 Developing a Research and Action Agenda for Examining Urbanization and Caregiving: Examples from Southern and Eastern Africa, Patrice L. Engle, Purnima Menon, James L. Garrett, and Alison Slack, April 1997 29 Gender, Property Rights, and Natural Resources, Ruth Meinzen-Dick, Lynn R. Brown, Hilary Sims Feldstein, and Agnes R. Quisumbing, May 1997 30 Plant Breeding: A Long-Term Strategy for the Control of Zinc Deficiency in Vulnerable Populations, Marie T. Ruel and Howarth E. Bouis, July 1997 31 Is There an Intrahousehold 'Flypaper Effect'? Evidence from a School Feeding Program, Hanan Jacoby, August 1997 32 The Determinants of Demand for Micronutrients: An Analysis of Rural Households in Bangladesh, Howarth E. Bouis and Mary Jane G. Novenario-Reese, August 1997 33 Human Milk—An Invisible Food Resource, Anne Hatløy and Arne Oshaug, August 1997 34 The Impact of Changes in Common Property Resource Management on Intrahousehold Allocation, Philip Maggs and John Hoddinott, September 1997 35 Market Access by Smallholder Farmers in Malawi: Implications for Technology Adoption, Agricultural Productivity, and Crop Income, Manfred Zeller, Aliou Diagne, and Charles Mataya, September 1997 36 The GAPVU Cash Transfer Program in Mozambique: An assessment, Gaurav Datt, Ellen Payongayong, James L. Garrett, and Marie Ruel, October 1997 37 Why Do Migrants Remit? An Analysis for the Dominican Sierra, Bénédicte de la Brière, Alain de Janvry, Sylvie Lambert, and Elisabeth Sadoulet, October 1997 FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 38 Systematic Client Consultation in Development: The Case of Food Policy Research in Ghana, India, Kenya, and Mali, Suresh Chandra Babu, Lynn R. Brown, and Bonnie McClafferty, November 1997 39 Whose Education Matters in the Determination of Household Income: Evidence from a Developing Country, Dean Jolliffe, November 1997 40 Can Qualitative and Quantitative Methods Serve Complementary Purposes for Policy Research? Evidence from Accra, Dan Maxwell, January 1998 41 The Political Economy of Urban Food Security in Sub-Saharan Africa, Dan Maxwell, February 1998 42 Farm Productivity and Rural Poverty in India, Gaurav Datt and Martin Ravallion, March 1998 43 How Reliable Are Group Informant Ratings? A Test of Food Security Rating in Honduras, Gilles Bergeron, Saul Sutkover Morris, and Juan Manuel Medina Banegas, April 1998 44 Can FAO's Measure of Chronic Undernourishment Be Strengthened?, Lisa C. Smith, with a Response by Logan Naiken, May 1998 45 Does Urban Agriculture Help Prevent Malnutrition? Evidence from Kampala, Daniel Maxwell, Carol Levin, and Joanne Csete, June 1998 46 Impact of Access to Credit on Income and Food Security in Malawi, Aliou Diagne, July 1998 47 Poverty in India and Indian States: An Update, Gaurav Datt, July 1998 48 Human Capital, Productivity, and Labor Allocation in Rural Pakistan, Marcel Fafchamps and Agnes R.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30066"><clusterid>2063</clusterid><authors>Quisumbing</authors><title>49 A Profile of Poverty</title><venue>in Egypt: 1997, Gaurav Datt, Dean Jolliffe, and Manohar Sharma</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>Quisumbing, July 1998 49 A Profile of Poverty in Egypt: 1997, Gaurav Datt, Dean Jolliffe, and Manohar Sharma, August 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30067"><clusterid>2064</clusterid><authors>Gaurav Datt Analysis</authors><title>50 Computational Tools for Poverty Measurement</title><venue>55 Efficiency in Intrahousehold Resource Allocation, Marcel Fafchamps</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>50 Computational Tools for Poverty Measurement and Analysis, Gaurav Datt, October 1998 51 Urban Challenges to Food and Nutrition Security: A Review of Food Security, Health, and Caregiving in the Cities, Marie T. Ruel, James L. Garrett, Saul S. Morris, Daniel Maxwell, Arne Oshaug, Patrice Engle, Purnima Menon, Alison Slack, and Lawrence Haddad, October 1998 52 Testing Nash Bargaining Household Models With Time-Series Data, John Hoddinott and Christopher Adam, November 1998 53 Agricultural Wages and Food Prices in Egypt: A Governorate-Level Analysis for 1976-1993, Gaurav Datt and Jennifer Olmsted, November 1998 54 Endogeneity of Schooling in the Wage Function: Evidence from the Rural Philippines, John Maluccio, November 1998 55 Efficiency in Intrahousehold Resource Allocation, Marcel Fafchamps, December 1998 56 How Does the Human Rights Perspective Help to Shape the Food and Nutrition Policy Research Agenda?, Lawrence Haddad and Arne Oshaug, February 1999 57 The Structure of Wages During the Economic Transition in Romania, Emmanuel Skoufias, February FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 58 Women's Land Rights in the Transition to Individualized Ownership: Implications for the Management of Tree Resources in Western Ghana, Agnes Quisumbing, Ellen Payongayong, J. B. Aidoo, and Keijiro Otsuka, February 1999 59 Placement and Outreach of Group-Based Credit Organizations: The Cases of ASA, BRAC, and PROSHIKA in Bangladesh, Manohar Sharma and Manfred Zeller, March 1999 60 Explaining Child Malnutrition in Developing Countries: A Cross-Country Analysis, Lisa C. Smith and Lawrence Haddad, April 1999 61 Does Geographic Targeting of Nutrition Interventions Make Sense in Cities? Evidence from Abidjan and Accra, Saul S. Morris, Carol Levin, Margaret Armar-Klemesu, Daniel Maxwell, and Marie T.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation><citation id="30068"><clusterid>2065</clusterid><authors>Ruel</authors><title>62 Good Care Practices Can Mitigate the Negative Effects of Poverty and Low Maternal Schooling on Children's Nutritional Status: Evidence from</title><venue>in Formal and Informal Credit Markets in Malawi, Aliou Diagne</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Lawrence</pubAddress><raw>Ruel, April 1999 62 Good Care Practices Can Mitigate the Negative Effects of Poverty and Low Maternal Schooling on Children's Nutritional Status: Evidence from Accra, Marie T. Ruel, Carol E. Levin, Margaret ArmarKlemesu, Daniel Maxwell, and Saul S. Morris, April 1999 63 Are Urban Poverty and Undernutrition Growing? Some Newly Assembled Evidence, Lawrence Haddad, Marie T. Ruel, and James L. Garrett, April 1999 64 Some Urban Facts of Life: Implications for Research and Policy, Marie T. Ruel, Lawrence Haddad, and James L. Garrett, April 1999 65 Are Determinants of Rural and Urban Food Security and Nutritional Status Different? Some Insights from Mozambique, James L. Garrett and Marie T. Ruel, April 1999 66 Working Women in an Urban Setting: Traders, Vendors, and Food Security in Accra, Carol E. Levin, Daniel G. Maxwell, Margaret Armar-Klemesu, Marie T. Ruel, Saul S. Morris, and Clement Ahiadeke, April 1999 67 Determinants of Household Access to and Participation in Formal and Informal Credit Markets in Malawi, Aliou Diagne, April 1999 68 Early Childhood Nutrition and Academic Achievement: A Longitudinal Analysis, Paul Glewwe, Hanan Jacoby, and Elizabeth King, May 1999 69 Supply Response of West African Agricultural Households: Implications of Intrahousehold Preference Heterogeneity, Lisa C. Smith and Jean-Paul Chavas, July 1999 70 Child Health Care Demand in a Developing Country: Unconditional Estimates from the Philippines, Kelly Hallman, August 1999 71 Social Capital and Income Generation in South Africa, 1993-98, John Maluccio, Lawrence Haddad, and Julian May, September 1999 72 Validity of Rapid Estimates of Household Wealth and Income for Health Surveys in Rural Africa, Saul S. Morris, Calogero Carletto, John Hoddinott, and Luc J. M. Christiaensen, October 1999 73 Social Roles, Human Capital, and the Intrahousehold Division of Labor: Evidence from Pakistan, Marcel Fafchamps and Agnes R. Quisumbing, October 1999 74 Can Cash Transfer Programs Work in Resource-Poor Countries? The Experience in Mozambique, Jan W. Low, James L. Garrett, and Vitória Ginja, October 1999 FCND DISCUSSION PAPERS 75 Determinants of Poverty in Egypt, 1997, Gaurav Datt and Dean Jolliffe, October 1999 76 Raising Primary School Enrolment in Developing Countries: The Relative Importance of Supply and Demand, Sudhanshu Handa, November 1999 77 The Political Economy of Food Subsidy Reform in Egypt, 1997, Tammi Gutner, November 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1602</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.ifpri.org/divs/fcnd/dp/papers/fcndp80.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>974203b3862664f2124a73086cabffb6da6f4edd</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>