<document id="10.1.1.1.1579"><clusterid>1602</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">The key to Czech vowel length (Arabic rule . . .</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Arabic rule in Middle Europe)     contrastive vowel length in these languages. Czech vowel length has been extensively studied since the 19th century.  However, no generalisation of any kind could be uncovered. Diachronically, it does not relate to either Indo-European  or Common Slavic vowel length, nor does it show any kinship with Baltic tones and East/ South Slavic accent.  Synchronically, closed syllable shortening (krva vs. krav, kravka &quot;cow NOMsg, GENpl, dim&quot;) appears to coexist with  closed syllable lengthening (n# vs. noe, n#ky &quot;knife NOMsg, GENsg, scissors&quot;). In sum, any attempt to propose a  regularity underlying this system seems desperate. Vowel length in Czech is therefore reputed to be anarchic and  unpredictable. This situation is mirrored in grammars by pages of amorphous lists of grammatical categories that exhibit  length or shortness.   Czech vowel length is driven by a simple mechanism that is known from other languages: templates. That is, a  certain amount of vocalic space is associated to a given morphological and/ or semantic category. If concatenation of  underlying long and short vowels produces more morae than the specific category allows for, shortening is observed. If  it produces less vocalic weight than the category at stake demands, lengthening ensues. This kind of templatic structure  is a typical feature of Afro-Asiatic languages, and I believe that the templatic regularities I present have not been  discovered before because nobody has ever looked at the relevant data through the prism of templates: these are  commonly held to be a typological pecularity of Afro-Asiatic, absent from Indo-European.   In order to illustrate the preceding claim, only a few of the instances of templatic activity that I have identified may  be quoted in t...</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2001</year><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Tobias Scheer</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29688"><clusterid>1603</clusterid><authors>Miroslav Grepl</authors><title>Příruční mluvnice češtiny. Praha: Nakladatelství Lidové Noviny</title><year>1995</year><raw>Grepl, Miroslav et al. 1995. Příruční mluvnice češtiny. Praha: Nakladatelství Lidové Noviny.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1579</paperid></citation><citation id="29689"><clusterid>1604</clusterid><authors>Bohuslav Havránek</authors><title>Alois Jedliček 1988. Ceská mluvnice. 6th edition Praha: SPN. Scheer, Tobias (forth). The Rhythmic Law in Czech: vowel-final Prefixes. To appear in: Junghans, Uwe (ed): Formal Description of Slavic Languages 3</title><raw>Havránek, Bohuslav &amp; Alois Jedliček 1988. Ceská mluvnice. 6th edition Praha: SPN. Scheer, Tobias (forth). The Rhythmic Law in Czech: vowel-final Prefixes. To appear in: Junghans, Uwe (ed): Formal Description of Slavic Languages 3.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1579</paperid></citation><citation id="29690"><clusterid>1605</clusterid><authors>František Trávníček</authors><title>De la quantité tchèque. Revue des Etudes Slaves 1</title><year>1929</year><raw>Trávníček, František 1929. De la quantité tchèque. Revue des Etudes Slaves 1.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1579</paperid></citation><citation id="29691"><clusterid>1606</clusterid><authors>František Trávníček</authors><title>Historická mluvnice Československá</title><year>1935</year><pubAddress>Praha: Melantrich</pubAddress><raw>Trávníček, František 1935. Historická mluvnice Československá. Praha: Melantrich.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1579</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.unice.fr/dsl/tobweb/papers/abstrPotsdam.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>