<document id="10.1.1.1.1593"><clusterid>1817</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">A learning approach to improving sentence-level MT evaluation</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">The problem of evaluating machine translation (MT) systems is more challenging than it may first appear, as diverse translations can often be considered equally correct. The task is even more difficult when practical circumstances require that evaluation be done automatically over short texts, for instance, during incremental system development and error analysis. While several automatic metrics, such as BLEU, have been proposed and adopted for largescale MT system discrimination, they all fail to achieve satisfactory levels of correlation with human judgments at the sentence level. Here, a new class of metrics based on machine learning is introduced. A novel method involving classifying translations as machine or humanproduced rather than directly predicting numerical human judgments eliminates the need for labor-intensive user studies as a source of training data. The resulting metric, based on support vector machines, is shown to significantly improve upon current automatic metrics, increasing correlation with human judgments at the sentence level halfway toward that achieved by an independent human evaluator. 1</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2004</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation (TMI</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4313930"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Alex Kulesza</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Division of Engineering and Applied Sciences; Harvard University</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">33 Oxford St.; Cambridge, MA 02138, USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">kulesza@post.harvard.edu</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4313931"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Stuart M. Shieber</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Division of Engineering and Applied Sciences; Harvard University</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">33 Oxford St.; Cambridge, MA 02138, USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">shieber@deas.harvard.edu</email><order src="null">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29902"><clusterid>1818</clusterid><authors>Ronan Collobert,Samy Bengio,Johnny Mariethoz</authors><title>Torch: a modular machine learning software library</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2002</year><tech>Tech. Rep. IDIAP-RR 02-46, IDIAP</tech><raw>Collobert, Ronan, Samy Bengio, and Johnny Mariethoz. 2002. Torch: a modular machine learning software library. Tech. Rep. IDIAP-RR 02-46, IDIAP.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29903"><clusterid>1902</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Support vector and kernel methods for learning</title><venue>ICML Tutorial</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><raw>Cristianini, Nello. 2001. Support vector and kernel methods for learning. ICML Tutorial.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29904"><clusterid>1819</clusterid><authors>George Doddington</authors><title>Automatic evaluation of machine translation quality using n-gram cooccurrence statistics</title><venue>In Human Language Technology: Notebook Proceedings</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>128--132</pages><pubAddress>San Diego</pubAddress><raw>Doddington, George. 2002. Automatic evaluation of machine translation quality using n-gram cooccurrence statistics. In Human Language Technology: Notebook Proceedings, 128–132. San Diego.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29905"><clusterid>1820</clusterid><authors>George Foster,Simona Gandrabur,Cyril Goutte,Erin Fitzgerald,Alberto Sanchis,Nicola Ueffing,John Blatz,Alex Kulesza</authors><title>Confidence estimation for machine translation</title><venue>Tech. Rep., Johns Hopkins Workshop on Speech and Language Engineering</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pubAddress>Baltimore, MD</pubAddress><raw>Foster, George, Simona Gandrabur, Cyril Goutte, Erin Fitzgerald, Alberto Sanchis, Nicola Ueffing, John Blatz, and Alex Kulesza. 2003. Confidence estimation for machine translation. Tech. Rep., Johns Hopkins Workshop on Speech and Language Engineering, Baltimore, MD.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29906"><clusterid>1821</clusterid><authors>Eduard Hovy,Margaret King</authors><title>Andrei Popescu-Belis. 2002. Principles of context-based machine translation evaluation. Machine Translation 16:1–33</title><raw>Hovy, Eduard, Margaret King, and Andrei Popescu-Belis. 2002. Principles of context-based machine translation evaluation. Machine Translation 16:1–33.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29907"><clusterid>1906</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Minimum error rate training for statistical machine translation</title><venue>In Acl 2003: Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pubAddress>Sapporo, Japan</pubAddress><raw>Och, Franz Josef. 2003. Minimum error rate training for statistical machine translation. In Acl 2003: Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Sapporo, Japan.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29908"><clusterid>1822</clusterid><authors>Franz Josef Och,Daniel Gildea,Sanjeev Khudanpur,Anoop Sarkar,Kenji Yamada,Alex Fraser,Shankar Kumar,Libin Shen,David Smith,Katherine Eng,Viren Jain,Zhen Jin,Dragomir Radev</authors><title>Syntax for statistical machine translation</title><venue>Tech. Rep., Johns Hopkins Workshop on Speech and Language Engineering</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pubAddress>Baltimore, MD</pubAddress><raw>Och, Franz Josef, Daniel Gildea, Sanjeev Khudanpur, Anoop Sarkar, Kenji Yamada, Alex Fraser, Shankar Kumar, Libin Shen, David Smith, Katherine Eng, Viren Jain, Zhen Jin, and Dragomir Radev. 2003. Syntax for statistical machine translation. Tech. Rep., Johns Hopkins Workshop on Speech and Language Engineering, Baltimore, MD.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29909"><clusterid>1823</clusterid><authors>Kishore A Papineni,Salim Roukos,Todd Ward,Wei-Jing Zhu</authors><title>BLEU: A method for automatic evaluation of machine translation</title><venue>Tech. Rep. RC22176 (W0109-022), IBM Research Division, Thomas J. Watson Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><pubAddress>Center, Yorktown Heights, NY</pubAddress><raw>Papineni, Kishore A., Salim Roukos, Todd Ward, and Wei-Jing Zhu. 2001. BLEU: A method for automatic evaluation of machine translation. Tech. Rep. RC22176 (W0109-022), IBM Research Division, Thomas J. Watson Research Center, Yorktown Heights, NY.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29910"><clusterid>1824</clusterid><authors>C Tillman,S Vogel,H Ney,H Sawaf,A Zubiaga</authors><title>Accelerated DP-based search for statistical translation</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 5th European Conference on Speech Communication and Technology (EuroSpeech</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>2667--2670</pages><pubAddress>Rhodes, Greece</pubAddress><volume>97</volume><raw>Tillman, C., S. Vogel, H. Ney, H. Sawaf, and A. Zubiaga. 1997. Accelerated DP-based search for statistical translation. In Proceedings of the 5th European Conference on Speech Communication and Technology (EuroSpeech ’97), 2667–2670. Rhodes, Greece.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation><citation id="29911"><clusterid>1825</clusterid><authors>Joseph P Turian,Luke Shen,I Dan Melamed</authors><title>Evaluation of machine translation and its evaluation</title><venue>In Proceedings of MT Summit IX</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>23--28</pages><pubAddress>New Orleans</pubAddress><raw>Turian, Joseph P., Luke Shen, and I. Dan Melamed. 2003. Evaluation of machine translation and its evaluation. In Proceedings of MT Summit IX, 23–28. New Orleans.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1593</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.eecs.harvard.edu/~shieber/Biblio/./Papers/kulesza-mt-evaluation04.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>