<document id="10.1.1.1.1555"><clusterid>1164</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Object-Relational Management of Multiply Represented Geographic Entities</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Multiple representation occurs when information about the same geographic entity is represented electronically more than once. This occurs frequently in practice, and it invariably results in the occurrence of inconsistencies among the different representations. We propose to resolve this situation by introducing a multiple representation management system (MRMS), the schema of which includes rules that specify how to identify representations of the same entity, rules that specify consistency requirements, and rules used to restore consistency when necessary. In this paper, we demonstrate by means of a prototype and a realworld case study that it is possible to implement a multiple representation schema language on top of an objectrelational database management system. Specifically, it is demonstrated how it is possible to map the constructs of the language used for specifying the multiple representation schema to functionality available in Oracle. Though some limitations exist, Oracle has proven to be a suitable platform for implementing an MRMS.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2003</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In International Conference on Scientific and Statistical Database Management</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">150--159</pages><publisher src="INFERENCE">IEEE Computer Society</publisher><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Anders Friis-Christensen National</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="4313526"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Anders Friis-christensen</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">National Survey and Cadastre</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Denmark</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">afc@kms.dk</email><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29234"><clusterid>1165</clusterid><authors>G Booch,J Rumbaugh,I Jacobson</authors><title>The Unified Modeling Language User Guide</title><year>1999</year><publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher><raw>G. Booch, J. Rumbaugh, and I. Jacobson. The Unified Modeling Language User Guide. Addison-Wesley, 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29235"><clusterid>1166</clusterid><authors>Circular</authors><title>About the Establishment of the Buildings and Dwellings Register</title><venue>Ministry of Housing, January</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1977</year><volume>6</volume><raw>BR. Circular About the Establishment of the Buildings and Dwellings Register. Ministry of Housing, January 6, 1977 (in Danish).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29236"><clusterid>1167</clusterid><authors>B P Buttenfield,J S DeLotto</authors><title>Multiple Representations – Scientific Report for the Specialist Meeting</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1989</year><pubAddress>Buffalo, USA</pubAddress><tech>Report 89-3, NCGIA</tech><raw>B. P. Buttenfield and J. S. DeLotto. Multiple Representations – Scientific Report for the Specialist Meeting. Report 89-3, NCGIA, Department of Geography, SUNY Buffalo, USA, 1989.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29237"><clusterid>1168</clusterid><authors>S Ceri,J Widom</authors><title>Managing Semantic Heterogeneity with Production Rules and Persistent Queries</title><venue>In VLDB</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>108--119</pages><raw>S. Ceri and J. Widom. Managing Semantic Heterogeneity with Production Rules and Persistent Queries. In VLDB, pp. 108– 119, 1993.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29238"><clusterid>1169</clusterid><authors>T Devogele,J Trevisan,L Raynal</authors><title>Building a Multiscale Database with Scale-transition Relationships</title><venue>In International Symposium on Spatial Data Handling</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>337--351</pages><raw>T. Devogele, J. Trevisan, and L. Raynal. Building a Multiscale Database with Scale-transition Relationships. In International Symposium on Spatial Data Handling, pp. 337–351, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29239"><clusterid>1170</clusterid><authors>A Friis-Christensen,C S Jensen,J P Nytun</authors><title>A Conceptual Schema Language to Manage Multiple Representation of Geographic Entities</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2003</year><tech>Technical report</tech><raw>A. Friis-Christensen, C. S. Jensen, and J. P. Nytun. A Conceptual Schema Language to Manage Multiple Representation of Geographic Entities. Technical report, Aalborg University, Awaiting submission, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29240"><clusterid>1164</clusterid><authors>A Friis-Christensen,D Skogan,C S Jensen,G Skagestein,N Tryfona</authors><title>Management of Multiply Represented Geographic Entities</title><venue>In IDEAS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>150--159</pages><raw>A. Friis-Christensen, D. Skogan, C. S. Jensen, G. Skagestein, and N. Tryfona. Management of Multiply Represented Geographic Entities. In IDEAS, pp. 150–159, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29241"><clusterid>1171</clusterid><authors>P W P J Grefen,J Widom</authors><title>Protocols for Integrity Constraint Checking</title><venue>in Federated Databases. Distributed and Parallel Databases</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><volume>5</volume><raw>P. W. P. J. Grefen and J. Widom. Protocols for Integrity Constraint Checking in Federated Databases. Distributed and Parallel Databases, 5(4):327–355, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29242"><clusterid>1172</clusterid><authors>C Jones,D Kidner,L Luo,G Bundy,J Ware</authors><title>Database Design for a Multi-scale Spatial Information System</title><venue>International Journal of Geographic Information Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><volume>10</volume><raw>C. Jones, D. Kidner, L. Luo, G. Bundy, and J. Ware. Database Design for a Multi-scale Spatial Information System. International Journal of Geographic Information Systems, 10(8):901–920, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29243"><clusterid>1173</clusterid><authors>G Karabatis,M Rusinkiewicz,A Sheth</authors><title>Interdependent Database Systems, Chapter 8</title><venue>Management of Heterogeneous and Autonomous Database Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>217--252</pages><editors>in A. Elmagarmid et al., editors</editors><publisher>Morgan Kaufman</publisher><raw>G. Karabatis, M. Rusinkiewicz, and A. Sheth. Interdependent Database Systems, Chapter 8, pp. 217–252. in A. Elmagarmid et al., editors, Management of Heterogeneous and Autonomous Database Systems. Morgan Kaufman, 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29244"><clusterid>1174</clusterid><authors>T Kilpeläinen</authors><title>Multiple Representation and Generalization of Geo-databases for Topographic Maps</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1997</year><tech>PhD thesis</tech><raw>T. Kilpeläinen. Multiple Representation and Generalization of Geo-databases for Topographic Maps. PhD thesis, Finnish Geodetic Institute, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29245"><clusterid>1175</clusterid><authors>Top10DK Specification</authors><title>National Survey and Cadastre</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Copenhagen</pubAddress><raw>KMS. Top10DK Specification. National Survey and Cadastre, Copenhagen, 1999. Version 3.1.0 (in Danish).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29246"><clusterid>1176</clusterid><authors>Q Li,D McLeod</authors><title>Managing Interdependencies among Objects in Federated Databases</title><venue>In IFIP Database Semantics Conference on Interoperable Database Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>331--347</pages><raw>Q. Li and D. McLeod. Managing Interdependencies among Objects in Federated Databases. In IFIP Database Semantics Conference on Interoperable Database Systems, pp. 331–347, 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29247"><clusterid>1177</clusterid><authors>A P Sheth,J A Larson</authors><title>Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed</title><venue>Heterogeneous, and Autonomous Databases. ACM Computing Surveys</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><volume>22</volume><raw>A. P. Sheth and J. A. Larson. Federated Database Systems for Managing Distributed, Heterogeneous, and Autonomous Databases. ACM Computing Surveys, 22(3):183–236, 1990.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29248"><clusterid>1178</clusterid><authors>S Spaccapietra,C Vangenot,C Parent,E Zimanyi</authors><title>MurMur: A Research Agenda on Multiple Representations</title><venue>In International Symposium on Database Applications in NonTraditional Environments</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>373--384</pages><raw>S. Spaccapietra, C. Vangenot, C. Parent, and E. Zimanyi. MurMur: A Research Agenda on Multiple Representations. In International Symposium on Database Applications in NonTraditional Environments, pp. 373–384, 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29249"><clusterid>1179</clusterid><authors>TK99 Specifications</authors><title>for Techinal Maps TK99. Committee under the Organization of Municipalities in</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Denmark</pubAddress><raw>TK99. Specifications for Techinal Maps TK99. Committee under the Organization of Municipalities in Denmark, 1999 (in Danish).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29250"><clusterid>702</clusterid><authors>J B Warmer,A G Kleppe</authors><title>The Object Constraint Language: Precise Modeling with UML</title><year>1999</year><publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher><raw>J. B. Warmer and A. G. Kleppe. The Object Constraint Language: Precise Modeling with UML. Addison-Wesley, 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation><citation id="29251"><clusterid>1180</clusterid><authors>R Weibel,G H Dutton</authors><title>Generalising Spatial Data and Dealing with Multiple Representations</title><venue>Rhind (eds), Geographic Information Systems - Principles and Technical Issues</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>R. Weibel and G. H. Dutton. Generalising Spatial Data and Dealing with Multiple Representations, in P. Longley, M. Goodchild, D. Maguire, and D. Rhind (eds), Geographic Information Systems - Principles and Technical Issues, 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1555</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.cs.auc.dk/~csj/Papers/Files/2003_friis-christensenSSDM.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>