<document id="10.1.1.1.1527"><clusterid>722</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">On-line Handwritten Japanese Text Recognition free from Constrains on Line Direction and Character Orientation</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper describes an on-line handwritten Japanese text recognition method that is liberated from constraints on writing direction (line direction) and character orientation. This method estimates the line direction and character orientation using the time sequence information of pen-tip coordinates and employs writingbox-free recognition with context processing combined. The method can cope with a mixture of vertical, horizontal and skewed lines with arbitrary character orientations. It is expected useful for tablet PC's, interactive electronic whiteboards and so on. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4246"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Masaki Nakagawa</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Graduate School of Technology, Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology,</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2-24-16 Naka-cho, Koganei-shi, Tokyo, 184-8588 Japan</address><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4247"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Motoki Onuma</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Graduate School of Technology, Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology,</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2-24-16 Naka-cho, Koganei-shi, Tokyo, 184-8588 Japan</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">motoki@hands.ei.tuat.ac.jp</email><order src="null">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28704"><clusterid>723</clusterid><authors>T Fukushima,M Nakagawa</authors><title>On-line Writing Box Free Recognition of Handwritten Text based on Stochastic Models</title><venue>in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.98-139, No.489</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>25--30</pages><raw>T. Fukushima and M. Nakagawa: On-line Writing Box Free Recognition of Handwritten Text based on Stochastic Models, (in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.98-139, No.489, pp.25-30 (1998.12).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1527</paperid></citation><citation id="28705"><clusterid>724</clusterid><authors>T Fukushima,M Nakagawa</authors><title>On-line Writing-box-free Recognition of Handwritten Japanese Text Considering Character Size Variations</title><venue>Proc. of 15th ICPR</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>359--363</pages><pubAddress>Barcelona</pubAddress><volume>2</volume><raw>T. Fukushima and M. Nakagawa: On-line Writing-box-free Recognition of Handwritten Japanese Text Considering Character Size Variations, Proc. of 15th ICPR, Barcelona, Vol.2, pp.359-363 (2000.9).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1527</paperid></citation><citation id="28706"><clusterid>725</clusterid><authors>S Senda,K Yamada</authors><title>A Maximum-Likelihood Approach to Segmentation-Based Recognition of Unconstrained Handwriting Text</title><venue>Proc. of 6th ICDAR</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>184--188</pages><pubAddress>Seattle</pubAddress><raw>S. Senda and K. Yamada: A Maximum-Likelihood Approach to Segmentation-Based Recognition of Unconstrained Handwriting Text, Proc. of 6th ICDAR, Seattle, pp.184-188 (2001.9).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1527</paperid></citation><citation id="28707"><clusterid>726</clusterid><authors>Y Inamura,T Fukushima,M Nakagawa</authors><title>An On-line Writing-box-free and Writing-direction Free Recognition System for Handwritten Japanese Text</title><venue>in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.100-37, No.135</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>17--24</pages><raw>Y. Inamura, T. Fukushima and M. Nakagawa: An On-line Writing-box-free and Writing-direction Free Recognition System for Handwritten Japanese Text, (in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.100-37, No.135, pp.17-24 (2000.6).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1527</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.csc.liv.ac.uk/%7Eprima/ICDAR2003/Papers/0095_627_masaki_n.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>fbf6a089a160c2f3621c55ce16bf802324e3c153</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>