<document id="10.1.1.83.9484"><clusterid>838266</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">A Review of the Development of Embodied Presentation Agents and Their Application Fields</title><abstract src="user correction"> Embodied conversational agents provide a promising option for presenting information to users. This contribution revisits a number of past and ongoing systems with animated characters that have been developed at DFKI. While in all systems the purpose of using characters is to convey information to the user, there are significant variations in the style of presentation and the assumed conversational setting. The spectrum of systems include systems that feature a single, TV-style presentation agent, dialogue systems, as well as systems that deploy multiple interactive characters. We also provide a technical view on these systems and sketch the underlying system architectures of each sample system.  </abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2003</year><venue src="user correction">IN PRENDINGER, H., ISHIZUKA, M., EDS.: LIFE-LIKE CHARACTERS – TOOLS, AFFECTIVE FUNCTIONS, AND APPLICATIONS</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">377--404</pages><volume src="user correction"></volume><number src="user correction"></number><publisher src="INFERENCE">Springer</publisher><pubAddress src="user correction"></pubAddress><tech src="user correction"></tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Thomas Rist</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction">1 DFKI GmbH, Stuhlsatzenhausweg 3, D-66123 Saarbrücken, Germany.</address><email src="user correction">rist@dfki.de,</email><order src="user correction">1</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Elisabeth André</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction">2 Augsburg University, Eichleitnerstr. 30, D-86135 Augsburg, Germany</address><email src="user correction">andre@informatik.uni-augsburg.de</email><order src="user correction">2</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Stephan Baldes</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction">1 DFKI GmbH, Stuhlsatzenhausweg 3, D-66123 Saarbrücken, Germany.</address><email src="user correction">baldes@dfki.de,</email><order src="user correction">3</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Patrick Gebhard</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction">pit@blinx.de</email><order src="user correction">4</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Martin Klesen</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction">1 DFKI GmbH, Stuhlsatzenhausweg 3, D-66123 Saarbrücken, Germany.</address><email src="user correction">klesen@dfki.de,</email><order src="user correction">5</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Michael Kipp, Peter Rist</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction">1 DFKI GmbH, Stuhlsatzenhausweg 3, D-66123 Saarbrücken, Germany.</address><email src="user correction">kipp@dfki.de,</email><order src="user correction">6</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Markus Schmitt</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction">1 DFKI GmbH, Stuhlsatzenhausweg 3, D-66123 Saarbrücken, Germany.</address><email src="user correction">mschmitt@dfki.de,</email><order src="user correction">7</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="15124922"><clusterid>507848</clusterid><authors>E André,Rist</authors><title>T.: Coping with temporal constraints in multimedia presentation planning</title><venue>In: Proc of the AAAI ‘96, Menlo Park</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>142--147</pages><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, London</pubAddress><raw>André, E., Rist, T.: Coping with temporal constraints in multimedia presentation planning. In: Proc of the AAAI ‘96, Menlo Park, Cambridge, London (AAAI Press/The MIT Press 1996) pp 142–147</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124923"><clusterid>97213</clusterid><authors>E André,G Herzog,Rist</authors><title>T.: Generating multimedia presentations for RoboCup soccer games. In: RoboCup ’97: Robot Soccer World Cup I, ed by Kitano</title><year>1997</year><pages>200--215</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>André, E., Herzog, G., Rist, T.: Generating multimedia presentations for RoboCup soccer games. In: RoboCup ’97: Robot Soccer World Cup I, ed by Kitano (Springer, New York 1997) pp 200–215</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124924"><clusterid>315413</clusterid><authors>E André,T Rist,J Müller</authors><title>Employing AI methods to control the behavior of animated interface agents</title><venue>Applied Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><volume>13</volume><raw>André, E., Rist, T., Müller, J.: Employing AI methods to control the behavior of animated interface agents. Applied Artificial Intelligence 13:415–448 (1999)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124925"><clusterid>64293</clusterid><authors>E André,T Rist,S van Mulken,M Klesen,Baldes</authors><title>S.: The automated design of believable dialogues for animated presentation teams. In: Embodied Conversational Agents, ed by</title><year>2000</year><pages>220--255</pages><publisher>The MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, MA</pubAddress><raw>André, E., Rist, T., van Mulken, S., Klesen, M., Baldes, S.: The automated design of believable dialogues for animated presentation teams. In: Embodied Conversational Agents, ed by Cassell, J., Sullivan, J., Prevost, S., Churchill, E. (The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA 2000) pp 220–255</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124926"><clusterid>363477</clusterid><authors>E André,K Binsted,K Tanaka-Ishii,S Luke,G Herzog,Rist</authors><title>T.: Three RoboCup Simulation League Commentator Systems</title><venue>AI Magazine</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><volume>21</volume><raw>André, E., Binsted, K., Tanaka-Ishii, K., Luke, S., Herzog, G., Rist, T.: Three RoboCup Simulation League Commentator Systems. AI Magazine 21(1):57–65 (2000)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124927"><clusterid>1460048</clusterid><authors>E André,S Baldes,Rist</authors><title>T.: From simulated dialogues to interactive performances</title><venue>In: Multi-Agent Systems and Applications II, ed by Marik</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>107--118</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>André, E., Baldes, S., Rist, T.: From simulated dialogues to interactive performances. In: Multi-Agent Systems and Applications II, ed by Marik, V., Stepankova, O., Krauwurmovpa, H., Luck, M. (Springer, New York 2002) pp 107–118</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124928"><clusterid>4708171</clusterid><authors>K Binsted,Luke</authors><title>S.: Character design for soccer commentary. In: RoboCup-98: Robot Soccer World Cup II, ed by Asada</title><year>1999</year><pages>22--33</pages><pubAddress>M., Kitano, H. (Springer, New York</pubAddress><raw>Binsted, K., Luke, S.: Character design for soccer commentary. In: RoboCup-98: Robot Soccer World Cup II, ed by Asada, M., Kitano, H. (Springer, New York 1999) pp 22–33</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124929"><clusterid>111811</clusterid><authors>B Blumberg,B Tomlinson,Downie</authors><title>M.: Multiple conceptions of characterbased interactive installations</title><venue>Computer Graphics International 2001 (2001) pp 5–11</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Blumberg, B., Tomlinson, B., Downie, M.: Multiple conceptions of characterbased interactive installations. Computer Graphics International 2001 (2001) pp 5–11</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124930"><clusterid>69125</clusterid><authors>J Cassell,C Pelachaud,N Badler,M Steedman,B Achorn,T Becket,B Douville,S Prevost,Stone</authors><title>M.: Animated conversation: Rule-based generation of facial expression, gesture &amp; spoken intonation for multiple conversational agents. Computer Graphics 28:413–420</title><year>1994</year><raw>Cassell, J., Pelachaud, C., Badler, N., Steedman, M., Achorn, B., Becket, T., Douville, B., Prevost, S., Stone, M.: Animated conversation: Rule-based generation of facial expression, gesture &amp; spoken intonation for multiple conversational agents. Computer Graphics 28:413–420 (1994) 26 Thomas Rist et al.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124931"><clusterid>69126</clusterid><authors>J Cassell,T Bickmore,L Camphell,H Vilhjalmsson,Yan</authors><title>H.: The human conversation as a system framework: Designing embodied conversational agents. In: Embodied Conversational Agents, ed by</title><year>2000</year><pages>29--63</pages><publisher>The MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge MA</pubAddress><raw>Cassell, J., Bickmore, T., Camphell, L., Vilhjalmsson, H., Yan, H.: The human conversation as a system framework: Designing embodied conversational agents. In: Embodied Conversational Agents, ed by Cassell, J., Sullivan, J., Prevost, S., Churchill, E. (The MIT Press, Cambridge MA 2000) pp 29–63</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124932"><clusterid>585797</clusterid><authors>M Cavazza,Charles</authors><title>F.: Interacting with virtual characters in interactive storytelling</title><venue>In: Proceedings of AAMAS’02 (2002) pp 318–325</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Cavazza, M., Charles, F.: Interacting with virtual characters in interactive storytelling. In: Proceedings of AAMAS’02 (2002) pp 318–325</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124933"><clusterid>32409</clusterid><authors>M M Cohen,J Beskow,Massaro</authors><title>DW.: Recent developments in facial animation: An inside view</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Auditory-Visual Speech Processing 98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Sydney, Australia</pubAddress><raw>Cohen, M.M., Beskow, J., Massaro, DW.: Recent developments in facial animation: An inside view. In: Proceedings of Auditory-Visual Speech Processing 98, Sydney, Australia (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124934"><clusterid>295783</clusterid><authors>P Gebhard</authors><title>Enhancing embodied intelligent agents with affective user modelling</title><venue>In: Proceedings of UM2001, Doctoral Consortium summary</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>Berlin</pubAddress><raw>Gebhard, P.: Enhancing embodied intelligent agents with affective user modelling. In: Proceedings of UM2001, Doctoral Consortium summary (Springer, Berlin 2001)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124935"><clusterid>346213</clusterid><authors>B Hayes-Roth,R van Gent,Huber</authors><title>D.: Acting in character. Creating personalities for synthetic actors, ed by Trappl</title><year>1997</year><pages>92--112</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Hayes-Roth, B., van Gent, R., Huber, D.: Acting in character. Creating personalities for synthetic actors, ed by Trappl, R., Petta, P. (Springer, New York 1997) pp 92–112</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124936"><clusterid>330035</clusterid><authors>K Höök,P Persson,Sjölinder</authors><title>M.: Evaluating users’ experience of a characterenhanced Information Space</title><venue>AI Communications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><volume>13</volume><raw>Höök, K., Persson, P., Sjölinder, M.: Evaluating users’ experience of a characterenhanced Information Space. AI Communications 13(3):195–212 (2000)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124937"><clusterid>183162</clusterid><authors>M Huber</authors><title>JAM: A BDI-theoretic mobile agent architecture</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Autonomous Agents, (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>236--243</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Huber, M.: JAM: A BDI-theoretic mobile agent architecture. In: Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Autonomous Agents, (ACM Press, New York 1999) pp 236–243</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124938"><clusterid>164762</clusterid><authors>K Isbister,H Nakanishi,T Ishida,Nass</authors><title>C.: Helper agent: Designing an assistant for human-human interaction in a virtual meeting space</title><venue>In: Proceedings of CHI 2000 (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>57--64</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Isbister, K., Nakanishi, H., Ishida, T., Nass, C.: Helper agent: Designing an assistant for human-human interaction in a virtual meeting space. In: Proceedings of CHI 2000 (ACM Press, New York 2000) pp 57–64</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124939"><clusterid>235106</clusterid><authors>M Ishizuka,T Tsutsui,S Saeyor,H Dohi,Y Zong,Prendinger</authors><title>H.: MPML: A multimodal presentation markup language with character control functions</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Achieving Human-like Behavior in Interactive Animated Agents, held in conj. with AAMAS’02 (2002) pp 50–54</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Ishizuka, M., Tsutsui, T., Saeyor, S., Dohi, H., Zong, Y., Prendinger, H.: MPML: A multimodal presentation markup language with character control functions. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Achieving Human-like Behavior in Interactive Animated Agents, held in conj. with AAMAS’02 (2002) pp 50–54</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124940"><clusterid>1252781</clusterid><authors>M Kipp</authors><title>From human gesture to synthetic action</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Multimodal Communication and Context in Embodied Agents, held in conj. with the Fifth International Conference on Autonomous Agents (2001) pp 9–14</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Kipp, M.: From human gesture to synthetic action. In: Proceedings of the Workshop on Multimodal Communication and Context in Embodied Agents, held in conj. with the Fifth International Conference on Autonomous Agents (2001) pp 9–14</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124941"><clusterid>89809</clusterid><authors>M Kipp</authors><title>Anvil – a generic annotation tool for multimodal dialogue</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Eurospeech’01 (2001) pp 1367–1370</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Kipp, M.: Anvil – a generic annotation tool for multimodal dialogue. In: Proceedings of Eurospeech’01 (2001) pp 1367–1370</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124942"><clusterid>72314</clusterid><authors>H Kitano,M Asada,Y Kuniyoshi,I Noda,E Osawa,Matsubara</authors><title>H.: RoboCup: A challenging problem for AI</title><venue>AI Magazine</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><volume>18</volume><raw>Kitano, H., Asada, M., Kuniyoshi, Y., Noda, I., Osawa, E., Matsubara, H.: RoboCup: A challenging problem for AI. AI Magazine 18(1):73–85 (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124943"><clusterid>1207457</clusterid><authors>M Klesen,J Szatkowski,Lehmann</authors><title>N.: A Dramatised Actant Model for Interactive Improvisational Plays</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the 3rd Intelligent Virtual Agents Workshop (IVA</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>181--194</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Klesen, M., Szatkowski, J., Lehmann, N.: A Dramatised Actant Model for Interactive Improvisational Plays. In: Proceedings of the 3rd Intelligent Virtual Agents Workshop (IVA) (Springer, New York 2001) pp 181–194</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124944"><clusterid>4566</clusterid><authors>D Kurlander,T Skelly,Salesin</authors><title>D.: Comic Chat</title><venue>In: Proceedings of SIGGRAPH’96</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>225--236</pages><raw>Kurlander, D., Skelly, T., Salesin, D.: Comic Chat. In: Proceedings of SIGGRAPH’96 (1996) pp 225–236</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124945"><clusterid>1471288</clusterid><authors>B Laurel</authors><title>Computers as Theatre (Addison-Wesley</title><year>1993</year><pubAddress>Reading MA</pubAddress><raw>Laurel, B.: Computers as Theatre (Addison-Wesley, Reading MA 1993)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124946"><clusterid>285140</clusterid><authors>J Voerman,J L Towns,S G Callaway</authors><title>C.B.: Deictic believability: Coordinated gesture, locomotion, and speech in lifelike pedagogical agents</title><venue>Applied Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><volume>13</volume><raw>Lester. J, Voerman, J.L., Towns, S.G., Callaway, C.B.: Deictic believability: Coordinated gesture, locomotion, and speech in lifelike pedagogical agents. Applied Artificial Intelligence 13:383–414 (1999)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124947"><clusterid>1460050</clusterid><authors>I Machado,A Paiva,Prada</authors><title>R.: Is the Wolf Angry or . . . Just Hungry</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Autonomous Agents (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>370--376</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Machado, I., Paiva, A., Prada, R.: Is the Wolf Angry or . . . Just Hungry? In: Proceedings of Autonomous Agents (ACM Press, New York 2001), pp 370–376</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124948"><clusterid>63279</clusterid><authors>P Maes,T Darrell,B Blumberg,Pentland</authors><title>A.: The ALIVE system: Wireless, full-Body Interaction with autonomous agents</title><venue>In: ACM Special Issue on Multimedia and Multisensory Virtual Worlds (1996)  Review on the Development of Embodied Presentation Agents 27</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Maes, P., Darrell, T., Blumberg, B., Pentland, A.: The ALIVE system: Wireless, full-Body Interaction with autonomous agents. In: ACM Special Issue on Multimedia and Multisensory Virtual Worlds (1996) A Review on the Development of Embodied Presentation Agents 27</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124949"><clusterid>235109</clusterid><authors>S C Marsella,W L Johnson,LaBore</authors><title>C.: Interactive pedagogical drama</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Autonomous Agents (ACM Press 2000) pp 301–308</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Marsella, S.C., Johnson, W.L., LaBore, C.: Interactive pedagogical drama. In: Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Autonomous Agents (ACM Press 2000) pp 301–308</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124950"><clusterid>42186</clusterid><authors>M Mateas</authors><title>An Oz-Centric review of interactive drama and believable agents</title><venue>School of CS, CMU</venue><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1997</year><pubAddress>Pittsburgh, PA</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report CMU-CS-97-156</tech><raw>Mateas, M.: An Oz-Centric review of interactive drama and believable agents. Technical Report CMU-CS-97-156, School of CS, CMU, Pittsburgh, PA. (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124951"><clusterid>27988</clusterid><authors>M Mateas,Stern</authors><title>A.: Towards integrating plot and character for interactive drama</title><venue>In: Working notes of the Social Intelligent Agents: The Human in the Loop Symposium (AAAI Press 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Mateas, M., Stern, A.: Towards integrating plot and character for interactive drama. In: Working notes of the Social Intelligent Agents: The Human in the Loop Symposium (AAAI Press 2000)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124952"><clusterid>2245436</clusterid><authors>H Matsubara,I Frank,K Tanaka-Ishii,I Noda,H Nakashima,Hasida</authors><title>K.: Character design for soccer commentary</title><venue>In: RoboCup-98: Robot Soccer World Cup II, ed by Asada, M., Kitano, H</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>34--49</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Matsubara, H., Frank, I., Tanaka-Ishii, K., Noda, I., Nakashima, H., Hasida, K.: Character design for soccer commentary. In: RoboCup-98: Robot Soccer World Cup II, ed by Asada, M., Kitano, H. (Springer, New York 1999) pp 34–49</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124953"><clusterid>1075971</clusterid><authors>K Nitta,O Hasegawa,T Akiba,T Kamishima,T Kurita,S Hayamizu,K Itoh,M Ishizuka,H Dohi,Okamura</authors><title>M.: An experimental multimodal disputation system</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the IJCAI ’97 Workshop on Intelligent Multimodal Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Nitta, K., Hasegawa, O., Akiba, T., Kamishima, T., Kurita, T., Hayamizu, S., Itoh, K., Ishizuka, M., Dohi, H., Okamura, M.: An experimental multimodal disputation system. In: Proceedings of the IJCAI ’97 Workshop on Intelligent Multimodal Systems (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124954"><clusterid>477117</clusterid><authors>T Noma,Badler</authors><title>N.: A virtual human presenter</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the IJCAI ’97 Workshop on Animated Interface Agents: Making them ntelligent</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>45--51</pages><raw>Noma, T., Badler, N.: A virtual human presenter. In: Proceedings of the IJCAI ’97 Workshop on Animated Interface Agents: Making them ntelligent (1997) pp 45–51</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124955"><clusterid>492726</clusterid><authors>C Pelachaud,V Carofiglio,B De Carolis,F de Rosis,Poggi</authors><title>I.: Embodied contextual agent in information delivering application</title><venue>Proceedings of AAMAS’02 (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>758--765</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Pelachaud, C., Carofiglio, V., De Carolis, B., de Rosis, F., Poggi, I.: Embodied contextual agent in information delivering application. Proceedings of AAMAS’02 (ACM Press, New York 2002) pp 758–765</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124956"><clusterid>19042</clusterid><authors>K Perlin,Goldberg</authors><title>A.: Improv: a system for scripting interactive actors in virtual worlds. Computer Graphics 30:205–216</title><year>1996</year><raw>Perlin, K., Goldberg, A.: Improv: a system for scripting interactive actors in virtual worlds. Computer Graphics 30:205–216 (1996)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124957"><clusterid>295785</clusterid><authors>H Prendinger,Ishizuka</authors><title>M.: Social role awareness in animated agents</title><venue>In: Proceedings 5th International Conference on Autonomous Agents (Agents-01) (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>270--277</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Prendinger, H., Ishizuka, M.: Social role awareness in animated agents. In: Proceedings 5th International Conference on Autonomous Agents (Agents-01) (ACM Press, New York 2001) pp 270–277</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124958"><clusterid>74501</clusterid><authors>C Rich,C L Sidner,Lesh</authors><title>N.: COLLAGEN: Applying collaborative discourse theory to human-computer interaction</title><venue>AI Magazine</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><volume>22</volume><raw>Rich, C., Sidner, C.L., Lesh, N.: COLLAGEN: Applying collaborative discourse theory to human-computer interaction. AI Magazine 22(4):15–25 (2001)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124959"><clusterid>1823619</clusterid><authors>J Rickel,Johnson</authors><title>W.L.: Virtual humans for team training in virtual reality</title><venue>In: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Artificial Intelligence in Education (IOS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>578--585</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>Amsterdam</pubAddress><raw>Rickel, J., Johnson, W.L.: Virtual humans for team training in virtual reality. In: Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Artificial Intelligence in Education (IOS Press, Amsterdam 1999) pp 578–585</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124960"><clusterid>705055</clusterid><authors>T Rist,E André,J Müller</authors><title>Adding animated presentation agents to the interface</title><venue>Proceedings of IUI 97 (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>79--86</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Rist, T., André, E., Müller, J.: Adding animated presentation agents to the interface. Proceedings of IUI 97 (ACM Press, New York 1997) pp 79–86</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124961"><clusterid>1028300</clusterid><authors>T Rist,E André,Baldes</authors><title>S.: A flexible platform for building applications with life-Like characters</title><venue>In: Proceedings of IUI’03 (ACM Press 2003) pp 158–165</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Rist, T., André, E., Baldes, S.: A flexible platform for building applications with life-Like characters. In: Proceedings of IUI’03 (ACM Press 2003) pp 158–165</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124962"><clusterid>295788</clusterid><authors>T Rist,Schmitt</authors><title>M.: Applying socio-psychological concepts of cognitive consistency to negotiation dialog scenarios with embodied conversational characters</title><venue>Proceedings of AISB’02 Symposium on Animated Expressive Characters for Social Interactions</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Rist, T., Schmitt, M.: Applying socio-psychological concepts of cognitive consistency to negotiation dialog scenarios with embodied conversational characters. Proceedings of AISB’02 Symposium on Animated Expressive Characters for Social Interactions (2002) pp 79–84 (Extended version submitted for publication in 2003)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124963"><clusterid>4708172</clusterid><authors>A E Scheflen</authors><title>The significance of posture in communication systems. Psychiatry 26:316–331</title><year>1964</year><raw>Scheflen, A.E.: The significance of posture in communication systems. Psychiatry 26:316–331 (1964)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124964"><clusterid>828964</clusterid><authors>M A Smith,S Farnham,Drucker</authors><title>S.M.: The social life of small graphical chat spaces</title><venue>In: Proceedings of CHI’2000 (2000) pp 462–469</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Smith, M.A., Farnham, S., Drucker, S.M.: The social life of small graphical chat spaces In: Proceedings of CHI’2000 (2000) pp 462–469</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124965"><clusterid>1400144</clusterid><authors>N Sgouros</authors><title>Dynamic generation, management and resolution of interactive plots</title><venue>Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><volume>107</volume><raw>Sgouros, N.: Dynamic generation, management and resolution of interactive plots. Artificial Intelligence 107(1):29–62 (1999)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124966"><clusterid>42230</clusterid><authors>W Swartout,R Hill,J Gratch,W L Johnson,C Kyriakakis,C LaBore,R Lindheim,S Marsella,D Miraglia,B Moore,J Morie,J Rickel,M Thiébaux,L Tuch,R Whitney,J Douglas</authors><title>Toward the Holodeck: Integrating graphics, sound, character and story</title><venue>In: Proceedings 5th International  Thomas Rist et al. Conference on Autonomous Agents (Agents-01) (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>409--416</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Swartout, W., Hill, R., Gratch, J., Johnson, W.L., Kyriakakis, C., LaBore, C., Lindheim, R., Marsella, S., Miraglia, D., Moore, B., Morie, J., Rickel, J., Thiébaux, M., Tuch, L., Whitney, R., Douglas, J.: Toward the Holodeck: Integrating graphics, sound, character and story. In: Proceedings 5th International 28 Thomas Rist et al. Conference on Autonomous Agents (Agents-01) (ACM Press, New York 2001) pp 409–416</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124967"><clusterid>2208281</clusterid><authors>N M Thalmann,Kalra</authors><title>P.: The simulation of a virtual TV presenter</title><venue>In: Computer graphics and applications (World Scientific</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>9--21</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>Singapore</pubAddress><raw>Thalmann, N.M., Kalra, P.: The simulation of a virtual TV presenter. In: Computer graphics and applications (World Scientific Press, Singapore 1995) pp 9–21</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124968"><clusterid>69152</clusterid><authors>D Traum,J Rickel</authors><title>Embodied agents for multi-party dialogue in immersive virtual worlds</title><venue>In: Proc of AAMAS’02 (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Traum, D., Rickel, J.: Embodied agents for multi-party dialogue in immersive virtual worlds. In: Proc of AAMAS’02 (ACM Press, New York 2002) pp 766–733</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124969"><clusterid>173109</clusterid><authors>H Vilhjalmsson,J Cassell</authors><title>BodyChat: Autonomous Communicative Behaviors in Avatars</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Autonomous Agents’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>269--276</pages><raw>Vilhjalmsson, H., Cassell, J.: BodyChat: Autonomous Communicative Behaviors in Avatars. In: Proceedings of Autonomous Agents’98 (1998) pp 269–276</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124970"><clusterid>146741</clusterid><authors>P Weyhrauch</authors><title>Guiding interactive drama</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1997</year><tech>Ph.D. thesis</tech><raw>Weyhrauch, P.: Guiding interactive drama. Ph.D. thesis. Carnegie Mellon University (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124971"><clusterid>4708173</clusterid><authors>J Yabe,S Takahashi,Shibayama</authors><title>E.: Automatic animation of discussions in usenet</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Advanced Visual Interfaces 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>84--91</pages><raw>Yabe, J., Takahashi, S., Shibayama, E.: Automatic animation of discussions in usenet. In: Proceedings of Advanced Visual Interfaces 2000 (2002) pp 84-91</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124972"><clusterid>1460052</clusterid><authors>M Young</authors><title>The cooperative contract in interactive entertainment. In: Socially Intelligent Agents: Creating Relationships with Computers and Robots, ed by Dautenhahn</title><year>2002</year><pages>229--234</pages><pubAddress>K., Bond, A.H., Canamero, L., Edmonds, B. (Kluwer, Dordrecht</pubAddress><raw>Young, M.: The cooperative contract in interactive entertainment. In: Socially Intelligent Agents: Creating Relationships with Computers and Robots, ed by Dautenhahn, K., Bond, A.H., Canamero, L., Edmonds, B. (Kluwer, Dordrecht 2002) pp 229–234</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124973"><clusterid>39557</clusterid><authors>W Wahlster,N Reithinger,Blocher</authors><title>A.: SmartKom: Multimodal communication with a life-Like character</title><venue>In: Proceedings of EUROSPEECH’01 (2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Wahlster, W., Reithinger, N., Blocher, A.: SmartKom: Multimodal communication with a life-Like character. In: Proceedings of EUROSPEECH’01 (2001)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation><citation id="15124974"><clusterid>111844</clusterid><authors>M A Walker,J E Cahn,Whittacker</authors><title>S.J.: Improvising linguistic style: Social and affective bases for agent personality</title><venue>In: Proceedings First International Conference on Autonomous Agents (Agents’97) (ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>10--17</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Walker, M.A., Cahn, J.E., Whittacker, S.J.: Improvising linguistic style: Social and affective bases for agent personality. In: Proceedings First International Conference on Autonomous Agents (Agents’97) (ACM Press, New York 1997) pp 10–17</raw><paperid>10.1.1.83.9484</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Apr 1, 2008</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://mm-werkstatt.informatik.uni-augsburg.de/files/publications/87/prendinger-2.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>