<document id="10.1.1.1.1595"><clusterid>1870</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Penelope --- A Pattern Tile Editor</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">lways is a current tile on which operations are performed. Penelope supports the following operations on tiles:  1. Setting and clearing the individual bits of a tile. Symmetrymodes allow performing these operations on symmetric positions of a tile.  2. Transforming tiles in various ways, such as shifting, flipping, and rotating.  3. Trimming, enlarging, resizing, and cropping tiles.  4. Adding annotations to tiles.  Operations on the tile list include:  1. Adding new tiles.  2. Deleting existing tiles.  3. Sorting in various ways.  These operations are described in more detail in subsequent sections.  The Penelope Window  Penelope provides a window for displaying various aspects of a tile and through which various operations can be performed:  The bar at the top contains pull-down menus for various operations. At the left side of the window is a collection of buttons for performing transformations on the current tile. To the right of these buttons is an editing grid in which the curre</abstract><keywords><keyword id="841052">The Penelope Window</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ralph Griswold Department</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="2343706"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ralph E. Griswold</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">; Department of Computer Science, The University of Arizona; WAttrib(&amp;quot;fillstyle=textured&amp;quot;); Pattern(mesh)</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">; FilllRectangle(0, 0, 100, 50)</address><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29957"><clusterid>1871</clusterid><authors>Clinton L Jeffery,Gregg M Townsend,Ralph E Griswold</authors><title>Graphics Facilities for the Icon Programming Language; Version 9.0</title><year>1994</year><raw>Clinton L. Jeffery, Gregg M. Townsend, and Ralph E. Griswold, Graphics Facilities for the Icon Programming Language; Version 9.0, Department of Computer Science, The University of Arizona, 1994.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1595</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.cs.arizona.edu/icon/docs/../ftp/doc/ipd234.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>