<document id="10.1.1.1.1575"><clusterid>1594</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">AN OPTIMIZATION-BASED MULTI-RESOLUTION SIMULATION METHODOLOGY</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">The need for new approaches to the consistent simulation of related phenomena at multiple levels of resolution is great. While many fields of application would benefit from a complete and approachable solution to this problem, such solutions have proven extremely difficult. We present a multi-resolution simulation methodology which uses numerical optimization as a tool for maintaining external consistency between models of the same phenomena operating at different levels of temporal and/or spatial resolution. Our approach follows from previous work in the disparate fields of inverse modeling and spacetime constraintbased animation. As a case study, our methodology is applied to two environmental models of forest canopy processes that make overlapping predictions under unique sets</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4379"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">E. Yücesan</name><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4380"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">C. -h. Chen</name><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4381"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. L. Snowdon</name><order src="null">3</order></author><author id="4382"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. M. Charnes</name><order src="null">4</order></author><author id="4383"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Darren T. Drewry</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Department of Computer Science; University of Virginia</affil><order src="null">5</order></author><author id="4384"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Paul F. Reynolds</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Department of Computer Science; University of Virginia</affil><order src="null">6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29602"><clusterid>1595</clusterid><authors>D D Baldocchi,P C Harley</authors><title>Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. II. Model testing and application</title><year>1995</year><raw>Baldocchi, D.D., and P.C. Harley. 1995. Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. II. Model testing and application.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29603"><clusterid>1596</clusterid><authors>Plant</authors><title>Cell and Environment</title><pages>18--1157</pages><raw>Plant, Cell and Environment 18:1157-1173.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29604"><clusterid>1597</clusterid><authors>D D Baldocchi,K B Wilson</authors><title>Modeling CO2 and water vapor exchange of a temperate broadleaved forest across hourly to decadal time scales. Ecological Modelling</title><year>2001</year><pages>142--155</pages><raw>Baldocchi, D.D., and K.B. Wilson. 2001. Modeling CO2 and water vapor exchange of a temperate broadleaved forest across hourly to decadal time scales. Ecological Modelling 142:155-184.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29605"><clusterid>1598</clusterid><authors>B H Braswell,D S Schimel,J L Privette,B Moore W J Emery,E W Sulzman,A T Hudak</authors><title>Extracting ecological and biophysical information from AVHRR optical data: An integrated algorithm based on inverse modeling</title><venue>Journal of Geophysical Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><pages>23--335</pages><volume>101</volume><raw>Braswell, B.H., D.S. Schimel, J.L. Privette, B. Moore III, W.J. Emery, E.W. Sulzman, and A.T. Hudak. 1996. Extracting ecological and biophysical information from AVHRR optical data: An integrated algorithm based on inverse modeling. Journal of Geophysical Research 101 (18): 23,335-23,348.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29606"><clusterid>1599</clusterid><authors>P K Davis,R Hillestad</authors><title>Families of models that cross levels of resolution: issues for design, calibration, and management</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1993 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>1003--1012</pages><editors>ed. G.W. Evans, M. Mollaghasemi, E.C. Russell, and W.E. Biles</editors><raw>Davis, P.K., and R. Hillestad. 1993. Families of models that cross levels of resolution: issues for design, calibration, and management. In Proceedings of the 1993 Winter Simulation Conference, ed. G.W. Evans, M. Mollaghasemi, E.C. Russell, and W.E. Biles, 1003-1012.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29607"><clusterid>1600</clusterid><authors>D T Drewry,P F Reynolds,W R Emanuel</authors><title>Optimization as a tool for consistency maintenance in multi-resolution simulation</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2002</year><pages>2002--16</pages><pubAddress>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report No. CS2002-16</tech><raw>Drewry, D.T., P.F. Reynolds, and W.R. Emanuel. 2002. Optimization as a tool for consistency maintenance in multi-resolution simulation. Technical Report No. CS2002-16, Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia. &lt;ftp://ftp. cs.virginia.edu/pub/techreports/CS2002-16.pdf&gt;.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29608"><clusterid>1601</clusterid><authors>G D Farquhar,S von Caemmerer,J A Berry</authors><title>A biochemical model of photosynthetic CO2 assimilation in leaves of C3 species</title><year>1980</year><pages>149--78</pages><publisher>Planta</publisher><raw>Farquhar, G.D., S. von Caemmerer, and J.A. Berry. 1980. A biochemical model of photosynthetic CO2 assimilation in leaves of C3 species. Planta 149:78-90.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29609"><clusterid>1602</clusterid><authors>M Gleicher</authors><title>Retargetting motion to new characters</title><venue>In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>32--42</pages><volume>98</volume><raw>Gleicher, M. 1998. Retargetting motion to new characters. In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH 98. 32-42.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29610"><clusterid>1603</clusterid><authors>M Gleicher,P Litwinowicz</authors><title>Constraint-based motion adaptation</title><venue>The Journal of Visualization and Computer Animation</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>2--65</pages><volume>9</volume><raw>Gleicher, M. and P. Litwinowicz. 1998. Constraint-based motion adaptation. The Journal of Visualization and Computer Animation. 9 (2):65-94.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29611"><clusterid>1604</clusterid><authors>N S Goel,D E Strebel</authors><title>Inversion of vegetation canopy reflectance models for estimating agronomic variables. I. Problem definition and initial results using the Suits model. Remote Sensing of Environment</title><year>1983</year><pages>13--487</pages><raw>Goel, N.S., and D.E. Strebel. 1983. Inversion of vegetation canopy reflectance models for estimating agronomic variables. I. Problem definition and initial results using the Suits model. Remote Sensing of Environment 13:487-507.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29612"><clusterid>1595</clusterid><authors>P C Harley,D D Baldocchi</authors><title>Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. I. Leaf model parametrization</title><year>1995</year><raw>Harley, P.C., and D. D. Baldocchi. 1995. Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. I. Leaf model parametrization.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29613"><clusterid>1596</clusterid><authors>Plant</authors><title>Cell and Environment</title><pages>18--1146</pages><raw>Plant, Cell and Environment 18:1146-1156.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29614"><clusterid>1605</clusterid><authors></authors><title>MATLAB The Technical Language of Computing, Using MATLAB, Version 6. Available online via com/access/helpdesk/help/pdf_doc/matl ab/using_ml.pdf&gt; [accessed on January 18</title><venue>In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>11--20</pages><volume>99</volume><raw>The MathWorks, Inc. 2001. MATLAB The Technical Language of Computing, Using MATLAB, Version 6. Available online via &lt;http://www.mathworks. com/access/helpdesk/help/pdf_doc/matl ab/using_ml.pdf&gt; [accessed on January 18, 2002] Popovic, Z., and A. Witkin. 1999. Physically based motion transformation. In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH 99. 11-20.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29615"><clusterid>1606</clusterid><authors>J L Privette,W J Emery,D S Schimel</authors><title>Inversion of a vegetation reflectance model with NOAA AVHRR data. Remote Sensing of Environment</title><year>1996</year><pages>58--187</pages><raw>Privette, J.L., W.J. Emery, and D.S. Schimel. 1996. Inversion of a vegetation reflectance model with NOAA AVHRR data. Remote Sensing of Environment 58:187-200.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29616"><clusterid>1607</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Using space-time constraints to guide model interoperability</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 2002 Spring Simulation Interoperability Workshop</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Reynolds, P.F. Jr. 2002. Using space-time constraints to guide model interoperability. In Proceedings of the 2002 Spring Simulation Interoperability Workshop.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29617"><clusterid>1608</clusterid><authors>P F Jr Reynolds,A Natrajan,S Srinivasan</authors><title>Consistency maintenance in multiresolution simulaDrewry, Reynolds, and Emanuel tions</title><venue>ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>7--3</pages><raw>Reynolds, P.F. Jr., A. Natrajan, and S. Srinivasan. 1997. Consistency maintenance in multiresolution simulaDrewry, Reynolds, and Emanuel tions. ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation 7(3):368-392.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation><citation id="29618"><clusterid>1609</clusterid><authors>A Witkin,M Kass</authors><title>Spacetime constraints</title><venue>In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1988</year><pages>159--168</pages><volume>88</volume><raw>Witkin A., and M. Kass. 1988. Spacetime constraints. In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH 88. 159-168.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1575</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc02papers/058.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>e913985bc9be8630ef1e191b092eb7155f0f0fe6</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>