<document id="10.1.1.1.1575"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">AN OPTIMIZATION-BASED MULTI-RESOLUTION SIMULATION METHODOLOGY</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">The need for new approaches to the consistent simulation of related phenomena at multiple levels of resolution is great. While many fields of application would benefit from a complete and approachable solution to this problem, such solutions have proven extremely difficult. We present a multi-resolution simulation methodology which uses numerical optimization as a tool for maintaining external consistency between models of the same phenomena operating at different levels of temporal and/or spatial resolution. Our approach follows from previous work in the disparate fields of inverse modeling and spacetime constraintbased animation. As a case study, our methodology is applied to two environmental models of forest canopy processes that make overlapping predictions under unique sets</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4379"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">E. Yücesan</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4380"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">C. -h. Chen</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4381"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. L. Snowdon</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4382"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. M. Charnes</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4383"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Darren T. Drewry</name><order>5</order></author><author id="4384"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Paul F. Reynolds</name><order>6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29602"><authors>D D Baldocchi,P C Harley</authors><title>Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. II. Model testing and application</title><year>1995</year><raw>Baldocchi, D.D., and P.C. Harley. 1995. Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. II. Model testing and application.</raw><contexts><context>. Brief descriptions of the two models are presented below, focusing on key similarities and differences between them, as well as features used as points of focus for this study. 2.2.1 CANOAK CANOAK (Baldocchi and Harley 1995; Harley and Baldocchi 1995) was designed as a detailed biophysical model of an oak canopy. The goal of this model is to simulate the high temporal resolution water, energy and carbon dioxide (CO2) fl</context><context>en validated at a site in Oak Ridge, Tennessee, and has been shown to have good performance in predicting water, energy, and CO2 exchange over a spectrum of timescales ranging from diurnal to annual (Baldocchi and Harley 1995; Baldocchi and Wilson 2001). The model separates a forest canopy into forty horizontal layers, with leaves distributed equally throughout each layer. Both micrometeorological and ecophysiological mod</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29603"><authors>Plant</authors><title>Cell and Environment</title><pages>18--1157</pages><raw>Plant, Cell and Environment 18:1157-1173.</raw></citation><citation id="29604"><authors>D D Baldocchi,K B Wilson</authors><title>Modeling CO2 and water vapor exchange of a temperate broadleaved forest across hourly to decadal time scales. Ecological Modelling</title><year>2001</year><pages>142--155</pages><raw>Baldocchi, D.D., and K.B. Wilson. 2001. Modeling CO2 and water vapor exchange of a temperate broadleaved forest across hourly to decadal time scales. Ecological Modelling 142:155-184.</raw><contexts><context>ak Ridge, Tennessee, and has been shown to have good performance in predicting water, energy, and CO2 exchange over a spectrum of timescales ranging from diurnal to annual (Baldocchi and Harley 1995; Baldocchi and Wilson 2001). The model separates a forest canopy into forty horizontal layers, with leaves distributed equally throughout each layer. Both micrometeorological and ecophysiological modules are coupled in an effo</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29605"><authors>B H Braswell,D S Schimel,J L Privette,B Moore W J Emery,E W Sulzman,A T Hudak</authors><title>Extracting ecological and biophysical information from AVHRR optical data: An integrated algorithm based on inverse modeling</title><venue>Journal of Geophysical Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><pages>23--335</pages><volume>101</volume><raw>Braswell, B.H., D.S. Schimel, J.L. Privette, B. Moore III, W.J. Emery, E.W. Sulzman, and A.T. Hudak. 1996. Extracting ecological and biophysical information from AVHRR optical data: An integrated algorithm based on inverse modeling. Journal of Geophysical Research 101 (18): 23,335-23,348.</raw><contexts><context> the surface features described by the set of controlling variables discussed above. Through what has been termed “model inversion”, an optimization scheme is applied to the canopy reflectance model (Braswell et al. 1996). The optimization process seeks to discover valid values of the controlling variables which produce near identical results of canopy reflectance as those measured by satellite imagery. The optimizat</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29606"><authors>P K Davis,R Hillestad</authors><title>Families of models that cross levels of resolution: issues for design, calibration, and management</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1993 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>1003--1012</pages><editors>ed. G.W. Evans, M. Mollaghasemi, E.C. Russell, and W.E. Biles</editors><raw>Davis, P.K., and R. Hillestad. 1993. Families of models that cross levels of resolution: issues for design, calibration, and management. In Proceedings of the 1993 Winter Simulation Conference, ed. G.W. Evans, M. Mollaghasemi, E.C. Russell, and W.E. Biles, 1003-1012.</raw></citation><citation id="29607"><authors>D T Drewry,P F Reynolds,W R Emanuel</authors><title>Optimization as a tool for consistency maintenance in multi-resolution simulation</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2002</year><pages>2002--16</pages><pubAddress>Charlottesville, Virginia</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report No. CS2002-16</tech><raw>Drewry, D.T., P.F. Reynolds, and W.R. Emanuel. 2002. Optimization as a tool for consistency maintenance in multi-resolution simulation. Technical Report No. CS2002-16, Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia. &lt;ftp://ftp. cs.virginia.edu/pub/techreports/CS2002-16.pdf&gt;.</raw></citation><citation id="29608"><authors>G D Farquhar,S von Caemmerer,J A Berry</authors><title>A biochemical model of photosynthetic CO2 assimilation in leaves of C3 species</title><year>1980</year><pages>149--78</pages><publisher>Planta</publisher><raw>Farquhar, G.D., S. von Caemmerer, and J.A. Berry. 1980. A biochemical model of photosynthetic CO2 assimilation in leaves of C3 species. Planta 149:78-90.</raw></citation><citation id="29609"><authors>M Gleicher</authors><title>Retargetting motion to new characters</title><venue>In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>32--42</pages><volume>98</volume><raw>Gleicher, M. 1998. Retargetting motion to new characters. In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH 98. 32-42.</raw><contexts><context>etime constraints was applied to the problem of adapting preexisting motions to characters other than those that were used to create it. This application has been referred to as “motion retargeting” (Gleicher 1998) and “motion transformation” (Popovic and Witkin 1999). We will use the term “motion retargeting” in this discussion. The motion retargeting problem differs from the original spacetime constraints ap</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29610"><authors>M Gleicher,P Litwinowicz</authors><title>Constraint-based motion adaptation</title><venue>The Journal of Visualization and Computer Animation</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>2--65</pages><volume>9</volume><raw>Gleicher, M. and P. Litwinowicz. 1998. Constraint-based motion adaptation. The Journal of Visualization and Computer Animation. 9 (2):65-94.</raw><contexts><context>ith drastically different kinematic descriptions. The utility of viewing character motion as one or more discrete time series of joint angles and joint positions has been presented in the literature (Gleicher and Litwinowicz 1998). This view naturally suggests the application of signal processing techniques to modify motion signals so as to preserve the desired qualities of the original while modifying it to meet the goals of</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29611"><authors>N S Goel,D E Strebel</authors><title>Inversion of vegetation canopy reflectance models for estimating agronomic variables. I. Problem definition and initial results using the Suits model. Remote Sensing of Environment</title><year>1983</year><pages>13--487</pages><raw>Goel, N.S., and D.E. Strebel. 1983. Inversion of vegetation canopy reflectance models for estimating agronomic variables. I. Problem definition and initial results using the Suits model. Remote Sensing of Environment 13:487-507.</raw><contexts><context>ped as a means of predicting canopy reflectance for specific vegetation covers in specific locations. The class of models providing this functionality is generally known as canopy reflectance models (Goel and Strebel 1983). Canopy reflectance models can also be used to identify values of the surface features described by the set of controlling variables discussed above. Through what has been termed “model inversion”, </context><context> ) 2 n OBJ ( p) = ∑ w H L ( ) i 1 i i − = i p (2) where w is the optional vector of weights between 0 and 1 used to signify the importance of each of the values represented in the objective function (Goel and Strebel 1983; Privette et al. 1996). H and L represent the actual model values that are differenced, with H being the value produced by the high resolution model, and L representing that produced by the low resol</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29612"><authors>P C Harley,D D Baldocchi</authors><title>Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. I. Leaf model parametrization</title><year>1995</year><raw>Harley, P.C., and D. D. Baldocchi. 1995. Scaling carbon dioxide and water vapour exchange from leaf to canopy in a deciduous forest. I. Leaf model parametrization.</raw><contexts><context> two models are presented below, focusing on key similarities and differences between them, as well as features used as points of focus for this study. 2.2.1 CANOAK CANOAK (Baldocchi and Harley 1995; Harley and Baldocchi 1995) was designed as a detailed biophysical model of an oak canopy. The goal of this model is to simulate the high temporal resolution water, energy and carbon dioxide (CO2) fluxes between an oak canopy </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29613"><authors>Plant</authors><title>Cell and Environment</title><pages>18--1146</pages><raw>Plant, Cell and Environment 18:1146-1156.</raw></citation><citation id="29614"><title>MATLAB The Technical Language of Computing, Using MATLAB, Version 6. Available online via com/access/helpdesk/help/pdf_doc/matl ab/using_ml.pdf&gt; [accessed on January 18</title><venue>In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>11--20</pages><volume>99</volume><raw>The MathWorks, Inc. 2001. MATLAB The Technical Language of Computing, Using MATLAB, Version 6. Available online via &lt;http://www.mathworks. com/access/helpdesk/help/pdf_doc/matl ab/using_ml.pdf&gt; [accessed on January 18, 2002] Popovic, Z., and A. Witkin. 1999. Physically based motion transformation. In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH 99. 11-20.</raw><contexts><context>y. 3 THE OPTIMIZATION-BASED APPROACH We have explored the application of constrained optimization to multi-resolution modeling. An introductory overview of our approach has been presented by Reynolds (2002). Our approach takes advantage of numerical optimization as a method to establish a set of model parameter values which meet specified criteria, or goals. These parameters may be model constants or re</context><context>lues indicate the importance of SW and CX in guiding carbon assimilation calculations in the formulation used in DOLY. A more detailed discussion of experimental results can be found in Drewry et al. (2002). 5 DISCUSSION The results presented above demonstrate the promise of the application of optimization to problems in multi-resolution simulation. The parameterization of DOLY found above represents on</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29615"><authors>J L Privette,W J Emery,D S Schimel</authors><title>Inversion of a vegetation reflectance model with NOAA AVHRR data. Remote Sensing of Environment</title><year>1996</year><pages>58--187</pages><raw>Privette, J.L., W.J. Emery, and D.S. Schimel. 1996. Inversion of a vegetation reflectance model with NOAA AVHRR data. Remote Sensing of Environment 58:187-200.</raw><contexts><context> L ( ) i 1 i i − = i p (2) where w is the optional vector of weights between 0 and 1 used to signify the importance of each of the values represented in the objective function (Goel and Strebel 1983; Privette et al. 1996). H and L represent the actual model values that are differenced, with H being the value produced by the high resolution model, and L representing that produced by the low resolution model. The set o</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29616"><title>Using space-time constraints to guide model interoperability</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 2002 Spring Simulation Interoperability Workshop</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Reynolds, P.F. Jr. 2002. Using space-time constraints to guide model interoperability. In Proceedings of the 2002 Spring Simulation Interoperability Workshop.</raw></citation><citation id="29617"><authors>P F Jr Reynolds,A Natrajan,S Srinivasan</authors><title>Consistency maintenance in multiresolution simulaDrewry, Reynolds, and Emanuel tions</title><venue>ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>7--3</pages><raw>Reynolds, P.F. Jr., A. Natrajan, and S. Srinivasan. 1997. Consistency maintenance in multiresolution simulaDrewry, Reynolds, and Emanuel tions. ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation 7(3):368-392.</raw><contexts><context> entity attributes when changing from high to low resolution, and disaggregation when moving in the opposite direction. Aggregation and disaggregation have been shown to suffer from several problems (Reynolds et al. 1997), including chain disaggregation, transitional latency, and difficulties in mapping between different levels of resolution. Reynolds et al. (1997) proposed, as an alternative, the concept of multi-re</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29618"><authors>A Witkin,M Kass</authors><title>Spacetime constraints</title><venue>In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1988</year><pages>159--168</pages><volume>88</volume><raw>Witkin A., and M. Kass. 1988. Spacetime constraints. In Proceedings of SIGGRAPH 88. 159-168.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc02papers/058.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>e913985bc9be8630ef1e191b092eb7155f0f0fe6</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>