<document id="10.1.1.1.1604"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">10-th Annual Meeting of the Organization for Human Brain Mapping 2004 Subpixel Curvature Estimation of the Corpus Callosum via Splines and its Application to Autism</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Autism is a neurodevelopmental disorder with abnormal corpus callosum (CC) size [1]. Most previous studies used the area of predefined Witelson partition</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4452"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Thomas J. Hoffmann</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4453"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Moo K. Chung</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4454"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Kim D. Dalton</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4455"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Andrew L. Alex</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4456"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Grace Wahba</name><order>5</order></author><author id="4457"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Richard J. Davidson</name><order>6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30072"><authors>A Y Harden</authors><venue>Corpus Callosum Size in Autism. Neurology</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>55--1033</pages><raw>Harden, A.Y. et al. Corpus Callosum Size in Autism. Neurology, 55:1033-1036, 2000.</raw><contexts><context>t of Biostatistics and Medical Informatics, 3 Keck Laboratory for Functional Brain Imaging and Behavior, Waisman Center Autism is a neurodevelopmental disorder with abnormal corpus callosum (CC) size [1]. Most previous studies used the area of predefined Witelson partition [5] as a morphometric measure but other shape metrics have not been considered. We present a new computational technique for curv</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30073"><authors>R Malladi,J A Sethian</authors><title>An o(n log(n)) Algorithm for Shape Modeling</title><venue>Applied Mathematics 18:9389– 9392</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><raw>Malladi, R. and Sethian, J.A. An o(n log(n)) Algorithm for Shape Modeling. Applied Mathematics 18:9389– 9392, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>, and 12 normal controls. The level set method was used to extract the boundary Ψ of the corpus callosum automatically by solving ∂Ψ ∂t + F |∇Ψ| = 0 where F is the given boundary propagation velocity [2]. Then the pixelated CC contour was reconstructed into a rough closed curve in Euclidean space (Figure 1. red). Smoothing of this zigzag contour was necessary to account for the partial volume effect </context></contexts></citation><citation id="30074"><authors>G Taubin</authors><title>A Signal Processing Approach to Fair Surface Design</title><venue>Computer Graphics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><volume>29</volume><raw>Taubin, G. A Signal Processing Approach to Fair Surface Design. Computer Graphics, 29:351–358, 1995.</raw><contexts><context>ontour was necessary to account for the partial volume effect (Figure 1. blue). Two different methods were used to smooth and estimate the curvature function. The first method uses Taubin’s smoothing [3], a Gaussian filtering without shrinkage, followed by the least-squares estimation. The second method uses quintic splines to estimate the first and second derivatives to compute the curvature: min g </context></contexts></citation><citation id="30075"><authors>K Wang,Y Wang</authors><title>Alignment of Curves by Dynamic Time Warping</title><venue>Annals of Statistics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><volume>25</volume><raw>Wang, K. and Wang, Y. Alignment of Curves by Dynamic Time Warping. Annals of Statistics, 25:1251–1276, 1997.</raw><contexts><context> shape metrics have not been considered. We present a new computational technique for curvature estimation via piecewise quintic splines and use it in both CC nonlinear dynamic time warping algorithm [4] and detecting the regions of curvature difference. Figure 1: Left: level set segmentation showing partial volume effect. Right: spline smoothing. A similar approach has been taken in [6]. Methods A g</context><context> all other curves were registered to the template. First an affine registration was used to normalize the global CC size differences. Second the fast nonlinear dynamic-time warping algorithm was used [4]. The algorithm penalized against large deformation and curvature difference, thereby matching the extrema of curvature while maintaining 4 Department of Psychiatry, 5 Department of Medical Physics, 6</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30076"><authors>S F Hand Witelson</authors><title>and sex differences in the isthmus and genu of the human corpus callosum</title><venue>Brain</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1989</year><pages>83--5</pages><volume>112</volume><raw>Witelson, S.F. Hand and sex differences in the isthmus and genu of the human corpus callosum. Brain 112:799– 835. 1989.</raw><contexts><context>al Brain Imaging and Behavior, Waisman Center Autism is a neurodevelopmental disorder with abnormal corpus callosum (CC) size [1]. Most previous studies used the area of predefined Witelson partition [5] as a morphometric measure but other shape metrics have not been considered. We present a new computational technique for curvature estimation via piecewise quintic splines and use it in both CC nonli</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30077"><authors>J D Carew,R K Dalal,G Wahba,S B Fain</authors><title>Estimating arterior wall shear stress</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><tech>Tech. Report 1088</tech><raw>Carew, J.D., Dalal, R.K., Wahba, G. and Fain, S.B. Estimating arterior wall shear stress. Tech. Report 1088, University of Wisconsin.</raw><contexts><context>ng algorithm [4] and detecting the regions of curvature difference. Figure 1: Left: level set segmentation showing partial volume effect. Right: spline smoothing. A similar approach has been taken in [6]. Methods A group of 2D mid sagittal cross section images of the corpus callosum was taken from males of similar age, 15 autistic, and 12 normal controls. The level set method was used to extract the </context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.stat.wisc.edu/~mchung/papers/HBM2004/HBM2004thomas-poster.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>92e95faf76ac304249de976334973f22337d1971</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>