<document id="10.1.1.1.1596"><clusterid>1872</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">On the Resolvability of Sinusoids with Nearby Frequencies in the Presence of Noise</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">This paper develops statistical algorithms and performance limits for resolving sinusoids with nearby frequencies, in the presence of noise. We address the problem of distinguishing whether the received signal is a single-frequency sinusoid or a double-frequency sinusoid, with possibly unequal, and unknown, amplitudes and phases. We derive a locally optimal detection strategy that can be applied in a stand-alone fashion or as a refinement step for existing spectral estimation methods, to yield improved performance. We further derive explicit relationships between the minimum detectable di#erence between the frequencies of two tones, for any particular false alarm and detection rate, and at a given SNR. # This work was supported in part by NSF CAREER Award CCR-9984246, and AFOSR grant F49620-03-1-0387.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Morteza Shahram And</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="2365387"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Morteza Shahram</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Department of Electrical Engineering; University of California, Santa Cruz</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">CA 95064</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">shahram @ee.ucsc.edu</email><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author><author id="2365388"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Peyman Milanfar</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Department of Electrical Engineering; University of California, Santa Cruz</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">CA 95064</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">milanfar@ee.ucsc.edu</email><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29958"><clusterid>1873</clusterid><authors>Don H Johnson,Dan E Dugeon</authors><title>Array Signal Processing: Concepts and Techniques</title><venue>IEEE Trans. Acoust., Speech and Signal Processing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>331--341</pages><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><volume>2</volume><raw>[1] Don H. Johnson and Dan E. Dugeon, Array Signal Processing: Concepts and Techniques, Prentice Hall, 1993 [2] M. Kaveh, A. J. Barabell, The statistical performance of the MUSIC and the MinimumNorm algorithms in resolving plane waves in noise, IEEE Trans. Acoust., Speech and Signal Processing, vol. ASSP-34, pp. 331-341, Apr. 1986.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29959"><clusterid>1874</clusterid><authors>L L Scharf,B Friedlander</authors><title>Matched subspace detectors</title><venue>IEEE Trans. on Signal Processing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>2146--2157</pages><volume>42</volume><raw>[3] L. L. Scharf and B. Friedlander, Matched subspace detectors, IEEE Trans. on Signal Processing, vol. 42, pp. 2146-2157, August 1994. [4] J. A. Cadzow, Y. S. Kim, D. C. Shiue, General direction-of-arrival estimation: a signal subspace approach , IEEE Trans. Aerospace and Electronic Systems, Vol. 25, Issue 1, pp.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29960"><clusterid>1875</clusterid><authors>Jan</authors><title>Direction finding: a signal subspace approach</title><venue>IEEE Trans Systems, Man and Cybernetics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1989</year><pages>1115--1124</pages><publisher>Prentice-Hall, Inc</publisher><volume>21</volume><raw>31-47, Jan. 1989 [5] J. A. Cadzow, Direction finding: a signal subspace approach, IEEE Trans Systems, Man and Cybernetics, , Vol. 21, Issue 5, pp. 1115-1124, Sept.-Oct. 1991 [6] S. M. Kay, Modern Spectral Estimation: Theory and Application. Prentice-Hall, Inc, 1988 [7] S. M. Kay, Spectrum Analysis: A Modern Perspective. Proc. IEEE, vol. 69, No. 11, pp. 1380-1418, 1981.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29961"><clusterid>1876</clusterid><authors>V U Reddy,L S Biradar</authors><title>SVD-based information theoretic criteria for detection of the number of damped/undamped sinusoids and their performance analysis</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Volume: 41 Issue: 9</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>2872--2881</pages><volume>9</volume><raw>[8] V.U. Reddy, L.S. Biradar, SVD-based information theoretic criteria for detection of the number of damped/undamped sinusoids and their performance analysis, IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Volume: 41 Issue: 9 , pp. 2872 -2881, Sept. 1993 [9] L.T. McWhorter, L.L. Scharf, Cramer-Rao bounds for deterministic modal analysis, IEEE Trans. Signal Proc., SP-41, pp. 1847-1862, May 1993.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29962"><clusterid>1877</clusterid><authors>L L Scharf,P H Moose</authors><title>Information measures and performance bounds for array processors</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Volume: 39 Issue: 12</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1976</year><pages>11--21</pages><volume>1</volume><raw>[10] L. L. Scharf, P. H. Moose, Information measures and performance bounds for array processors, IEEE Trans. on Information Theory, Vol IT-22, No. 1, pp. 11-21, Jan 1976 [11] H. V. Hamme, A stochastical limit to the resolution of least squares estimation of the frequencies of a double complex sinusoid, IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, Volume: 39 Issue: 12 , pp. 2652 -2658, Dec. 1991 [12] P. Stoica and A. Nehorai, MUSIC, maximum likelihood, and Cramr-Rao bound, IEEE Trans. Acoust., Speech Signal Processing, vol. 37, pp. 720-741, May 1989.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29963"><clusterid>1878</clusterid><authors>P Stoica,A Nehorai,MUSIC</authors><title>maximum likelihood, and Cramr-Rao bound: Further results and comparisons</title><venue>IEEE Trans. Acoust., Speech, Signal Processing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><pages>2140215--0</pages><volume>38</volume><raw>[13] P. Stoica and A. Nehorai, MUSIC, maximum likelihood, and Cramr-Rao bound: Further results and comparisons, IEEE Trans. Acoust., Speech, Signal Processing, vol. 38, pp. 21402150, Dec. 1990.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29964"><clusterid>1879</clusterid><authors>A Weiss,B Friedlander</authors><title>Effects of modeling error on the resolution threshold of the MUSIC algorithm</title><venue>IEEE Trans on Signal Processing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>147--155</pages><volume>42</volume><raw>[14] A. Weiss, B. Friedlander, Effects of modeling error on the resolution threshold of the MUSIC algorithm, IEEE Trans on Signal Processing, Vol. 42, No. 1, pp. 147-155, 1994.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29965"><clusterid>1880</clusterid><authors>H B Lee,M S Wegrovitz</authors><title>Resolution threshold of beamspace MUSIC for two closely spaced emitters</title><venue>IEEE Trans. on Acoustic, Speech, Signal Proc</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><pages>1545--1559</pages><volume>38</volume><raw>[15] H. B. Lee, M. S. Wegrovitz, Resolution threshold of beamspace MUSIC for two closely spaced emitters , IEEE Trans. on Acoustic, Speech, Signal Proc, vol. 38, pp. 1545-1559, Sep. 1990 [16] R. O. Schmidt, Multiple emitter location and signal parameter estimation, IEEE Trans.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29966"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors></authors><venue>Antennas Prop., AP-34</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1986</year><pages>276--280</pages><raw>Antennas Prop., AP-34, pp. 276–280, 1986.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29967"><clusterid>1881</clusterid><authors>A J Barabell</authors><title>Improving the resolution performance of eigenstructurebased directionfinding algorithms</title><venue>in Proc. ICASSP, Apr.1983</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>336--339</pages><pubAddress>Boston, MA</pubAddress><raw>[17] A. J. Barabell, Improving the resolution performance of eigenstructurebased directionfinding algorithms, in Proc. ICASSP, Apr.1983, pp. 336–339, Boston, MA.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29968"><clusterid>1882</clusterid><authors>S T Smith</authors><title>Statistical Resolution Limits and the Complexified Cramer-Rao Bound, To appear in</title><venue>In Proc. 32d Asilomar Conf. Signals, Systems and Computers</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><volume>19</volume><raw>[18] S. T. Smith, Statistical Resolution Limits and the Complexified Cramer-Rao Bound, To appear in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing [19] M. Zatman, S. T. Smith, Resolution and ambiguity bounds for interferometric-like systems, In Proc. 32d Asilomar Conf. Signals, Systems and Computers, 1998. [20] S. T. Smith, Cramer-Rao and resolution bounds for adaptive sensor array processing, Proc.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29969"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors></authors><venue>IEEE Statistical Signal Array Proc. Workshop</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>374--0</pages><pubAddress>Portland, OR</pubAddress><raw>IEEE Statistical Signal Array Proc. Workshop, Portland, OR, pp. 3740, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29970"><clusterid>1883</clusterid><authors>P Milanfar,A Shakouri</authors><title>A Statistical Analysis of Diffraction-Limited Imaging</title><venue>Proc. of the International Conference on Image Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>864--867</pages><raw>[21] P. Milanfar, A. Shakouri, A Statistical Analysis of Diffraction-Limited Imaging, Proc. of the International Conference on Image Processing, pp. 864-867, September 2002, Rochester,NY.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation><citation id="29971"><clusterid>1884</clusterid><authors>M Shahram,P Milanfar</authors><title>Imaging Below the Diffraction Limit, A Statistical Analysis</title><venue>in Incoherent Imaging, Proceedings of the SPIE Annual Meeting, Signal and Data Processing of Small Tergets 2003</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>677--689</pages><publisher>Prentice-Hall, Inc</publisher><pubAddress>San Diego, CA</pubAddress><volume>13</volume><raw>[22] M. Shahram, P. Milanfar, Imaging Below the Diffraction Limit, A Statistical Analysis, IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, vol. 13, no. 5, pp. 677-689, May 2004 [23] M. Shahram, P. Milanfar, A Statistical Analysis of Achievable Resolution in Incoherent Imaging, Proceedings of the SPIE Annual Meeting, Signal and Data Processing of Small Tergets 2003, August 2003, San Diego, CA [24] S. M. Kay, Fundamentals of Statistical Signal Processing, Estimation Theory. Prentice-Hall, Inc, 1998 [25] S. M. Kay, Fundamentals of Statistical Signal Processing, Detection Theory. Prentice-Hall, Inc, 1998 [26] L. L. Scharf, Statistical Signal Processing, Detection, Estimation, and Time Series Analysis. Addison-Wesley, 1991 [27] S. Kullback, Information Theory and Statistics, Dover Publications, Inc, 1968.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1596</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.cse.ucsc.edu/~milanfar/Freq_Res_Paper.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>