<document id="10.1.1.1.1556"><clusterid>1181</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Netview: Application Software for Constructing and Visually Exploring Phylogenetic Networks</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Introduction  Reconstructing evolutionary history of a group of species is a major task in biological study. Many methods exist for reconstructing such history, or phylogeny, but most of them are based on an assumption that evolution of given gene family can be represented as a tree. However some families of genes may have alternative historical structure that cannot be represented as a tree. Such history can result from events such as recombination, gene conversion and horizontal gene transfer, and require not tree but network for accurate representation. Parallel substitutions are also sources of non-tree networks. For the purpose of understanding such history we developed a program Netview, which enables constructing phylogenetic network based on the sequence data.  2 Netview  Netview uses following approach to construct a network: First, it constructs a NJ-tree [1] for provided set of sequences, using nucleotide di#erence distance matrix (Fig. 1). Then every nucleotide site positio</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2003</year><venue src="INFERENCE">Genome Informatics</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">JOURNAL</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">2003</pages><volume src="INFERENCE">14</volume><keywords><keyword id="856520">phylogenetic network</keyword><keyword id="856521">neighbor-joining method</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="2386856"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Kirill Kryukov</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Division of Population Genetics, National Institute of Genetics / Department of Genetics,</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Graduate University for Advanced Studies, Mishima 411-8540, Japan</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">kkryukov@lab.nig.ac.jp</email><order>1</order></author><author id="2386857"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Naruya Saitou</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Division of Population Genetics, National Institute of Genetics / Department of Genetics,</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Graduate University for Advanced Studies, Mishima 411-8540, Japan</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">nsaitou@genes.nig.ac.jp</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29252"><clusterid>1182</clusterid><authors>N Saitou,M Nei</authors><title>The neighbor-joining method: a new method for reconstructing phylogenetic trees, Molecular Biology and Evolution</title><year>1987</year><pages>4--406</pages><raw>Saitou, N. and Nei, M., The neighbor-joining method: a new method for reconstructing phylogenetic trees, Molecular Biology and Evolution, 4:406–425, 1987.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1556</paperid></citation><citation id="29253"><clusterid>1183</clusterid><authors>N Saitou,F-I Yamamoto</authors><title>Evolution of primate ABO blood group genes and their homologous genes, Molecular Biology and Evolution</title><year>1997</year><raw>Saitou, N. and Yamamoto, F.-I., Evolution of primate ABO blood group genes and their homologous genes, Molecular Biology and Evolution, 14(4):399–411, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1556</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://hc.ims.u-tokyo.ac.jp/JSBi/journal/GIW03/GIW03SS06.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>