<document id="10.1.1.1.1514"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract Human-Robot Interactions in Active Sensor Networks</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper considers the modes of interaction between one or several human operators and an active sensor network – a fully decentralized network of sensors some or all of which have actuators and are in that sense active. The primary goal of this study is to investigate the conditions under which the human involvement will not jeopardize scalability of the overall system. Two aspects of human-robot interaction are considered: the ways in which the global view of the system may be conveyed to the operators, and how the operators may influence the behavior of the system during the course of its operation. The results of analysis favor peer-topeer information-based interactions between the operators and the network whereby the humans act as extended sensors and communication nodes of the network itself. Experiments on an indoor active sensor network are described. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4193"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Alexei Makarenko</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Australia</address><order>1</order></author><author id="4194"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Ben Grocholsky</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Australia</address><order>2</order></author><author id="4195"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Hugh Durrant-whyte</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Australia</address><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28434"><authors>H F Durrant-Whyte,M Stevens</authors><title>Data fusion in decentralised sensing networks</title><venue>In 4th Int. Conf. on Information Fusion</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pubAddress>Montreal, Canada</pubAddress><raw>H.F. Durrant-Whyte and M. Stevens. Data fusion in decentralised sensing networks. In 4th Int. Conf. on Information Fusion, Montreal, Canada, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>ly decentralized network of sensors some or all of which have actuators and are, in that sense, active. Sensor networks which are based on decentralized architecture are scalable, robust, and modular [1]. For an ASN, both the data fusion and the control parts must be decentralized and scalable. For an ASN with a human operator in the loop, the human-robot interface must also be designed with scalabil</context><context>part of this work. 3 Active Sensor Networks The active sensor networks considered in this paper are based on a decentralized architecture. A decentralized system is characterized by three constraints [1]: 1. There is no single central information fusion or coordination center; no node should be central to the successful operation of the network. 2. There is no common communication facility; nodes can</context><context>t i in team α S world states (terrain, features, agents, etc.) agent’s domain-level actions Ai Σi Pi Ωi Oi Bi agent’s communication actions world model, i.e. transitional probability P : S × Aα × S → [0, 1] P (s, a, s ′ ) = P r(S t+1 = s ′ |S t = s, A t = a) agent’s observations agent’s observation function Oi(s, a, ω) = P r(Ω t i = ω|S t = s, A t−1 = a) agent’s belief states, updated through observatio</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28435"><authors>D Estrin,R Govindan,J S Heidemann,S Kumar</authors><title>Next century challenges: Scalable coordination in sensor networks</title><venue>In Mobile Computing and Networking</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>263--270</pages><pubAddress>Seattle, WA, USA</pubAddress><raw>D. Estrin, R. Govindan, J. S. Heidemann, and S. Kumar. Next century challenges: Scalable coordination in sensor networks. In Mobile Computing and Networking, pages 263–270, Seattle, WA, USA, 1999.</raw><contexts><context> passive (uncontrolled) sensor networks grew out of the field of distributed sensing, estimation, and data fusion. Recent work focuses on large dynamic sensor networks in which attribute based naming [2] must be used instead of traditional address naming. Simulations of information-theoretic sensor selection algorithms in networks of up to a 100 nodes are reported in [17]. This work builds on a decen</context><context>R), or • what additional information about the world to use (an observation ω or a belief b) Technically, all of these options can implemented in scalable fashion provided that attribute based naming [2] is used and proper communication infrastructure is available. A tree network created and maintained by the DDF algorithm is suitable for transmitting such command messages as well. The four options c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28436"><authors>T Fong,C Thorpe</authors><title>Robot as partner: Vehicle teleoperation with collaborative control</title><venue>In NRL Workshop on Multi-Robot Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>195--202</pages><pubAddress>Washington, DC, USA</pubAddress><raw>T. Fong and C. Thorpe. Robot as partner: Vehicle teleoperation with collaborative control. In NRL Workshop on Multi-Robot Systems, pages 195–202, Washington, DC, USA, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>ms (II): The research in this field to date has been limited to communication between one or several humans and a small number of robots. The field of adjustable autonomy [8] or collaborative control [3] is an active research area which aims to span the gap between teleoperation and full autonomy. Current solutions call for bidirectional communication in the form of a human-robot dialog. With respect</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28437"><authors>B Grocholsky</authors><title>Information-Theoretic Control of Multiple Sensor Platforms</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2002</year><tech>Phd</tech><raw>B. Grocholsky. Information-Theoretic Control of Multiple Sensor Platforms. Phd, The University of Sydney, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>ensors and environment as a set of continuous states, together with the use of information as payoff, allows the information acquisition problem to be formulated as a standard optimal control problem [4]. Several classification systems for human-robot interactions have been suggested. For example, Scholtz [14] identifies mechanic, supervisory, and peer-to-peer levels of human-robot interaction. Alter</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28438"><authors>B Grocholsky,A Makarenko,T Kaupp,H Durrant-Whyte</authors><title>Scalable control of decentralised sensor platforms</title><venue>In The 2nd Int. Workshop on Information Processing in Sensor Networks (IPSN’03</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pubAddress>Palo Alto, CA, USA</pubAddress><raw>B. Grocholsky, A. Makarenko, T. Kaupp, and H. Durrant-Whyte. Scalable control of decentralised sensor platforms. In The 2nd Int. Workshop on Information Processing in Sensor Networks (IPSN’03), Palo Alto, CA, USA, 2003.</raw><contexts><context> of three indoor robots cooperatively build an map of a building in [15]. Both data fusion and control part of the algorithm are centralized. Decentralized control techniques are combined with DDF in [5]. In all of these works, the issues of human-robot interface are not addressed. This research area also includes a large body of work on reactive architectures, most of which are fully decentralized a</context><context>the platform, the sensor and actuator models, and the current state of the world supplied by the node, the controller will issue commands to the actuator which will maximize a certain reward function [5]. Any number of nodes, sensors, and actuators may be attached to a single platform but from the point of view of a node, a sensor, or a controller platform assignment is unique. Likewise, an arbitrary</context><context>dentified as point features by the laser range finders. The objective of the network is to find and localize the point features. An information surfing controller is implemented on the Pioneer robots [5]. It is a zero look-ahead control law which moves the platform in the direction of the steepest descent in information space. All software components run as separate applications and communicate with </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28439"><authors>Y-C Ho</authors><title>Team decision theory and information structures</title><venue>Proceedings of the IEEE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1980</year><volume>68</volume><raw>Y.-C. Ho. Team decision theory and information structures. Proceedings of the IEEE, 68(6):644–654, 1980.</raw><contexts><context> be constructed and programmed in a modular fashion. 3.1 Multi-Agent Framework To make discussion of various aspects of communication within an ASN more concrete, a formal team framework will be used [6, 12]. The problem is stated as two tuples. 〈S, Aα, Σα, P, Ωα, Oα, Bα, R, T 〉 , 〈πΣ, πA〉 (1) where for each agent i in team α S world states (terrain, features, agents, etc.) agent’s domain-level actions A</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28440"><authors>B Horling,R Vincent,R Mailler,J Shen,R Becker,K Rawlins,V Lesser</authors><title>Distributed sensor network for real time tracking</title><venue>In the 5th Int. Conf. on Autonomous Agents</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>417--424</pages><pubAddress>Montreal, Canada</pubAddress><raw>B. Horling, R. Vincent, R. Mailler, J. Shen, R. Becker, K. Rawlins, and V. Lesser. Distributed sensor network for real time tracking. In the 5th Int. Conf. on Autonomous Agents, pages 417–424, Montreal, Canada, 2001.</raw><contexts><context> a decentralized data fusion (DDF) architecture [16], demonstrated in a network of up to 8 nodes. Active sensor networks (I): A hierarchical architecture applied to real time tracking is described in [7]. The system of up to 32 nodes performed data fusion and made control decision, but it is not fully decentralized and human-robot issues are not addressed. An architecture for DDF and control with an </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28441"><authors>D Kortenkamp,D Schreckenghost,C Martin</authors><title>User interaction with multi-robot systems</title><venue>In NRL Workshop on Multi-Robot Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>213--220</pages><pubAddress>Washington, DC, USA</pubAddress><raw>D. Kortenkamp, D. Schreckenghost, and C. Martin. User interaction with multi-robot systems. In NRL Workshop on Multi-Robot Systems, pages 213–220, Washington, DC, USA, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>eraction in multi-robot systems (II): The research in this field to date has been limited to communication between one or several humans and a small number of robots. The field of adjustable autonomy [8] or collaborative control [3] is an active research area which aims to span the gap between teleoperation and full autonomy. Current solutions call for bidirectional communication in the form of a hum</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28442"><authors>A G O Mutambara</authors><title>Decentralized estimation and control for multisensor systems</title><year>1998</year><publisher>CRC Press</publisher><pubAddress>Boca Raton</pubAddress><raw>A. G. O. Mutambara. Decentralized estimation and control for multisensor systems. CRC Press, Boca Raton, 1998.</raw><contexts><context> data fusion and made control decision, but it is not fully decentralized and human-robot issues are not addressed. An architecture for DDF and control with an emphasis on scalability is described in [9]. A team of three indoor robots cooperatively build an map of a building in [15]. Both data fusion and control part of the algorithm are centralized. Decentralized control techniques are combined with</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28443"><authors>L E Parker</authors><title>Cooperative motion control for multitarget observation</title><venue>In IROS ’97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>1591--1598</pages><raw>L. E. Parker. Cooperative motion control for multitarget observation. In IROS ’97, pages 1591–1598, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>robot interface are not addressed. This research area also includes a large body of work on reactive architectures, most of which are fully decentralized and some were applied to sensing applications [10, 11]. They fall outside of the scope of this work because they do not perform network-level data fusion and typically do not interact with humans. Human-robot interaction in multi-robot systems (II): The </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28444"><authors>P Pirjanian,M J Mataric</authors><title>Multi-robot target acquisition using multiple objective behavior coordination</title><venue>In ICRA’00</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pubAddress>San Francisco, USA</pubAddress><raw>P. Pirjanian and M. J. Mataric. Multi-robot target acquisition using multiple objective behavior coordination. In ICRA’00, San Francisco, USA, 2000.</raw><contexts><context>robot interface are not addressed. This research area also includes a large body of work on reactive architectures, most of which are fully decentralized and some were applied to sensing applications [10, 11]. They fall outside of the scope of this work because they do not perform network-level data fusion and typically do not interact with humans. Human-robot interaction in multi-robot systems (II): The </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28445"><authors>D Pynadath,M Tambe</authors><title>The communicative multiagent team decision problem: Analyzing teamwork theories and models</title><venue>Journal of AI Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2002</year><raw>D. Pynadath and M. Tambe. The communicative multiagent team decision problem: Analyzing teamwork theories and models. Journal of AI Research, 2002.</raw><contexts><context> be constructed and programmed in a modular fashion. 3.1 Multi-Agent Framework To make discussion of various aspects of communication within an ASN more concrete, a formal team framework will be used [6, 12]. The problem is stated as two tuples. 〈S, Aα, Σα, P, Ωα, Oα, Bα, R, T 〉 , 〈πΣ, πA〉 (1) where for each agent i in team α S world states (terrain, features, agents, etc.) agent’s domain-level actions A</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28446"><authors>W D Rencken,H Durrant-Whyte</authors><title>A quantitative model for adaptive task allocation in human-computer interfaces</title><venue>IEEE Trans. on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><volume>23</volume><raw>W.D. Rencken and H. Durrant-Whyte. A quantitative model for adaptive task allocation in human-computer interfaces. IEEE Trans. on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, 23(4):1072–1090, 1993.</raw><contexts><context>ch precludes, at current stage, the use of techniques related to adjustable autonomy. Full autonomous operation is therefore assumed. Human-robot interactions in sensor networks (III): Rencken et al. [13] describes a DDF system of four camPASSIVE SENSOR NETWORKS IV II I III MULTI-ROBOT SYSTEMS HUMAN-ROBOT INTERFACE Figure 1: Convergence of the traditional field of multirobot systems with the fields o</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28447"><authors>J C Scholtz</authors><title>Human-robot interaction: Creating synergistic cyber forces</title><venue>In NRL Workshop on Multi-Robot Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>177--184</pages><pubAddress>Washington, DC, USA</pubAddress><raw>J. C. Scholtz. Human-robot interaction: Creating synergistic cyber forces. In NRL Workshop on Multi-Robot Systems, pages 177–184, Washington, DC, USA, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>s the information acquisition problem to be formulated as a standard optimal control problem [4]. Several classification systems for human-robot interactions have been suggested. For example, Scholtz [14] identifies mechanic, supervisory, and peer-to-peer levels of human-robot interaction. Alternatively, the potential control methods can be identified by examining Equation 1. An operator can tell a ro</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28448"><authors>R G Simmons,D Apfelbaum,W Burgard,D Fox,M Moors,S Thrun,H Younes</authors><title>Coordination for multi-robot exploration and mapping</title><venue>In AAAI Nat. Conf. on Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>852--858</pages><pubAddress>Austin, TX, USA</pubAddress><raw>R.G. Simmons, D. Apfelbaum, W. Burgard, D. Fox, M. Moors, S. Thrun, and H. Younes. Coordination for multi-robot exploration and mapping. In AAAI Nat. Conf. on Artificial Intelligence, pages 852–858, Austin, TX, USA, 2000.</raw><contexts><context>uman-robot issues are not addressed. An architecture for DDF and control with an emphasis on scalability is described in [9]. A team of three indoor robots cooperatively build an map of a building in [15]. Both data fusion and control part of the algorithm are centralized. Decentralized control techniques are combined with DDF in [5]. In all of these works, the issues of human-robot interface are not </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28449"><authors>S Sukkarieh,E Nettleton,J-H Kim,M Ridley,A Goktogan,H Durrant-Whyte</authors><title>The ANSER project – multi UAV data fusion</title><venue>Int. J. of Robotics Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><raw>S. Sukkarieh, E. Nettleton, J.-H. Kim, M. Ridley, A. Goktogan, and H. Durrant-Whyte. The ANSER project – multi UAV data fusion. Int. J. of Robotics Research, to be published, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>ress naming. Simulations of information-theoretic sensor selection algorithms in networks of up to a 100 nodes are reported in [17]. This work builds on a decentralized data fusion (DDF) architecture [16], demonstrated in a network of up to 8 nodes. Active sensor networks (I): A hierarchical architecture applied to real time tracking is described in [7]. The system of up to 32 nodes performed data fus</context><context>elief to the human operator. In the notation of team framework, DDF algorithm is primarily a communication policy π DDF Σ which is to send all new information about the environment along the channels [16]. This policy insures that a consistent belief Bα about the state of the world is maintained across all members of the team. One of the properties of the DDF architecture is that each node in the netw</context><context>n information form) to that node. When a node is connected to another node it means that they establish and maintain a DDF link leading to synchronization of their belief about the state of the world [16]. Finally, a controller can connect to a platform, a node, and a sensor. This means that, based on the current pose of the platform, the sensor and actuator models, and the current state of the world </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28450"><authors>F Zhao,J Shin,J Reich</authors><title>Information-driven dynamic sensor collaboration for tracking applications</title><venue>IEEE Signal Processing Magazine</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>F. Zhao, J. Shin, and J. Reich. Information-driven dynamic sensor collaboration for tracking applications. IEEE Signal Processing Magazine, 2002.</raw><contexts><context> which attribute based naming [2] must be used instead of traditional address naming. Simulations of information-theoretic sensor selection algorithms in networks of up to a 100 nodes are reported in [17]. This work builds on a decentralized data fusion (DDF) architecture [16], demonstrated in a network of up to 8 nodes. Active sensor networks (I): A hierarchical architecture applied to real time trac</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.grasp.upenn.edu/~bpg/makarenko03_hum_rob_in_asn.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>441a909d9d6025a5c176f0e193ea15195c58e515</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>