<document id="10.1.1.1.1559"><clusterid>1206</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Visualizing Multimedia Content on Paper Documents: Components of Key Frame Selection for Video Paper</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">The components of a key frame selection algorithm for a paper-based multimedia browsing interface called Video Paper are described. Analysis of video image frames is combined with the results of processing the closed caption to select key frames that are printed on a paper document together with the closed caption. Bar codes positioned near the key frames allow a user to play the video from the corresponding times. This paper describes several component techniques that are being investigated for key frame selection in the Video Paper system, including face detection and text recognition. The Video Paper system implementation is also discussed.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="2393825"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Jonathan J. Hull</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ricoh Innovations, Inc.</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Menlo Park, CA</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">hull @rii.ricoh.com</email><order>1</order></author><author id="2393826"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Berna Erol</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ricoh Innovations, Inc.</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Menlo Park, CA</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">berna_erol @rii.ricoh.com</email><order>2</order></author><author id="2393827"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Jamey Graham</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ricoh Innovations, Inc.</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Menlo Park, CA</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">jamey @rii.ricoh.com</email><order>3</order></author><author id="2393828"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Dar-shyang Lee</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ricoh Innovations, Inc.</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Menlo Park, CA</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">dsl@rii.ricoh.com</email><order>4</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29277"><clusterid>1207</clusterid><authors>T Arai,D Aust,S E Hudson</authors><title>PaperLink: A technique for hyperlinking from real paper to electronic content</title><venue>Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>327--334</pages><raw>Arai, T., Aust, D., and Hudson, S. E., “PaperLink: A technique for hyperlinking from real paper to electronic content,” Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 1997), 327-334.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29278"><clusterid>1208</clusterid><authors>J Boreczky,A Girgensohn,G Golovchinsky,S Uchihashi</authors><title>An Interactive Comic Book Presentation for Exploring Video</title><venue>Conference on Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition (ICDAR 2003) 0-7695-1960-1/03 $17.00 © 2003 IEEE Human factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>185--192</pages><raw>Boreczky, J., A. Girgensohn, G. Golovchinsky, and S. Uchihashi, “An Interactive Comic Book Presentation for Exploring Video,” Conference on Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition (ICDAR 2003) 0-7695-1960-1/03 $17.00 © 2003 IEEE Human factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2000), pp. 185-192, 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29279"><clusterid>1209</clusterid><authors>P Chiu,A Kapuskar,S Reitmeier,L Wilcox</authors><title>Notelook: Taking Notes</title><venue>in Meetings with Digital Video and Ink,” ACM Multimedia ’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Orlando, FL</pubAddress><raw>P. Chiu, A. Kapuskar, S. Reitmeier, and L. Wilcox, “Notelook: Taking Notes in Meetings with Digital Video and Ink,” ACM Multimedia ’99, Oct. 1999, Orlando, FL.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29280"><clusterid>1210</clusterid><authors>J Graham</authors><title>The Reader´s Helper: A Personalized Document Reading Environment</title><venue>Proc. of the CHI 99 conference on Human factors in computing systems: the CHI is the limit</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>481--488</pages><raw>J. Graham, “The Reader´s Helper: A Personalized Document Reading Environment,” Proc. of the CHI 99 conference on Human factors in computing systems: the CHI is the limit, May 1999, 481-488.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29281"><clusterid>1211</clusterid><authors>J Graham,J J Hull</authors><title>Video Paper: A Paperbased interface for skimming and watching video</title><venue>International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>214--215</pages><pubAddress>Los Angeles, CA</pubAddress><raw>J. Graham and J. J. Hull, “Video Paper: A Paperbased interface for skimming and watching video,” International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE), Los Angeles, CA, June 2002, 214-215.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29282"><clusterid>1212</clusterid><authors>D L Hecht</authors><title>Printed Embedded Data Graphical User Interfaces</title><venue>IEEE Computer</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><pages>4--7</pages><raw>D. L. Hecht, “Printed Embedded Data Graphical User Interfaces,” IEEE Computer, March 2001, 47-</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29283"><clusterid>1213</clusterid><authors>S Klemmer,J Graham,G Wolff,J Landay</authors><title>Books with voices: Paper transcripts as a physical interface to oral histories</title><venue>ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI-2003), Fort Lauderdale</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>5--10</pages><pubAddress>Florida</pubAddress><raw>S. Klemmer, J. Graham, G. Wolff, and J. Landay, “Books with voices: Paper transcripts as a physical interface to oral histories,” ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI-2003), Fort Lauderdale, Florida, April 5-10, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29284"><clusterid>1214</clusterid><authors>H Li,D Doermann,O Kia</authors><title>Automatic Text Detection and Tracking</title><venue>in Digital Video,” IEEE Transactions on Image Processing - Special Issue on Image and Video Processing for Digital Libraries</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>147--156</pages><volume>9</volume><raw>H. Li, D. Doermann, and O. Kia. “Automatic Text Detection and Tracking in Digital Video,” IEEE Transactions on Image Processing - Special Issue on Image and Video Processing for Digital Libraries, 9(1), 147-156, 2000 .</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29285"><clusterid>1215</clusterid><authors>B Shahraray,D C Gibbon</authors><title>Automated Authoring of Hypermedia Documents of Video Programs</title><venue>ACM Multimedia 95</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>5--9</pages><pubAddress>San Francisco, CA</pubAddress><raw>B. Shahraray and D. C. Gibbon, “Automated Authoring of Hypermedia Documents of Video Programs”, ACM Multimedia 95, November 5-9, 1995, San Francisco, CA.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29286"><clusterid>1216</clusterid><authors>M A Smith,T Kanade</authors><title>Video skimming and characterization through the combination of image and language understanding</title><venue>in Proc. IEEE International Workshop on Content Based Access of Image and Video Database</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>61--70</pages><raw>M.A. Smith and T. Kanade, &amp;quot;Video skimming and characterization through the combination of image and language understanding, &amp;quot; in Proc. IEEE International Workshop on Content Based Access of Image and Video Database, 1998, pp. 61--70.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29287"><clusterid>1217</clusterid><authors>L Stifelman,B Arons,C Schmandt</authors><title>The Audio Notebook: Paper and Pen Interaction with Structured Speech</title><venue>ACM CHI Conference</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>182--189</pages><pubAddress>Seattle, WA</pubAddress><volume>5</volume><raw>L. Stifelman, B. Arons, and C. Schmandt, “The Audio Notebook: Paper and Pen Interaction with Structured Speech,” ACM CHI Conference, Seattle, WA, March 31 – April 5, 2001, 182-189.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation><citation id="29288"><clusterid>1218</clusterid><authors>A Waibel,M Bett,F Metze,K Ries,T Schaaf,T Schultz,H Soltau,H Yu,K Zechner</authors><title>Advances in automatic meeting record creation and access</title><venue>Proceedings of the International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>200--1</pages><volume>597600</volume><raw>A. Waibel, M. Bett, F. Metze, K. Ries, T. Schaaf, T. Schultz, H. Soltau, H. Yu, and K. Zechner, &amp;quot;Advances in automatic meeting record creation and access&amp;quot;, Proceedings of the International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing, 597600, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1559</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.csc.liv.ac.uk/%7Eprima/ICDAR2003/Papers/0071_631_hull_j.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>