<document id="10.1.1.1.1560"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Automatic Topic Identification Using Ontology Hierarchy</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract. This paper proposes a method of using ontology hierarchy in automatic topic identification. The fundamental idea behind this work is to exploit an ontology hierarchical structure in order to find a topic of a text. The keywords which are extracted from a given text will be mapped onto their corresponding concepts in the ontology. By optimizing the corresponding concepts, we will pick a single node among the concepts nodes which we believe is the topic of the target text. However, a limited vocabulary problem is encountered while mapping the keywords onto their corresponding concepts. This situation forces us to extend the ontology by enriching each of its concepts with new concepts using the external linguistics knowledge-base (WordNet). Our intuition of a high number keywords mapped onto the ontology concepts is that our topic identification technique can perform at its best. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4347"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Sabrina Tiun</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">UTMK, P.Pengajian Sains Komputer, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800; Pulau Pinang, Malaysia</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">sab@cs.usm.my</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4348"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Rosni Abdullah</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">UTMK, P.Pengajian Sains Komputer, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800; Pulau Pinang, Malaysia</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">rosni@cs.usm.my</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4349"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Tang Enya Kong</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">UTMK, P.Pengajian Sains Komputer, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800; Pulau Pinang, Malaysia</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">enyakong@cs.usm.my</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29289"><authors>S Banerjee,V O Mittal</authors><title>On the Use of Linguistics Ontologies for Acessing Distributed Digital Libraries</title><venue>Proceeding of the First Annual Conference on Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>Banerjee, S., Mittal, V.O.: On the Use of Linguistics Ontologies for Acessing Distributed Digital Libraries. Proceeding of the First Annual Conference on Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries (1994)</raw><contexts><context> words in many ways. We try to take advantage of these semantics relationships to establish links between the words of Yahoo concepts and WordNet vocabulary. Based on our review on past related works [1], [13], [24] we decide to use three types of semantics relationships found in the WordNet and they are synonym 1 , hypernym/hyponym 2 and meronym/holonym 3 . Using these three semantics relationships,</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29290"><authors>S Chakrabarti,B Dom,Indyk</authors><title>P.: Enhanced Hypertext Categorization Using Hyperlinks</title><venue>ACM SIGMIND</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Seattle, Washington</pubAddress><raw>Chakrabarti, S., Dom, B., Indyk, P.: Enhanced Hypertext Categorization Using Hyperlinks. ACM SIGMIND, Seattle, Washington (1998)</raw></citation><citation id="29291"><authors>C Chekuri,M H Goldwasser,P Raghavan,Upfal</authors><title>E.: Web Search Using Automated Classification</title><venue>Poster at the Sixth International World Wide Web Conference (WWW6</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Chekuri, C., Goldwasser, M.H, Raghavan, P., Upfal, E.: Web Search Using Automated Classification. Poster at the Sixth International World Wide Web Conference (WWW6) (1997)</raw><contexts><context> followed by our conclusion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node cate</context><context>r, some web documents maybe lack of HTML tags and therefore our extraction technique is not appropriate to be used. In this case, alternative way of extracting web document like words frequency [18], [3] ,[11] and positional policy [16] are more applicable. Since in this paper we are interested in extracting out information from the web document based on HTML tag, we consider extracting information f</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29292"><authors>D’ Alessio,D Murray,K Schiaffino,R Kreshenbaum</authors><title>A.: Hierarchical Text Categorization. Proceeding RIAO2000</title><year>2000</year><raw>D’ Alessio, D., Murray, K., Schiaffino, R., Kreshenbaum, A.: Hierarchical Text Categorization. Proceeding RIAO2000 (2000)</raw><contexts><context>y our conclusion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node categories of t</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29293"><authors>D’ Alessio,D Murray,K Schiaffino,R Kreshenbaum</authors><title>A.: The effect of Topological Structure on Hierarchical Text Categorization</title><venue>Proceeding of the Sixth Workshop on Very Large Corpora, COLLING ACL ’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>D’ Alessio, D., Murray, K., Schiaffino, R., Kreshenbaum, A.: The effect of Topological Structure on Hierarchical Text Categorization. Proceeding of the Sixth Workshop on Very Large Corpora, COLLING ACL ’98 (1998)</raw></citation><citation id="29294"><authors>A Gelbukh,G Sidorov,Guzman</authors><title>A.: A Method of Describing Document Contents through Topic Selection</title><venue>In Proc. of International Symposium on String Processing and Information Retrieval, Cancun, Mexico. Library of Congress 99-64139, IEEE Computer</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><publisher>Society Press</publisher><raw>Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman, A.: A Method of Describing Document Contents through Topic Selection. In Proc. of International Symposium on String Processing and Information Retrieval, Cancun, Mexico. Library of Congress 99-64139, IEEE Computer Society Press (1999)</raw><contexts><context>. Using the height of generalization, they can limit the number of steps upward through the hypernym hierarchy for each word. The most comparable works to our technique of topic identification are by [6], [7] and [12] who uses a concept tree which was built manually (in our work, we use existing Yahoo ontology). In [12], the program called CLASITEX will analyze a document and look for words or colloc</context><context>ncept tree and this counting includes the upper level concepts. At the end, some parts of the concept tree will have higher counts and those parts are most likely the topics of the given document. In [6] and [7], they use numerical weight in measuring the relevance of the words for topics and the important of the nodes of the hierarchy to determine the principle topics of a given document. This metho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29295"><authors>A Gelbukh,G Sidorov,Guzman</authors><title>A.: Use of a Weighted Topic Hierarchy for Document Classification</title><venue>In Václav Matoušek et al (eds.): Text, Speech and Dialogue in Poc. 2 nd International Workshop. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, No.92, ISBN 3-54066494-7, Springer-Verlag., Czech Republic</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>130--135</pages><raw>Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman, A.: Use of a Weighted Topic Hierarchy for Document Classification. In Václav Matoušek et al (eds.): Text, Speech and Dialogue in Poc. 2 nd International Workshop. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, No.92, ISBN 3-54066494-7, Springer-Verlag., Czech Republic (1999) 130-135</raw><contexts><context>tion 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node categories of the hierarchy. By placin</context><context>ng the height of generalization, they can limit the number of steps upward through the hypernym hierarchy for each word. The most comparable works to our technique of topic identification are by [6], [7] and [12] who uses a concept tree which was built manually (in our work, we use existing Yahoo ontology). In [12], the program called CLASITEX will analyze a document and look for words or collocation</context><context>ee and this counting includes the upper level concepts. At the end, some parts of the concept tree will have higher counts and those parts are most likely the topics of the given document. In [6] and [7], they use numerical weight in measuring the relevance of the words for topics and the important of the nodes of the hierarchy to determine the principle topics of a given document. This method is imp</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29296"><authors>A Gelbukh,G Sidorov,Guzman</authors><title>A.,: Text Categorization Using a Hierarchical Topic Dictionary</title><venue>Proc. Text Mining Workshop at 16th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Stockholm, Sweden</pubAddress><raw>Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman, A.,: Text Categorization Using a Hierarchical Topic Dictionary. Proc. Text Mining Workshop at 16th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI’99), Stockholm, Sweden (1999)</raw></citation><citation id="29297"><authors>N Gövert,M Lalmas,Fuhr</authors><title>N.: A Probabilistic Description-Oriented Approach for Categorizing Web Document</title><venue>Proceeding of the Eighth International Conference on Information Knowledge Management</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>475--482</pages><pubAddress>Kansas City, MO USA</pubAddress><raw>Gövert, N., Lalmas, M., Fuhr, N.: A Probabilistic Description-Oriented Approach for Categorizing Web Document. Proceeding of the Eighth International Conference on Information Knowledge Management, Kansas City, MO USA (1999) 475-482</raw><contexts><context>uracy result was 45% on 100 test documents. [11] had their best result on accuracy at 51% using Yahoo hierarchy and Yahoo web documents. The non-hierarchical web documents automatic categorization by [9] that used probabilistic description-oriented had worst result on their preliminary experiment with only an average precision of 2.13%. Later after they had increased the size of their sample learning</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29298"><authors>R Greiner,A Grove,Schuurmans</authors><title>D.: On learning hierarchical Classifications</title><year>1997</year><raw>Greiner, R., Grove, A, Schuurmans, D.: On learning hierarchical Classifications (1997)</raw><contexts><context>s because if we already choose the wrong node at the top, our topic node will be wrong too. This problem is faced by most of the automatic text classification using hierarchical structure [14], [25], [10]. In this experiment we only use a small size of web ontology. This is because we are only interested in how our topic identification system performs on real data regardless of size. However, for futu</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29299"><authors>M Grobelnik,Mladenic</authors><title>D.: Fast Categorization</title><venue>In Proceedings of Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery Data Mining</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>Grobelnik, M., Mladenic, D.: Fast Categorization. In Proceedings of Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery Data Mining (1998)</raw><contexts><context>owed by our conclusion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node categories</context><context>me web documents maybe lack of HTML tags and therefore our extraction technique is not appropriate to be used. In this case, alternative way of extracting web document like words frequency [18], [3] ,[11] and positional policy [16] are more applicable. Since in this paper we are interested in extracting out information from the web document based on HTML tag, we consider extracting information from no</context><context>ning techniques on web documents classification. [18] obtained 37% of accuracy result using Yahoo with 151 classes and 50 documents. Their best attained accuracy result was 45% on 100 test documents. [11] had their best result on accuracy at 51% using Yahoo hierarchy and Yahoo web documents. The non-hierarchical web documents automatic categorization by [9] that used probabilistic description-oriented</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29300"><authors>A Guzman</authors><title>Finding the Main Themes in a Spanish Document. Journal Expert Systems with Application</title><year>1998</year><pages>139--148</pages><raw>Guzman, A.: Finding the Main Themes in a Spanish Document. Journal Expert Systems with Application (1998) 139-148</raw><contexts><context>eight of generalization, they can limit the number of steps upward through the hypernym hierarchy for each word. The most comparable works to our technique of topic identification are by [6], [7] and [12] who uses a concept tree which was built manually (in our work, we use existing Yahoo ontology). In [12], the program called CLASITEX will analyze a document and look for words or collocations appeari</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29301"><authors>E Hoenkamp</authors><title>Spotting Ontological Lacunae through Spectrum Analysis Of Retrieved Documents</title><venue>13 th European Conference On Artificial Intelligent, ECAI98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Brighton, England</pubAddress><raw>Hoenkamp, E.: Spotting Ontological Lacunae through Spectrum Analysis Of Retrieved Documents. 13 th European Conference On Artificial Intelligent, ECAI98, Brighton, England (1998)</raw><contexts><context>s in many ways. We try to take advantage of these semantics relationships to establish links between the words of Yahoo concepts and WordNet vocabulary. Based on our review on past related works [1], [13], [24] we decide to use three types of semantics relationships found in the WordNet and they are synonym 1 , hypernym/hyponym 2 and meronym/holonym 3 . Using these three semantics relationships, we ca</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29302"><authors>D Koller,Sahami</authors><title>M.: Hierarchically Classifying Documents Using Very Few Words</title><venue>In the Proceeding of Machine Learning (ICML-97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>170--176</pages><raw>Koller, D., Sahami, M.: Hierarchically Classifying Documents Using Very Few Words. In the Proceeding of Machine Learning (ICML-97) (1997) 170-176</raw><contexts><context>tion 5 followed by our conclusion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node</context><context>of the new document will be identified by computing the similarity between the document feature and each of the node categories feature or the probability that the document belongs to a node category [14]. Other methods are like [21] that emphasise on representing a document with hypernym density using the WordNet hypernym hierarchy and [15] which combines clustering method with text categorization. O</context><context>able mistakes because if we already choose the wrong node at the top, our topic node will be wrong too. This problem is faced by most of the automatic text classification using hierarchical structure [14], [25], [10]. In this experiment we only use a small size of web ontology. This is because we are only interested in how our topic identification system performs on real data regardless of size. Howev</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29303"><authors>J Shin Lee</authors><title>D.: Multilevel Automatic Categorization for Webpages. The INET Proceeding ’98</title><year>1998</year><raw>Lee, J. Shin, D.: Multilevel Automatic Categorization for Webpages. The INET Proceeding ’98 (1998)</raw><contexts><context>usion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node categories of the hierarchy</context><context>the probability that the document belongs to a node category [14]. Other methods are like [21] that emphasise on representing a document with hypernym density using the WordNet hypernym hierarchy and [15] which combines clustering method with text categorization. Our approach of identifying the topic of a document has been inspired by the works of [21] and [17]. [17] extends the word frequency countin</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29304"><authors>C Y Lin,Hovy</authors><title>E.: Identifying Topics by Position</title><venue>In the Proceeding of The Workshop of Intelligent Scalable Text Summarization ’97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Lin, C.Y, Hovy, E.: Identifying Topics by Position. In the Proceeding of The Workshop of Intelligent Scalable Text Summarization ’97 (1997)</raw><contexts><context> of HTML tags and therefore our extraction technique is not appropriate to be used. In this case, alternative way of extracting web document like words frequency [18], [3] ,[11] and positional policy [16] are more applicable. Since in this paper we are interested in extracting out information from the web document based on HTML tag, we consider extracting information from non-structured document as a </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29305"><authors>C Y Lin</authors><title>Knowledge-based Automatic Topic Identification</title><venue>In the Proceeding of The 33 rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics ’95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Lin, C.Y: Knowledge-based Automatic Topic Identification. In the Proceeding of The 33 rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics ’95 (1995)</raw><contexts><context>using the WordNet hypernym hierarchy and [15] which combines clustering method with text categorization. Our approach of identifying the topic of a document has been inspired by the works of [21] and [17]. [17] extends the word frequency counting (the classic way of identifying text topic) to concept counting. He uses the WordNet taxonomy to collect interesting concepts and later generalizes the conce</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29306"><authors>A McCallum,R Rosenfeld,T Mitchell,Y A Ng</authors><title>Improving Text Classification by Shrinkage in a Hierarchy of Classes</title><venue>Proceeding of the 15 th Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>McCallum, A., Rosenfeld, R., Mitchell, T., Ng, Y.A.: Improving Text Classification by Shrinkage in a Hierarchy of Classes. Proceeding of the 15 th Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-98) (1998)</raw><contexts><context>in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node categories of the hierarchy. By p</context><context>However, some web documents maybe lack of HTML tags and therefore our extraction technique is not appropriate to be used. In this case, alternative way of extracting web document like words frequency [18], [3] ,[11] and positional policy [16] are more applicable. Since in this paper we are interested in extracting out information from the web document based on HTML tag, we consider extracting informat</context><context>ing concepts. Analysis. Our result is quite comparable to that result produced by the topic identification (text classification) that used machine learning techniques on web documents classification. [18] obtained 37% of accuracy result using Yahoo with 151 classes and 50 documents. Their best attained accuracy result was 45% on 100 test documents. [11] had their best result on accuracy at 51% using Y</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29307"><authors>G A Miller,R Beckwith,C Fellbaum,D Gross,Miller</authors><title>K.: Introduction to WordNet</title><venue>An-Online Lexical Database. Five Papers on WordNet</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><raw>Miller, G.A, Beckwith, R., Fellbaum, C., Gross, D., Miller, K.: Introduction to WordNet: An-Online Lexical Database. Five Papers on WordNet (1993)</raw><contexts><context>t with human knowledge toward Internet. Our external linguistics database is WordNet. WordNet is developed based on the theory of psycholinguistics by a group of researchers from Princeton University [19]. In this linguistic knowledge-base, we can find words semantically related with the other words in many ways. We try to take advantage of these semantics relationships to establish links between the </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29308"><authors>C Y Quek,Mitchell</authors><title>T: Classification of World Wide Web Documents. Seniors Honors Thesis</title><year>1998</year><raw>Quek, C.Y, Mitchell, T: Classification of World Wide Web Documents. Seniors Honors Thesis, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Melon University (1998)</raw></citation><citation id="29309"><authors>S Scott,S Matwin</authors><title>Text Classification using WordNet Hypernyms</title><venue>In the Proceeding of Workshop – Usage of WordNet in Natural Language Processing Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Montreal, Canada</pubAddress><raw>Scott, S., Matwin, S.: Text Classification using WordNet Hypernyms. In the Proceeding of Workshop – Usage of WordNet in Natural Language Processing Systems, Montreal, Canada (1998)</raw><contexts><context>in section 5 followed by our conclusion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to th</context><context>dentified by computing the similarity between the document feature and each of the node categories feature or the probability that the document belongs to a node category [14]. Other methods are like [21] that emphasise on representing a document with hypernym density using the WordNet hypernym hierarchy and [15] which combines clustering method with text categorization. Our approach of identifying th</context><context>c way of identifying text topic) to concept counting. He uses the WordNet taxonomy to collect interesting concepts and later generalizes the concepts to identify the main topic of the target text. In [21], they transform the bag-of-words representation of the text into hypernym density. Using the height of generalization, they can limit the number of steps upward through the hypernym hierarchy for eac</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29310"><authors>Sense Tagger</authors><venue>UTMK Internal Paper. Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, Malaysia</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Sense Tagger. UTMK Internal Paper. Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, Malaysia (1999)</raw><contexts><context>Net are sense-tagged whereas the words of Yahoo concepts are ambiguous. Therefore we have to disambiguate these words of Yahoo concept according to WordNet sense numbers using a sense tagging process [22]. Basically, what we have to do for the sense-tagging process is to prepare a “dictionary file”. This dictionary file contains all words found in the ontology domain with all the possible word 1 Two w</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29311"><authors>S Soderland</authors><title>Learning to extract text-based information from World Wide Web</title><venue>In the Proceeding of the Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and DataMining</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Soderland, S.: Learning to extract text-based information from World Wide Web. In the Proceeding of the Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and DataMining (1997)</raw></citation><citation id="29312"><authors>E M Voorhees</authors><title>On Expanding Query Vectors with Lexically Related Words</title><venue>Proceeding of the Second Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-2), NIST Special Publication</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pubAddress>Gatherburg, Maryland</pubAddress><raw>Voorhees, E.M.: On Expanding Query Vectors with Lexically Related Words. Proceeding of the Second Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-2), NIST Special Publication, Gatherburg, Maryland (1993)</raw><contexts><context> conclusion in section 6. 2 Related Works We found that the topic identification based on hierarchical structure technique is usually applied in text classification system [21], [14], [3], [11], [4], [24], [15], [18], [7]. Most of these works utilize a hierarchical structure to decompose a huge and single classifier task into a set of small classifiers that correspond to the node categories of the hie</context><context>any ways. We try to take advantage of these semantics relationships to establish links between the words of Yahoo concepts and WordNet vocabulary. Based on our review on past related works [1], [13], [24] we decide to use three types of semantics relationships found in the WordNet and they are synonym 1 , hypernym/hyponym 2 and meronym/holonym 3 . Using these three semantics relationships, we can retr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29313"><authors>A S Weigned,E D Wiener,J O Pedersen</authors><title>Working Papers IS-98-22</title><venue>Of Business, New York University</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><raw>Weigned, A.S, Wiener, E.D, Pedersen, J.O.: Working Papers IS-98-22. Dept. of Info. System, Leonard N. Stern, School Of Business, New York University (1998)</raw><contexts><context>istakes because if we already choose the wrong node at the top, our topic node will be wrong too. This problem is faced by most of the automatic text classification using hierarchical structure [14], [25], [10]. In this experiment we only use a small size of web ontology. This is because we are only interested in how our topic identification system performs on real data regardless of size. However, fo</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://utmk.cs.usm.my/pdf/CICLing01.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>093fa94a1c9b889eb83d9d7e6ac8751ce0ea990d</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>