<document id="10.1.1.1.1565"><clusterid>1428</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference D.J. Medeiros, E.F. Watson, J.S. Carson and M.S. Manivannan, eds. ABSTRACT ADVANCED METHODS FOR SIMULATION OUTPUT ANALYSIS</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper reviews statistical methods for analyzing output data from computer simulations of single systems. In particular, it focuses on the problems of choosing initial conditions and estimating steady-state system parameters. The estimation techniques include the replication/deletion approach, the regenerative method, the batch means method, and the standardized time series method. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4359"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Christos Alexopoulos</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">School of Industrial and Systems Engineering; Georgia Institute of Technology</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Atlanta, Georgia 30332–0205, U.S.A.</address><order src="null">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29433"><clusterid>1429</clusterid><authors>C Alexopoulos,A F Seila</authors><title>Output data analysis</title><venue>In Handbook of Simulation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><editors>ed. J. Banks, Chapter 7</editors><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Alexopoulos, C., and A. F. Seila. 1998. Output data analysis. In Handbook of Simulation, ed. J. Banks, Chapter 7, New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29434"><clusterid>1430</clusterid><authors>C Alexopoulos,A F Seila,G S Fishman</authors><title>Computational experience with the batch means method</title><year>1998</year><raw>Alexopoulos, C., A. F. Seila and G. S. Fishman. 1998. Computational experience with the batch means method.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29435"><clusterid>1431</clusterid><authors>P Billingsley</authors><title>Convergence of probability measures</title><year>1968</year><publisher>Wiley</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Billingsley, P. 1968. Convergence of probability measures, Wiley, New York.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29436"><clusterid>1432</clusterid><authors>P Bratley,B L Fox,L E Schrage</authors><title>A guide to simulation, 2d Ed</title><year>1987</year><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><pubAddress>New York, New York</pubAddress><raw>Bratley, P., B. L. Fox, and L. E. Schrage. 1987. A guide to simulation, 2d Ed. Springer-Verlag, New York, New York.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29437"><clusterid>1433</clusterid><authors>F Chance,L W Schruben</authors><title>Establishing a truncation point in simulation output</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Ithaca, New York</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report</tech><raw>Chance, F., and L. W. Schruben. 1992. Establishing a truncation point in simulation output. Technical Report, School of Operations Research and Industrial Engineering, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29438"><clusterid>1434</clusterid><authors>J M Charnes</authors><title>Statistical analysis of multivariate discrete-event simulation output</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1989</year><pubAddress>Minneapolis, Minnesota</pubAddress><tech>Ph.D. Thesis</tech><raw>Charnes, J. M. 1989. Statistical analysis of multivariate discrete-event simulation output. Ph.D. Thesis, Department of Operations and Management Science, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29439"><clusterid>1435</clusterid><authors>J M Charnes</authors><title>Power comparisons for the multivariate batch-means method</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference, 281–287. IEEE, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Charnes, J. M. 1990. Power comparisons for the multivariate batch-means method. In Proceedings of the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference, 281–287. IEEE, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29440"><clusterid>1436</clusterid><authors>J M Charnes</authors><title>Multivariate simulation output analysis</title><year>1991</year><raw>Charnes, J. M. 1991. Multivariate simulation output analysis.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29441"><clusterid>1437</clusterid><authors>R D Chen,A F Seila</authors><title>Multivariate inference in stationary simulation using batch means</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1987 Winter Simulation Conference, 302–304. IEEE, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1987</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Chen, R. D., and A. F. Seila. 1987. Multivariate inference in stationary simulation using batch means. In Proceedings of the 1987 Winter Simulation Conference, 302–304. IEEE, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29442"><clusterid>1438</clusterid><authors>C-H Chien</authors><title>Small sample theory for steady state confidence intervals</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1989</year><pubAddress>Palo Alto, California</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report No. 37</tech><raw>Chien, C.-H. 1989. Small sample theory for steady state confidence intervals. Technical Report No. 37, Department of Operations Research, Stanford University, Palo Alto, California.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29443"><clusterid>1439</clusterid><authors>C Chien,D Goldsman,B Melamed</authors><title>Largesample results for batch means</title><venue>Management Science 43:1288–1295</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Chien, C., D. Goldsman, and B. Melamed. 1997. Largesample results for batch means. Management Science 43:1288–1295.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29444"><clusterid>1440</clusterid><authors>Y S Chow,H Robbins</authors><title>On the asymptotic theory of fixed-width sequential confidence intervals for the mean</title><venue>Annals of Mathematical Statistics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1965</year><volume>36</volume><raw>Chow, Y. S., and H. Robbins. 1965. On the asymptotic theory of fixed-width sequential confidence intervals for the mean. Annals of Mathematical Statistics 36:457–462.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29445"><clusterid>1441</clusterid><authors>R W Conway</authors><title>Some tactical problems in digital simulation. Management Science 10:47–61</title><year>1963</year><raw>Conway, R. W. 1963. Some tactical problems in digital simulation. Management Science 10:47–61.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29446"><clusterid>1442</clusterid><authors>M A Crane,D L Iglehart</authors><title>Simulating stable stochastic systems, I: General multiserver queues</title><venue>Journal of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1974</year><volume>21</volume><raw>Crane, M. A., and D. L. Iglehart. 1974a. Simulating stable stochastic systems, I: General multiserver queues. Journal of the ACM 21:103–113.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29447"><clusterid>1443</clusterid><authors>M A Crane,D L Iglehart</authors><title>Simulating stable stochastic systems, II: Markov chains</title><venue>Journal of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1974</year><volume>21</volume><raw>Crane, M. A., and D. L. Iglehart. 1974b. Simulating stable stochastic systems, II: Markov chains. Journal of the ACM 21:114–123.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29448"><clusterid>1444</clusterid><authors>M A Crane,D L Iglehart</authors><title>Simulating stable stochastic systems III: Regenerative processes and discrete-event simulations. Operations Research 23:33–45</title><year>1975</year><raw>Crane, M. A., and D. L. Iglehart. 1975. Simulating stable stochastic systems III: Regenerative processes and discrete-event simulations. Operations Research 23:33–45.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29449"><clusterid>1445</clusterid><authors>H Damerdji</authors><title>Strong consistency of the variance estimator in steady-state simulation output analysis</title><venue>Mathematics of Operations Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><raw>Damerdji, H. 1994. Strong consistency of the variance estimator in steady-state simulation output analysis. Mathematics of Operations Research 19:494–512.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29450"><clusterid>1446</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman</authors><title>Statistical analysis for queueing simulations. Management Science 20:363–369</title><year>1973</year><raw>Fishman, G. S. 1973. Statistical analysis for queueing simulations. Management Science 20:363–369.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29451"><clusterid>1447</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman</authors><title>Estimation of multiserver queueing simulations</title><venue>Operations Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1974</year><volume>22</volume><raw>Fishman, G. S. 1974. Estimation of multiserver queueing simulations. Operations Research 22:72–78.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29452"><clusterid>1448</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman</authors><title>Principles of discrete event simulation</title><year>1978</year><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Fishman, G. S. 1978. Principles of discrete event simulation, New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29453"><clusterid>1449</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman</authors><title>Monte Carlo: Concepts, algorithms, and applications</title><year>1996</year><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Fishman, G. S. 1996. Monte Carlo: Concepts, algorithms, and applications. New York: Springer-Verlag.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29454"><clusterid>1450</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman</authors><title>LABATCH.2 for analyzing sample path data</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1998</year><tech>Technical Report UNC/OR TR-97/04</tech><raw>Fishman, G. S. 1998a. LABATCH.2 for analyzing sample path data. Technical Report UNC/OR TR-97/04, Department of Operations Research, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29455"><clusterid>1451</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman</authors><title>LABATCH2: Software for statistical analysis of simulation sample data</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference, this volume. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Fishman, G. S. 1998b. LABATCH2: Software for statistical analysis of simulation sample data. In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference, this volume. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29456"><clusterid>1452</clusterid><authors>G S Fishman,L S Yarberry</authors><title>An implementation of the batch means method</title><venue>INFORMS Journal on Computing 9:296–310</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Fishman, G. S., and L. S. Yarberry. 1997. An implementation of the batch means method. INFORMS Journal on Computing 9:296–310.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29457"><clusterid>1453</clusterid><authors>A V Gafarian,C J Ancker,F Morisaku</authors><title>Evaluation of commonly used rules for detecting steady-state in computer simulation. Naval Research Logistics Quarterly 25:511–529</title><year>1978</year><raw>Gafarian, A.V., C. J. Ancker, and F. Morisaku. 1978. Evaluation of commonly used rules for detecting steady-state in computer simulation. Naval Research Logistics Quarterly 25:511–529.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29458"><clusterid>1454</clusterid><authors>P W Glynn,D L Iglehart</authors><title>Simulation analysis using standardized time series</title><venue>Mathematics of Operations Research 15:1–16</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>Glynn, P. W., and D. L. Iglehart. 1990. Simulation analysis using standardized time series. Mathematics of Operations Research 15:1–16.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29459"><clusterid>1455</clusterid><authors>D Goldsman,M Meketon,L W Schruben</authors><title>Properties of standardized time series weighted area variance estimators. Management Science 36:602–612</title><year>1990</year><raw>Goldsman, D., M. Meketon, and L. W. Schruben. 1990. Properties of standardized time series weighted area variance estimators. Management Science 36:602–612.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29460"><clusterid>1456</clusterid><authors>D Goldsman,L W Schruben</authors><title>Asymptotic properties of some confidence interval estimators for simulation output. Management Science 30:1217–1225</title><year>1984</year><raw>Goldsman, D., and L. W. Schruben. 1984. Asymptotic properties of some confidence interval estimators for simulation output. Management Science 30:1217–1225.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29461"><clusterid>1457</clusterid><authors>D Goldsman,L W Schruben</authors><title>New confidence interval estimators using standardized time series. Management Science 36:393–397</title><year>1990</year><raw>Goldsman, D., and L. W. Schruben. 1990. New confidence interval estimators using standardized time series. Management Science 36:393–397.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29462"><clusterid>1458</clusterid><authors>D Goldsman,L W Schruben,J J Swain</authors><title>Tests for transient means in simulated time series. Naval Research Logistics 41:171–187</title><year>1994</year><raw>Goldsman, D., L. W. Schruben, and J. J. Swain. 1994. Tests for transient means in simulated time series. Naval Research Logistics 41:171–187.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29463"><clusterid>1459</clusterid><authors>P Heidelberger,P A W Lewis</authors><title>Quantile estimation in dependent sequences</title><venue>Operations Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1984</year><volume>32</volume><raw>Heidelberger, P., and P. A. W. Lewis. 1984. Quantile estimation in dependent sequences. Operations Research 32:185–209.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29464"><clusterid>1460</clusterid><authors>P Heidelberger,P D Welch</authors><title>A spectral method for confidence interval generation and run length control in simulations</title><venue>Communications of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1981</year><volume>24</volume><raw>Heidelberger, P., and P. D. Welch. 1981a. A spectral method for confidence interval generation and run length control in simulations. Communications of the ACM 24:233–245.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29465"><clusterid>1461</clusterid><authors>D L Iglehart</authors><title>Advanced Methods for Simulation Output Analysis</title><year>1975</year><raw>Advanced Methods for Simulation Output Analysis Iglehart, D. L. 1975. Simulating stable stochastic systems, V: Comparison of ratio estimators. Naval Research Logistics Quarterly 22:553–565.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29466"><clusterid>1462</clusterid><authors>D L Iglehart</authors><title>Simulating stable stochastic systems, VI: Quantile estimation</title><venue>Journal of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1976</year><pages>36--0</pages><volume>23</volume><raw>Iglehart, D. L. 1976. Simulating stable stochastic systems, VI: Quantile estimation. Journal of the ACM 23:347– 360.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29467"><clusterid>1463</clusterid><authors>D L Iglehart</authors><title>The regenerative method for simulation analysis</title><venue>In Current Trends in Programming Methodology</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1978</year><editors>III, eds. K. M. Chandy, and K. M. Yeh, 52–71</editors><publisher>Prentice-Hall</publisher><pubAddress>Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Iglehart, D. L. 1978. The regenerative method for simulation analysis. In Current Trends in Programming Methodology, Vol. III, eds. K. M. Chandy, and K. M. Yeh, 52–71. Prentice-Hall, Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29468"><clusterid>1464</clusterid><authors>W D Kelton</authors><title>Random initialization methods in simulation</title><venue>IIE Transactions</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1989</year><volume>21</volume><raw>Kelton, W. D. 1989. Random initialization methods in simulation. IIE Transactions 21:355–367.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29469"><clusterid>1465</clusterid><authors>A M Law,J S Carson</authors><title>A sequential procedure for determining the length of a steady-state simulation</title><year>1979</year><raw>Law, A. M., and J. S. Carson. 1979. A sequential procedure for determining the length of a steady-state simulation.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29470"><clusterid>1466</clusterid><authors>A M Law,W D Kelton</authors><title>Simulation modeling and analysis, 2d Ed</title><year>1991</year><publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Law, A. M., and W. D. Kelton. 1991. Simulation modeling and analysis, 2d Ed. McGraw-Hill, New York.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29471"><clusterid>1467</clusterid><authors>H Mechanic,W McKay</authors><title>Confidence intervals for averages of dependent data</title><venue>in simulations II. Technical Report ASDD 17–202, IBM Corporation, Yorktown Heights</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1966</year><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Mechanic, H., and W. McKay. 1966. Confidence intervals for averages of dependent data in simulations II. Technical Report ASDD 17–202, IBM Corporation, Yorktown Heights, New York.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29472"><clusterid>1468</clusterid><authors>M S Meketon,B W Schmeiser</authors><title>Overlapping batch means: Something for nothing</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1984 Winter Simulation Conference, 227–230. IEEE, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1984</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Meketon, M. S., and B. W. Schmeiser. 1984. Overlapping batch means: Something for nothing? In Proceedings of the 1984 Winter Simulation Conference, 227–230. IEEE, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29473"><clusterid>1469</clusterid><authors>L W Moore</authors><title>Quantile estimation in regenerative processes</title><venue>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1980</year><raw>Moore, L. W. 1980. Quantile estimation in regenerative processes. Ph.D. Thesis, Curriculum in Operations Research and Systems Analysis, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29474"><clusterid>1470</clusterid><authors>A Nadas</authors><title>An extension of the theorem of Chow and Robbins on sequential confidence intervals for the mean</title><venue>Annals of Mathematical Statistics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1969</year><volume>40</volume><raw>Nadas, A. 1969. An extension of the theorem of Chow and Robbins on sequential confidence intervals for the mean. Annals of Mathematical Statistics 40:667–671.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29475"><clusterid>1471</clusterid><authors>D H Ockerman</authors><title>Initialization bias tests for stationary stochastic processes based upon standardized time series techniques</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1995</year><pubAddress>Atlanta, Georgia</pubAddress><tech>Ph.D. Thesis</tech><raw>Ockerman, D. H. 1995. Initialization bias tests for stationary stochastic processes based upon standardized time series techniques. Ph.D. Thesis, School of Industrial and Systems Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29476"><clusterid>1472</clusterid><authors>S I Resnick</authors><title>Adventures in stochastic processes</title><year>1994</year><pubAddress>Boston: Birkhaüser</pubAddress><raw>Resnick, S. I. 1994. Adventures in stochastic processes. Boston: Birkhaüser.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29477"><clusterid>1473</clusterid><authors>R G Sargent,K Kang,D Goldsman</authors><title>An investigation of finite-sample behavior of confidence interval estimators. Operations Research 40:898–913</title><year>1992</year><raw>Sargent, R. G., K. Kang, and D. Goldsman. 1992. An investigation of finite-sample behavior of confidence interval estimators. Operations Research 40:898–913.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29478"><clusterid>1474</clusterid><authors>B W Schmeiser</authors><title>Batch size effects in the analysis of simulation output</title><venue>Operations Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1982</year><volume>30</volume><raw>Schmeiser, B. W. 1982. Batch size effects in the analysis of simulation output. Operations Research 30:556–568.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29479"><clusterid>1475</clusterid><authors>T J Schriber,R W Andrews</authors><title>Interactive analysis of simulation output by the method of batch means</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1979 Winter Simulation Conference, 513–525. IEEE, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1979</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Schriber, T. J., and R. W. Andrews. 1979. Interactive analysis of simulation output by the method of batch means. In Proceedings of the 1979 Winter Simulation Conference, 513–525. IEEE, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29480"><clusterid>1476</clusterid><authors>L W Schruben</authors><title>Detecting initialization bias in simulation output. Operations Research 30:569–590</title><year>1982</year><raw>Schruben, L. W. 1982. Detecting initialization bias in simulation output. Operations Research 30:569–590.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29481"><clusterid>1457</clusterid><authors>L W Schruben</authors><title>Confidence interval estimation using standardized time series. Operations Research 31:1090–1108</title><year>1983</year><raw>Schruben, L. W. 1983. Confidence interval estimation using standardized time series. Operations Research 31:1090–1108.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29482"><clusterid>1477</clusterid><authors>L W Schruben,H Singh,L Tierney</authors><title>Optimal tests for initialization bias in simulation output</title><year>1983</year><raw>Schruben, L. W., H. Singh, and L. Tierney. 1983. Optimal tests for initialization bias in simulation output.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29483"><clusterid>1478</clusterid><authors>A F Seila</authors><title>A batching approach to quantile estimation in regenerative simulations. Management Science 28:573–581</title><year>1982</year><raw>Seila, A. F. 1982a. A batching approach to quantile estimation in regenerative simulations. Management Science 28:573–581.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29484"><clusterid>1479</clusterid><authors>A F Seila</authors><title>Percentile estimation in discrete event simulation. Simulation 39:193–200</title><year>1982</year><raw>Seila, A. F. 1982b. Percentile estimation in discrete event simulation. Simulation 39:193–200.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29485"><clusterid>1480</clusterid><authors>W-M T Song,B W Schmeiser</authors><title>Optimal mean-squared-error batch sizes. Management Science 41:110–123</title><year>1993</year><raw>Song, W.-M. T., and B. W. Schmeiser. 1993. Optimal mean-squared-error batch sizes. Management Science 41:110–123.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29486"><clusterid>1481</clusterid><authors>J von Neumann</authors><title>Distribution of the ratio of the mean square successive difference and the variance</title><venue>Annals of Mathematical Statistics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1941</year><volume>12</volume><raw>von Neumann, J. 1941. Distribution of the ratio of the mean square successive difference and the variance. Annals of Mathematical Statistics 12:367–395.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29487"><clusterid>1482</clusterid><authors>P D Welch</authors><title>The statistical analysis of simulation results</title><year>1983</year><editors>In</editors><publisher>Academic Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Welch, P. D. 1983. The statistical analysis of simulation results. In The computer performance modeling handbook, ed. S. Lavenberg, 268–328. New York: Academic Press.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29488"><clusterid>1483</clusterid><authors>P D Welch</authors><title>On the relationship between batch means, overlapping batch means and spectral estimation</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1987 Winter Simulation Conference, 320–323. IEEE, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1987</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Welch, P. D. 1987. On the relationship between batch means, overlapping batch means and spectral estimation, In Proceedings of the 1987 Winter Simulation Conference, 320–323. IEEE, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29489"><clusterid>1484</clusterid><authors>J R Wilson,A A B Pritsker</authors><title>A survey of research on the simulation startup problem. Simulation 31:55–58</title><year>1978</year><raw>Wilson, J. R., and A. A. B. Pritsker. 1978a. A survey of research on the simulation startup problem. Simulation 31:55–58.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29490"><clusterid>1485</clusterid><authors>J R Wilson,A A B Pritsker</authors><title>Evaluation of startup policies in simulation experiments. Simulation 31:79–89</title><year>1978</year><raw>Wilson, J. R., and A. A. B. Pritsker. 1978b. Evaluation of startup policies in simulation experiments. Simulation 31:79–89.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29491"><clusterid>1486</clusterid><authors>L S Yarberry</authors><title>Incorporating a dynamic batch size selection mechanism in a fixed-sample-size batch means procedure</title><venue>Department of Operations Research, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina</venue><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1993</year><tech>Ph.D. dissertation</tech><raw>Yarberry, L. S. 1993. Incorporating a dynamic batch size selection mechanism in a fixed-sample-size batch means procedure. Ph.D. dissertation, Department of Operations Research, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina. AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES CHRISTOS ALEXOPOULOS is an Associate Professor in the School of Industrial and Systems Engineering at the Georgia Institute of Technology. He received his Ph.D.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation><citation id="29492"><clusterid>1487</clusterid><authors>in Operations</authors><title>Research from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. His research interests are in the areas of applied probability, statistics, and optimization of stochastic systems. His recent work involves problems related to the optimal design of telecommu</title><venue>Proceedings of the 1995 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>in Operations Research from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. His research interests are in the areas of applied probability, statistics, and optimization of stochastic systems. His recent work involves problems related to the optimal design of telecommunications and transportation systems. Dr. Alexopoulos is a member of INFORMS and the INFORMS College of Simulation. He served as a Co-Editor for the Proceedings of the 1995 Winter Simulation Conference.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1565</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc98papers/015.PDF</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>PDF</fileType><sha1>eabbc9b00e882b4a2098c7aed4228de4f7b24ded</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>