<document id="10.1.1.1.1533"><clusterid>792</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">ANSWERS TO THE TOP TEN INPUT MODELING QUESTIONS</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">In this tutorial we provide answers to the top ten inputmodeling questions that new simulation users ask, point out common mistakes that occur and give relevant references. We assume that commercial input-modeling software will be used when possible, and only suggest non-commercial options when there is little else available. Detailed examples will be provided in the tutorial presentation. 1 WHY USE INPUT MODELS AT ALL? This question could be rephrased as, “Why do stochastic simulation? ” The premise behind stochastic simulation— simulation that includes randomness—is that the uncertainty in the system cannot be wished away without painting an unrealistic picture of system performance. Input models represent the uncertainty. For the purpose of this tutorial, “input modeling ” will mean selecting and fitting a probability distribution (perhaps multivariate) to represent some process whose behavior cannot be predicted with certainty. For example, suppose you are a supplier of a component that is supposed to last for one year, a component that you know has a mean time to failure of 2 years. A client is willing to pay $1000 for your component, but wants you to pay a penalty of $5000 if failure occurs in less than one year. Should you take this contract? If you ignore the uncertainty in the component’s life time and base your decision on the average two-year life, then this is a no-brainer: You will pocket $1000 for each component you sell. On the other hand, if you know that the distribution of time to failure is well modeled as being exponentially distributed (an input model) with mean 2 years, then it turns out that you can expect to lose about $967 on each component you sell. In this simple example the expected or long-run average profit can be computed so you do not need simulation to estimate it, but the same point applies to simulation experiments: You cannot just</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4264"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">E. Yücesan</name><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4265"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">C. -h. Chen</name><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4266"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. L. Snowdon</name><order src="null">3</order></author><author id="4267"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. M. Charnes</name><order src="null">4</order></author><author id="4268"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Bahar Biller</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Dept. of Manufacturing &amp; Operations Management; Graduate School of Industrial Administration; Carnegie Mellon University</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Pittsburgh, PA 15213, U.S.A</address><order src="null">5</order></author><author id="4269"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Barry L. Nelson</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">; Department of Industrial Engineering; Northwestern University</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">; Evanston, IL 60208-3119, U.S.A.</address><order src="null">6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28778"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>J Banks,J S Carson,B L Nelson,D Nicol</authors><venue>Discrete-Event System Simulation. 3d ed. Upper Saddle River</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Banks, J., J. S. Carson, B. L. Nelson and D. Nicol. 2001. Discrete-Event System Simulation. 3d ed. Upper Saddle River, New Jersey: Prentice Hall.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation><citation id="28779"><clusterid>95</clusterid><authors>A M Law,W D Kelton</authors><title>Simulation Modeling and Analysis</title><year>2000</year><editors>3d ed</editors><publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Law, A. M. and W. D. Kelton. 2000. Simulation Modeling and Analysis. 3d ed. New York: McGraw-Hill.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation><citation id="28780"><clusterid>793</clusterid><authors>B L Nelson,M Yamnitsky</authors><title>Input modeling tools for complex problems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><editors>ed. D. J. Medeiros, E. F. Watson, J. S. Carson and M. S. Manivannan, 105– 112. Piscataway</editors><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Nelson, B. L. and M. Yamnitsky. 1998. Input modeling tools for complex problems. In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference, ed. D. J. Medeiros, E. F. Watson, J. S. Carson and M. S. Manivannan, 105– 112. Piscataway, New Jersey: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation><citation id="28781"><clusterid>794</clusterid><authors>S Vincent</authors><title>Input data analysis. In The Handbook of Simulation</title><venue>is the Krebs Professor of Industrial Engineering and Management Sciences at Northwestern University, and is Director of the Master of Engineering Management Program there. His research centers on the design and analysis of</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><editors>ed. J. Banks, 55–91. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons. AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES BAHAR BILLER</editors><raw>Vincent, S. 1998. Input data analysis. In The Handbook of Simulation, ed. J. Banks, 55–91. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons. AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES BAHAR BILLER is an assistant professor of Operations Management and Manufacturing at Carnegie Mellon University. She received her Ph.D. from Northwestern University. Her research interests are in computer simulation of stochastic systems and stochastic input modeling. BARRY L. NELSON is the Krebs Professor of Industrial Engineering and Management Sciences at Northwestern University, and is Director of the Master of Engineering Management Program there. His research centers on the design and analysis of computer simulation experiments on models of stochastic systems. He has published numerous papers and two books. Nelson has served the profession as the Simulation Area Editor of Operations Research and President of the INFORMS (then TIMS) College on Simulation.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc02papers/005.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>e8ec21c639c472a5bf8490deabc307a8edd373f9</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>