<document id="10.1.1.1.1513"><clusterid>472</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Reducing the Computational Load of Energy Evaluations for</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Predicting the native conformation using computational protein models requires a large number  of energy evaluations even with simplified models such as hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP)  models. Clearly, energy evaluations constitute a significant portion of computational time. We  hypothesize that given the structured nature of algorithms that search for candidate conformations  such as stochastic methods, energy evaluation computations can be cached and reused,  thus saving computational time and e#ort. In this paper, we present a caching approach and  apply it to 2D triangular HP lattice model. We provide theoretical analysis and prediction of  the expected savings from caching as applied this model. We conduct experiments using a sophisticated  evolutionary algorithm that contains elements of local search, memetic algorithms,  diversity replacement, etc. in order to verify our hypothesis and demonstrate a significant level  1  of savings in computational e#ort and time that caching can provide.</abstract><keywords><keyword id="846881">protein folding</keyword><keyword id="846882">triangular lattice</keyword><keyword id="846883">HP energy model</keyword><keyword id="846884">caching</keyword><keyword id="846885">reuse</keyword><keyword id="846886">evolutionary</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Protein Folding Eunice</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="2359358"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Eunice E. Santos</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Department of Computer Science; Virginia Polytechnic Institute &amp; State University</affil><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">santos@cs.vt.edu</email><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author><author id="2359359"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Eugene Santos</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Department of Computer Science and Engineering; University of Connecticut, Storrs</affil><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">eugene@cse.uconn.edu</email><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28426"><clusterid>473</clusterid><authors>R Agarwala,S Batzoglou,V Dancik,S Decatur,M Farach,S Hannenhali,S Muthukrishnan,S Skiena</authors><title>Local rules for protein folding on a triangular lattice and generalized hydrophobicity in the HP model</title><venue>Journal of Computational Biology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>4--2</pages><raw>R. Agarwala, S. Batzoglou, V. Dancik, S. Decatur, M. Farach, S. Hannenhali, S. Muthukrishnan, and S. Skiena. Local rules for protein folding on a triangular lattice and generalized hydrophobicity in the HP model. Journal of Computational Biology, 4(2):275-296, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28427"><clusterid>474</clusterid><authors>B Berger,T Leighton</authors><title>Protein folding in the hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) model is NP</title><venue>Journal of Computational Biology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>27--40</pages><volume>5</volume><raw>B. Berger, T. Leighton. Protein folding in the hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) model is NPcomplete. Journal of Computational Biology, 5(1), 27-40, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28428"><clusterid>475</clusterid><authors>B P Blackburne,J D Hirst</authors><title>Evolution of Functional model Proteins</title><venue>Journal of Chemical Physics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><pages>1934--1942</pages><volume>115</volume><raw>B.P. Blackburne and J.D. Hirst. Evolution of Functional model Proteins. Journal of Chemical Physics, 115(4), 1934-1942, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28429"><clusterid>476</clusterid><authors>E Bornberg-Bauer</authors><title>Simple folding model for hp lattice proteins</title><venue>In Proceedings of Bioinformatics German Conference on Bioinformatics GCB ’96</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>125--36</pages><raw>E. Bornberg-Bauer. Simple folding model for hp lattice proteins. In Proceedings of Bioinformatics German Conference on Bioinformatics GCB ’96, 125-36, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28430"><clusterid>477</clusterid><authors>P Crescenzi,D Goldman,C Piccolboni,M Yannakanis</authors><title>On the complexity of protein folding</title><venue>Journal of Computational Biology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>5--3</pages><raw>P. Crescenzi, D. Goldman, C. Piccolboni, M. Yannakanis. On the complexity of protein folding. Journal of Computational Biology 5(3):423-465, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28431"><clusterid>478</clusterid><authors>K A Dill,S Bomberg,K Yue,K M Fiebig,D P Yee,P D Thomas,H S Chan</authors><title>Principles of protein folding: A perspective from simple exact models. Protein Sci 4</title><year>1995</year><pages>561--602</pages><raw>K.A. Dill, S. Bomberg, K. Yue, K.M. Fiebig, D.P. Yee, P.D. Thomas, H.S. Chan. Principles of protein folding: A perspective from simple exact models. Protein Sci 4, 561-602. 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28432"><clusterid>479</clusterid><authors>W E Hart,S Istrail</authors><title>Fast protein folding in the hydrophobic-bydrophilic model within three-eighths of optimal</title><venue>In Proceedings of Twenty-seventh Annual ACM Symposium on Theory of Computing(STOC95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>157--68</pages><raw>Hart, W. E., and Istrail, S. Fast protein folding in the hydrophobic-bydrophilic model within three-eighths of optimal. In Proceedings of Twenty-seventh Annual ACM Symposium on Theory of Computing(STOC95), 157-68, 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation><citation id="28433"><clusterid>480</clusterid><authors>N Krasnogor,B Blackburnem,J D Hirst,E K Burke</authors><title>Multimeme Algorithms for Protein Structure Prediction</title><venue>in Proceedings of Parallel Problem Solving From Nature, 2002, Lecture</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>N. Krasnogor, B. Blackburnem, J.D. Hirst, E.K. Burke. Multimeme Algorithms for Protein Structure Prediction in Proceedings of Parallel Problem Solving From Nature, 2002, Lecture</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1513</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://excalibur.brc.uconn.edu/Papers/Conference/bibe04-submit.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>