<document id="10.1.1.1.1547"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Computerising Natural History Card Archives</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper summarises the achievements of a multidisciplinary Bioinformatics project which has the objective of providing a general mechanism for efficient computerisation of typewritten/hand-annotated archive card indexes, of the type found in most museums, archives and libraries. In addition to efficiently scanning, recognising and databasing the content of the cards, the original card images must be maintained as the ultimate source record, and a flexible database structure is required to allow taxonomists to reorganise and update the resulting online archive. Implementation mechanisms for each part of the overall system are described, and conversion performance for a demonstrator database of 27,578 Pyralid moth archive cards is reported. The system is currently being used to convert the full NHM archive of Lepidoptera totalling 290,886 cards. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4313"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A. C. Downton</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">University of Essex, UK</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">acd@essex.ac.uk</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4314"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">S. M. Lucas</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Natural History Museum, London, UK</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">gsr@nhm.ac.uk</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4315"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">G. Patoulas</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">University of Essex, UK</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">sml@essex.ac.uk</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29085"><authors>i Poole,R W</authors><title>Lepidopterorum Catalogus (New Series) Edited by J.B. Heppner. Fascicle 118 Noctuidae Parts 1-3: 1314 pp</title><venue>E.J. Brill / Flora &amp; Fauna Publications. Leiden - New York - Kobenhavn - Koln</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1989</year><raw>i Poole, R. W. 1989. Lepidopterorum Catalogus (New Series) Edited by J.B. Heppner. Fascicle 118 Noctuidae Parts 1-3: 1314 pp]. E.J. Brill / Flora &amp; Fauna Publications. Leiden - New York - Kobenhavn - Koln.</raw></citation><citation id="29086"><authors>ii Scoble,M J</authors><title>Geometrid Moths of the World : A Catalogue. Volumes 1</title><venue>index 129</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>pp.</pages><publisher>CSIRO Publishing</publisher><pubAddress>Canberra</pubAddress><volume>2</volume><raw>ii Scoble, M. J. (Ed.) 1999. Geometrid Moths of the World : A Catalogue. Volumes 1 and 2: 1016 pp. + index 129 pp. CSIRO Publishing, Canberra.</raw></citation><citation id="29087"><authors>iii Pitkin,B R</authors><title>Butterflies &amp; Moths of the World: Generic Names &amp; their Type-species. http://www.nhm.ac.uk/entomology/butmoth/ iv</title><year>2002</year><raw>iii Pitkin, B. R. &amp; Jenkins, P. 2002. Butterflies &amp; Moths of the World: Generic Names &amp; their Type-species. http://www.nhm.ac.uk/entomology/butmoth/ iv Downton, A.C., A.C. Tams, G.J. Wells, A.C. Holmes, S.M. Lucas, M. Scoble, G. Robinson and G.</raw></citation><citation id="29088"><title>Beccaloni,Constructing Web-Based Legacy Index Card Archives – Architectural Design Issues and Initial Data Acquisition</title><venue>Proc. ICDAR2001 6 th Int. Conf. on Document Analysis and Recognition</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>10--13</pages><pubAddress>Seattle</pubAddress><raw>Beccaloni,Constructing Web-Based Legacy Index Card Archives – Architectural Design Issues and Initial Data Acquisition Proc. ICDAR2001 6 th Int. Conf. on Document Analysis and Recognition, Seattle, September 10-13, 2001, pp. 854-858.</raw></citation><citation id="29089"><authors>v C Cracknell,A C Downton</authors><title>TABS – script-based software framework for research in image processing, analysis and understanding</title><venue>IEE Proc. VISP</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>194--202</pages><volume>145</volume><raw>v C. Cracknell and A. C. Downton, TABS – script-based software framework for research in image processing, analysis and understanding, IEE Proc. VISP, v.145 No. 3, pp. 194-202 June 1998. vi He, J and A.C. Downton, User-Assisted Archive Document Image Analysis for Digital Library Construction, to appear at ICDAR2003 vii E. Ishidera, S. M. Lucas and A. C. Downton, Likelihood word image generation model for word recognition, Proc.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.csc.liv.ac.uk/%7Eprima/ICDAR2003/Papers/0064_562_downton_a.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>dd68d158ef0d332636d375d00435b2ee480cff9a</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>