<document id="10.1.1.1.1576"><clusterid>3685242</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">Robust ego-motion estimation and 3D model refinement using depth based parallax model</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">We present an iterative algorithm for robustly estimating the egomotion and refining and updating a coarse, noisy and partial depth map using a depth based parallax model and brightness derivatives extracted from an image pair. Given a coarse, noisy and partial depth map acquired by a range-finder or obtained from a Digital Elevation Map (DEM), we first estimate the ego-motion by combining a global ego-motion constraint and a local brightness constancy constraint. Using the estimated camera motion and the available depth map estimate, motion of the 3D points is compensated. We utilize the fact that the resulting surface parallax field is an epipolar field and knowing its direction from the previous motion estimates, estimate its magnitude and use it to refine the depth map estimate. Instead of assuming a smooth parallax field or locally smooth depth models, we locally model the parallax magnitude using the depth map, formulate the problem as a generalized eigen-value analysis and obtain better results. In addition, confidence measures for depth estimates are provided which can be used to remove regions with potentially incorrect (and outliers in) depth estimates for robustly estimating ego-motion in the next iteration. Results on both synthetic and real examples are presented.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2004</year><venue src="INFERENCE">Proc. Int’l Conf. Image Processing</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="7693694"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Amit K Agrawal</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="7693695"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Rama Chellappa</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29619"><clusterid>1542</clusterid><authors>T S Huang,A N Netravali</authors><title>Motion and structure from feature correspondences: A review</title><venue>Proceedings of the IEEE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>252--268</pages><volume>82</volume><raw>T.S. Huang and A.N. Netravali, “Motion and structure from feature correspondences: A review,” Proceedings of the IEEE, vol. 82, pp. 252–268, 1994.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29620"><clusterid>1543</clusterid><authors>G S Young,R Chellappa</authors><title>3-D motion estimation using a sequence of noisy stereo images: Models, estimation, and uniqueness results</title><venue>IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><pages>735--759</pages><volume>12</volume><raw>G.S. Young and R. Chellappa, “3-D motion estimation using a sequence of noisy stereo images: Models, estimation, and uniqueness results,” IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 12, pp. 735–759, 1990.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29621"><clusterid>1544</clusterid><authors>H Liu,R Chellappa,A Rosenfeld</authors><title>A hierarchical approach for obtaining structure from two-frame optical flow</title><venue>Proceedings of Workshop on Motion and Video Computing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>214--219</pages><raw>H. Liu, R. Chellappa, and A. Rosenfeld, “A hierarchical approach for obtaining structure from two-frame optical flow,” Proceedings of Workshop on Motion and Video Computing, pp. 214–219, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29622"><clusterid>1545</clusterid><authors>G Adiv</authors><title>Determining 3-d motion and structure from optical flow generated by several moving objects</title><venue>IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1985</year><pages>384--401</pages><volume>7</volume><raw>G. Adiv, “Determining 3-d motion and structure from optical flow generated by several moving objects,” IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 7, no. 4, pp. 384–401, July 1985.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29623"><clusterid>1546</clusterid><authors>Y Aloimonos,C M Brown</authors><title>Direct processing of curvilinear sensor motion from a sequence of perspective images</title><venue>in CVWS84</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1984</year><pages>72--77</pages><raw>Y. Aloimonos and C.M. Brown, “Direct processing of curvilinear sensor motion from a sequence of perspective images,” in CVWS84, 1984, pp. 72–77.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29624"><clusterid>8918667</clusterid><authors>B K P Horn,E Weldon</authors><title>Direct methods for recovering motion,” IJCV</title><year>1988</year><pages>51--76</pages><raw>B.K.P. Horn and E. Weldon, “Direct methods for recovering motion,” IJCV, pp. 51–76, 1988.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29625"><clusterid>1548</clusterid><authors>K J Hanna</authors><title>Direct multi-resolution estimation of egomotion and structure from motion</title><venue>in MOTION91</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1991</year><pages>156--162</pages><raw>K.J. Hanna, “Direct multi-resolution estimation of egomotion and structure from motion,” in MOTION91, 1991, pp. 156–162.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29626"><clusterid>1549</clusterid><authors>S Negahdaripour,N Kolagani,B Y Hayashi</authors><title>Direct motion stereo for passive navigation</title><venue>in CVPR92</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>425--431</pages><raw>S. Negahdaripour, N. Kolagani, and B.Y. Hayashi, “Direct motion stereo for passive navigation,” in CVPR92, 1992, pp. 425–431.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29627"><clusterid>1550</clusterid><authors>R Kumar,P Anandan,K J Hanna</authors><title>Direct recovery of shape from multiple views: a parallax based approach</title><venue>Proceedings of the 12th IAPR International Conference on Pattern Recognition</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>685--688</pages><volume>1</volume><raw>R. Kumar, P. Anandan, and K.J. Hanna, “Direct recovery of shape from multiple views: a parallax based approach,” Proceedings of the 12th IAPR International Conference on Pattern Recognition, vol. 1, pp. 685–688, 1994.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29628"><clusterid>1551</clusterid><authors>J R Bergen,P Anandan,K J Hanna,R Hingorani</authors><title>Hierarchical model-based motion estimation</title><venue>Proceedings of Eurpoean Conference on Computer Vision</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>237--252</pages><raw>J.R. Bergen, P. Anandan, K.J. Hanna, and R. Hingorani, “Hierarchical model-based motion estimation,” Proceedings of Eurpoean Conference on Computer Vision, pp. 237–252, 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29629"><clusterid>1552</clusterid><authors>M Irani,P Anandan,M Cohen</authors><title>Direct recovery of planar-parallax from multiple frames</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2002</year><pages>1528--1534</pages><volume>24</volume><raw>M. Irani, P. Anandan, and M. Cohen, “Direct recovery of planar-parallax from multiple frames,” IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 24, no. 11, pp. 1528–1534, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29630"><clusterid>1553</clusterid><authors>A K Agrawal,R Chellappa</authors><title>3d model refinement using surface-parallax</title><year>2004</year><raw>A.K. Agrawal and R. Chellappa, “3d model refinement using surface-parallax,” to be published in ICASSP, 2004.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29631"><clusterid>1554</clusterid><authors>H Liu,R Chellappa,A Rosenfeld</authors><title>Accurate dense optical flow estimation and segementation using adaptive structure tensors and a parametric model</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Image Processing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><pages>1170--1180</pages><volume>12</volume><raw>H. Liu, R. Chellappa, and A. Rosenfeld, “Accurate dense optical flow estimation and segementation using adaptive structure tensors and a parametric model,” IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, vol. 12, no. 10, pp. 1170–1180, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation><citation id="29632"><clusterid>1555</clusterid><authors>H Liu,T H Hong,M Herman,R Chellappa</authors><title>A general motion model and spatio-temporal filters for computing optical flow</title><venue>IJCV</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>141--172</pages><volume>22</volume><raw>H. Liu, T.H. Hong, M. Herman, and R. Chellappa, “A general motion model and spatio-temporal filters for computing optical flow,” IJCV, vol. 22, pp. 141–172, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1576</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.cfar.umd.edu/~aagrawal/agrawal_icip.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>