<document id="10.1.1.1.1533"><clusterid>8718103</clusterid><title src="user correction">Answers to the Top Ten Input Modeling Questions</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">In this tutorial we provide answers to the top ten inputmodeling questions that new simulation users ask, point out common mistakes that occur and give relevant references. We assume that commercial input-modeling software will be used when possible, and only suggest non-commercial options when there is little else available. Detailed examples will be provided in the tutorial presentation.</abstract><year src="user correction">2002</year><venue src="user correction">PROCEEDINGS OF THE 2002 WINTER SIMULATION CONFERENCE</venue><venType src="user correction"></venType><volume src="user correction"></volume><number src="user correction"></number><publisher src="user correction"></publisher><pubAddress src="user correction"></pubAddress><tech src="user correction"></tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Bahar Biller</name><affil src="user correction">Dept. of Manufacturing &amp; Operations Management; Graduate School of Industrial Administration; Carnegie Mellon University</affil><address src="user correction">Pittsburgh, PA 15213, U.S.A</address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">1</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Barry L. Nelson</name><affil src="user correction"> Department of Industrial Engineering; Northwestern University</affil><address src="user correction"> Evanston, IL 60208-3119, U.S.A.</address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">7</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28778"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>J Banks,J S Carson,B L Nelson,D Nicol</authors><venue>Discrete-Event System Simulation. 3d ed. Upper Saddle River</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Banks, J., J. S. Carson, B. L. Nelson and D. Nicol. 2001. Discrete-Event System Simulation. 3d ed. Upper Saddle River, New Jersey: Prentice Hall.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation><citation id="28779"><clusterid>95</clusterid><authors>A M Law,W D Kelton</authors><title>Simulation Modeling and Analysis</title><year>2000</year><editors>3d ed</editors><publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Law, A. M. and W. D. Kelton. 2000. Simulation Modeling and Analysis. 3d ed. New York: McGraw-Hill.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation><citation id="28780"><clusterid>775</clusterid><authors>B L Nelson,M Yamnitsky</authors><title>Input modeling tools for complex problems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><editors>ed. D. J. Medeiros, E. F. Watson, J. S. Carson and M. S. Manivannan, 105– 112. Piscataway</editors><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Nelson, B. L. and M. Yamnitsky. 1998. Input modeling tools for complex problems. In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference, ed. D. J. Medeiros, E. F. Watson, J. S. Carson and M. S. Manivannan, 105– 112. Piscataway, New Jersey: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation><citation id="28781"><clusterid>8918555</clusterid><authors>S Vincent</authors><title>Input data analysis. In The Handbook of Simulation</title><venue>is the Krebs Professor of Industrial Engineering and Management Sciences at Northwestern University, and is Director of the Master of Engineering Management Program there. His research centers on the design and analysis of</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><editors>ed. J. Banks, 55–91. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons. AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES BAHAR BILLER</editors><raw>Vincent, S. 1998. Input data analysis. In The Handbook of Simulation, ed. J. Banks, 55–91. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons. AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES BAHAR BILLER is an assistant professor of Operations Management and Manufacturing at Carnegie Mellon University. She received her Ph.D. from Northwestern University. Her research interests are in computer simulation of stochastic systems and stochastic input modeling. BARRY L. NELSON is the Krebs Professor of Industrial Engineering and Management Sciences at Northwestern University, and is Director of the Master of Engineering Management Program there. His research centers on the design and analysis of computer simulation experiments on models of stochastic systems. He has published numerous papers and two books. Nelson has served the profession as the Simulation Area Editor of Operations Research and President of the INFORMS (then TIMS) College on Simulation.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1533</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc02papers/005.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>