<document id="10.1.1.1.1603"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">REDTOP-2: Rocket Engine Design Tool Featuring Engine Performance, Weight, Cost, and Reliability</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">created engineering design tool for use in the conceptual and preliminary design of space transportation systems utilizing liquid propulsion rocket engines. REDTOP-2, one of many unique engineering tools commercially available from SpaceWorks Engineering, Inc. (SEI), represents a novel entry into the current suite of propulsion modeling tools. REDTOP-2 is capable of analyzing the flowpath characteristics of numerous engine configurations to perform a power balance of the turbomachinery hardware (pumps and turbines) to achieve a user specified main chamber combustion pressure. The engine performance, in terms of thrust and specific impulse (Isp), is then determined based on the results of this power balance and the flow conditions (pressure, temperature, flowrate, etc.) in the chamber(s) and nozzle(s). Engine weight is assessed at the main component level using a combination of empirical and physics based analysis methods to provide vacuum, ambient, and sea-level thrust-to-weight (T/W) values. A cost model capable of predicting engine development, first unit, and production costs has been incorporated. Additionally, REDTOP-2 features a topdown modeling approach for computing engine safety and reliability metrics. REDTOP-2 is written in the modern, object-oriented C++ programming language and will execute on PC,</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4449"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. E. Bradford</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">GA, 30338</address><order>1</order></author><author id="4450"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A. Charania</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4451"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">B. St. Germain</name><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30069"><authors>S Gordon,B J McBride</authors><title>Computer Program for Calculation of</title><venue>Complex Chemical Equilibrium Compositions and Applications,” NASA Reference Publication 1311</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>1 Gordon, S. and McBride, B.J., “Computer Program for Calculation of Complex Chemical Equilibrium Compositions and Applications,” NASA Reference Publication 1311, Oct. 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="30070"><authors>M W Chase,C A Davies,J R Downey,D J Frurip</authors><venue>JANAF Thermochemical Tables,” 3rd Edition, National Bureau of Standards, American Institute of Physics, Inc</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1986</year><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>2 Chase, M.W., Davies, C.A., Downey, J.R., and Frurip, D.J., “JANAF Thermochemical Tables,” 3rd Edition, National Bureau of Standards, American Institute of Physics, Inc., New York, 1986.</raw></citation><citation id="30071"><authors>D Manski,J R Hulka,B D Goracke</authors><title>et al., “Cycles for Earth-to-Orbit Propulsion</title><venue>Journal of Propulsion and Power</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><volume>14</volume><raw>3 Manski, D., Hulka, J.R., Goracke, B.D., et al., “Cycles for Earth-to-Orbit Propulsion,” Journal of Propulsion and Power, Vol. 14, No. 5, Sept-Oct. 1998.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.sei.aero/library/paper_archive/AIAA-2004-3514.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>bc6188db410e8ca34f4cb6017b0f86f53d744ed1</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>