<document id="10.1.1.1.1554"><clusterid>1147</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">BioMed Central</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Background: Quantitative studies are becoming more recognized as important to understanding  health care with all of its richness and complexities. The purpose of this descriptive survey was to  provide a quantitative evaluation of the qualitative studies published in 170 core clinical journals for  2000.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Bmc Medical Informatics</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="2401920"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Biomed Central</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author><author id="2401922"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Cynthia S Gadd Open Access</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2Health Information Research Unit Department of Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University Faculty of Health Sciences; Hamilton, Ontario</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Canada L8S 1V8</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">csg@cbmi.pitt.edu</email><order>3</order></author><author id="2401921"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Kathleen Ann Mckibbon</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2Health Information Research Unit Department of Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University Faculty of Health Sciences; Hamilton, Ontario</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Canada L8S 1V8</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">mckib@mcmaster.ca</email><order>4</order></author><author id="2401923"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Kathleen Ann Mckibbon</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2Health Information Research Unit Department of Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, McMaster University Faculty of Health Sciences; Hamilton, Ontario</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Canada L8S 1V8</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">mckib@mcmaster.ca</email><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">5</order></author><author id="2401924"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Cynthia S Gadd</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29216"><clusterid>1148</clusterid><authors>Miller WL</authors><title>Crabtree BF: Clinical research. Handbook of Qualitative Research 2nd edition. Edited by</title><venue>Denzin N K and Lincoln Y S. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>2001--607</pages><raw>Miller WL, Crabtree BF: Clinical research. Handbook of Qualitative Research 2nd edition. Edited by: Denzin N K and Lincoln Y S. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2001:607-631.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29217"><clusterid>1149</clusterid><authors>Creswell JW</authors><title>Fetters MD, Ivankova NY: Designing a mixed methods study in primary care</title><venue>Annals of Family Medicine</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>2--7</pages><volume>2004</volume><raw>Creswell JW, Fetters MD, Ivankova NY: Designing a mixed methods study in primary care. Annals of Family Medicine 2004, 2:7-12.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29218"><clusterid>1150</clusterid><authors>K Jolly,F Bradley,S Sharp,H Smith</authors><title>Mant D: Follow-up care in general practice of patients with myocardial infarction or angina pectoris: initial results of the SHIP trial. Southampton Heart Integrated Care Project. Fam Pract</title><year>1998</year><pages>15--548</pages><raw>Jolly K, Bradley F, Sharp S, Smith H, Mant D: Follow-up care in general practice of patients with myocardial infarction or angina pectoris: initial results of the SHIP trial. Southampton Heart Integrated Care Project. Fam Pract 1998, 15:548-555.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29219"><clusterid>1151</clusterid><authors>R Wiles</authors><title>Patients&apos; perceptions of their heart attack and recovery: the influence of epidemiological &amp;quot;evidence&amp;quot; and personal experience. Soc Sci Med</title><year>1998</year><pages>46--1477</pages><raw>Wiles R: Patients&apos; perceptions of their heart attack and recovery: the influence of epidemiological &amp;quot;evidence&amp;quot; and personal experience. Soc Sci Med 1998, 46:1477-1486.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29220"><clusterid>1152</clusterid><authors>Willms</authors><title>DG: A new stage, a new life: individual success in quitting smoking. Soc Sci Med</title><year>1991</year><pages>33--1365</pages><raw>Willms DG: A new stage, a new life: individual success in quitting smoking. Soc Sci Med 1991, 33:1365-1371.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29221"><clusterid>1153</clusterid><authors>Gilbert JR,Wilson DM,Best JA,Taylor DW,Lindsay EA,J Singer,Willms</authors><title>DG: Smoking cessation in primary care. A randomized controlled trial of nicotine-bearing chewing gum. J Fam Pract</title><year>1989</year><pages>28--49</pages><raw>Gilbert JR, Wilson DM, Best JA, Taylor DW, Lindsay EA, Singer J, Willms DG: Smoking cessation in primary care. A randomized controlled trial of nicotine-bearing chewing gum. J Fam Pract 1989, 28:49-55.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29222"><clusterid>1154</clusterid><authors>Willms GG,Best JA,W Taylor</authors><title>D: A systematic approach for using qualitative methods in primary prevention research. Medical Anthropology Quarterly</title><year>1990</year><pages>4--391</pages><raw>Willms GG, Best JA, W Taylor D: A systematic approach for using qualitative methods in primary prevention research. Medical Anthropology Quarterly 1990, 4:391-409.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29223"><clusterid>1155</clusterid><authors>Borkan JM,M Quirk,Sullivan</authors><title>M: Finding meaning after the fall: injury narratives from elderly hip fracture patients. Soc Sci Med</title><year>1991</year><pages>33--947</pages><raw>Borkan JM, Quirk M, Sullivan M: Finding meaning after the fall: injury narratives from elderly hip fracture patients. Soc Sci Med 1991, 33:947-957.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29224"><clusterid>1156</clusterid><authors>J Donovan,N Mills,M Smith,L Brindle,A Jacoby,T Peters,S Frankel,D Neal</authors><title>Hamdy F: Quality improvement report: Improving design and conduct of randomised trials by embedding them in qualitative research: ProtecT (prostate testing for cancer and treatment) study. Commentary: presenting unbiased Page 7 of 8 (page number not for c</title><venue>BMJ</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>325--766</pages><volume>2002</volume><raw>Donovan J, Mills N, Smith M, Brindle L, Jacoby A, Peters T, Frankel S, Neal D, Hamdy F: Quality improvement report: Improving design and conduct of randomised trials by embedding them in qualitative research: ProtecT (prostate testing for cancer and treatment) study. Commentary: presenting unbiased Page 7 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes) BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making 2004, 4:11 http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11 information to patients can be difficult.[see comment]. BMJ 2002, 325:766-770.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29225"><clusterid>1157</clusterid><authors>N Rousseau,E McColl,J Newton,J Grimshaw,Eccles</authors><title>M: Practice based, longitudinal, qualitative interview study of computerised evidence based guidelines in primary care.[see comment</title><venue>BMJ</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>326--314</pages><volume>2003</volume><raw>Rousseau N, McColl E, Newton J, Grimshaw J, Eccles M: Practice based, longitudinal, qualitative interview study of computerised evidence based guidelines in primary care.[see comment]. BMJ 2003, 326:314.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29226"><clusterid>1158</clusterid><authors>M Eccles,E McColl,N Steen,N Rousseau,J Grimshaw,D Parkin</authors><title>Purves I: Effect of computerised evidence based guidelines on management of asthma and angina in adults in primary care: cluster randomised controlled trial.[see comment</title><venue>BMJ</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>325--941</pages><volume>2002</volume><raw>Eccles M, McColl E, Steen N, Rousseau N, Grimshaw J, Parkin D, Purves I: Effect of computerised evidence based guidelines on management of asthma and angina in adults in primary care: cluster randomised controlled trial.[see comment]. BMJ 2002, 325:941.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29227"><clusterid>1159</clusterid><authors>Haynes</authors><title>RB: ACP Journal Club: Purpose and procedure. [http:/ /www/acpjc.org/shared/purpose_and_procedure.htm</title><raw>Haynes RB: ACP Journal Club: Purpose and procedure. [http:/ /www/acpjc.org/shared/purpose_and_procedure.htm].</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29228"><clusterid>1160</clusterid><authors>Haynes RB,N Wilczynski,McKibbon KA,Walker CJ,Sinclair</authors><title>JC: Developing optimal search strategies for detecting clinically sound studies</title><venue>in MEDLINE. J Am Med Inform Assoc</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>1--447</pages><raw>Haynes RB, Wilczynski N, McKibbon KA, Walker CJ, Sinclair JC: Developing optimal search strategies for detecting clinically sound studies in MEDLINE. J Am Med Inform Assoc 1994, 1:447-458.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29229"><clusterid>1161</clusterid><authors>Giacomini MK,Cook</authors><title>DJ: Users&apos; guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care B. What are the results and how do they help me care for my patients? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group</title><venue>JAMA</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>284--478</pages><volume>2000</volume><raw>Giacomini MK, Cook DJ: Users&apos; guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care B. What are the results and how do they help me care for my patients? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group. JAMA 2000, 284:478-482.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29230"><clusterid>1161</clusterid><authors>Giacomini MK,Cook</authors><title>DJ: Users&apos; guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care A. Are the results of the study valid? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group</title><venue>JAMA</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>284--357</pages><volume>2000</volume><raw>Giacomini MK, Cook DJ: Users&apos; guides to the medical literature: XXIII. Qualitative research in health care A. Are the results of the study valid? Evidence-Based Medicine Working Group. JAMA 2000, 284:357-362.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29231"><clusterid>1162</clusterid><authors>Denzin NK,Lincoln</authors><title>YS: Handbook of Qualitative Research. 2nd edition</title><venue>Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><raw>Denzin NK, Lincoln YS: Handbook of Qualitative Research. 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29232"><clusterid>1222</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Tongprateep T: The essential elements of spirituality among rural Thai elders</title><venue>J Adv Nurs</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>31--197</pages><volume>2000</volume><raw>Tongprateep T: The essential elements of spirituality among rural Thai elders. J Adv Nurs 2000, 31:197-203.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation><citation id="29233"><clusterid>1163</clusterid><authors>Creswell JW</authors><title>Research Design: Qualitative, Quantative and Mixed Methods Approaches. 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2003. Pre-publication history The pre-publication history for this paper can be accessed here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947</title><raw>Creswell JW: Research Design: Qualitative, Quantative and Mixed Methods Approaches. 2nd edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, Sage Publications; 2003. Pre-publication history The pre-publication history for this paper can be accessed here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/1472-6947/4/11/prepub Publish with BioMed Central and every scientist can read your work free of charge &amp;quot;BioMed Central will be the most significant development for disseminating the results of biomedical research in our lifetime.&amp;quot; Sir Paul Nurse, Cancer Research UK Your research papers will be: available free of charge to the entire biomedical community peer reviewed and published immediately upon acceptance cited in PubMed and archived on PubMed Central yours — you keep the copyright BioMedcentral Submit your manuscript here: http://www.biomedcentral.com/info/publishing_adv.asp Page 8 of 8 (page number not for citation purposes)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1554</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.biomedcentral.com/content/pdf/1472-6947-4-11.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>