<document id="10.1.1.1.1577"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Introduction Bandwidth Brokers</title><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4385"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Lance Freedman</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4386"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Steve Ni</name><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29633"><authors>L DaSilva</authors><title>Advanced Topics in Computer Engineering: Network Quality of Service</title><raw>L. DaSilva. Advanced Topics in Computer Engineering: Network Quality of Service. January 2001, work in progress.</raw></citation><citation id="29634"><authors>I Khalil,T Braun</authors><title>Implementation of a Bandwidth Broker for Dynamic End-to-End Resource Reservation in Outsourced Virtual Private Networks</title><year>2000</year><raw>I. Khalil and T. Braun. Implementation of a Bandwidth Broker for Dynamic End-to-End Resource Reservation in Outsourced Virtual Private Networks. University of Berne, June 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29635"><authors>M Günter,T Braun</authors><title>Evaluation of Bandwidth Broker Signaling</title><year>1999</year><raw>M. Günter and T. Braun. Evaluation of Bandwidth Broker Signaling. University of Berne, April 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29636"><authors>T Han,Y Jeong</authors><title>A Service Interworking Unit for Accommodating Multimedia Communications with Quality of Service between</title><venue>ATM and Internet. Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>T. Han and Y. Jeong. A Service Interworking Unit for Accommodating Multimedia Communications with Quality of Service between ATM and Internet. Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute, September 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29637"><authors>L Guedes,P Oliveira,L Faina,E Cardozo</authors><title>QoS Agency: An Agent-based Architecture for Supporting Quality of Service in Distributed Multimedia Systems</title><year>1997</year><raw>L. Guedes, P. Oliveira, L. Faina, and E. Cardozo. QoS Agency: An Agent-based Architecture for Supporting Quality of Service in Distributed Multimedia Systems. June 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29638"><authors>G Armitage</authors><title>Quality of Service</title><venue>in IP Networks. Macmillan Technical Publishing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>G. Armitage. Quality of Service in IP Networks. Macmillan Technical Publishing, 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29639"><authors>N Giroux,S Ganti</authors><venue>Quality of Service in ATM Networks. Prentice-Hall</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>N. Giroux and S. Ganti. Quality of Service in ATM Networks. Prentice-Hall, 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29640"><title>Integrated Services Operation over Diffserv Networks, Internet Draft</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Bernet, Yavatkar, Ford, Baker, Zhang, Speer, Braden, Davie</pubAddress><raw>Integrated Services Operation over Diffserv Networks, &lt;draft-ietf-issll-diffserv-rsvp-03.txt&gt; Internet Draft, Bernet, Yavatkar, Ford, Baker, Zhang, Speer, Braden, Davie, June 1999, Work in progress</raw></citation><citation id="29641"><authors>QBone Architecture,Internet Draft,B Teitelbaum,Guy Almes,Philip F Chimento,Larry Dunn,Rüdiger Geib,Roch Guerin,Kathleen Nichols,John Wroclawski,Matt Zekauskas</authors><year>1999</year><raw>QBone Architecture, &lt;draft-i2-qbone-arch-1.0.html&gt; Internet Draft, B. Teitelbaum, Guy Almes, Philip F. Chimento, Larry Dunn, Rüdiger Geib, Roch Guerin, Kathleen Nichols, John Wroclawski, and Matt Zekauskas, August 1999, Work in progress</raw></citation><citation id="29642"><authors>Draft Bandwidth</authors><title>Broker Requirements for the Internet2 QBone, version 0.7</title><venue>Work in progress 27 March, 2001 37 References (cont’d</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Draft Bandwidth Broker Requirements for the Internet2 QBone, version 0.7, R. Neilson, J. Wheeler, F. Reichmeyer, S. Hares, August 1999, Work in progress 27 March, 2001 37 References (cont’d)</raw></citation><citation id="29643"><title>Differentiated Services for the Internet, slide show</title><year>1998</year><raw>Differentiated Services for the Internet, slide show, Van Jacobson, Berkeley National Laboratory, May 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29644"><authors>Multidomain Bandwidth Broker Model,D Spence</authors><year>1999</year><raw>Multidomain Bandwidth Broker Model, D. Spence, September 1999, Work in progress</raw></citation><citation id="29645"><title>The IP QoS FAQ, The Quality of Service Forum</title><year>1999</year><raw>The IP QoS FAQ, The Quality of Service Forum, 1999, Draft version 0.7</raw></citation><citation id="29646"><authors>Deepak Sreekantan</authors><title>and Dhananjaya Rao, Implementation of a Bandwidth Broker System for Resource Management in Differentiated Services. The</title><raw>Sreekantan, Deepak and Dhananjaya Rao, Implementation of a Bandwidth Broker System for Resource Management in Differentiated Services. The University of Kansas</raw></citation><citation id="29647"><title>CA*net II Differentiated Services Bandwidth Broker High-Level Design. British</title><venue>Columbia Institute of Technology</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>CA*net II Differentiated Services Bandwidth Broker High-Level Design. British Columbia Institute of Technology, Nov. 1998 Revision # 0.4</raw></citation><citation id="29648"><title>CA*netII Differentiated Services Bandwidth Broker System Specification. British</title><venue>Columbia Institute of Technology</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>CA*netII Differentiated Services Bandwidth Broker System Specification. British Columbia Institute of Technology, Oct. 1998 Revision # 1.1</raw></citation><citation id="29649"><authors>Internet2</authors><title>The University Corporation for Advanced Internet Development (UCAID) non-profit consortium led by over 180 universities, http://www.internet2.edu</title><raw>Internet2, The University Corporation for Advanced Internet Development (UCAID) non-profit consortium led by over 180 universities, http://www.internet2.edu</raw></citation><citation id="29650"><title>The Internet Engineering Task Force Site of Internet Society (ISOC), http://www.ietf.org 27</title><year>2001</year><pages>3--8</pages><raw>The Internet Engineering Task Force Site of Internet Society (ISOC), http://www.ietf.org 27 March, 2001 38</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ee.vt.edu/~ldasilva/6504/BB.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>ea5ffad4e2a5b23c97fb0c9c7b5f25fa28a90d0e</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>