<document id="10.1.1.1.1544"><clusterid>960062</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">Hidden-action in multi-hop routing</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">In any multi-hop routing scheme, cooperation by the intermediate nodes are essential for the succesful delivery of traffic. However, the effort exerted by the intermediate nodes are often unobservable by the source and/or destination nodes. We show it is possible to overcome this problem of hidden action by designing contracts, in the form of payments, to induce cooperation from the intermediate nodes. Interestingly, the ability to monitor per-hop or per-path outcomes, even if costless to implement, may not improve the welfare of the participants or the performance of the network.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2005</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In EC’05</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">117--126</pages><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="7693609"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Michal Feldman</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="7693610"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> John Chuang</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28938"><clusterid>919</clusterid><authors>D G ANDERSEN,H BALAKRISHNAN,M F KAASHOEK,R MORRIS</authors><title>Resilient Overlay Networks</title><venue>In 18th ACM SOSP</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>[1] ANDERSEN, D. G., BALAKRISHNAN, H., KAASHOEK, M. F., AND MORRIS, R. Resilient Overlay Networks. In 18th ACM SOSP (2001).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28939"><clusterid>8918571</clusterid><authors>A BANERJEE,A BEGGS</authors><title>Simultaneous versus Sequential Move Structures in Principal-Agent Models. University of Oxford, working paper</title><year>1997</year><raw>[2] BANERJEE, A., AND BEGGS, A. Simultaneous versus Sequential Move Structures in Principal-Agent Models. University of Oxford, working paper (1997).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28940"><clusterid>921</clusterid><authors>S BANSAL,M BAKER</authors><title>Observation-based cooperation enforcement in ad hoc networks</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2003</year><tech>Technical report</tech><raw>[3] BANSAL, S., AND BAKER, M. Observation-based cooperation enforcement in ad hoc networks. Technical report, Stanford university (2003).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28941"><clusterid>922</clusterid><authors>S BUCHEGGER,J-Y L BOUDEC</authors><title>Performance Analysis of the CONFIDANT Protocol: Cooperation of Nodes - Fairness in Dynamic Ad Hoc Networks</title><venue>In IEEE/ACM Symposium on Mobile Ad Hoc Networking and Computing (MobiHOC</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>[4] BUCHEGGER, S., AND BOUDEC, J.-Y. L. Performance Analysis of the CONFIDANT Protocol: Cooperation of Nodes - Fairness in Dynamic Ad Hoc Networks. In IEEE/ACM Symposium on Mobile Ad Hoc Networking and Computing (MobiHOC) (2002).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28942"><clusterid>923</clusterid><authors>S BUCHEGGER,J-Y L BOUDEC</authors><title>Coping with False Accusations in Misbehavior Reputation Systems For Mobile Ad Hoc Networks</title><venue>In EPFL, Technical report</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>[5] BUCHEGGER, S., AND BOUDEC, J.-Y. L. Coping with False Accusations in Misbehavior Reputation Systems For Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. In EPFL, Technical report (2003).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28943"><clusterid>924</clusterid><authors>S BUCHEGGER,J-Y L BOUDEC</authors><title>The effect of rumor spreading in reputation systems for mobile ad-hoc networks</title><venue>In WiOpt’03: Modeling and Optimization in Mobile Ad Hoc and Wireless Networks</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>[6] BUCHEGGER, S., AND BOUDEC, J.-Y. L. The effect of rumor spreading in reputation systems for mobile ad-hoc networks. In WiOpt’03: Modeling and Optimization in Mobile Ad Hoc and Wireless Networks (2003).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28944"><clusterid>925</clusterid><authors>L BUTTYAN,J HUBAUX</authors><title>Stimulating Cooperation in Self-Organizing Mobile Ad-Hoc Networks</title><venue>ACM/Kluwer Journal on Mobile Networks and Applications (MONET) (2003). [8] CAILLAUD, B., AND HERMALIN, B. Hidden Action and Incentives. Teaching</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>[7] BUTTYAN, L., AND HUBAUX, J. Stimulating Cooperation in Self-Organizing Mobile Ad-Hoc Networks. ACM/Kluwer Journal on Mobile Networks and Applications (MONET) (2003). [8] CAILLAUD, B., AND HERMALIN, B. Hidden Action and Incentives. Teaching Notes. U.C. Berkeley.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28945"><clusterid>926</clusterid><authors>N CHRISTIN,J CHUANG</authors><title>On the Cost of Participating in a Peer-to-Peer Network</title><venue>In 3rd International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><pubAddress>FEIGENBAUM, J., PAPADIMITRIOU, C., SAMI</pubAddress><volume>10</volume><raw>[9] CHRISTIN, N., AND CHUANG, J. On the Cost of Participating in a Peer-to-Peer Network. In 3rd International Workshop on Peer-to-Peer Systems (2004). [10] FEIGENBAUM, J., PAPADIMITRIOU, C., SAMI, R., AND SHENKER, S. A BGP-based Mechanism for Lowest-Cost Routing.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28946"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors></authors><venue>In Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>In Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing (2002).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28947"><clusterid>927</clusterid><authors>J FEIGENBAUM,R SAMI,S SHENKER</authors><title>Mechanism Design for Policy Routing</title><venue>Yale University</venue><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2003</year><tech>Technical Report</tech><raw>[11] FEIGENBAUM, J., SAMI, R., AND SHENKER, S. Mechanism Design for Policy Routing. In Yale University, Technical Report (2003).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28948"><clusterid>928</clusterid><authors>J FEIGENBAUM,S SHENKER</authors><title>Distributed Algorithmic Mechanism Design: Recent Results and Future Directions</title><venue>In Proceedings of the International Workshop on Discrete Algorithms and Methods for Mobile Computing and Communications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>[12] FEIGENBAUM, J., AND SHENKER, S. Distributed Algorithmic Mechanism Design: Recent Results and Future Directions. In Proceedings of the International Workshop on Discrete Algorithms and Methods for Mobile Computing and Communications (2002).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28949"><clusterid>929</clusterid><authors>E FRIEDMAN,S SHENKER</authors><title>Learning and implementation on the internet</title><venue>Rutgers University, Department of Economics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pubAddress>New Brunswick</pubAddress><raw>[13] FRIEDMAN, E., AND SHENKER, S. Learning and implementation on the internet. In Manuscript. New Brunswick: Rutgers University, Department of Economics (1997).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28950"><clusterid>930</clusterid><authors>D GOLDSCHLAG,M REED,P SYVERSON</authors><title>Onion Routing for Anonymous and Private Internet Connections</title><venue>In Communications of the ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>4--2</pages><raw>[14] GOLDSCHLAG, D., REED, M., AND SYVERSON, P. Onion Routing for Anonymous and Private Internet Connections. In Communications of the ACM (1999), vol. 42.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28951"><clusterid>931</clusterid><authors>B HOLMSTROM</authors><title>Moral Hazard in Teams</title><venue>Bell Journal of Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1982</year><pages>324--340</pages><volume>13</volume><raw>[15] HOLMSTROM, B. Moral Hazard in Teams. Bell Journal of Economics 13 (1982), 324–340.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28952"><clusterid>932</clusterid><authors>Y HU,A PERRIG,D JOHNSON</authors><title>Ariadne: A Secure On-Demand Routing Protocol for Ad Hoc Networks</title><venue>In Eighth Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking (Mobicom) (2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>12--23</pages><raw>[16] HU, Y., PERRIG, A., AND JOHNSON, D. Ariadne: A Secure On-Demand Routing Protocol for Ad Hoc Networks. In Eighth Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking (Mobicom) (2002), pp. 12–23.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28953"><clusterid>933</clusterid><authors>Y HU,A PERRIG,D JOHNSON</authors><title>SEAD: Secure Efficient Distance Vector Routing for Mobile Ad Hoc Networks</title><venue>In 4th IEEE Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (WMCSA</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>[17] HU, Y., PERRIG, A., AND JOHNSON, D. SEAD: Secure Efficient Distance Vector Routing for Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. In 4th IEEE Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (WMCSA) (2002).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28954"><clusterid>934</clusterid><authors>M JAKOBSSON,J-P HUBAUX,L BUTTYAN</authors><title>A MicroPayment Scheme Encouraging Collaboration in Multi-Hop Cellular Networks</title><venue>In Financial Cryptography</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>[18] JAKOBSSON, M., HUBAUX, J.-P., AND BUTTYAN, L. A MicroPayment Scheme Encouraging Collaboration in Multi-Hop Cellular Networks. In Financial Cryptography (2003).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28955"><clusterid>935</clusterid><authors>S MARTI,T J GIULI,K LAI,M BAKER</authors><title>Mitigating Routing Misbehavior in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks</title><venue>In Proceedings of MobiCom (2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>255--265</pages><raw>[19] MARTI, S., GIULI, T. J., LAI, K., AND BAKER, M. Mitigating Routing Misbehavior in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks. In Proceedings of MobiCom (2000), pp. 255–265.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28956"><clusterid>936</clusterid><authors>A MASS-COLELL,M WHINSTON,J GREEN</authors><title>Microeconomic Theory</title><year>1995</year><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><raw>[20] MASS-COLELL, A., WHINSTON, M., AND GREEN, J. Microeconomic Theory. Oxford University Press, 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28957"><clusterid>937</clusterid><authors>B RAGHAVAN,A SNOEREN</authors><title>Priority Forwarding in Ad Hoc Networks with Self-Ineterested Parties</title><venue>In Workshop on Economics of Peer-to-Peer Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>[21] RAGHAVAN, B., AND SNOEREN, A. Priority Forwarding in Ad Hoc Networks with Self-Ineterested Parties. In Workshop on Economics of Peer-to-Peer Systems (June 2003).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28958"><clusterid>938</clusterid><authors>E RASMUSEN</authors><title>Moral Hazard in Risk-Averse Teams</title><venue>Rand Journal of Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1987</year><pages>428--435</pages><volume>18</volume><raw>[22] RASMUSEN, E. Moral Hazard in Risk-Averse Teams. Rand Journal of Economics 18 (1987), 428–435.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28959"><clusterid>939</clusterid><authors>S RATNASAMY,P FRANCIS,M HANDLEY,R KARP,S SHENKER</authors><title>A Scalable Content-Addressable Network</title><venue>In Proceedings of ACM SIGCOM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>[23] RATNASAMY, S., FRANCIS, P., HANDLEY, M., KARP, R., AND SHENKER, S. A Scalable Content-Addressable Network. In Proceedings of ACM SIGCOM (2001).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28960"><clusterid>940</clusterid><authors>A ROWSTRON,P DRUSCHEL</authors><title>Pastry: Scalable, Distributed Object Location and Routing for Large-Scale Peer-toPeer Systems</title><venue>In Proceedings of IFIP/ACM International Conference on Distributed Systems Platforms (Middleware</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>[24] ROWSTRON, A., AND DRUSCHEL, P. Pastry: Scalable, Distributed Object Location and Routing for Large-Scale Peer-toPeer Systems. In Proceedings of IFIP/ACM International Conference on Distributed Systems Platforms (Middleware) (2001).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28961"><clusterid>941</clusterid><authors>K SANZGIRI,B DAHILL,B LEVINE,C SHIELDS,E BELDING-ROYER</authors><title>A Secure Routing Protocol for Ad Hoc Networks</title><venue>In International Conference on Network Protocols (ICNP</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>[25] SANZGIRI, K., DAHILL, B., LEVINE, B., SHIELDS, C., AND BELDING-ROYER, E. A Secure Routing Protocol for Ad Hoc Networks. In International Conference on Network Protocols (ICNP) (2002).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28962"><clusterid>942</clusterid><authors>J SHNEIDMAN,D C PARKES</authors><title>Overcoming rational manipulation in mechanism implementation</title><year>2004</year><raw>[26] SHNEIDMAN, J., AND PARKES, D. C. Overcoming rational manipulation in mechanism implementation, 2004.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28963"><clusterid>943</clusterid><authors>I STOICA,R MORRIS,D KARGER,M F KAASHOEK,H BALAKRISHNAN</authors><title>Chord: A Scalable Peer-to-Peer Lookup Service for Internet Applications</title><venue>In Proceedings of ACM SIGCOM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>[27] STOICA, I., MORRIS, R., KARGER, D., KAASHOEK, M. F., AND BALAKRISHNAN, H. Chord: A Scalable Peer-to-Peer Lookup Service for Internet Applications. In Proceedings of ACM SIGCOM (2001).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation><citation id="28964"><clusterid>944</clusterid><authors>R STRAUSZ</authors><title>Moral Hazard in Sequential Teams. Departmental Working Paper. Free</title><year>1996</year><volume>29</volume><raw>[28] STRAUSZ, R. Moral Hazard in Sequential Teams. Departmental Working Paper. Free University of Berlin (1996). [29] ZHONG, S., CHEN, J., AND YANG, Y. R. Sprite: A Simple, Cheat-Proof, Credit-Based System for Mobile Ad-Hoc Networks.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1544</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.eecs.harvard.edu/p2pecon/confman/papers/s3p1.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>