<document id="10.1.1.1.1537"><clusterid>8918565</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">The InfoVis Toolkist</title><abstract src="user correction">This report presents the InfoVis Toolkit, designed to support the creation,  extension and integration of advanced 2D Information Visualization components into interactive  Java Swing applications. The InfoVis Toolkit provides specific data structures to  achieve a fast action/feedback loop required by dynamic queries. It comes with a large  set of components such as range sliders and tailored control panels required to control and  configure the visualizations. These components are integrated into a coherent framework  that simplifies the management of rich data structures and the design and extension of  visualizations. Supported data structures currently include tables, trees and graphs. Supported  visualizations include scatter plots, time series, Treemaps, node-link diagrams for  trees and graphs and adjacency matrix for graphs. All visualizations can use fisheye lenses  and dynamic labeling. The InfoVis Toolkit supports hardware acceleration when available  through Agile2D, an implementation of the Java Graphics API based on OpenGL, achieving  speedups of 10 to 60 times. The report</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2003</year><venue src="user correction"></venue><venType src="user correction"></venType><volume src="user correction"></volume><number src="user correction"></number><publisher src="user correction"></publisher><pubAddress src="user correction"></pubAddress><tech src="user correction"></tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Jean-Daniel Fekete</name><affil src="user correction"> </affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28828"><clusterid>818</clusterid><authors>C Ahlberg,B Shneiderman</authors><title>The Alphaslider: A Compact and Rapid</title><venue>Selector, ACM CHI &apos;94 Conference Proc</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>24--28</pages><pubAddress>Boston, MA</pubAddress><raw>Ahlberg, C. and Shneiderman, B. The Alphaslider: A Compact and Rapid Selector, ACM CHI &apos;94 Conference Proc. (Boston, MA, April 24-28, 1994) 365-371.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28829"><clusterid>819</clusterid><authors>C Ahlberg,B Shneiderman</authors><title>Visual Information Seeking: Tight Coupling of Dynamic Query Filters with Starfield Displays</title><venue>Proceedings of CHI &apos;94</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>24--28</pages><publisher>ACM</publisher><pubAddress>Boston, MA</pubAddress><raw>Ahlberg, C. and Shneiderman, B. Visual Information Seeking: Tight Coupling of Dynamic Query Filters with Starfield Displays. Proceedings of CHI &apos;94, (Boston, MA, April 24-28) ACM, New York, (1994), pp. 313-317.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28830"><clusterid>820</clusterid><authors>C Ahlberg,E Wistrand</authors><title>IVEE: An Information Visualization &amp; Exploration Environment</title><venue>Proceedings of Information Visualization &apos;95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>6--6</pages><raw>Ahlberg, C. and Wistrand, E. &amp;quot;IVEE: An Information Visualization &amp; Exploration Environment,&amp;quot; Proceedings of Information Visualization &apos;95, p. 66-</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28831"><clusterid>821</clusterid><authors>T Neville Barlow</authors><title>P.: A Comparison of 2-D Visualizations of Hierarchies</title><venue>IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><pages>22--23</pages><pubAddress>San Diego, CA, USA</pubAddress><volume>2001</volume><raw>Barlow, T. Neville, P.: A Comparison of 2-D Visualizations of Hierarchies. IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization 2001 (INFOVIS&apos;01), 22-23 October 2001, San Diego, CA, USA. IEEE Computer Society pp 131-138</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28832"><clusterid>822</clusterid><authors>B B Bederson</authors><title>PhotoMesa: A Zoomable Image Browser Using Quantum Treemaps and Bubblemaps</title><venue>UIST 2001, ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, CHI Letters</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>7--1</pages><volume>3</volume><raw>Bederson, B. B. PhotoMesa: A Zoomable Image Browser Using Quantum Treemaps and Bubblemaps. UIST 2001, ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, CHI Letters, 3(2), pp. 71-</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28833"><clusterid>823</clusterid><authors>B Bederson,J Hollan,K Perlin,J Meyer,D Bacon,G Furnas</authors><title>Pad++: A Zoomable Graphical Sketchpad for Exploring Alternate Interface Physics</title><venue>Journal of Visual Languages and Computing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><pages>3--31</pages><volume>7</volume><raw>Bederson, B., Hollan, J., Perlin, K., Meyer, J., Bacon, D., and Furnas, G., Pad++: A Zoomable Graphical Sketchpad for Exploring Alternate Interface Physics, Journal of Visual Languages and Computing, 7, 3-31, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28834"><clusterid>824</clusterid><authors>B Bederson,J Meyer,L Good</authors><title>Jazz: An Extensible Zoomable User Interface Graphics Toolkit</title><venue>in Java, In ACM UIST 2000 ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>171--180</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><raw>Bederson, B., Meyer, J., Good, L., Jazz: An Extensible Zoomable User Interface Graphics Toolkit in Java, In ACM UIST 2000 ACM Press, pp. 171-180</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28835"><clusterid>825</clusterid><authors>J Bertin</authors><title>Graphics and Graphic Information Processing. Walter de Gruter</title><year>1981</year><pubAddress>Co., Berlin</pubAddress><raw>Bertin, J. Graphics and Graphic Information Processing. Walter de Gruter &amp; Co., Berlin, 1981.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28836"><clusterid>826</clusterid><authors>C A Brewer</authors><title>Guidelines for Use of the Perceptual Dimensions of Color for Mapping and Visualization</title><venue>in Color Hard Copy and Graphic Arts III, edited by J. Bares, Proceedings of the International Society for Optical Engineering (SPIE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>54--63</pages><pubAddress>San José</pubAddress><volume>2171</volume><raw>Brewer, C. A., Guidelines for Use of the Perceptual Dimensions of Color for Mapping and Visualization, in Color Hard Copy and Graphic Arts III, edited by J. Bares, Proceedings of the International Society for Optical Engineering (SPIE), San José, 1994, Vol. 2171, pp. 54-63.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28837"><clusterid>827</clusterid><authors>M S T Carpendale,C Montagnese</authors><title>A framework for unifying presentation space</title><venue>in Proc. of the 14th annual ACM symposium on User interface software and technology, 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>61--70</pages><pubAddress>Orlando, Florida</pubAddress><raw>Carpendale, M. S. T. and Montagnese, C. A framework for unifying presentation space, in Proc. of the 14th annual ACM symposium on User interface software and technology, 2001, Orlando, Florida, pp. 61 – 70.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28838"><clusterid>828</clusterid><authors>E H CHI</authors><title>A Framework for Information Visualization Spreadsheets</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1999</year><tech>PhD thesis</tech><raw>CHI, E. H. A Framework for Information Visualization Spreadsheets. PhD thesis, Department of Computer Science, University of Minnesota, March 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28839"><clusterid>829</clusterid><authors>J-D Fekete,C Plaisant</authors><title>Interactive Information Visualization of a Million Items</title><venue>Proceedings of IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization, 2002, pp 117 -124</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pubAddress>Boston</pubAddress><raw>Fekete, J.-D. and Plaisant, C. Interactive Information Visualization of a Million Items Proceedings of IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization, 2002, pp 117 -124, Boston, October 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28840"><clusterid>830</clusterid><authors>J-D Fekete,C Plaisant</authors><title>Excentric labeling: Dynamic neighborhood labeling for data visualization</title><venue>In Proc. of CHI &apos;9, ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>512--519</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><raw>Fekete, J.-D., and Plaisant, C. Excentric labeling: Dynamic neighborhood labeling for data visualization. In Proc. of CHI &apos;9, ACM Press, May 1999, pp. 512-519.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28841"><clusterid>750</clusterid><authors>G Furnas</authors><title>Generalized fisheye views</title><venue>in Proc. of CHI&apos;86, ACM</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1986</year><pages>16--23</pages><publisher>Press</publisher><raw>Furnas, G. Generalized fisheye views in Proc. of CHI&apos;86, ACM Press, 1986, pp. 16-23.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28842"><clusterid>831</clusterid><authors>J Grosjean,C Plaisant,B Bederson</authors><title>SpaceTree: Supporting Exploration in Large Node Link Tree, Design Evolution and Empirical Evaluation</title><venue>Proceedings of IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization, 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>5--7</pages><pubAddress>64, Boston</pubAddress><raw>Grosjean, J., Plaisant, C., Bederson, B., SpaceTree: Supporting Exploration in Large Node Link Tree, Design Evolution and Empirical Evaluation, Proceedings of IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization, 2002 pp. 57 -64, Boston, October</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28843"><clusterid>832</clusterid><authors>D Hopkins</authors><title>The design and implementation of pie menus</title><venue>Dr. Dobb&apos;s Journal</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>16--26</pages><volume>16</volume><raw>Hopkins, D., The design and implementation of pie menus, Dr. Dobb&apos;s Journal, v.16 n.12, p.16-26, Dec.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28844"><clusterid>833</clusterid><authors>D E Knuth</authors><title>The Art of Computer Programming, Volume 1, Fundamental Algorithms, Third Edition</title><year>1997</year><publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher><pubAddress>Reading, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Knuth, D.E. The Art of Computer Programming, Volume 1, Fundamental Algorithms, Third Edition, Addison-Wesley, Reading, Mass. 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28845"><clusterid>834</clusterid><authors>S Lecolinet Pook,E Vaysseix,G,E Barillot</authors><title>Control Menu: Execution and Control in a Single Inter-actor</title><venue>In Extended Abstracts of CHI2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>263--264</pages><raw>Pook, S. Lecolinet, E. Vaysseix, G. and Barillot, E. Control Menu: Execution and Control in a Single Inter-actor. In Extended Abstracts of CHI2000, pages 263- 264, 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28846"><clusterid>835</clusterid><authors>W Martin Schroeder,K Lorensen,B</authors><title>The Visualization Toolkit: An Object Oriented Approach to 3D Graphics 3rd Edition</title><venue>Kitware, Inc.; Feb, 2003, ISBN</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>1--930934</pages><volume>1</volume><raw>Schroeder, W Martin, K Lorensen, B. The Visualization Toolkit: An Object Oriented Approach to 3D Graphics 3rd Edition. Kitware, Inc.; Feb, 2003, ISBN: 1 1-930934-07-6</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28847"><clusterid>836</clusterid><authors>E Tanin,R Beigel,B Shneiderman</authors><title>Incremental Data Structures and Algorithms for Dynamic Query</title><venue>Interfaces, SIGMOD Record</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>21--24</pages><volume>25</volume><raw>Tanin, E., Beigel, R., and Shneiderman, B., Incremental Data Structures and Algorithms for Dynamic Query Interfaces, SIGMOD Record (25) 4, 21-24, December</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28848"><clusterid>837</clusterid><authors>D Braun Thompson,J Ford,R</authors><title>OpenDX: Paths to Visualization</title><venue>VIS, Inc. 5515 Skyway Drive</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pubAddress>Missoula, MT 59804, http://www.vizsolutions.com/paths.html</pubAddress><raw>Thompson, D. Braun, J. Ford, R. OpenDX: Paths to Visualization. VIS, Inc. 5515 Skyway Drive, Missoula, MT 59804, http://www.vizsolutions.com/paths.html.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28849"><clusterid>838</clusterid><authors>M Neider Woo,J Davis,T,D Shreiner</authors><title>OpenGL Programming Guide, Third Edition</title><publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher><raw>Woo, M. Neider, J. Davis, T. and Shreiner, D. OpenGL Programming Guide, Third Edition, Addison-Wesley,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation><citation id="28850"><clusterid>859</clusterid><authors></authors><title>de recherche INRIA Futurs Domaine de Voluceau - Rocquencourt - BP 105 - 78153 Le Chesnay Cedex (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Lorraine : LORIA, Technopôle de Nancy-Brabois - Campus scientifique 615, rue du Jardin Botanique - BP 101 - 54602 Villers-lès-</title><venue>INRIA Rocquencourt : Domaine de Voluceau - Rocquencourt - BP 105 - 78153 Le Chesnay Cedex (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Sophia Antipolis : 2004, route des Lucioles - BP 93 - 06902 Sophia Antipolis Cedex (France) Éditeur INRIA - Domaine de Voluceau - R</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>0249--6399</pages><raw> Unité de recherche INRIA Futurs Domaine de Voluceau - Rocquencourt - BP 105 - 78153 Le Chesnay Cedex (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Lorraine : LORIA, Technopôle de Nancy-Brabois - Campus scientifique 615, rue du Jardin Botanique - BP 101 - 54602 Villers-lès-Nancy Cedex (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Rennes : IRISA, Campus universitaire de Beaulieu - 35042 Rennes Cedex (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Rhône-Alpes : 655, avenue de l’Europe - 38330 Montbonnot-St-Martin (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Rocquencourt : Domaine de Voluceau - Rocquencourt - BP 105 - 78153 Le Chesnay Cedex (France) Unité de recherche INRIA Sophia Antipolis : 2004, route des Lucioles - BP 93 - 06902 Sophia Antipolis Cedex (France) Éditeur INRIA - Domaine de Voluceau - Rocquencourt, BP 105 - 78153 Le Chesnay Cedex (France) http://www.inria.fr ISSN 0249-6399</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1537</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>ftp://ftp.inria.fr/INRIA/publication/publi-pdf/RR/RR-4818.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>