<document id="10.1.1.1.1522"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">of the Enabling Technology for Modeling and Simulation</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper addresses the opportunity to put into place a virtual consortium for modeling and simulation. While periodic conferences such as the Winter Simulation Conference are tremendously vital to the continued growth of modeling and simulation research, they do not offer the day-to-day technical exchange that can now be made possible with matured collaborative technologies. We call this web-based meeting place Virtual M&amp;S Lyceum, after the research institute founded by Aristotle in 335 BC; where young Athenian students were imparted great knowledge and insight by the great minds of the time. (Interestingly enough, the physical Lyceum recently came into the news again after 2300 years, when advance excavation crews, preparing for the construction of the new Museum of Modern Art, unearthed what is believed to be Aristotle’s original school). It is in the spirit of this “hall of learning ” that we try to create a place – albeit a virtual one – in which great minds can once again impart knowledge and insight to the masses. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4225"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. J. Medeiros</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4226"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">E. F. Watson</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4227"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. S. Carson</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4228"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">M. S. Manivannan</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4229"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Steven D. Farr</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">525 Brooks Rd; Rome, New York 13441-4505, U.S.A.</address><order>5</order></author><author id="4230"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Alex F. Sisti</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">525 Brooks Rd; Rome, New York 13441-4505, U.S.A.</address><order>6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28619"><authors>P A Fishwick</authors><title>Web-based Simulation: Some Personal Observations</title><venue>Proceedings of the 1996 Winter Simulation Conference, Dec 96</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>772--779</pages><raw>Fishwick, P.A. , 1996. “Web-based Simulation: Some Personal Observations”, Proceedings of the 1996 Winter Simulation Conference, Dec 96: 772-779.</raw></citation><citation id="28620"><authors>Internet2 Home Page</authors><title>http://www.internet2.edu/, Site updated as of 8</title><year>1998</year><raw>Internet2 Home Page, http://www.internet2.edu/, Site updated as of 8 July, 1998.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc98papers/228.PDF</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>PDF</fileType><sha1>bb0659a0e7d15ee01716d03be0360867938f9263</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>