<document id="10.1.1.1.1584"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">To Search for Images on the Web, Look at the Text, Then Look at the Images</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">The World Wide Web can be viewed many different ways. It is simultaneously a giant library, a world-encompassing read-mostly file system, a novel means of expression, and an incredible business</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4408"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Ethan V. Munson</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Milwaukee, WI 53211 USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">munson@cs.uwm.edu</email><order>1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29755"><authors>A Antonacopoulos,D Karatzas,J O Lopez</authors><title>Accessing textual information embedded in internet images</title><venue>In Proceedings of Electronic Imaging 2001: Internet Imaging II</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pubAddress>San Jose, California USA. SPIE</pubAddress><raw>A. Antonacopoulos, D. Karatzas, and J. O. Lopez. Accessing textual information embedded in internet images. In Proceedings of Electronic Imaging 2001: Internet Imaging II, San Jose, California USA. SPIE, Jan. 2001.</raw><contexts><context>LE element and 87.5% for the value of the ALT attribute. The most surprising result is the high level of precision for the ALT attribute of the IMG element. Previous research by Antonacopoulos et al. [1] and by Lopresti and Zhou [6] has shown that more than half of the text values of ALT attributes are empty or wrong. This would suggest that the ALT attribute would have little utility in identifying </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29756"><authors>M G Brown,J T Foote,G J F Jones,K S Jones,S J Young</authors><title>Automatic content-based retrieval of broadcast news</title><venue>In Proceedings ACM Multimedia ’95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>35--44</pages><publisher>ACM Press</publisher><raw>M. G. Brown, J. T. Foote, G. J. F. Jones, K. S. Jones, and S. J. Young. Automatic content-based retrieval of broadcast news. In Proceedings ACM Multimedia ’95, pages 35–44. ACM Press, Nov. 1995.</raw><contexts><context>e other text in the document conveys some of the images’ semantics. So, it is natural for Web image search systems to use text as part of the process. This approach is similar to that of Brown et al. [2, 3], who used close-captioned text and speech analysis to index video data. 3 Using HTML Metadata to Find Web Images We studied the effectiveness of HTML metadata (textual content and structure) for find</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29757"><authors>M G Brown,J T Foote,G J F Jones,K S Jones,S J Young</authors><title>Open-vocabulary speech indexing for voice and video mail retrieval</title><venue>In Proceedings ACM Multimedia ’96</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>307--316</pages><publisher>ACM Press</publisher><raw>M. G. Brown, J. T. Foote, G. J. F. Jones, K. S. Jones, and S. J. Young. Open-vocabulary speech indexing for voice and video mail retrieval. In Proceedings ACM Multimedia ’96, pages 307–316. ACM Press, Nov. 1996.</raw><contexts><context>e other text in the document conveys some of the images’ semantics. So, it is natural for Web image search systems to use text as part of the process. This approach is similar to that of Brown et al. [2, 3], who used close-captioned text and speech analysis to index video data. 3 Using HTML Metadata to Find Web Images We studied the effectiveness of HTML metadata (textual content and structure) for find</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29758"><authors>M Flickner,H Sawhney,W Niblack,J Ashley,Q Huang,B Dom,M Gorkani,J Hafner,D Lee,D Petkovic,D Steele,P Yanker</authors><title>Query by image and video content: the QBIC system</title><venue>Computer</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><volume>28</volume><raw>M. Flickner, H. Sawhney, W. Niblack, J. Ashley, Q. Huang, B. Dom, M. Gorkani, J. Hafner, D. Lee, D. Petkovic, D. Steele, and P. Yanker. Query by image and video content: the QBIC system. Computer, 28(9):23–32, Sept. 1995.</raw><contexts><context>body of research on multimedia indexing and retrieval. Most of this research has been performed using closed databases whose content was under the direct control of the researchers. Systems like QBIC [4] have users provide sample images or sketches and then find images in the database with similar image features, such as shape, color, texture, or object layout. This approach can work well when users </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29759"><authors>C Frankel,M Swain,V Athitsos</authors><title>WebSeer: An image search engine for the World Wide Web</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1996</year><tech>Technical Report 96-14</tech><raw>C. Frankel, M. Swain, and V. Athitsos. WebSeer: An image search engine for the World Wide Web. Technical Report 96-14, University of Chicago, Department of Computer Science, July 1996.</raw><contexts><context>f image file names. The individual images are assigned to a topic by a human judge. Users can browse or search the topics in the database and can also search usingsimage features. Research on WebSeer [5] investigated how to classify images into categories such as photographs, portraits and computer-generated drawings. To do this, WebSeer supplemented information from image content analysis with infor</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29760"><authors>D P Lopresti,J Zhou</authors><title>Locating and recognizing text in WWW images</title><venue>Information Retrieval</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><volume>2</volume><raw>D. P. Lopresti and J. Zhou. Locating and recognizing text in WWW images. Information Retrieval, 2(2/3):177–206, May 2000.</raw><contexts><context>value of the ALT attribute. The most surprising result is the high level of precision for the ALT attribute of the IMG element. Previous research by Antonacopoulos et al. [1] and by Lopresti and Zhou [6] has shown that more than half of the text values of ALT attributes are empty or wrong. This would suggest that the ALT attribute would have little utility in identifying Web image content. In fact, o</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29761"><authors>J Smith,S F Chang</authors><title>Visually searching the Web for content</title><venue>IEEE Multimedia</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><volume>4</volume><raw>J. Smith and S. F. Chang. Visually searching the Web for content. IEEE Multimedia, 4(3):12–20, JulySeptember 1997.</raw><contexts><context> parameters of the query to those of the images in the database in order to find good matches. This approach can be quite effective and these techniques have been applied to the Web with some success [7]. In this paper, we want to argue that image pro¡ This material is based upon work supported by the U. S. Department of Defense and by the National Science Foundation under Grant No. 9734102. Addition</context><context>t layout. This approach can work well when users seek images with a particular appearance, but it fails when users want to find images with semantics that do not map neatly to image features. WebSeek [7] is an attempt to create a directory and database of images from the Web. Images in WebSeek’s database are categorized into a hierarchy of topics derived from an analysis of image file names. The indi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29762"><authors>Y Tsymbalenko,E V Munson</authors><title>Using HTML metadata to find relevant images on the Web</title><venue>In Proceedings of Internet Computing 2001, Volume II, Las Vegas</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>842--848</pages><publisher>CSREA Press</publisher><raw>Y. Tsymbalenko and E. V. Munson. Using HTML metadata to find relevant images on the Web. In Proceedings of Internet Computing 2001, Volume II, Las Vegas, pages 842–848. CSREA Press, June 2001. Clue Query Image Document Image Anchor Anchor Paragraph Centered Nearby Word Filename Title ALT text text Title text text &amp; image heading Gorbachev 26.0 84.0 5.0 0.0 0.0 5.0 0.0 0.0 Yeltsin 60.0 60.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Streisand 23.0 84.6 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Yelena 11.1 85.0 5.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Ekaterina 0.0 60.0 14.3 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Paris 62.0 62.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 London 12.5 95.8 12.5 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Bremen 80.0 90.0 33.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Spokane 90.0 100.0 30.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Explosion 25.0 75.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Sunset 88.8 11.1 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Hurricane 53.8 38.5 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 Median % 39.9 79.5 2.5 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0</raw><contexts><context>oned text and speech analysis to index video data. 3 Using HTML Metadata to Find Web Images We studied the effectiveness of HTML metadata (textual content and structure) for finding images on the Web [8]. We built a prototype image search system that accepted one word textual queries and returned a set of images. This system used the Alta Vista search engine to find HTML documents matching the textua</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.csc.liv.ac.uk/~wda2001/Papers/25_munson_wda2001.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>fcffc7bc974997d8fe2e40d5986bf5a86e00efca</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>