<document id="10.1.1.1.1523"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">IDENTIFYING INDICATORS OF VULNERABILITYTO FAMINE ANDCHRONIC FOOD INSECURITY</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">The Inter na tional Food Pol icy Research Insti tute was estab-lished in 1975 to iden tify and ana lyze alter na tive national and inter na tional strate gies and poli cies for meet ing food needs of the devel op ing world on a sus tain able basis, with par ticu lar empha sis on low- income coun tries and on the poorer groups in those coun tries. While the research effort is geared to the pre-cise objec tive of con trib ut ing to the reduc tion of hun ger and mal nu tri tion, the fac tors involved are many and wide- ranging, requir ing analy sis of under ly ing processes and extend ing beyond a nar rowly defined food sec tor. The Insti tute’s research pro gram reflects world wide col labo ra-tion with gov ern ments and pri vate and pub lic insti tu tions inter ested in increasing food pro duc tion and improv ing the equity of its dis tri bu tion. Research results are dis semi nated to poli cy mak ers, opin ion form ers, admin is tra tors, pol icy ana lysts, research ers, and oth ers con cerned with national and inter na tional food and agri cul tural pol icy.</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1248">FAMINE AND CHRONIC FOOD INSECURITY YISE HAC YO HAN NES</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4231"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Auser Manualfor</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4232"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Yisehac Yohannes</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4233"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patrick Webb</name><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28621"><authors>D A Bloch,M R Segal</authors><title>Empiri cal com pari son of approaches of form ing strata: Using clas si fi ca tion trees to adjust for covari ates. Jour nal of the Ameri can Sta tis ti cal Asso cia tion 84 (408): 897–905</title><year>1989</year><raw>Bloch, D. A., and M. R. Segal. 1989. Empiri cal com pari son of approaches of form ing strata: Using clas si fi ca tion trees to adjust for covari ates. Jour nal of the Ameri can Sta tis ti cal Asso cia tion 84 (408): 897–905.</raw></citation><citation id="28622"><authors>Bor ton,J,J Sho ham</authors><title>Map ping vul ner abil ity to food in se cu - rity: Ten ta tive guide lines for WFP coun try of fices. Lon don: Re lief and De vel op ment In sti tute</title><year>1991</year><raw>Bor ton, J., and J. Sho ham. 1991. Map ping vul ner abil ity to food in se cu - rity: Ten ta tive guide lines for WFP coun try of fices. Lon don: Re lief and De vel op ment In sti tute.</raw></citation><citation id="28623"><authors>Brei man,J H Fried man L,R A Ol shen,C J Stone</authors><title>Classification and re gres sion trees. Mon terey</title><year>1984</year><publisher>Wadsworth, Inc</publisher><pubAddress>Calif., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Brei man, L., J. H. Fried man, R. A. Ol shen, and C. J. Stone. 1984. Classification and re gres sion trees. Mon terey, Calif., U.S.A.: Wadsworth, Inc.</raw><contexts><context>fi ca tion and regres sion trees, CART’s major goal is to pro duce an accu rate set of data clas si fi ers by uncov er - ing the pre dic tive struc ture of the prob lem under con sid era tion (Brei - man et al. 1984). That is, CART helps in under stand ing the vari ables or inter ac tion of vari ables that are respon si ble for a given phe nome non, such as fam ine, and that best deter mine one out come rather t</context><context>e ter mined by the ana lyst. 9s10 SUMMING UP CART’S STRENGTHS AND WEAKNESSES CART meth od ol ogy fur ther de vel ops and en hances the work on clas si fi ca tion meth od ol ogy of AID and THAID (Brei man et al. 1984). But CART over comes the prob lems as so ci ated with these al go rithms and some of the draw backs as so ci ated with the clas si fi ca tion meth ods in Group 2. Brei man et al. (1984) made sev era</context><context>he maxi mum number of split points on X is equal to N . If Z is a cate gori cal vari able with m dis - tinct points in a sam ple, then the number of pos si ble split points on Z equals 2 m–1 –1 (Brei man et al. 1984, 30). Un less oth er wise speci fied, CART soft ware as sumes that each split will be based on only a sin gle vari able. This com po nent re quires defi ni tion of the im pu rity func tion and im pu </context><context>of other rules for their own ana lyti cal needs. CART uses the Gini cri te - rion (also known as Gini diver sity index) as its default split ting rule. The twoing rule is dis cussed in detail in Brei man et al. 1984 and will not be cov ered here. A brief expo si tion of the lin ear com bi na tion splits is pro vided later in this chap ter. The Gini im pu rity meas ure at node t is de fined as i (t) = 1 – S , whe</context><context> ing one on out liers and split points come from Sey - oum et al. 1995.scom plex ity be come larger. The “right- sized” tree with “cor rect” com plex ity should lie be tween these two ex tremes. Brei man et al. 1984 dis cuss how to es ti mate β and of fer a de tailed ac count of the prun ing pro cess. The search for the “right- sized” tree starts by prun ing or col laps ing some of the branches of the larg est t</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28624"><authors>Cur rey,B</authors><title>Map ping of ar eas li able to fam ine in Bang la desh. Ph.D. the sis (un pub lished). Ge og ra phy De part ment, Uni ver sity of Ha waii, Hono lulu, Ha waii</title><year>1978</year><pubAddress>U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Cur rey, B. 1978. Map ping of ar eas li able to fam ine in Bang la desh. Ph.D. the sis (un pub lished). Ge og ra phy De part ment, Uni ver sity of Ha waii, Hono lulu, Ha waii, U.S.A.</raw></citation><citation id="28625"><authors>Cut ler,B</authors><title>Map ping risks of po ten tial food cri ses in Ethio pia. A re port to the Food Pol icy and Nu tri tion Di vi sion of the Food and Ag ri cul tural Or gani za tion of the United Na tions. Ad dis Ababa. Pho to copy</title><year>1986</year><raw>Cut ler, B. 1986. Map ping risks of po ten tial food cri ses in Ethio pia. A re port to the Food Pol icy and Nu tri tion Di vi sion of the Food and Ag ri cul tural Or gani za tion of the United Na tions. Ad dis Ababa. Pho to copy.</raw></citation><citation id="28626"><authors>Down ing,T E</authors><title>Assess ing socio eco nomic vul ner abil ity to fam ine: Frame works, con cepts, and appli ca tions. Work ing Paper No. 2. Arling ton</title><year>1990</year><pubAddress>Va., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Down ing, T. E. 1990. Assess ing socio eco nomic vul ner abil ity to fam ine: Frame works, con cepts, and appli ca tions. Work ing Paper No. 2. Arling ton, Va., U.S.A.: Fam ine Early Warn ing Sys tem Pro ject, Tulane Uni ver sity/Pragma Cor po ra tion.</raw></citation><citation id="28627"><title>Re gions/vul ner able groups in FEWS meth od ol ogy</title><year>1993</year><raw>———. 1993. Re gions/vul ner able groups in FEWS meth od ol ogy.</raw><contexts><context> ables should be for the pur pose of a valid analy sis. For ex am ple, Bor ton and Sho ham (1991) sug gest 20 core in di ca tors; Cut ler (1986), Frank en berger (1992), and Sea man, Holt, and Al len (1993) each take be tween 20 and 30 in di ca tors as the start ing point; Ri ely (1993) and Down ing (1993) both sug gest more than 50 vari ables; while Cur rey (1978), one of the ear li est prac ti tio - n</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28628"><authors>Memo ran</authors><title>dum for USAID FEWS Pro ject</title><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Rome</pubAddress><volume>2</volume><raw>Memo ran dum for USAID FEWS Pro ject, Rosslyn, Va., U.S.A. FAO (Food and Ag ri cul ture Or gani za tion of the United Na tions). 1998. Guide lines for na tional food in se cu rity and vul ner abil ity in for ma - tion and map ping sys tems (FIVIMS): Back ground and prin ci ples. Re port to the Com mit tee on World Food Se cu rity, Twenty- Fourth Ses sion, Rome, 2–5 June. FAO, Rome.</raw></citation><citation id="28629"><authors>FEWS</authors><title>ine Early Warn ing Sys tem Pro ject</title><year>1993</year><raw>FEWS (Fam ine Early Warn ing Sys tem Pro ject). 1993. Vul ner abil ity assess ment. Report pre pared for the United States Agency for Inter na tional Devel op ment’s Bureau for Africa, Office of Analy sis Research and Tech ni cal Serv ices. Wash ing ton, D.C.: Tulane Uni - ver sity/Pragma Cor po ra tion.</raw><contexts><context>ca tors should reflect the behav ior and live li hood con di tions of tar get popu la tions—those that are most often, and more severely, affected by acute food inse cu rity (Bor ton and Shoham 1991; FEWS 1993; FAO 1998). Such groups include the rural poor, women- headed house holds, asset- poor pas tor al ists, recently reset tled house holds, house holds con strained by a high depend ency ratio, the land</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28630"><authors>Frank en berger,T</authors><title>ca tors and data col lec tion meth ods for as sess ing house hold food se cu rity. In House hold food se cu rity: Con cepts, in di ca tors</title><year>1992</year><editors>In di</editors><raw>Frank en berger, T. 1992. In di ca tors and data col lec tion meth ods for as sess ing house hold food se cu rity. In House hold food se cu rity: Con cepts, in di ca tors, and meth ods, ed. S. Max well and T. Frank - en berger. Rome: United Na tions Chil drens Fund/In ter na tional Fund for Ag ri cul tural De vel op ment.</raw></citation><citation id="28631"><authors>Fryd man,E I Alt man H,D-L Kao</authors><title>In tro duc ing re cur sive par ti tion ing for fi nan cial clas si fi ca tion: The case of fi nan cial dis - tress. Jour nal of Fi nance</title><year>1985</year><pages>269--291</pages><volume>40</volume><raw>Fryd man, H., E. I. Alt man, and D.-L. Kao. 1985. In tro duc ing re cur sive par ti tion ing for fi nan cial clas si fi ca tion: The case of fi nan cial dis - tress. Jour nal of Fi nance 40 (1): 269–291.</raw></citation><citation id="28632"><authors>Hutchin son,P Gil ruth C,R Hay,S Marsh,C Lee</authors><title>Geo - graphic in for ma tion sys tems ap pli ca tions in crop as sess ment and fam ine early warn ing. Re port for the Food and Ag ri cul ture Or gani - za tion of the United Na tions. Uni ver sity of Ari zona, Tuc son</title><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Ariz., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Hutchin son, C., P. Gil ruth, R. Hay, S. Marsh, and C. Lee. 1992. Geo - graphic in for ma tion sys tems ap pli ca tions in crop as sess ment and fam ine early warn ing. Re port for the Food and Ag ri cul ture Or gani - za tion of the United Na tions. Uni ver sity of Ari zona, Tuc son, Ariz., U.S.A.</raw><contexts><context>com ings in de fin ing data needs, weight ing the rela tive value of in di vid ual vari ables, and de fin - ing the sig nifi cance of al ter nate (proxy) vari ables (Bor ton and Sho ham 1991; Hutchin son et al. 1992; Ri ely 1993). Vul ner abil ity to food in se cu rity and fam ine can not be meas ured by sin gle, dis crete vari ables. Given the close re la tion ship be tween re - sources, food pro duc tion, pric</context><context>). Such limi ta tions can lead to crea tive (some times very suc cess ful) approaches to com par ing and com bin ing data that are, in fact, incom pa ra ble and incom pati ble (Down ing 1990; Hutchin son et al. 1992). Effec tive vul ner abil ity analy sis and early warn ing need to go beyond the cata log ing and arbi trary index ing of avail able data. In the past, the prob lems of deter min ing the rela tive si</context><context>ed “con ver gence of evi dence” (Down ing 1990; Bor ton and Sho ham 1991). As a result, many ana lysts have called for refine ments in meth od ol ogy (Down ing 1990; Bor ton and Sho ham 1991; Hutchin son et al. 1992). So far, only two other meth ods have been explored. The first is to work closely with local experts who can help define indi ca tors of local sig nifi cance, thereby improv ing thesreli abil ity of</context><context>s and com bi na tions of vari ables) against observed bench mark meas ures of cri ses, such as num bers of peo ple actu ally affected by fam ine or receiv ing exter nal assis tance by region (Hutchin son et al. 1992). IFPRI’s re search on vul ner abil ity con trib utes to the lat ter ap - proach. The analy sis seeks to un der stand which in di ca tors of vul ner - abil ity best ex plain re ported num bers of “pe</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28633"><authors>G V Kass</authors><title>An ex plora tory tech nique for in ves ti gat ing large quan ti ties of cate gori cal data. Ap plied Sta tis tics 29</title><year>1980</year><pages>119--127</pages><volume>2</volume><raw>Kass, G. V. 1980. An ex plora tory tech nique for in ves ti gat ing large quan ti ties of cate gori cal data. Ap plied Sta tis tics 29 (2): 119–127.</raw></citation><citation id="28634"><authors>Mad dala,G S</authors><title>Lim ited de pend ent and quali ta tive vari ables in econo met rics. Cam bridge: Cam bridge Uni ver sity</title><year>1983</year><publisher>Press</publisher><raw>Mad dala, G. S. 1983. Lim ited de pend ent and quali ta tive vari ables in econo met rics. Cam bridge: Cam bridge Uni ver sity Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28635"><authors>Ma rais,M L,J M Pa tell,M A Wolf son</authors><title>The ex peri men tal de sign of clas si fi ca tion mod els: An ap pli ca tion of re cur sive par ti - tion ing and boot strap ping to com mer cial bank loan clas si fi ca tions</title><year>1985</year><raw>Ma rais, M. L., J. M. Pa tell, and M. A. Wolf son. 1985. The ex peri men tal de sign of clas si fi ca tion mod els: An ap pli ca tion of re cur sive par ti - tion ing and boot strap ping to com mer cial bank loan clas si fi ca tions.</raw></citation><citation id="28636"><title>Jour nal of Ac count ing Re search 22 (Sup ple ment</title><year>1984</year><pages>87--114</pages><raw>Jour nal of Ac count ing Re search 22 (Sup ple ment 1984): 87–114.</raw><contexts><context> IFPRI sur vey of house holds in famine- affected ar eas of Ethio pia. The re gional analy sis used regional- level, time- series data sets that were ac quired and com piled by IFPRI. Brei man et al. (1984) sug gest that CART meth od ol ogy should “not be used to the ex clu sion of other meth ods,” even though em piri cal evi dence shows that CART per forms much bet ter than other pro ce dures, such as </context><context>com pared with re - sults ob tained by ap ply ing other meth ods to the same data set. The main ref er ence ma te rial on CART is the book Clas si fi ca tion and Re gres sion Trees by Brei man et al. (1984). It is the only book that of fers both the ory and meth od ol ogy of CART and il lus trates a number of ex am ples in many dis ci plines. This man ual is or gan ized as fol lows. Chap ter 2 pro vides</context><context>rei man et al. 1984). But CART over comes the prob lems as so ci ated with these al go rithms and some of the draw backs as so ci ated with the clas si fi ca tion meth ods in Group 2. Brei man et al. (1984) made sev eral com para tive analy ses of CART and dis crimi nant analy sis re sults and found that CART per formed bet - ter than dis crimi nant analy sis. Ma rais, Pa tell, and Wolf son (1985) also </context><context> tion study of com mer cial loans, as did Srini vasan and Kim (1987) in their credit- granting study. But in mod els where lin ear struc ture and the as sump tion of nor mal ity hold, Brei man et al. (1984) found that re sults from dis crimi nant analy sis were bet ter than those from CART. Re gard less of the prob lems with other pro ce dures, Brei man et al. (1984) ad vise not to use CART “to the ex c</context><context>e tree and de ter mine the pro por tion of cases miss clas si fied. In em piri cal stud ies, the pos si bil ity of get ting such a data set is re mote. To over come this dif fi culty, Brei man et al. (1984) pro vide three pro ce dures for es ti mat ing the ac cu racy of tree- structured clas si fi ers. First, let c(X) or c = a tree- structured clas si fier, where X is a vec tor of char ac ter is tics va</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28637"><authors>Max well,S</authors><title>Food inse cu rity in North Sudan. IDS Dis cus sion Paper 262. Brigh ton, U.K.: Insti tute of Devel op ment Stud ies, Uni - ver sity of Sus sex</title><year>1989</year><raw>Max well, S. 1989. Food inse cu rity in North Sudan. IDS Dis cus sion Paper 262. Brigh ton, U.K.: Insti tute of Devel op ment Stud ies, Uni - ver sity of Sus sex.</raw></citation><citation id="28638"><authors>Mor gan,J N,R C</authors><title>Mes sen ger. 1973. THAID: A se quen tial search pro gram for the analy sis of nomi nal scale de pend ent vari ables. Tech ni cal re port. In sti tute for So cial Re search, Uni ver sity of Michi - gan, Ann Ar</title><pubAddress>bor, Mich., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Mor gan, J. N., and R. C. Mes sen ger. 1973. THAID: A se quen tial search pro gram for the analy sis of nomi nal scale de pend ent vari ables. Tech ni cal re port. In sti tute for So cial Re search, Uni ver sity of Michi - gan, Ann Ar bor, Mich., U.S.A.</raw></citation><citation id="28639"><authors>Mor gan,J N,J A Son quist</authors><title>Prob lems in the analy sis of sur vey data, and a pro posal. Jour nal of Ameri can Sta tis ti cal As so - cia tion 58</title><year>1963</year><pages>415--434</pages><raw>Mor gan, J. N., and J. A. Son quist. 1963. Prob lems in the analy sis of sur vey data, and a pro posal. Jour nal of Ameri can Sta tis ti cal As so - cia tion 58: 415–434.</raw></citation><citation id="28640"><authors>Ri ely,F</authors><title>Vul ner abil ity analy sis in the FEWS proj ect. Re port to the United States Agency for In ter na tional De vel op ment. Tu lane Uni ver sity, New Or leans</title><year>1993</year><pubAddress>La., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Ri ely, F. 1993. Vul ner abil ity analy sis in the FEWS proj ect. Re port to the United States Agency for In ter na tional De vel op ment. Tu lane Uni ver sity, New Or leans, La., U.S.A. Pho to copy.</raw></citation><citation id="28641"><authors>Sea man,J Holt J,P Al len</authors><title>A new ap proach to vul nerabil ity map ping for ar eas at risk of food cri sis</title><venue>In terim re port on the Risk- Mapping Pro ject. Save the Chil dren Fund (UK), Lon</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><raw>Sea man, J., J. Holt, and P. Al len. 1993. A new ap proach to vul nerabil ity map ping for ar eas at risk of food cri sis. In terim re port on the Risk- Mapping Pro ject. Save the Chil dren Fund (UK), Lon don. Pho to copy.</raw></citation><citation id="28642"><authors>Sey oum,E Rich ard son S,P Webb,F Ri ely,Y Yo</authors><title>han nes</title><year>1995</year><raw>Sey oum, S., E. Rich ard son, P. Webb, F. Ri ely, and Y. Yo han nes. 1995. Ana lyz ing and map ping food in se cu rity: An ex plora tory “CART” meth od ol ogy ap plied to Ethio pia. Fi nal re port to the United States Agency for In ter na tional De vel op ment. In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute, Wash ing ton, D.C. Pho to copy.</raw><contexts><context>to in tro duce the reader to the ba sic prin ci - ples of CART meth od ol ogy. It pro vides ex am ples of CART analy sis from IFPRI’s ear lier fam ine vul ner abil ity stud ies (Webb et al. 1994; Sey oum et al. 1995) and dis cusses when and why CART might be use ful for data analy sis. In ad di tion, the man ual pro vides ex am ples of com puter pro - gram codes and dis cusses CART hard ware and soft ware re qui</context><context>helps in under stand ing the vari ables or inter ac tion of vari ables that are respon si ble for a given phe nome non, such as fam ine, and that best deter mine one out come rather than another (Sey oum et al. 1995). The pur pose of such clas si fi ers or clas si fi - ca tion rules is to enable one to pre dict the class (vul ner able or not vul - ner able, in the case of fam ine house holds) of any future obser</context><context> This is essen tially how the struc ture of the tree is deter mined in the first place, through k-fold cross- validation, which will be dis cussed in Chap ter 3. 1 The fol low ing is adapted from Sey oum et al. 1995. 11s3 THE PREDICTIVE ACCURACY OF CART BASIC PRINCIPLES OF CART METHODOLOGY Ac cu racy is the most im por tant fea ture of a clas si fi ca tion tree. All clas - si fi ca tion pro ce dures, how ever, i</context><context> will have the low est cost com plex ity. As val ues of β de crease and ap proach zero, trees that mini mize cost 2 This sec tion and the fol low ing one on out liers and split points come from Sey - oum et al. 1995.scom plex ity be come larger. The “right- sized” tree with “cor rect” com plex ity should lie be tween these two ex tremes. Brei man et al. 1984 dis cuss how to es ti mate β and of fer a de tailed ac</context><context> the list of vari ables sup plied for gen er at ing the tree is given in Ta ble 3. The re gres sion tree in Fig ure 5 is based on analy sis from a re gional vul - ner abil ity study in Ethio pia (Sey oum et al. 1995) that uses six years (1982–87) of time- series data col lected from 77 ad min is tra tive re gions (awra jas) of Ethio pia. The data con tain 92 vari ables, all listed in Ta ble 3. This study of fam </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28643"><authors>Srini vasan,V,Y H Kim</authors><title>Credit grant ing: A com para tive analy sis of clas si fi ca tion pro ce dures. Jour nal of Fi nance</title><year>1987</year><pages>665--683</pages><volume>42</volume><raw>Srini vasan, V., and Y. H. Kim. 1987. Credit grant ing: A com para tive analy sis of clas si fi ca tion pro ce dures. Jour nal of Fi nance 42 (3): 665–683.</raw></citation><citation id="28644"><authors>Ste in berg,D,P Colla</authors><title>CART: Tree- structured non para met - ric data analy sis</title><year>1995</year><pubAddress>San Di ego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal</pubAddress><raw>Ste in berg, D., and P. Colla. 1995. CART: Tree- structured non para met - ric data analy sis. San Di ego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal ford Sys tems.</raw></citation><citation id="28645"><authors>Ste in berg,P Colla D,K Mar tin</authors><title>CART—Clas si fi ca tion and regres sion trees: Sup ple men tary man ual for Win dows</title><year>1998</year><pubAddress>San Diego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal</pubAddress><raw>Ste in berg, D., P. Colla, and K. Mar tin. 1998. CART—Clas si fi ca tion and regres sion trees: Sup ple men tary man ual for Win dows. San Diego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal ford Sys tems.</raw></citation><citation id="28646"><authors>T Teklu,J von Braun,E Zaki</authors><title>Drought and fam ine re la - tion ships in Su dan: Pol icy im pli ca tions. Re search Re port 88. Wash - ing ton, D.C.: In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute</title><year>1991</year><raw>Teklu, T., J. von Braun, and E. Zaki. 1991. Drought and fam ine re la - tion ships in Su dan: Pol icy im pli ca tions. Re search Re port 88. Wash - ing ton, D.C.: In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute.</raw></citation><citation id="28647"><authors>P Webb,J von Braun</authors><title>Fam ine and food se cu rity in Ethio - pia: Les sons for Af rica. Lon don</title><year>1994</year><publisher>John Wiley</publisher><raw>Webb, P., and J. von Braun. 1994. Fam ine and food se cu rity in Ethio - pia: Les sons for Af rica. Lon don: John Wiley.</raw></citation><citation id="28648"><authors>P Webb,J von Braun,Y Yo</authors><title>han nes</title><year>1992</year><raw>Webb, P., J. von Braun, and Y. Yo han nes. 1992. Fam ine in Ethio pia: Pol icy im pli ca tions of cop ing fail ure at na tional and house hold lev els. Re search Re port 92. Wash ing ton, D.C.: In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute.</raw></citation><citation id="28649"><authors>P Webb,E Rich ard son,S Sey oum,Y Yohan nes</authors><title>Vul ner - abil ity map ping and geo graphi cal tar get ing: An explora tory method applied to Ethio pia. Inter na tional Food Pol icy Research Insti tute, Wash ing ton, D.C. Pho to copy</title><year>1994</year><raw>Webb, P., E. Rich ard son, S. Sey oum, and Y. Yohan nes. 1994. Vul ner - abil ity map ping and geo graphi cal tar get ing: An explora tory method applied to Ethio pia. Inter na tional Food Pol icy Research Insti tute, Wash ing ton, D.C. Pho to copy.</raw><contexts><context>clas sify com mer cial loans. The Inter na tional Food Pol icy Research Insti tute (IFPRI) has used CART to iden tify indi ca tors of vul - ner abil ity to fam ine at regional and house hold lev els (Webb et al. 1994). This man ual is a guide for set ting up CART- based infor ma tion sys tems to iden tify indi ca tors of vul ner abil ity to fam ine, chronic food inse cu rity, and other fail ures of enti tle ment.</context><context> man ual is in tended to in tro duce the reader to the ba sic prin ci - ples of CART meth od ol ogy. It pro vides ex am ples of CART analy sis from IFPRI’s ear lier fam ine vul ner abil ity stud ies (Webb et al. 1994; Sey oum et al. 1995) and dis cusses when and why CART might be use ful for data analy sis. In ad di tion, the man ual pro vides ex am ples of com puter pro - gram codes and dis cusses CART hard ware</context><context>ca tion of “meas ures of ac cu racy of the tree.” These will be de scribed in full in Chap ter 3. In Fig ure 1, the re sults of a CART analy sis based on re search on the vul ner abil ity to fam ine (Webb et al. 1994) is sum ma rized graphi cally in the form of an in verted tree. The CART analy sis has two ma jor ob jec - tives: (1) to get a bet ter un der stand ing of the char ac ter is tics of house - holds tha</context><context>use splits are gen er ally de ter mined at non- outlier val ues. If out - liers ex ist in the de pend ent vari able, they are iso lated in small nodes, where they do not af fect the rest of the tree (Webb et al. 1994). Large trees can have two prob lems: (1) Al though they are highly ac cu - rate, with low or zero mis clas si fi ca tion rates, large trees pro vide poor re sults when ap plied to new data sets (Ste</context><context>od and, hence, food ac ces si bil - ity, than awra jas with less green vege ta tion. In deed, it turns out that these awra jas ex tend west, south, south west, and north west from cen tral Ethio pia (Webb et al. 1994, Map 6.0). These awra jas also pro duce sur plus grain in the coun try. Some awra jas in Group 9 do rep re sent pock ets of vul ner abil ity in this surplus- producing re gion. Awra jas in Groups 1 t</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28650"><authors>Wil liams,M A,H de Silva,M F Koehn,S I Orn stein</authors><title>Why did so many sav ings and loans go bank rupt? Eco nom ics Let ters (36): 61–66</title><year>1991</year><raw>Wil liams, M. A., H. de Silva, M. F. Koehn, and S. I. Orn stein. 1991. Why did so many sav ings and loans go bank rupt? Eco nom ics Let ters (36): 61–66.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ifpri.org/pubs/microcom/micro3.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>f08ba735574c00cb536153efce7865c50ce05b0e</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>