<document id="10.1.1.1.1562"><clusterid>1314</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">PARTITION SAMPLING FOR ACTIVE VIDEO DATABASE ANNOTATION</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Annotating a video-database requires an intensive human effort that is time consuming and error prone. However this task is mandatory to bridge the gap between low-level video features and the semantic content. We propose a partition sampling active learning method to minimize human effort in labeling. Formally, active learning is a process where new unlabeled samples are iteratively selected and presented to teachers. The major problem is then to find the best selection function that maximizes the knowledge gain acquired from new samples. In contrast with existing active learning approaches, we focus on the selection of multiple samples. We propose to select samples such that their contribution to the knowledge gain is complementary and optimal. Hence, at each iteration we ensure to maximize the knowledge gain. Our method offers many advantages; among them the possibility to share the annotation effort among several teachers. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4351"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Fabrice Souvannavong</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Département Communications Multimédias; Institut Eurécom</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2229, route des crêtes; 06904 Sophia-Antipolis- France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Fabrice.Souvannavong @eurecom.fr</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4352"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Bernard Merialdo</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Département Communications Multimédias; Institut Eurécom</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2229, route des crêtes; 06904 Sophia-Antipolis- France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Bernard.Merialdo @eurecom.fr</email><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4353"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Benoît Huet</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Département Communications Multimédias; Institut Eurécom</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2229, route des crêtes; 06904 Sophia-Antipolis- France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Benoit.Huet)@eurecom.fr</email><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29321"><clusterid>1315</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Reference removed for double blind reviewing</title><raw>Reference removed for double blind reviewing.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29322"><clusterid>1316</clusterid><authors>Tsuhan Chen Cha Zhang</authors><title>An active learning framework for content-based information retrieval</title><venue>In IEEE Transactions on Multimedia</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>260--268</pages><volume>4</volume><raw>Tsuhan Chen Cha Zhang. An active learning framework for content-based information retrieval. In IEEE Transactions on Multimedia, volume 4, pages 260–268, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29323"><clusterid>1317</clusterid><authors>Shih-Fu Chang,W Chen,H J Meng,H Sundaram,Di Zhong</authors><title>A fully automated content-based video search engine supporting spatiotemporal queries</title><venue>In IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>602--615</pages><volume>8</volume><raw>Shih-Fu Chang, W. Chen, H.J. Meng, H. Sundaram, and Di Zhong. A fully automated content-based video search engine supporting spatiotemporal queries. In IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, volume 8, pages 602– 615, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29324"><clusterid>1318</clusterid><authors>Micahel I Jordan David A Cohn</authors><title>Zoubin Ghahramani. Active learning with statistical models</title><venue>Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><volume>4</volume><raw>Micahel I. Jordan David A. Cohn, Zoubin Ghahramani. Active learning with statistical models. Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research, 4:129–145, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29325"><clusterid>1319</clusterid><authors>Yoav Freund,H Sebastian Seung,Eli Shamir,Naftali Tishby</authors><title>Selective sampling using the query by committee algorithm</title><venue>Machine Learning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><volume>28</volume><raw>Yoav Freund, H. Sebastian Seung, Eli Shamir, and Naftali Tishby. Selective sampling using the query by committee algorithm. Machine Learning, 28:133–168, 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29326"><clusterid>1320</clusterid><authors>Ching-Yung Lin,Belle L Tseng,John R Smith</authors><title>Video collaborative annotation forum: Establishing ground-truth labels on large multimedia datasets</title><venue>In Proceedings of the TRECVID 2003 Workshop</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>Ching-Yung Lin, Belle L. Tseng, and John R. Smith. Video collaborative annotation forum: Establishing ground-truth labels on large multimedia datasets. In Proceedings of the TRECVID 2003 Workshop, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29327"><clusterid>1321</clusterid><authors>M R Naphade,T Kristjansson,B Frey,T S Huang</authors><title>Probabilistic multimedia objects (multijects): a novel approach to video indexing and retrieval</title><venue>In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>536--540</pages><volume>3</volume><raw>M.R. Naphade, T. Kristjansson, B. Frey, and T.S. Huang. Probabilistic multimedia objects (multijects): a novel approach to video indexing and retrieval. In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing, volume 3, pages 536–540, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29328"><clusterid>1322</clusterid><authors>Kamal Nigam,Andrew K McCallum,Sebastian Thrun,Tom M Mitchell</authors><title>Text classification from labeled and unlabeled documents using EM</title><venue>Machine Learning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>13--4</pages><volume>39</volume><raw>Kamal Nigam, Andrew K. McCallum, Sebastian Thrun, and Tom M. Mitchell. Text classification from labeled and unlabeled documents using EM. Machine Learning, 39(2/3):103– 134, 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation><citation id="29329"><clusterid>1323</clusterid><authors>Alexander Hauptmann Rong Yan,Jie Yang</authors><title>Automatically labeling video data using multi-class active learning</title><venue>In IEEE International Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Alexander Hauptmann Rong Yan, Jie Yang. Automatically labeling video data using multi-class active learning. In IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision. Error rate Error rate 0.06 0.05 0.04 0.03 0.02 0.01 0.06 0.05 0.04 0.03 0.02 0.01 (x1,000) Training size (a) unique selection at each round Random Greedy−Like Training size (b) pool selection at each round Random Extended G−L Partition Sampling</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1562</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.eurecom.fr/~huet/papers/wiamis04.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>f4ac3cc22a7f7a5c80d35cd740968e5e50d74b12</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>