<document id="10.1.1.1.1599"><clusterid>1258333</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">Hierarchical web caching systems: Modeling, design and experimental results</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">This paper aims at finding fundamental design principles for hierarchical web caching. An analytical modeling technique is developed to characterize an uncooperative twolevel hierarchical caching system where the least recently used (LRU) algorithm is locally run at each cache. With this modeling technique, we are able to identify a characteristic time for each cache, which plays a fundamental role in understanding the caching processes. In particular, a cache can be viewed roughly as a low-pass filter with its cutoff frequency equal to the inverse of the characteristic time. Documents with access frequencies lower than this cutoff frequency have good chances to pass through the cache without cache hits. This viewpoint enables us to take any branch of the cache tree as a tandem of low-pass filters at different cutoff frequencies, which further results in the finding of two fundamental design principles. Finally, to demonstrate how to use the principles to guide the caching algorithm design, we propose a cooperative hierarchical web caching architecture based on these principles. Both model-based and real trace simulation studies show that the proposed cooperative architecture results in more than 50% memory saving and substantial central processing unit (CPU) power saving for the management and update of cache entries compared with the traditional uncooperative hierarchical caching architecture.</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2002</year><venue src="INFERENCE">IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">JOURNAL</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">2002</pages><volume src="INFERENCE">20</volume><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="7693763"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Hao Che</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="7693764"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Ye Tung</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author><author id="7693765"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Zhijun Wang</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30012"><clusterid>1926</clusterid><authors>K Ross</authors><title>Hash routing for collections of shared web caches</title><venue>IEEE Network Mag</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>37--45</pages><raw>K. Ross, “Hash routing for collections of shared web caches,” IEEE Network Mag., pp. 37–45, Nov. 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30013"><clusterid>1927</clusterid><authors>H Che,Z Wang,Y Tung</authors><title>Analysis and design of hierarchical web caching systems</title><venue>Proc. IEEE INFOCOM’01</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>1416--1424</pages><volume>3</volume><raw>H. Che, Z. Wang, and Y. Tung, “Analysis and design of hierarchical web caching systems,” Proc. IEEE INFOCOM’01, vol. 3, pp. 1416–1424, Apr. 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30014"><clusterid>1928</clusterid><authors>J Zhang,R Izmailov,D Reininger,M Ott</authors><title>Web caching framework: Analytical models and beyond</title><venue>in IEEE Workshop Internet Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>132--141</pages><raw>J. Zhang, R. Izmailov, D. Reininger, and M. Ott, “Web caching framework: Analytical models and beyond,” in IEEE Workshop Internet Applications 1999, July 1999, pp. 132–141.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30015"><clusterid>2014</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Proxy Caching that Estimates Page Load Delays</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><tech>edu/~chitra/docs/96trNEW</tech><raw>Proxy Caching that Estimates Page Load Delays, R. P. Wooster and M. Abrams. [Online]. Available: http://vtopus.cs.vt. edu/~chitra/docs/96trNEW/</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30016"><clusterid>1929</clusterid><authors>S G Dykes,C L Jeffery,S Das</authors><title>Taxonomy and design analysis for distributed web caching</title><venue>in Proc. HICSS-32</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>286--295</pages><raw>S. G. Dykes, C. L. Jeffery, and S. Das, “Taxonomy and design analysis for distributed web caching,” in Proc. HICSS-32, 1999, pp. 286–295.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30017"><clusterid>1930</clusterid><authors>P Cao,S Irani</authors><title>Cost-Aware WWW Proxy Caching Algorithms</title><venue>in Proc. 1997 USENIX Symp. Internet Technology and Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>193--206</pages><raw>P. Cao and S. Irani, “Cost-Aware WWW Proxy Caching Algorithms,” in Proc. 1997 USENIX Symp. Internet Technology and Systems, Dec. 1997, pp. 193–206.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30018"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>C R Cunha,A Bestavros,M E Crovella</authors><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1995</year><pubAddress>Boston, MA</pubAddress><tech>02 215, Tech. Rep.BUCS-TR-1995-010</tech><raw>C. R. Cunha, A. Bestavros, and M. E. Crovella, “Characteristics of WWW Client-Based Traces,” Boston University, CS Dept., Boston, MA 02 215, Tech. Rep.BUCS-TR-1995-010, Apr. 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30019"><clusterid>1931</clusterid><authors>A Belloum,L O Hertzberger</authors><title>Dealing with one-timer-documents in web caching</title><venue>in Proc. 24th Euromicro Conf</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>544--550</pages><volume>2</volume><raw>A. Belloum and L. O. Hertzberger, “Dealing with one-timer-documents in web caching,” in Proc. 24th Euromicro Conf., vol. 2, 1998, pp. 544–550.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30020"><clusterid>2018</clusterid><authors></authors><title>A Hierarchical Internet Object Cache</title><raw>A Hierarchical Internet Object Cache, A. Chankhunthod, P. B. Danzig, C. Neerdaels, M. F. Schwartz, and K. J. Worrell. [Online]. Available: http://netweb.usc.edu/danzig/cache/cache.html</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30021"><clusterid>175</clusterid><authors>L Breslau,P Cao,L Fan,G Phillips,S Shenker</authors><title>Web caching and Zipf-like distributions: Evidence and implications</title><venue>Proc. IEEE INFOCOM’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>126--134</pages><volume>1</volume><raw>L. Breslau, P. Cao, L. Fan, G. Phillips, and S. Shenker, “Web caching and Zipf-like distributions: Evidence and implications,” Proc. IEEE INFOCOM’99, vol. 1, pp. 126–134, Apr. 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30022"><clusterid>1932</clusterid><authors>M R Korupolu,M Dahlin</authors><title>Coordinated placement and replacement for large-scale distributed caches</title><venue>in Proc. IEEE Workshop on Internet Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>62--71</pages><raw>M. R. Korupolu and M. Dahlin, “Coordinated placement and replacement for large-scale distributed caches,” in Proc. IEEE Workshop on Internet Applications, June 1999, pp. 62–71.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30023"><clusterid>1933</clusterid><authors>J Wang</authors><title>A survey of web caching schemes for the internet</title><venue>ACM Comp. Commun. Rev</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><pages>36--46</pages><volume>29</volume><raw>J. Wang, “A survey of web caching schemes for the internet,” ACM Comp. Commun. Rev., vol. 29, no. 5, pp. 36–46, Oct. 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30024"><clusterid>1934</clusterid><authors>M Abrams,C R Standridge,G Abdulla,S Williams,E A Fox</authors><title>Caching proxies: Limitations and potentials</title><venue>in Proc. 4th Int. World-Wide Web Conf</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pubAddress>Boston, MA</pubAddress><raw>M. Abrams, C. R. Standridge, G. Abdulla, S. Williams, and E. A. Fox, “Caching proxies: Limitations and potentials,” in Proc. 4th Int. World-Wide Web Conf, Boston, MA, Dec. 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30025"><clusterid>1935</clusterid><authors>F P Kelly</authors><title>The clifford Paterson lecture</title><venue>in Proc. Royal Society, London A</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><pages>1--20</pages><volume>444</volume><raw>F. P. Kelly, “The clifford Paterson lecture, 1995: Modeling communication networks, present and future,” in Proc. Royal Society, London A, vol. 444, 1995, pp. 1–20.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30026"><clusterid>1936</clusterid><authors>D Bertsekas,R Gallager</authors><title>Data Networks</title><year>1987</year><publisher>Prentice-Hall</publisher><pubAddress>Englewood Cliffs, NJ</pubAddress><raw>D. Bertsekas and R. Gallager, Data Networks. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, 1987.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30027"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>G R Grimmett,D R Stirzaker</authors><venue>Probability and Random Processes</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><publisher>Univ. Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>G. R. Grimmett and D. R. Stirzaker, Probability and Random Processes. New York: Oxford Univ. Press, 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation><citation id="30028"><clusterid>8918735</clusterid><authors>Xian University,P R China</authors><title>Anonymized Access Log [Online]. Available: ftp://ircache.nlanr. net/Traces/ Hao Che received the B.S. degree from</title><venue>Nanjing University</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Nanjing, China</pubAddress><raw>Anonymized Access Log [Online]. Available: ftp://ircache.nlanr. net/Traces/ Hao Che received the B.S. degree from Nanjing University, Nanjing, China, the M.S. degree in physics from the University of Texas at Arlington, TX, in 1994, and the Ph.D. degree in electrical engineering from the University of Texas at Austin, TX, in 1998. He was an Assistant Professor of Electrical Engineering at the Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, from 1998 to 2001. Since July 2000, he has been a System Architect with Santera Systems, Inc., Plano, TX . He has also served as an Adjunct Assistant Professor at the Pennsylvania State University and a Visiting Professor in the school of Information Science and Engineering, Yunnan University, China, since 2001. His current research interests include network architecture and design, network resource management, multiservice switching architecture, and network processor design. Ye Tung (S’95–M’01) received the B.S. degree from Xian Jiaotong University, Xian, P. R. China, in 1990, and the Ph.D. degree from the Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, in 2001. Since January 2002, he has been an Assistant Professor at the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of South Alabama, Mobile, Alabama. His current research interests include communication systems, computer networking, and server technology. Zhijun Wang received the M.S. degree in physics from Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China, in 1992, and the M.S. degree in electrical engineering from the Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, in 2001. He is working toward the Ph.D. degree in computer science and engineering at the University of Texas at Arlington, TX. His current research interests include wireless web cache management, mobile computing, and wireless networks.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1599</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://crystal.uta.edu/~hche/PUBLICATIONS/papers/caching-jsac.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>