<document id="10.1.1.1.1527"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">On-line Handwritten Japanese Text Recognition free from Constrains on Line Direction and Character Orientation</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper describes an on-line handwritten Japanese text recognition method that is liberated from constraints on writing direction (line direction) and character orientation. This method estimates the line direction and character orientation using the time sequence information of pen-tip coordinates and employs writingbox-free recognition with context processing combined. The method can cope with a mixture of vertical, horizontal and skewed lines with arbitrary character orientations. It is expected useful for tablet PC's, interactive electronic whiteboards and so on. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4246"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Masaki Nakagawa</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2-24-16 Naka-cho, Koganei-shi, Tokyo, 184-8588 Japan</address><order>1</order></author><author id="4247"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Motoki Onuma</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2-24-16 Naka-cho, Koganei-shi, Tokyo, 184-8588 Japan</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">motoki@hands.ei.tuat.ac.jp</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28704"><authors>T Fukushima,M Nakagawa</authors><title>On-line Writing Box Free Recognition of Handwritten Text based on Stochastic Models</title><venue>in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.98-139, No.489</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>25--30</pages><raw>T. Fukushima and M. Nakagawa: On-line Writing Box Free Recognition of Handwritten Text based on Stochastic Models, (in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.98-139, No.489, pp.25-30 (1998.12).</raw><contexts><context>tion with a writing box or frame imposed for each character, handwritten text recognition without writing boxes or frames (writing-boxfree recognition) has been also needed, and our previous research [4] was employed into products. Further demand is conceived to recognize handwriting made on large surfaces by people. We mix horizontal lines and vertical lines and even write text slantingly. Most of t</context><context>the line direction free recognizer already developed [7]. This recognizer employs segmentation likelihood, character recognition likelihood, context (bi-gram) likelihood and character size likelihood [4, 5]. 3.5. Selection of most plausible interpretation The recognition of text lines described above is applied for every CO-revised text lines for each text line element. This step selects the highest rec</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28705"><authors>T Fukushima,M Nakagawa</authors><title>On-line Writing-box-free Recognition of Handwritten Japanese Text Considering Character Size Variations</title><venue>Proc. of 15th ICPR</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>359--363</pages><pubAddress>Barcelona</pubAddress><volume>2</volume><raw>T. Fukushima and M. Nakagawa: On-line Writing-box-free Recognition of Handwritten Japanese Text Considering Character Size Variations, Proc. of 15th ICPR, Barcelona, Vol.2, pp.359-363 (2000.9).</raw><contexts><context> on large surfaces by people. We mix horizontal lines and vertical lines and even write text slantingly. Most of the previous publications and systems have been assuming only horizontal lines of text [4, 5, 6] while we have been trying to relinquish any writing constraint from on-line text input. We proposed a method to recognize mixtures of horizontal, vertical and slanted lines of text with assuming norm</context><context>the line direction free recognizer already developed [7]. This recognizer employs segmentation likelihood, character recognition likelihood, context (bi-gram) likelihood and character size likelihood [4, 5]. 3.5. Selection of most plausible interpretation The recognition of text lines described above is applied for every CO-revised text lines for each text line element. This step selects the highest rec</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28706"><authors>S Senda,K Yamada</authors><title>A Maximum-Likelihood Approach to Segmentation-Based Recognition of Unconstrained Handwriting Text</title><venue>Proc. of 6th ICDAR</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>184--188</pages><pubAddress>Seattle</pubAddress><raw>S. Senda and K. Yamada: A Maximum-Likelihood Approach to Segmentation-Based Recognition of Unconstrained Handwriting Text, Proc. of 6th ICDAR, Seattle, pp.184-188 (2001.9).</raw><contexts><context> on large surfaces by people. We mix horizontal lines and vertical lines and even write text slantingly. Most of the previous publications and systems have been assuming only horizontal lines of text [4, 5, 6] while we have been trying to relinquish any writing constraint from on-line text input. We proposed a method to recognize mixtures of horizontal, vertical and slanted lines of text with assuming norm</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28707"><authors>Y Inamura,T Fukushima,M Nakagawa</authors><title>An On-line Writing-box-free and Writing-direction Free Recognition System for Handwritten Japanese Text</title><venue>in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.100-37, No.135</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>17--24</pages><raw>Y. Inamura, T. Fukushima and M. Nakagawa: An On-line Writing-box-free and Writing-direction Free Recognition System for Handwritten Japanese Text, (in Japanese) IEICE Technical Report, PRMU, Vol.100-37, No.135, pp.17-24 (2000.6).</raw><contexts><context>g to relinquish any writing constraint from on-line text input. We proposed a method to recognize mixtures of horizontal, vertical and slanted lines of text with assuming normal character orientation [7], but left handwriting recognition with characters are also rotated like handwritings often made on whiteboards. In this paper, while improving the above-mentioned method and solving remaining problem</context><context>17.00 © 2003 IEEE vague Th: Threshold ofsEvery CO-normalized text line element has the downward character orientation, so that it is recognized by the line direction free recognizer already developed [7]. This recognizer employs segmentation likelihood, character recognition likelihood, context (bi-gram) likelihood and character size likelihood [4, 5]. 3.5. Selection of most plausible interpretation </context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.csc.liv.ac.uk/%7Eprima/ICDAR2003/Papers/0095_627_masaki_n.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>fbf6a089a160c2f3621c55ce16bf802324e3c153</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>