<document id="10.1.1.1.1539"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">AUTOMOBILE MANUFACTURING SUPPLY CHAIN SIMULATION IN THE GRIDS ENVIRONMENT ABSTRACT</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A Supply Chain is the series of activities that an organization uses to deliver value to its customers. In today’s competitive environment, the globalization of markets has rapidly substituted the traditional integrated business. The competitive success of an organization no longer depends only on its own efforts, but relies on the efficiency of the entire supply chain. Therefore, building an effective supply chain is fast becoming paramount in today’s marketplace. Distributed Supply Chain (DSC) Simulation has been identified as one of the best means to test and analyze the performance of supply chains. The Generic Runtime Infrastructure for Distributed Simulation (GRIDS) is a middleware that supports the reuse and interoperation of DSC simulations. This paper reports the experience on employing the GRIDS to support the distributed collaboration of an automobile manufacture supply chain simulation. Several advantages of GRIDS are also discussed here which make it an ideal middleware for DSC simulations. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4283"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">S. Chick</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4284"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">P. J. Sánchez</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4285"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. Ferrin</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4286"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. J. Morrice</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4287"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Gary Tan</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">3 Science Drive 2; Singapore 117543, SINGAPORE</address><order>5</order></author><author id="4288"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Na Zhao</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">3 Science Drive 2; Singapore 117543, SINGAPORE</address><order>6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28871"><authors>G Archibald,N Karabakal,N,P Karlsson,P</authors><year>1999</year><raw>Archibald,G., N. Karabakal, N. and P. Karlsson, P. 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="28872"><title>Supply Chain vs. Supply Chain: Using Simulation to Compete Beyond the Four Walls</title><venue>Proceedings of the 1999 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>1207--1214</pages><raw>Supply Chain vs. Supply Chain: Using Simulation to Compete Beyond the Four Walls. Proceedings of the 1999 Winter Simulation Conference, 1207-1214.</raw></citation><citation id="28873"><title>Document Object Model (DOM) Level 3 Core Specification Version 1.0. 2002. W3C Working Draft 22</title><year>2002</year><raw>Document Object Model (DOM) Level 3 Core Specification Version 1.0. 2002. W3C Working Draft 22 October 2002.</raw></citation><citation id="28874"><authors>J K Liker,Y Wu</authors><venue>Japanese Automakers</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pubAddress>U.S</pubAddress><raw>Liker, J.K. and Y. Wu. 2000. Japanese Automakers, U.S.</raw><contexts><context>irstly, suppliers can respond more quickly to changes in customers’ demand. They can identify any defects in products quickly and thus have fewer potentially defective parts that need to be reworked (Liker and Wu 2000). Secondly, fewer people are needed to perform wasteful activities, such as moving large batches of inventory from place to place in the plant. Productivity rises via labour force saving. 3.2 Simulat</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28875"><venue>Suppliers and Supply-Chain Superiority, Sloan Management Review, Fall</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>81--93</pages><raw>Suppliers and Supply-Chain Superiority, Sloan Management Review, Fall 2000. 81-93.</raw></citation><citation id="28876"><authors>2000b</authors><title>GRIDS: A Novel Architecture for Distributed Supply Chain</title><venue>Management, proceedings of the Fall 2000 Simulation Interoperability Workshop. Simulation Interoperability Standards Organization, Institute for Simulation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>Sudra, R., S.J.E. Taylor and T. Janahan. 2000b. GRIDS: A Novel Architecture for Distributed Supply Chain Management, proceedings of the Fall 2000 Simulation Interoperability Workshop. Simulation Interoperability Standards Organization, Institute for Simulation and Training. Florida. 00F-SIW-051, 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="28877"><title>Extensibility: Modular HLA RTI</title><venue>Services, proceedings of 2002 European Simulation Interoperability Workshop (E-SIW</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>02--049</pages><pubAddress>North London, UK</pubAddress><raw>Sudra, R., S.J.E. Taylor. 2002. Extensibility: Modular HLA RTI Services, proceedings of 2002 European Simulation Interoperability Workshop (E-SIW), North London, UK, Jun 2002. 02E-SIW-049.</raw></citation><citation id="28878"><title>Developing An Object Exchange Model Template (OEMT</title><venue>for GRIDS Tan, Zhao, and Taylor Distributed Supply Chain (DSC) Simulations, proceedings of 35th Annual Simulation Symposium</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pubAddress>San Diego, USA</pubAddress><raw>Tan, G., W.N. Ng, and S. Taylor. 2002. Developing An Object Exchange Model Template (OEMT) for GRIDS Tan, Zhao, and Taylor Distributed Supply Chain (DSC) Simulations, proceedings of 35th Annual Simulation Symposium, San Diego, USA.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc03papers/142.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>66a42429eccc2447220c3c6fccb1ef6dac2a8b5e</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>