<document id="10.1.1.1.1521"><clusterid>8884949</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">In this paper we compare the average performance of one class of low-discrepancy quasi-Monte Carlo sequences for global optimization. Weiner measure is assumed as the probability prior on all optimized functions. We show how to construct van der Corput sequences and we prove their consistency. Numerical experimentation shows that the van der Corput sequence in base 2 has a better average performance.</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1998</year><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="7693541"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Medeiros Watson Carson</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28610"><clusterid>608</clusterid><authors>H Al-Mharmah,J Calvin</authors><title>Comparison of Monte Carlo and deterministic methods for nonadaptive optimization</title><venue>Proceedings of the 1997 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>348--351</pages><raw>Al-Mharmah, H. and J. Calvin 1997. Comparison of Monte Carlo and deterministic methods for nonadaptive optimization. Proceedings of the 1997 Winter Simulation Conference: 348-351.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28611"><clusterid>609</clusterid><authors>B Betró</authors><title>Bayesian methods in global optimization</title><venue>Journal of Global Optimization</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>1--1</pages><raw>Betró, B. 1991. Bayesian methods in global optimization. Journal of Global Optimization 1:1-14.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28612"><clusterid>610</clusterid><authors>J Calvin</authors><title>Average performance of nonadaptive algorithms for global optimization</title><venue>Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Calvin, J. 1995. Average performance of nonadaptive algorithms for global optimization. Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications 191:608–617.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28613"><clusterid>611</clusterid><authors>J Mockus</authors><title>Bayesian Approach to Global Optimization: Theory and Applications</title><year>1989</year><publisher>Kluwer</publisher><pubAddress>Dordrecht</pubAddress><raw>Mockus, J. 1989. Bayesian Approach to Global Optimization: Theory and Applications. Dordrecht: Kluwer.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28614"><clusterid>612</clusterid><authors>H Niederreiter</authors><title>Random Number Generation and Quasi-Monte Carlo Methods</title><venue>Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Philadelphia</pubAddress><raw>Niederreiter, H. 1992. Random Number Generation and Quasi-Monte Carlo Methods. Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, Philadelphia.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28615"><clusterid>613</clusterid><authors>K Ritter</authors><title>Approximation and optimization on the Wiener space</title><venue>Journal of Complexity</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><pages>6--337</pages><raw>Ritter, K. 1990. Approximation and optimization on the Wiener space, Journal of Complexity 6:337-364.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28616"><clusterid>614</clusterid><authors>A Törn,A ˇZilinskas</authors><title>Global Optimization</title><year>1989</year><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><pubAddress>Berlin</pubAddress><raw>Törn, A. and A. ˇZilinskas 1989. Global Optimization. Berlin: Springer-Verlag.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28617"><clusterid>8918504</clusterid><authors>A Zhigljavsky</authors><title>Theory of Global Random</title><year>1991</year><publisher>Kluwer</publisher><pubAddress>Search, Dordrecht</pubAddress><raw>Zhigljavsky, A. 1991. Theory of Global Random Search, Dordrecht: Kluwer.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation><citation id="28618"><clusterid>8918505</clusterid><authors>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES HISHAM A</authors><title>AL-MHARMAH is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Industrial Engineering at the University of Jordan. He received a B.S. in Civil Engineering and an M.S</title><venue>in Industrial Engineering from the University of Jordan in 1986 and</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES HISHAM A. AL-MHARMAH is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Industrial Engineering at the University of Jordan. He received a B.S. in Civil Engineering and an M.S. in Industrial Engineering from the University of Jordan in 1986 and 1990 respectively. He joined the school of Industrial and Systems Engineering at Georgia Institute of Technology in 1991, and received a Ph.D.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1521</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc98papers/083.PDF</url></urls></fileInfo></document>