<document id="10.1.1.1.1570"><clusterid>8917949</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Toward a Taxonomy of Time-Constrained Applications</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">We are developing a taxonomy for classifying applications based on their time constraints. The taxonomy is based on three components that capture the key characteristics between different classes of applications: the process&apos;s execution behavior, the timing constraints it requests, and the level of guarantee it is willing to accept from the system. The taxonomy is useful for two reasons: it provides a survey of the types of existing real-time scheduling applications, and it is a tool for understanding how to develop integrated schedulers that handle multiple classes of applications simultaneously.</abstract><year src="user correction">2007</year><venue src="user correction"></venue><venType src="user correction"></venType><volume src="user correction"></volume><number src="user correction"></number><publisher src="user correction"></publisher><pubAddress src="user correction"></pubAddress><tech src="user correction"></tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Scott Banachowski  </name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">1</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Scott A. Brandt </name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29559"><clusterid>1487</clusterid><authors>A K Atlas,A Bestavros</authors><title>Statistical rate monotonic scheduling</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 19th IEEE Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><publisher>IEEE</publisher><pubAddress>Madrid, Spain</pubAddress><raw>A. K. Atlas and A. Bestavros. Statistical rate monotonic scheduling. In Proceedings of the 19th IEEE Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS 1998), Madrid, Spain, Dec. 1998. IEEE.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29560"><clusterid>1488</clusterid><authors>M Beck,H Böhme,M Dziadzka,U Kunitz,R Magnus,D Verworner</authors><title>Linux Kernel Internals. Addison–Wesley, 2nd edition</title><year>1998</year><raw>M. Beck, H. Böhme, M. Dziadzka, U. Kunitz, R. Magnus, and D. Verworner. Linux Kernel Internals. Addison–Wesley, 2nd edition, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29561"><clusterid>1489</clusterid><authors>H Chu,K Nahrstedt</authors><title>A soft real time scheduling server in UNIX operating system</title><venue>In European Workshop on Interactive Distributed Multimedia Systems and Telecommunication Services</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>H. Chu and K. Nahrstedt. A soft real time scheduling server in UNIX operating system. In European Workshop on Interactive Distributed Multimedia Systems and Telecommunication Services, Sept. 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29562"><clusterid>1490</clusterid><authors>H Chu,K Nahrstedt</authors><title>CPU service classes for multimedia applications</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1999 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Computing and Systems (ICMCS ’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>H. Chu and K. Nahrstedt. CPU service classes for multimedia applications. In Proceedings of the 1999 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Computing and Systems (ICMCS ’99), June 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29563"><clusterid>1491</clusterid><authors>M K Gardner,J W Liu</authors><title>Analyzing stochastic fixedpriority realtime systems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems, Joint European Conferences on Theory and Practice of Software</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>45--58</pages><publisher>SpringerVerlag</publisher><volume>1579</volume><raw>M. K. Gardner and J. W. Liu. Analyzing stochastic fixedpriority realtime systems. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems, Joint European Conferences on Theory and Practice of Software, volume 1579 of Lecture Notes in Computer Science, pages 45–58. SpringerVerlag, Mar. 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29564"><clusterid>1492</clusterid><authors>M Hamdaoui,P Ramanathan</authors><title>A dynamic priority assignment technique for streams with (m,k)-firm deadlines</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Computers</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><volume>44</volume><raw>M. Hamdaoui and P. Ramanathan. A dynamic priority assignment technique for streams with (m,k)-firm deadlines. IEEE Transactions on Computers, 44(12):1443–1451, Apr. 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29565"><clusterid>1493</clusterid><authors>K Jeffay,D Bennett</authors><title>A rate-based execution abstraction for multimedia computing</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Fifth International Workshop on Network and Operating System Support for Digital Audio and Video</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>K. Jeffay and D. Bennett. A rate-based execution abstraction for multimedia computing. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Workshop on Network and Operating System Support for Digital Audio and Video, Apr. 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29566"><clusterid>1494</clusterid><authors>E D Jensen,C D Locke,H Tokuda</authors><title>A time-driven scheduling model for real-time operating systems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 6th IEEE Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1985</year><raw>E. D. Jensen, C. D. Locke, and H. Tokuda. A time-driven scheduling model for real-time operating systems. In Proceedings of the 6th IEEE Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS 1985), Dec. 1985.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29567"><clusterid>1495</clusterid><authors>M B Jones,D Ros¸u,M-C Ros¸u</authors><title>CPU reservations and time constraints: Efficient, predictable scheduling of independent activities</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 16th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP ’97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>pages</pages><raw>M. B. Jones, D. Ros¸u, and M.-C. Ros¸u. CPU reservations and time constraints: Efficient, predictable scheduling of independent activities. In Proceedings of the 16th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP ’97), pages 198–211, Oct. 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29568"><clusterid>1496</clusterid><authors>C L Liu,J W Layland</authors><title>Scheduling algorithms for multiprogramming in a hard-real-time environment</title><venue>Journal of the Association for Computing Machinery</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1973</year><volume>20</volume><raw>C. L. Liu and J. W. Layland. Scheduling algorithms for multiprogramming in a hard-real-time environment. Journal of the Association for Computing Machinery, 20(1):46–61, Jan. 1973.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29569"><clusterid>1497</clusterid><authors>J W Liu,K Lin,W Shih,A C Yu,J Chung,W Zhao</authors><title>Algorithms for scheduling imprecise computations</title><venue>IEEE Computer</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><volume>25</volume><raw>J. W. Liu, K. Lin, W. Shih, A. C. Yu, J. Chung, and W. Zhao. Algorithms for scheduling imprecise computations. IEEE Computer, 25(5):58–68, May 1991.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29570"><clusterid>1498</clusterid><authors>C D Locke</authors><title>Best-Effort Decision Making for Real-Time Scheduling</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1986</year><tech>PhD thesis</tech><raw>C. D. Locke. Best-Effort Decision Making for Real-Time Scheduling. PhD thesis, Carnegie-Mellon University, May 1986.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29571"><clusterid>1499</clusterid><authors>M K McKusick,K Bostic,M J Karels,J S Quarterman</authors><title>The Design and Implementation of the 4.4 BSD Operating System</title><year>1996</year><publisher>Addison–Wesley</publisher><raw>M. K. McKusick, K. Bostic, M. J. Karels, and J. S. Quarterman. The Design and Implementation of the 4.4 BSD Operating System. Addison–Wesley, 1996.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29572"><clusterid>1500</clusterid><authors>C W Mercer,S Savage,H Tokuda</authors><title>Processor capacity reserves: Operating system support for multimedia applications</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1994 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Computing and Systems (ICMCS ’94</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>90--99</pages><raw>C. W. Mercer, S. Savage, and H. Tokuda. Processor capacity reserves: Operating system support for multimedia applications. In Proceedings of the 1994 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Computing and Systems (ICMCS ’94), pages 90–99, May 1994.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29573"><clusterid>1501</clusterid><authors>R Rajkumar,C Lee,J Lehoczky,D Siewiorek</authors><title>A resource allocation model for QoS management</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 18th IEEE Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>R. Rajkumar, C. Lee, J. Lehoczky, and D. Siewiorek. A resource allocation model for QoS management. In Proceedings of the 18th IEEE Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS 1997), Dec. 1997.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29574"><clusterid>1502</clusterid><authors>J Regehr</authors><title>Using Hierarchical Scheduling to Support Soft Real-Time Applications on General-Purpose Operating Systems</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2001</year><tech>PhD thesis</tech><raw>J. Regehr. Using Hierarchical Scheduling to Support Soft Real-Time Applications on General-Purpose Operating Systems. PhD thesis, University of Virginia, May 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29575"><clusterid>1503</clusterid><authors>T-S Tia,Z Deng,M Shankar,M Storch,J Sun,L Wu,J W Liu</authors><title>Probabilistic performance guarantee for realtime tasks with varying computation times</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Real-Time Technology and Applications Symposium (RTAS95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>164--173</pages><raw>T.-S. Tia, Z. Deng, M. Shankar, M. Storch, J. Sun, L. Wu, and J. W. Liu. Probabilistic performance guarantee for realtime tasks with varying computation times. In Proceedings of the Real-Time Technology and Applications Symposium (RTAS95), pages 164–173, May 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation><citation id="29576"><clusterid>1504</clusterid><authors>H Tokuda,T Kitayama</authors><title>Dynamic QoS control based on real-time threads</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Fourth International Workshop on Network and Operating System Support for Digital Audio and Video</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>114--123</pages><raw>H. Tokuda and T. Kitayama. Dynamic QoS control based on real-time threads. In Proceedings of the Fourth International Workshop on Network and Operating System Support for Digital Audio and Video, pages 114–123, 1993.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1570</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~zaher/rtss-wip/07.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>