<document id="10.1.1.1.1534"><clusterid>8718103</clusterid><title src="user correction">A Simulation Study of an Automotive Foundry . . . </title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">This paper discusses the initial efforts to implement simulation modeling as a visual management and analysis tool at an automotive foundry plant manufacturing engine blocks. The foundry process was modeled using Pro Model to identify bottlenecks and evaluate machine performance, cycle times and production data (total parts, rejects, throughput, products/hr) essential for efficient production control. Results from the current system identified assembly machine work area as the bottleneck (although utilization was greater than 95% for two assembly machines) resulting in high work-in-process (WIP) inventory level, low resource and machine utilization. Based on these results, optimum numbers were identified through use of scenarios by varying the number of assembly machines and processing time of each machine. In addition to these scenarios, strategies for production control involving buffer sizes were also made.</abstract><year src="user correction">2002</year><venue src="user correction">PROCEEDINGS OF THE 2002 WINTER SIMULATION CONFERENCE</venue><venType src="user correction"></venType><volume src="user correction"></volume><number src="user correction"></number><publisher src="user correction"></publisher><pubAddress src="user correction"></pubAddress><tech src="user correction"></tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Sang D. Choi</name><affil src="user correction">Human Performance Institute</affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">1</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Anil R. Kumar</name><affil src="user correction">Human Performance Institute</affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">7</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Abdolazim Houshyar</name><affil src="user correction"></affil><address src="user correction"></address><email src="user correction"></email><order src="user correction">8</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28782"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>R B Chase,N J Aquilano,F R Jacobs</authors><venue>Operations Management for Competitive Advantage (9 th Ed.). McGraw-Hill/Irwin</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pubAddress>New York, NY</pubAddress><raw>Chase, R.B., Aquilano, N.J., and Jacobs, F.R. 2001. Operations Management for Competitive Advantage (9 th Ed.). McGraw-Hill/Irwin, New York, NY.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1534</paperid></citation><citation id="28783"><clusterid>8918556</clusterid><authors>C R Harrell,K Tumay</authors><title>ProModel PC TUTOTIAL</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>Harrell, C.R. and Tumay, K. 1990. ProModel PC TUTOTIAL. In Proceedings of the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference, O. Balci, R.P. Sadowski, R.E. Nance (Eds.), 128–131.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1534</paperid></citation><citation id="28784"><clusterid>8918557</clusterid><authors>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES SANG D CHOI</authors><title>holds a BSIE</title><year>1996</year><raw>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES SANG D. CHOI holds a BSIE (1996) from Kwan-Dong University and a MSIE (1999) from Wichita State University. He is currently a Ph.D. candidate in the Industrial and Manufacturing Engineering Department at Western Michigan University in Kalamazoo. His research interests are in occupational ergonomics and work/process design. He is a member of HFES and IIE. His email address is &lt;s9choi@wmich.edu&gt;.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1534</paperid></citation><citation id="28785"><clusterid>8918558</clusterid><authors>ANIL R KUMAR</authors><title>holds a Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering (1997) from University of Pune, India and a MSIE (2001) from Wichita State University. He is pursuing a doctorial degree at</title><raw>ANIL R. KUMAR holds a Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering (1997) from University of Pune, India and a MSIE (2001) from Wichita State University. He is pursuing a doctorial degree at Western Michigan University in Kalamazoo. He is currently working in the Human Performance Institute as a graduate assistant. His email address is &lt;a1kumar@wmich.edu&gt;.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1534</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc02papers/138.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>