<document id="10.1.1.1.1586"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Efficient Reasoning with Range and Domain Constraints</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">We show how a tableaux algorithm for SHIQ can be extended to support role boxes that include range and domain axioms, prove that the extended algorithm is still a decision procedure for the satisfiability and subsumption of SHIQ concepts w.r.t. such a role box, and show how support for range and domian axioms can be exploited in order to add a new form of absorption optimisation called role absorption. We illustrate the effectiveness of the optimised algorithm by analysing the perfomance of our FaCT++ implementation when classifying terminologies derived from realistic ontologies. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4412"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Dmitry Tsarkov</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Manchester, UK</address><order>1</order></author><author id="4413"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Ian Horrocks</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Manchester, UK</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">tsarkov|horrocks@cs.man.ac.uk</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29805"><authors>S Bechhofer,I Horrocks,C Goble,R Stevens</authors><title>OilEd: a reason-able ontology editor for the semantic web</title><venue>In Proc. of the Joint German/Austrian Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (KI 2001), number 2174 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>396--408</pages><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><raw>S. Bechhofer, I. Horrocks, C. Goble, and R. Stevens. OilEd: a reason-able ontology editor for the semantic web. In Proc. of the Joint German/Austrian Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (KI 2001), number 2174 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, pages 396–408. Springer-Verlag, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>oncept absorption (see [10]). Role absorption is important because in ontology derived KBs range and domain constraints will often have been transformed into GCIs. This is because tools such as OilEd [1] and Protégé [11] are designed to work with range of DL reasoners, some of which (e.g., FaCT) do not support range and domain axioms. Moreover, these forms of GCI are not, in general, amenable to stan</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29806"><authors>Mike Dean,Dan Connolly,Frank van Harmelen,James Hendler,Ian Horrocks,Deborah L McGuinness,Peter F Patel-Schneider,Lynn Andrea Stein</authors><title>OWL web on language 1.0 reference. W3C Proposed Recommendation, 15 December 2003. Available athttp://www.w3.org/TR/owl-ref</title><raw>Mike Dean, Dan Connolly, Frank van Harmelen, James Hendler, Ian Horrocks, Deborah L. McGuinness, Peter F. Patel-Schneider, and Lynn Andrea Stein. OWL web ontology language 1.0 reference. W3C Proposed Recommendation, 15 December 2003. Available athttp://www.w3.org/TR/owl-ref/.</raw><contexts><context>lysing the perfomance of our FaCT++ implementation when classifying terminologies derived from realistic ontologies. 1 Introduction Many modern ontology languages (e.g., OIL [3], DAML+OIL [8] and OWL [2]) are based on expressive description logics, and in particular on the SHIQ family of description logics [9]. These ontology languages typically support domain and range constraints on roles, i.e., ax</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29807"><authors>D Fensel,F van Harmelen,I Horrocks,D McGuinness,P F Patel-Schneider</authors><title>OIL: An ontology infrastructure for the semantic web</title><venue>IEEE Intelligent Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--1</pages><volume>16</volume><raw>D. Fensel, F. van Harmelen, I. Horrocks, D. McGuinness, and P. F. Patel-Schneider. OIL: An ontology infrastructure for the semantic web. IEEE Intelligent Systems, 16(2):38–45, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>optimised algorithm by analysing the perfomance of our FaCT++ implementation when classifying terminologies derived from realistic ontologies. 1 Introduction Many modern ontology languages (e.g., OIL [3], DAML+OIL [8] and OWL [2]) are based on expressive description logics, and in particular on the SHIQ family of description logics [9]. These ontology languages typically support domain and range cons</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29808"><authors>Volker Haarslev,Ralf Möller</authors><title>High performance reasoning with very large knowledge bases: A practical case study</title><venue>In Proc. of the 17th Int. Joint Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>161--168</pages><raw>Volker Haarslev and Ralf Möller. High performance reasoning with very large knowledge bases: A practical case study. In Proc. of the 17th Int. Joint Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI 2001), pages 161–168, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>order for the Racer system to be able to classify large KBs containing many range and domain constraints, it is necessary to give a special treatment to the GCIs introduced by range and domain axioms [4]. The approach used by Racer is to extend the lazy unfolding optimisation so that concepts equivalent to those that would besintroduced by the GCIs are introduced only as necessary. In the approach pr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29809"><authors>RACER</authors><title>system description</title><venue>In Proc. of the Int. Joint Conf. on Automated Reasoning (IJCAR 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>701--705</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><volume>2083</volume><raw>Volker Haarslev and Ralf Möller. RACER system description. In Proc. of the Int. Joint Conf. on Automated Reasoning (IJCAR 2001), volume 2083 of Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, pages 701–705. Springer, 2001.</raw><contexts><context> so that they can be efficiently dealt with using the lazy unfolding optimisation [6]. Absorption is one of the crucial optimisations that enable state of the art DL reasoners such as FaCT [7], Racer [5] and Pellet [12] to deal effectively with large knowledge bases (KBs), and these reasoners perform much less well with KBs containing significant numbers of unabsorbable GCIs. Unfortunately, many onto</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29810"><authors>I Horrocks</authors><title>Implementation and optimisation techniques</title><venue>The Description Logic Handbook: Theory, Implementation, and Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>306--346</pages><editors>In Franz Baader, Diego Calvanese, Deborah McGuinness, Daniele Nardi, and Peter F. Patel-Schneider, editors</editors><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>I. Horrocks. Implementation and optimisation techniques. In Franz Baader, Diego Calvanese, Deborah McGuinness, Daniele Nardi, and Peter F. Patel-Schneider, editors, The Description Logic Handbook: Theory, Implementation, and Applications, pages 306– 346. Cambridge University Press, 2003.</raw><contexts><context> transformation is that such GCIs are not amenable to absorption, an optimisation technique that tries to rewrite GCIs so that they can be efficiently dealt with using the lazy unfolding optimisation [6]. Absorption is one of the crucial optimisations that enable state of the art DL reasoners such as FaCT [7], Racer [5] and Pellet [12] to deal effectively with large knowledge bases (KBs), and these r</context><context>ased on the same tableaux algorithms as the original FaCT, but has a different architecture and is written in C++ instead of Lisp. Absorption Absorption in FaCT++ uses the same basic approach as FaCT [10, 6]. Given a TBox T , the absorption algorithm constructs a triple of TBoxes 〈Tdef, Tsub, Tg〉 such that: • Tdef is a set of axioms of the form A ≡ C (equivalent to a pair of axioms {A ⊑ C, C ⊑ A} ⊆ T ), </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29811"><authors>Ian Horrocks</authors><title>Using an expressive description logic: FaCT or fiction</title><venue>In Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>636--647</pages><raw>Ian Horrocks. Using an expressive description logic: FaCT or fiction? In Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR’98), pages 636–647, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>ewrite GCIs so that they can be efficiently dealt with using the lazy unfolding optimisation [6]. Absorption is one of the crucial optimisations that enable state of the art DL reasoners such as FaCT [7], Racer [5] and Pellet [12] to deal effectively with large knowledge bases (KBs), and these reasoners perform much less well with KBs containing significant numbers of unabsorbable GCIs. Unfortunately</context><context>on and Empirical Evaluation We have implemented the extended tableaux algorithm and role absorption optimisation in the FaCT++ DL reasoner. FaCT++ is a next generation of the well-known FaCT reasoner [7], being developed as part of the EU WonderWeb project (see http://wonderweb. semanticweb.org/); it is based on the same tableaux algorithms as the original FaCT, but has a different architecture and i</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29812"><authors>Ian Horrocks,Peter F Patel-Schneider,Frank van Harmelen</authors><title>Reviewing the design of DAML+OIL: An ontology language for the semantic web</title><venue>In Proc. of the 18th Nat. Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>792--797</pages><publisher>AAAI Press</publisher><raw>Ian Horrocks, Peter F. Patel-Schneider, and Frank van Harmelen. Reviewing the design of DAML+OIL: An ontology language for the semantic web. In Proc. of the 18th Nat. Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2002), pages 792–797. AAAI Press, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>rithm by analysing the perfomance of our FaCT++ implementation when classifying terminologies derived from realistic ontologies. 1 Introduction Many modern ontology languages (e.g., OIL [3], DAML+OIL [8] and OWL [2]) are based on expressive description logics, and in particular on the SHIQ family of description logics [9]. These ontology languages typically support domain and range constraints on rol</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29813"><authors>Ian Horrocks,Ulrike Sattler,Stephan Tobies</authors><title>Practical reasoning for expressive description logics</title><venue>Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Logic for Programming and Automated Reasoning (LPAR’99), number 1705 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>161--180</pages><editors>In Harald Ganzinger, David McAllester, and Andrei Voronkov, editors</editors><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>Ian Horrocks, Ulrike Sattler, and Stephan Tobies. Practical reasoning for expressive description logics. In Harald Ganzinger, David McAllester, and Andrei Voronkov, editors, Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Logic for Programming and Automated Reasoning (LPAR’99), number 1705 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, pages 161–180. Springer, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>ologies. 1 Introduction Many modern ontology languages (e.g., OIL [3], DAML+OIL [8] and OWL [2]) are based on expressive description logics, and in particular on the SHIQ family of description logics [9]. These ontology languages typically support domain and range constraints on roles, i.e., axioms asserting that if an individual x is related to an individual y by a role R, then x must be an instance</context><context>mantics of the SHIQ logic, including the semantics of role boxes extended with range and domain axioms. Most details of the logic and the tableaux algorithm are little changed from those presented in [9]. We will, therefore, focus mainly on the parts that have been added in order to deal with range and domain axioms, and refer the reader to [9] for complete information on the remainder. The absolutel</context><context>I satisfying R and T . Theorem 1 Satisfiability and subsumption of SHIQ-concepts w.r.t. terminologies and role boxes is polynomially reducible to (un)satisfiability of SHIQ-concepts w.r.t. role boxes [9]. 3 Tableaux Reasoning with Range and Domain Here we present an algorithm for deciding the satisfiability of a SHIQ-concept C w.r.t. a role box R; it is an extension of the SHIQ tableaux algorithm fro</context><context>g when a clash occurs, and answers “D is satisfiable” iff the completion rules can be applied in such a way that they yield a complete and clash-free completion tree. Note that the only change w.r.t. [9] is addition of the domain and range-rules that add concepts to node labels as required by domain and range axioms. Lemma 2 Let D be an SHIQ-concept. 1. The tableaux algorithm terminates when started </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29814"><authors>Ian Horrocks,Stephan Tobies</authors><title>Reasoning with axioms: Theory and practice</title><venue>In Proc. of the 7th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>285--296</pages><raw>Ian Horrocks and Stephan Tobies. Reasoning with axioms: Theory and practice. In Proc. of the 7th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR 2000), pages 285–296, 2000.</raw><contexts><context>makes sense to transform GCIs into range and domain axioms. We call this new form of absorption role absorption in contrast to the usual form of absorption we will refer to as concept absorption (see [10]). Role absorption is important because in ontology derived KBs range and domain constraints will often have been transformed into GCIs. This is because tools such as OilEd [1] and Protégé [11] are de</context><context>ased on the same tableaux algorithms as the original FaCT, but has a different architecture and is written in C++ instead of Lisp. Absorption Absorption in FaCT++ uses the same basic approach as FaCT [10, 6]. Given a TBox T , the absorption algorithm constructs a triple of TBoxes 〈Tdef, Tsub, Tg〉 such that: • Tdef is a set of axioms of the form A ≡ C (equivalent to a pair of axioms {A ⊑ C, C ⊑ A} ⊆ T ), </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29815"><authors>N F Noy,M Sintek,S Decker,M Crubezy,R W Fergerson,M A Musen</authors><title>Creating semantic web contents with Protégé-2000</title><venue>IEEE Intelligent Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--1</pages><volume>16</volume><raw>N. F. Noy, M. Sintek, S. Decker, M. Crubezy, R. W. Fergerson, and M. A. Musen. Creating semantic web contents with Protégé-2000. IEEE Intelligent Systems, 16(2):60– 71, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>n (see [10]). Role absorption is important because in ontology derived KBs range and domain constraints will often have been transformed into GCIs. This is because tools such as OilEd [1] and Protégé [11] are designed to work with range of DL reasoners, some of which (e.g., FaCT) do not support range and domain axioms. Moreover, these forms of GCI are not, in general, amenable to standard concept abso</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29816"><title>A semantic infosphere</title><venue>Proc. of the 2003 International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC 2003), number 2870 in Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>882--896</pages><editors>Michael Uschold, Peter Clark, Fred Dickey, Casey Fung, Sonia Smith, Stephen Uczekaj Michael Wilke, Sean Bechhofer, and Ian Horrocks</editors><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>Michael Uschold, Peter Clark, Fred Dickey, Casey Fung, Sonia Smith, Stephen Uczekaj Michael Wilke, Sean Bechhofer, and Ian Horrocks. A semantic infosphere. In Dieter Fensel, Katia Sycara, and John Mylopoulos, editors, Proc. of the 2003 International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC 2003), number 2870 in Lecture Notes in Computer Science, pages 882–896. Springer, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>e example. The RTIMS ontology is taken from a publish and subscribe application where it is used by document publishers to annotate documents so that they can be routed to the appropriate subscribers [13]. The ontology contains about 250 concepts (with medium-complex structure), 76 range and domain constraints and 14 GCIs that are not absorbable by concept absorption. This ontology is too small to sho</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://sunsite.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/Publications/CEUR-WS//Vol-104/05Tsarkow-final.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>82226639bb1264b2aaa810a95687bd39c593c2c9</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>