<document id="10.1.1.1.1524"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1"></title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">An approach for locating segmentation points of handwritten digit strings using a neural network An approach for segmentation of handwritten touching numeral strings is presented in this paper. A neural network has been designed to deal with various types of touching observed frequently in numeral strings. A numeral string image is split into a number of line segments while stroke extraction is being performed and the segments are represented with straight lines. Four types of primitive are defined based on the lines and used for representing the numeral string in more abstractive way and extracting clues on touching information from the string. Potential segmentation points are located using the neural network by active interpretation of the features collected from the primitives. Also, the run-length coding scheme is employed for efficient representation and manipulation of images. On a test set collected from real mail pieces, the segmentation accuracy of 89.1 % was achieved, in image level, in a preliminary experiment. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28651"><authors>R G Casey,E Lecolinet</authors><title>Strategies in character segmentation : A survey</title><venue>In Proceedings of International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>1028--1033</pages><raw>R. G. Casey and E. Lecolinet. Strategies in character segmentation : A survey. In Proceedings of International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition, pages 1028–1033, 1995.</raw><contexts><context>wever, touching between digits in handwritten scripts is common place. Issues that related to the segmentation and recognition of handwritten strings have been dealt with various ways for last decades[1]. It is well known that the difficulties stem from not only variations existing in shape but also various ways of touching. And, in many cases, the segmentation and the recognition could not be consid</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28652"><authors>Y K Chen,J F Wang</authors><title>Segmentation of single- or multiple-touching handwritten numeral string using background and foreground analysis</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><volume>22</volume><raw>Y. K. Chen and J. F. Wang. Segmentation of single- or multiple-touching handwritten numeral string using background and foreground analysis. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 22(11):1304–1317, November 2000.</raw><contexts><context>on could not be considered independently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28653"><authors>G Congedo,G Dimauro,S Impedovo,G Pirlo</authors><title>Segmentation of numeric strings</title><venue>In Proceedings of International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>1038--1041</pages><raw>G. Congedo, G. Dimauro, S. Impedovo, and G. Pirlo. Segmentation of numeric strings. In Proceedings of International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition, pages 1038–1041, 1995.</raw><contexts><context>ently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correct segmentation is important s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28654"><authors>H Fujisawa,Y Nakano,K Kurino</authors><title>Segmentation Methods for Character Recognition: From Segmentation to Document Structure Analysis</title><venue>Proceedings of the IEEE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><volume>80</volume><raw>H. Fujisawa, Y. Nakano, and K. Kurino. Segmentation Methods for Character Recognition: From Segmentation to Document Structure Analysis. Proceedings of the IEEE, 80(7):1079–1092, 1992.</raw><contexts><context>on could not be considered independently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28655"><authors>T M Ha,M Zimmermann,H Bunke</authors><title>Offline handwritten numeral string recognition by combining segmentation-based and segmentation-free methods</title><venue>Pattern Recognition</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><volume>31</volume><raw>T. M. Ha, M. Zimmermann, and H. Bunke. Offline handwritten numeral string recognition by combining segmentation-based and segmentation-free methods. Pattern Recognition, 31(3):257–272, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>ently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correct segmentation is important s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28656"><authors>K Kim,J Kim,C Suen</authors><title>Segmentation-based recognition of handwritten touching pairs of digits using structural features</title><venue>Pattern Recognition Letters</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--2</pages><volume>23</volume><raw>K. Kim, J. Kim, and C. Suen. Segmentation-based recognition of handwritten touching pairs of digits using structural features. Pattern Recognition Letters, 23:13–24, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>on could not be considered independently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28657"><authors>S-W Lee,S-Y Kim</authors><title>Integrated segmentation and recognition of handwritten numerals with cascade neural networks</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics - Part C: Applications and Reviews</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><volume>29</volume><raw>S.-W. Lee and S.-Y. Kim. Integrated segmentation and recognition of handwritten numerals with cascade neural networks. IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics - Part C: Applications and Reviews, 29(2):285–290, February 1999.</raw><contexts><context>ently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correct segmentation is important s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28658"><authors>Z Lu,Z Chi,W Siu,P Shi</authors><title>A background-thinningbased approach for separating and recognizing connected handwritten digit strings</title><venue>Pattern Recognition</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><volume>32</volume><raw>Z. Lu, Z. Chi, W. Siu, and P. Shi. A background-thinningbased approach for separating and recognizing connected handwritten digit strings. Pattern Recognition, 32:921–933, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>on could not be considered independently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28659"><authors>S Madhvanath</authors><title>The Holistic Paradigm in Handwritten Word Recognition and Its Application to Large and Dynamic Lexicon Scenarios</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1996</year><tech>PhD thesis</tech><raw>S. Madhvanath. The Holistic Paradigm in Handwritten Word Recognition and Its Application to Large and Dynamic Lexicon Scenarios. PhD thesis, Dept. of Computer Science, State University of New York at Buffalo, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>tween characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correct segmentation is important since errors mad</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28660"><authors>T Pavlidis</authors><title>Algorithms for Graphics and Image Processing</title><year>1982</year><publisher>Computer Science Press</publisher><pubAddress>Rockville, MD</pubAddress><raw>T. Pavlidis. Algorithms for Graphics and Image Processing. Computer Science Press, Rockville, MD, 1982.</raw><contexts><context>ed in the primitive under examine. Performance of the proposed scheme is compared with a rule-based method and some of particular cases are illustrated. Also, we introduce the run-length coding scheme[10] for image manipulation to make the overall process more efficient. Figure 1 illustrates the overview of the approach. Organization of this paper is as follows. Section 2 describes the image represent</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28661"><authors>Z Shi,V Govindaraju</authors><title>Segmentation and Recognition of Connected Handwritten Numeral Strings</title><venue>In The Fifth International Workshop on Frontiers in Handwriting Recognition</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>305--308</pages><pubAddress>Essex, England</pubAddress><raw>Z. Shi and V. Govindaraju. Segmentation and Recognition of Connected Handwritten Numeral Strings. In The Fifth International Workshop on Frontiers in Handwriting Recognition, Essex, England, pages 305–308, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>ms dealing with digit segmentation that have been reported in the literature are primarily rule-based. Types of touching are analyzed and rules for locating potential segmentation points are developed[11]. In this paper, we propose a method for locating possible segmentation points in a digit string image using a neural network. To provide inputs for the neural network, we define primitives that repre</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28662"><authors>N W Strathy,C Y Suen</authors><title>A new system for reading handwritten zip codes</title><venue>In Proceedings of International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>74--77</pages><raw>N. W. Strathy and C. Y. Suen. A new system for reading handwritten zip codes. In Proceedings of International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition, pages 74– 77, 1995.</raw><contexts><context>ently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correct segmentation is important s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28663"><authors>D Yu,H Yan</authors><title>Separation of touching handwritten multinumeral strings based on morphological structural features</title><venue>Pattern Recognition</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--1</pages><volume>34</volume><raw>D. Yu and H. Yan. Separation of touching handwritten multinumeral strings based on morphological structural features. Pattern Recognition, 34:587–599, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>on could not be considered independently when touching between characters/digits is assumed. There have been three strategies for dealing with the segmentation problem: segmentation-based (dissection)[2, 4, 6, 8, 13], recognition-based[3,5,7,12],andholistic[9] Daekeun You and Gyeonghwan Kim Dept. of Electronic Engineering Sogang University CPO Box 1142, Seoul 100-611 Korea gkim@ccs.sogang.ac.kr approaches. Correc</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.csc.liv.ac.uk/%7Eprima/ICDAR2003/Papers/0025_697_kim_g.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>35818f54723d98980415080952af56b3c12cd8ee</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>