<document id="10.1.1.1.1528"><clusterid>8918540</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Data Transformation for Warehousing Web Data</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">In order to analyze market trends and make reasonable business plans, a company&apos;s local data is not sufficient. Decision making must also be based on information from suppliers, partners and competitors. This external data can be obtained from the Web in many cases, but must be integrated with the company&apos;s own data, for example, in a data warehouse. To this end, Web data has to be mapped to the star schema of the warehouse. In this paper we propose a semi-automatic approach to support this transformation process. Our approach is based on the use a rooted labeled tree representation of Web data and the existing warehouse schema. Based on this common view we can compare source and target schemata to identify correspondences. We show how the correspondences guide the transformation to be accomplished automatically. We also explain the meaning of recursion and restructuring in mapping rules, which are the core of the transformation algorithm.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2001</year><venue src="user correction">PROCEEDINGS OF THE 3RD INTERNATIONAL WORKSHOP ON ADVANCED ISSUES OF E-COMMERCE AND WEB-BASED INFORMATION SYSTEMS</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><volume src="user correction"></volume><number src="user correction"></number><publisher src="user correction"></publisher><pubAddress src="user correction"></pubAddress><tech src="user correction"></tech><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Yan Zhu</name><affil src="user correction">Department of Computer Science, Darmstadt University of Technology</affil><address src="user correction">64283 Darmstadt, Germany</address><email src="user correction">zhu @dvs1.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de</email><order src="user correction">1</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Christof Bornhövd</name><affil src="user correction">Department of Computer Science, Darmstadt University of Technology</affil><address src="user correction">64283 Darmstadt, Germany</address><email src="user correction">christof bornhoevd@hp.com</email><order src="user correction">3</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction">Alejandro P. Buchmann</name><affil src="user correction">Department of Computer Science, Darmstadt University of Technology</affil><address src="user correction">64283 Darmstadt, Germany</address><email src="user correction">buchmann@dvs1.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de</email><order src="user correction">4</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28708"><clusterid>710</clusterid><authors>S Abiteboul,D Quass,J McHugh,J Widom,J L Wiener</authors><title>The Lorel Query Language for</title><venue>Semistructure Data, International Journal on Digital Libraries 1(1</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>68--88</pages><raw>S. Abiteboul, D. Quass, J. McHugh, J. Widom, J. L. Wiener: The Lorel Query Language for Semistructure Data, International Journal on Digital Libraries 1(1): 68-88, 1997</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28709"><clusterid>711</clusterid><authors>C Bornhövd,A P</authors><title>Buchmann: A Prototype for Metadatabased Integration of Internet Sources</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>CAiSE’99, Heidelberg, Germany</pubAddress><raw>C. Bornhövd, A. P. Buchmann: A Prototype for Metadatabased Integration of Internet Sources, CAiSE’99, Heidelberg, Germany, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28710"><clusterid>712</clusterid><authors>P Buneman,S Davidson,G Hillebrand,D</authors><title>Suciu: AQuery Language and Optimization Techniques for Unstructured Data,SIGMOD’96</title><year>1996</year><pubAddress>Montreal, Canada</pubAddress><raw>P. Buneman, S. Davidson, G. Hillebrand, D. Suciu: AQuery Language and Optimization Techniques for Unstructured Data,SIGMOD’96, Montreal, Canada, 1996</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28711"><clusterid>713</clusterid><authors>P Buneman,M Fernandez,D</authors><title>Suciu: UnQL: a Query Languag and Algebra for Semistructured</title><venue>Data Based on Structural Recursion, VLDB Journal</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><pages>76--110</pages><volume>9</volume><raw>P. Buneman, M. Fernandez, D. Suciu: UnQL: a Query Languag and Algebra for Semistructured Data Based on Structural Recursion, VLDB Journal 9(1): 76-110, 2000</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28712"><clusterid>714</clusterid><authors>C Beeri,T Milo</authors><title>Schemas for Integration and Translation</title><venue>of Structured and Semi-structured Data, ICDT’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Jerusalem, Israel</pubAddress><raw>C. Beeri and T. Milo: Schemas for Integration and Translation of Structured and Semi-structured Data, ICDT’99, Jerusalem, Israel, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28713"><clusterid>715</clusterid><authors>C Bornhövd MIX</authors><title>A Representation Model for the Integration of Web-based Data</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1999</year><tech>Technical Report, DVS99-1</tech><raw>C. Bornhövd: MIX – A Representation Model for the Integration of Web-based Data, Technical Report, DVS99-1, Department of Computer Science, Darmstadt University of Technology, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28714"><clusterid>716</clusterid><authors>C Bornhövd</authors><title>Semantic Metadata for the Integration of Web-based Data for Electronic</title><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Commerce, WECWIS’99, Santa Clara, USA</pubAddress><raw>C. Bornhövd: Semantic Metadata for the Integration of Web-based Data for Electronic Commerce, WECWIS’99, Santa Clara, USA, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28715"><clusterid>8918541</clusterid><authors>C Bornhövd</authors><title>Semantic Metadata for the Integration of Data Source from the Internet</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2001</year><pubAddress>Germany</pubAddress><tech>Ph.D. thesis</tech><raw>C. Bornhövd: Semantic Metadata for the Integration of Data Source from the Internet, Ph.D. thesis, Darmstadt University of Technology, Germany, Jan. 2001</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28716"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>S Cluet,C Delobel,J Simeón,K</authors><venue>Smaga: Your Mediators Need Data Conversion!, SIGMOD’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Seattle, WA, USA</pubAddress><raw>S. Cluet, C. Delobel, J. Simeón and K. Smaga: Your Mediators Need Data Conversion!, SIGMOD’98, Seattle, WA, USA, 1998</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28717"><clusterid>718</clusterid><authors>A Deutsch,M F Fernandez,D Florescu,A Y Levy,D</authors><title>Suciu: A Query Language for</title><venue>XML, WWW8 / Computer Networks</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>31--11</pages><raw>A. Deutsch, M. F. Fernandez, D. Florescu, A. Y. Levy, D. Suciu: A Query Language for XML, WWW8 / Computer Networks 31(11-16): 1155-1169, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28718"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>M Fernandez,D Florescu,J Kang,A Levy,D</authors><venue>Suciu: STRUDEL : A Web Site Management System, SIGMOD’97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pubAddress>Tucson, USA</pubAddress><raw>M. Fernandez, D. Florescu, J. Kang, A. Levy, D. Suciu: STRUDEL : A Web Site Management System, SIGMOD’97, Tucson, USA, 1997</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28719"><clusterid>8918542</clusterid><authors>D Florescu,D Kossmann</authors><title>Storing and Querying XML Data Using a RDBMS, Bulletin on Data Engineering 22(3</title><year>2000</year><pages>27--34</pages><raw>D. Florescu, D. Kossmann: Storing and Querying XML Data Using a RDBMS, Bulletin on Data Engineering 22(3): 27-34, 2000</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28720"><clusterid>720</clusterid><authors>T Milo,S Zohar</authors><title>Using Schema Matching to Simplify Heterogeneous Data Translation</title><year>1998</year><pubAddress>VLDB’98, New York City, USA</pubAddress><raw>T. Milo and S. Zohar, Using Schema Matching to Simplify Heterogeneous Data Translation, VLDB’98, New York City, USA, 1998</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28721"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>A Schmidt,M Kersten,M Windhouwer,F</authors><venue>Waas: Efficient Relational Storage and Retrieval of XML Documents, WebDB’00</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pubAddress>Dallas, USA</pubAddress><raw>A. Schmidt, M. Kersten, M. Windhouwer, F. Waas: Efficient Relational Storage and Retrieval of XML Documents, WebDB’00, Dallas, USA, 2000</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28722"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>J Shanmugasundaram,K Tufte,G He,C Zhang,D DeWitt,J</authors><venue>Naughton: Relational Databases for Querying XML Documents: Limitations and Opportunities, VLDB’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Edinburgh, Scotland</pubAddress><raw>J. Shanmugasundaram, K. Tufte, G. He, C. Zhang, D. DeWitt, J. Naughton: Relational Databases for Querying XML Documents: Limitations and Opportunities, VLDB’99, Edinburgh, Scotland, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28723"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>Y Zhu,C Bornhövd,D Sautner,A P</authors><venue>Buchmann: Materializing Web Data for OLAP and DSS, WAIM’00</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pubAddress>Shanghai, China</pubAddress><raw>Y. Zhu, C. Bornhövd, D. Sautner, A. P. Buchmann: Materializing Web Data for OLAP and DSS, WAIM’00, Shanghai, China, 2000</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation><citation id="28724"><clusterid>8918543</clusterid><authors>Y Zhu</authors><title>A Framework for Warehousing the Web Contents, ICSC’99, Hong Kong</title><venue>Proceedings of the Third Int’l Workshop Advanced Issues of E-Commerce and Web-Based Information Systems (WECWIS’01) 1530-1354/01 $10.00 © 2001 IEEE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Y. Zhu: A Framework for Warehousing the Web Contents, ICSC’99, Hong Kong, 1999 Proceedings of the Third Int’l Workshop Advanced Issues of E-Commerce and Web-Based Information Systems (WECWIS’01) 1530-1354/01 $10.00 © 2001 IEEE</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1528</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.cs.kun.nl/is/Library/./Data/2001/Zhu/Data/2001-Zhu-Data.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>