<document id="10.1.1.1.1605"><clusterid>1987</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">On Global Warming (Softening Global Constraints</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">We describe soft versions of the global cardinality constraint  and the regular constraint, with e#cient filtering algorithms maintaining  domain consistency. For both constraints, the softening is achieved by  augmenting the underlying graph. The softened constraints can be used  to extend the meta-constraint framework for over-constrained problems  proposed by Petit, Regin and Bessiere.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2004</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In Proc. of the 6th International Workshop on Preferences and Soft Constraints</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4314124"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Willem Jan Van Hoeve</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">1 CWI, P.O. Box 94079, 1090 GB Amsterdam, The Netherlands</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">W.J.van.Hoeve@cwi.nl</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4314125"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Gilles Pesant</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">1 CWI, P.O. Box 94079, 1090 GB Amsterdam, The Netherlands</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">pesant@crt.umontreal.ca</email><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4314126"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Louis-martin Rousseau</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">1 CWI, P.O. Box 94079, 1090 GB Amsterdam, The Netherlands</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">louism@crt.umontreal.ca</email><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30078"><clusterid>1988</clusterid><authors>R K Ahuja,T L Magnanti,J B Orlin</authors><title>Network Flows</title><year>1993</year><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><raw>R.K. Ahuja, T.L. Magnanti, and J.B. Orlin. Network Flows. Prentice Hall, 1993.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30079"><clusterid>1989</clusterid><authors>K R Apt</authors><title>Principles of Constraint Programming</title><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>K.R. Apt. Principles of Constraint Programming. Cambridge University Press,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30080"><clusterid>1990</clusterid><authors>N Beldiceanu,M Carlsson,T Petit</authors><title>Deriving Filtering Algorithms from Constraint Checkers</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2004), volume 3258 of LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>N. Beldiceanu, M. Carlsson, and T. Petit. Deriving Filtering Algorithms from Constraint Checkers. In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2004), volume 3258 of LNCS. Springer, 2004.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30081"><clusterid>1991</clusterid><authors>N Beldiceanu,T Petit</authors><title>Cost Evaluation of Soft Global Constraints</title><venue>In CPAIOR 2004: Proceedings of the First International Conference, volume 3011 of LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><pages>80--95</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>N. Beldiceanu and T. Petit. Cost Evaluation of Soft Global Constraints. In CPAIOR 2004: Proceedings of the First International Conference, volume 3011 of LNCS, pages 80–95. Springer, 2004.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30082"><clusterid>1992</clusterid><authors>S Bistarelli</authors><title>Semirings for Soft Constraint Solving and Programming, volume 2962 of LNCS</title><year>2004</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>S. Bistarelli. Semirings for Soft Constraint Solving and Programming, volume 2962 of LNCS. Springer, 2004.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30083"><clusterid>1993</clusterid><authors>D Dubois,H Fargier,H Prade</authors><title>The calculus of fuzzy restrictions as a basis for flexible constraint satisfaction</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Second IEEE International Conference on Fuzzy Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>1131--1136</pages><volume>2</volume><raw>D. Dubois, H. Fargier, and H. Prade. The calculus of fuzzy restrictions as a basis for flexible constraint satisfaction. In Proceedings of the Second IEEE International Conference on Fuzzy Systems, volume 2, pages 1131–1136, 1993.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30084"><clusterid>1994</clusterid><authors>H Fargier,J Lang,T Schiex</authors><title>Selecting preferred solutions in fuzzy constraint satisfaction problems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the first European Congress on Fuzzy and Intelligent Technologies</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><raw>H. Fargier, J. Lang, and T. Schiex. Selecting preferred solutions in fuzzy constraint satisfaction problems. In Proceedings of the first European Congress on Fuzzy and Intelligent Technologies, 1993.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30085"><clusterid>1995</clusterid><authors>R Freuder,M Wallace</authors><title>Partial Constraint Satisfaction</title><venue>Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1992</year><volume>58</volume><raw>R. Freuder and M. Wallace. Partial Constraint Satisfaction. Artificial Intelligence, 58:21–70, 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30086"><clusterid>1996</clusterid><authors>W J van Hoeve</authors><title>A Hyper-Arc Consistency Algorithm for the Soft Alldifferent Constraint</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2004), volume 3258 of LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>W.J. van Hoeve. A Hyper-Arc Consistency Algorithm for the Soft Alldifferent Constraint. In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2004), volume 3258 of LNCS. Springer,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30087"><clusterid>1997</clusterid><authors>J Larrosa</authors><title>Node and Arc Consistency in Weighted CSP</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Eighteenth National Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>48--53</pages><publisher>AAAI Press/The MIT Press</publisher><raw>J. Larrosa. Node and Arc Consistency in Weighted CSP. In Proceedings of the Eighteenth National Conference on Artificial Intelligence, pages 48–53. AAAI Press/The MIT Press, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30088"><clusterid>1998</clusterid><authors>In</authors><title>the quest of the best form of local consistency for Weighted CSP</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>239--244</pages><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><raw>J. Larrosa and T. Schiex. In the quest of the best form of local consistency for Weighted CSP. In Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, pages 239–244. Morgan Kaufmann, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30089"><clusterid>1999</clusterid><authors>G Pesant</authors><title>A Regular Language Membership Constraint for Finite Sequences of Variables</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2004), volume 3258 of LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>G. Pesant. A Regular Language Membership Constraint for Finite Sequences of Variables. In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2004), volume 3258 of LNCS. Springer,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30090"><clusterid>2000</clusterid><authors>T Petit,J-C Régin,C Bessière</authors><title>Meta constraints on violations for over constrained problems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 12th IEEE International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence (ICTAI</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>358--365</pages><raw>T. Petit, J.-C. Régin, and C. Bessière. Meta constraints on violations for over constrained problems. In Proceedings of the 12th IEEE International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence (ICTAI), pages 358–365, 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30091"><clusterid>2001</clusterid><authors>T Petit,J-C Régin,C Bessière</authors><title>Specific Filtering Algorithms for Over Constrained Problems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2001), volume 2239 of LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>451--463</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>T. Petit, J.-C. Régin, and C. Bessière. Specific Filtering Algorithms for Over Constrained Problems. In Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP 2001), volume 2239 of LNCS, pages 451–463. Springer, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30092"><clusterid>2002</clusterid><authors>J-C Régin</authors><title>Generalized Arc Consistency for Global Cardinality Constraint</title><venue>In Proceedings of AAAI/IAAI</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>209--215</pages><publisher>AAAI Press/The MIT Press</publisher><volume>1</volume><raw>J.-C. Régin. Generalized Arc Consistency for Global Cardinality Constraint. In Proceedings of AAAI/IAAI, volume 1, pages 209–215. AAAI Press/The MIT Press,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30093"><clusterid>2002</clusterid><authors>J-C Régin</authors><title>Arc Consistency for Global Cardinality Constraints with Costs</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP’99), volume 1713 of LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>390--404</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>J.-C. Régin. Arc Consistency for Global Cardinality Constraints with Costs. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Principles and Practice of Constraint Programming (CP’99), volume 1713 of LNCS, pages 390–404. Springer,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30094"><clusterid>2002</clusterid><authors>J-C Régin</authors><title>Cost-Based Arc Consistency for Global Cardinality Constraints</title><venue>Constraints</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--2</pages><volume>7</volume><raw>J.-C. Régin. Cost-Based Arc Consistency for Global Cardinality Constraints. Constraints, 7:387–405, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30095"><clusterid>2003</clusterid><authors>T Schiex</authors><title>Possibilistic Constraint Satisfaction Problems or “How to handle soft constraints</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 8th Annual Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pages>268--275</pages><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><raw>T. Schiex. Possibilistic Constraint Satisfaction Problems or “How to handle soft constraints ?”. In Proceedings of the 8th Annual Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence, pages 268–275. Morgan Kaufmann, 1992.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30096"><clusterid>2004</clusterid><authors>T Schiex,H Fargier,G Verfaillie</authors><title>Valued Constraint Satisfaction Problems: Hard and Easy Problems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>631--639</pages><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><raw>T. Schiex, H. Fargier, and G. Verfaillie. Valued Constraint Satisfaction Problems: Hard and Easy Problems. In Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, pages 631–639. Morgan Kaufmann, 1995.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation><citation id="30097"><clusterid>2005</clusterid><authors>A Schrijver</authors><title>Combinatorial Optimization - Polyhedra and Efficiency</title><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>A. Schrijver. Combinatorial Optimization - Polyhedra and Efficiency. Springer,</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1605</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://homepages.cwi.nl/~wjvh/papers/softglob.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>