<document id="10.1.1.1.1595"><clusterid>1955</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Tiles and Patterns Penelope — A Pattern Tile Editor</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A pattern tile is a small rectangular bitmap that is used to produce a pattern when drawing lines and filling shapes. Conceptually, the tile is aligned at the upper-left corner of the window and replicated as necessary to fill the window. When a line is drawn or a shape is filled, the pattern produced by the tiling “shows through ” in the filled area. For example the 8-by-8 tile produces the pattern In order for lines and filled shapes to be patterened, the fill style must be textured or masked. In the case of textured, pixels that correspond to bits set in the tile are drawn in the foreground color and all other pixels are drawn in the background color. In the case of stippled, only foreground pixels are drawn, leaving the background pixels as they were. The function Pattern(s) sets the tile to be used, where s is a string that encodes the bits of the pattern. See Reference 1 for the ways that tiles can be encoded as strings. For example, in a window with a white background and a black foreground,</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1279">The Penelope Window</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4436"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Ralph E. Griswold</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">; Department of Computer Science, The University of Arizona; WAttrib(&amp;quot;fillstyle=textured&amp;quot;); Pattern(mesh)</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">; FilllRectangle(0, 0, 100, 50)</address><order src="null">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29957"><clusterid>1956</clusterid><authors>Clinton L Jeffery,Gregg M Townsend,Ralph E Griswold</authors><title>Graphics Facilities for the Icon Programming Language; Version 9.0</title><year>1994</year><raw>Clinton L. Jeffery, Gregg M. Townsend, and Ralph E. Griswold, Graphics Facilities for the Icon Programming Language; Version 9.0, Department of Computer Science, The University of Arizona, 1994.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1595</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://www.cs.arizona.edu/icon/docs/../ftp/doc/ipd234.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>16e9d77490e1c695eea6fb4c18a70aa95df022d3</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>