<document id="10.1.1.1.1510"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Genetic Improvisation Model a framework for real-time performance environments</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper presents the current state in an ongoing development of the Genetic Improvisation Model (GIM): a framework for the design of real-time improvisational systems. The aesthetic rationale for the model is presented, followed by a discussion of its general principles. A discussion of the Emonic Environment, a networked system for audiovisual creation built on GIM’s principles, follows.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4182"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Paul Nemirovsky</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">20 Ames St., Cambridge, MA, USA 02139</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">pauln @media.mit.edu</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4183"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Richard Watson</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">20 Ames St., Cambridge, MA, USA 02139</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">watsonr@media.mit.edu</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28381"><authors>G Lewis</authors><title>Interacting with latter-day musical automata</title><venue>Contemporary Music Review</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><raw>Lewis, G., Interacting with latter-day musical automata. Contemporary Music Review,</raw><contexts><context> human performers for thousands of years; yet, until recently, these methods have remained untouched by most engineers and technical artists to whom they would seem relevant. Projects such as Voyager [1], Galapagos [2], ChaOs [3], Swarm Music [4], and others, while not always being explicitly improvisational, explore media-informational spaces in nearly-improvisational ways, allowing the user to modi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28382"><authors>K Sims,Galapagos</authors><title>Information online at: http://www.genarts.com/galapagos</title><year>1993</year><raw>Sims, K., Galapagos. 1993. Information online at: http://www.genarts.com/galapagos/</raw><contexts><context>rs for thousands of years; yet, until recently, these methods have remained untouched by most engineers and technical artists to whom they would seem relevant. Projects such as Voyager [1], Galapagos [2], ChaOs [3], Swarm Music [4], and others, while not always being explicitly improvisational, explore media-informational spaces in nearly-improvisational ways, allowing the user to modify the explorat</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28383"><authors>E R Miranda</authors><title>On the Origins and Evolution of Music in Virtual Worlds</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann ; Academic Press</publisher><pubAddress>San Francisco, CA. San Diego, CA</pubAddress><tech>2002</tech><raw>Miranda, E. R., On the Origins and Evolution of Music in Virtual Worlds, in Bentley, P. and D. Corne, Creative evolutionary systems. 2002, San Francisco, CA. San Diego, CA: Morgan Kaufmann ; Academic Press.</raw><contexts><context>sands of years; yet, until recently, these methods have remained untouched by most engineers and technical artists to whom they would seem relevant. Projects such as Voyager [1], Galapagos [2], ChaOs [3], Swarm Music [4], and others, while not always being explicitly improvisational, explore media-informational spaces in nearly-improvisational ways, allowing the user to modify the exploratory process</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28384"><authors>T M Blackwell,P J Bentley</authors><venue>Improvised Music with Swarms”, 2002 Congress on Evolutionary Computation, CEC-2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Blackwell T.M. and Bentley P.J. (2002) “Improvised Music with Swarms”, 2002 Congress on Evolutionary Computation, CEC-2002</raw><contexts><context>et, until recently, these methods have remained untouched by most engineers and technical artists to whom they would seem relevant. Projects such as Voyager [1], Galapagos [2], ChaOs [3], Swarm Music [4], and others, while not always being explicitly improvisational, explore media-informational spaces in nearly-improvisational ways, allowing the user to modify the exploratory process in the course of</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28385"><authors>J R Koza</authors><title>Genetic programming : on the programming of computers by means of natural selection. Complex adaptive systems</title><year>1992</year><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Koza, J.R., Genetic programming : on the programming of computers by means of natural selection. Complex adaptive systems. 1992, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.</raw><contexts><context>le principles such as tonality, melodic principles, proportion, etc) and (b) the predominant computer science paradigm which concerns itself with predefined operational rules or parameters (what Koza [5] calls the strive for simplicity, convergence, conciseness). In opposition to the school of thinking that studies channels of human perception and activity in isolation, we believe, drawing our inspir</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28386"><authors>F J Varela,E Thompson,E Rosch</authors><title>The embodied mind : cognitive science and human experience</title><year>1991</year><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Varela, F.J., E. Thompson, and E. Rosch, The embodied mind : cognitive science and human experience. 1991, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.</raw><contexts><context>for simplicity, convergence, conciseness). In opposition to the school of thinking that studies channels of human perception and activity in isolation, we believe, drawing our inspiration from Varela [6], Claxton [7], and others that any creative activity is ultimately a social act, tied to the world around and within the improviser. As an implication of that view, creative processes, whatever their </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28387"><authors>G Claxton</authors><title>Cognitive psychology : new directions. International library of psychology</title><year>1980</year><publisher>Routledge &amp; Kegan Paul</publisher><pubAddress>London ; Boston</pubAddress><raw>Claxton, G., Cognitive psychology : new directions. International library of psychology. 1980, London ; Boston: Routledge &amp; Kegan Paul.</raw><contexts><context>y, convergence, conciseness). In opposition to the school of thinking that studies channels of human perception and activity in isolation, we believe, drawing our inspiration from Varela [6], Claxton [7], and others that any creative activity is ultimately a social act, tied to the world around and within the improviser. As an implication of that view, creative processes, whatever their output medium</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28388"><authors>G F Marcus</authors><title>The algebraic mind : integrating connectionism and cognitive science. Learning, development, and conceptual change. 2001</title><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Marcus, G.F., The algebraic mind : integrating connectionism and cognitive science. Learning, development, and conceptual change. 2001, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.</raw><contexts><context> questions: (1) what kind of representation does the improviser employ and (2) how do all the disparate ‘things’ become unified into one improvisational experience? It has been argued (e.g. in Marcus [8]) that the representations are never distinctly high- or low- level, but rather always a combination. We have adopted this conception as it makes sense and suits our model well. We have named the spec</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28389"><authors>B M Stafford</authors><title>Visual analogy : consciousness as the art of connecting</title><year>1999</year><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Stafford, B.M., Visual analogy : consciousness as the art of connecting. 1999, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.</raw><contexts><context> combination. We have adopted this conception as it makes sense and suits our model well. We have named the special combination of levels of representation a mediated layer, borrowing from Stafford’s [9] concept of a mediating image. 6 Through forming connections in the mediated layer, new meaning is then made. Creative thoughts rarely come solely in a form of “play a C4, then an E3 flat, then double</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28390"><title>Traveling Salesman Problem. Information online at http://www.math.princeton.edu/tsp</title><raw>Traveling Salesman Problem. Information online at http://www.math.princeton.edu/tsp/</raw><contexts><context>at a true model of improvisation is incompatible with an implementation that can use it? GIM vs. TSP Those familiar with genetic algorithms know of the traveling salesman (optimization) problem (TSP) [10] – an example that illustrates how GAs may overcome painful levels of combinatorial complexity. Though a GIM parameter space is much larger than that of the TSP, our goal criteria are not as exclusive</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28391"><authors>M Mauss</authors><title>The gift; forms and functions of exchange in archaic societies</title><year>1954</year><pages>p.</pages><pubAddress>Glencoe, Ill</pubAddress><volume>130</volume><raw>Mauss, M., The gift; forms and functions of exchange in archaic societies. 1954, Glencoe, Ill.,: Free press. xiv, 130 p.</raw><contexts><context> meaning happens through the exchange of elements. In other words, a sound or an image acquires its meaning only through the details of its history of use – where and how it has been employed before. [11] These details determine how it or similar elements are perceived the next time they are encountered. 10 th : Audience as participant. From the passive audience of the linear storytelling to the nearl</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28392"><authors>M Nyman</authors><title>Experimental music : Cage and beyond</title><year>1999</year><editors>2nd ed</editors><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge ; New York: Cambridge</pubAddress><raw>Nyman, M., Experimental music : Cage and beyond. 2nd ed. 1999, Cambridge ; New York: Cambridge University Press.</raw><contexts><context>ended mistakes and successes. 9 This of course is not a binary dichotomy; discussion of near-improvisational compositional movements however is beyond the scope of this paper; see for example Nyman’s [12] excellent account of the experimental music movement. 10 This memories-perception inside-outside Descartian dichotomy is questionable to say the least; we use it for the reasons of space, not to endo</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28393"><authors>G Deleuze,F l Guattari</authors><title>A thousand plateaus : capitalism and schizophrenia</title><year>1987</year><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>Minneapolis</pubAddress><raw>Deleuze, G. and F.l. Guattari, A thousand plateaus : capitalism and schizophrenia. 1987, Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.</raw><contexts><context>mental music movement. 10 This memories-perception inside-outside Descartian dichotomy is questionable to say the least; we use it for the reasons of space, not to endorse it. The idea of the rhizome [13] seems to be much better fit for the description of improvisational processes.s7 th : Issues of control/responsibility. In an improvisational performance, no fixed contract specifying responsibilities</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28394"><authors>M L Minsky</authors><title>The society of mind. 1st</title><year>1988</year><editors>Touchstone ed. Touchstone book</editors><publisher>Simon &amp; Schuster</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Minsky, M.L., The society of mind. 1st Touchstone ed. Touchstone book. 1988, New York: Simon &amp; Schuster.</raw></citation><citation id="28395"><authors>Bentley</authors><title>Creative evolutionary systems</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann ; Academic Press</publisher><pubAddress>San Francisco, CA. San Diego, CA</pubAddress><tech>2002</tech><raw>Bentley et al, in Bentley, P. and D. Corne, Creative evolutionary systems. 2002, San Francisco, CA. San Diego, CA: Morgan Kaufmann ; Academic Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28396"><authors>J A Sloboda</authors><title>Generative processes in music : the psychology of performance, improvisation, and composition</title><publisher>Press</publisher><pubAddress>2000, Oxford [England] New York: Clarendon</pubAddress><raw>Sloboda, J.A., Generative processes in music : the psychology of performance, improvisation, and composition. 2000, Oxford [England] New York: Clarendon Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28397"><authors>M A Boden</authors><title>The philosophy of artificial life. Oxford readings in philosophy</title><year>1996</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Oxford ; New York: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>Boden, M.A., The philosophy of artificial life. Oxford readings in philosophy. 1996, Oxford ; New York: Oxford University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28398"><authors>R Dawkins</authors><title>The selfish</title><year>1989</year><editors>gene. New ed</editors><publisher>Univ. Press</publisher><pubAddress>Oxford; New York: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>Dawkins, R., The selfish gene. New ed. 1989, Oxford; New York: Oxford Univ. Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28399"><authors>E R Miranda</authors><title>Readings in music and artificial intelligence. Contemporary music studies</title><publisher>Harwood Academic</publisher><pubAddress>Amsterdam</pubAddress><volume>20</volume><raw>Miranda, E.R., Readings in music and artificial intelligence. Contemporary music studies, v. 20. 2000, Amsterdam: Harwood Academic.</raw></citation><citation id="28400"><authors>E R Miranda</authors><title>Composing music with computers. Music technology series. 2001</title><publisher>Focal Press</publisher><pubAddress>Oxford ; Boston</pubAddress><raw>Miranda, E.R., Composing music with computers. Music technology series. 2001, Oxford ; Boston: Focal Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28401"><authors>J Moroni</authors><title>et al, Vox Populi: Evolutionary Computation for Music Evolution</title><raw>Moroni, J. et al, Vox Populi: Evolutionary Computation for Music Evolution.</raw></citation><citation id="28402"><authors>R Rowe</authors><title>Interactive music systems : machine listening and composing</title><year>1993</year><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Rowe, R., Interactive music systems : machine listening and composing. 1993, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28403"><authors>I F U M Lotman</authors><title>Universe of the mind : a semiotic theory of culture</title><year>1990</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Bloomington: Indiana</pubAddress><raw>Lotman, I.F.U.M., Universe of the mind : a semiotic theory of culture. 1990, Bloomington: Indiana University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28404"><authors>B Degazio</authors><title>Evolution of Musical Organisms, Leonardo Music Journal</title><year>1997</year><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><raw>Degazio, B., Evolution of Musical Organisms, Leonardo Music Journal, MIT Press, 1997</raw></citation><citation id="28405"><authors>H Hendriks-Jansen</authors><title>Catching ourselves in the act : situated activity, interactive emergence, evolution, and human thought. Complex adaptive systems</title><year>1996</year><pages>36--7</pages><publisher>MIT Press. xii</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Hendriks-Jansen, H., Catching ourselves in the act : situated activity, interactive emergence, evolution, and human thought. Complex adaptive systems. 1996, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press. xii, 367.</raw></citation><citation id="28406"><authors>P Todd,G M Werner</authors><title>Frankensteinian methods for evolutionary music composition in</title><year>1999</year><pages>38--5</pages><publisher>MIT Press. xv</publisher><pubAddress>Cambridge, Mass</pubAddress><raw>Todd, P.; Werner, G.M., Frankensteinian methods for evolutionary music composition in Griffith, N. and P.M. Todd, Musical networks : parallel distributed perception and performance. 1999, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press. xv, 385.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.media.mit.edu/~pauln/research/emonic/docs/evomusart2003.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>896d47906f9ebbd3aac2fb37d5b4da23f4b169df</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>