<document id="10.1.1.1.1566"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D.J. Medeiros, E.F. Watson, J.S. Carson and M.S. Manivannan, eds. ABSTRACT DISCRETE EVENT SIMULATION EXPERIMENTS AND GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS IN CONGESTION MANAGEMENT PLANNING</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A regional transportation system and the movement of large traffic volumes through it, are characteristic of stochastic systems. The standard traffic management or transportation planning approach uses a slice in time view of the system. Static, mean values of system variables are used for the basis of incident-caused, congestion management decisions. By reason of the highly variable nature of transportation systems, discrete event simulation is used in the planning process. The simulation model is highly dependent on the spatial accuracy of real world coordinates of nodes and the lengths of the roadway network links. Link travel times, queue spill back and turn lane queue size are directly related to the magnitude of incident-caused congestion, and the roadway system’s ability to recover from it. The incorporation of accurate Geographic Information System (GIS) data with a powerful transportation simulation software package and properly designed data collection and analysis techniques are invaluable in support of transportation incident management decisions. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4360"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Roy Brooks Wiley</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4361"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">White Dove Court</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Pueblo, CO 81001-1871, U.S.A.</address><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29493"><authors>CDOT</authors><title>Sites 5320000 and 10240000: monthly traffic volume report for</title><year>1996</year><pages>03--01</pages><raw>CDOT. 1996, 1997. Sites 5320000 and 10240000: monthly traffic volume report for 03/01/96-05/31/96, 10/01/9710/31/97.</raw><contexts><context>ea, 29 th St. in the south and the parallel arterial, Elizabeth St. to the west. Special characteristics of the area include the roadway sections with the highest average annual daily traffic (AADT) (CDOT, 1996) and the most complex, six-way intersection in the city. State Highway 47 0.6 0 0.6 1.2 Miles Figure 1: Pueblo IMP Study Sub-Area 1088 29th W Roadway Network N S EsDiscrete Event Simulation Experimen</context><context>a Traffic counts for the interstate are conducted continually by the Colorado Department of Transportation. These countssare compiled on an hourly basis, 24 hours per day. Data for 1996 is available (CDOT, 1996). The City of Pueblo collects turn-movement counts approximately twice yearly on major intersections (Centa, 1996). For the study area, the most recent sampling is during September, 1997 through Dece</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29494"><authors>Dan Centa</authors><title>Traffic Engineer, City of Pueblo, Personal communication</title><year>1996</year><raw>Centa, Dan. 1996. Traffic Engineer, City of Pueblo, Personal communication.</raw><contexts><context> countssare compiled on an hourly basis, 24 hours per day. Data for 1996 is available (CDOT, 1996). The City of Pueblo collects turn-movement counts approximately twice yearly on major intersections (Centa, 1996). For the study area, the most recent sampling is during September, 1997 through December, 1997, (Pueblo Department of Transportation, 1997a, 1997b). The counter’s collection periods are only active </context><context>etailed monitoring and analysis of alternate routes and the urban network. The impacts of the rerouted traffic from the interstate on the urban network are unknown but are expected to be significant (Centa, 1996). Simulated queues spill-back and impact upstream links in under 5 minutes. This congestion blocks two upstream alternate route accesses. Furthermore, emergency managers estimate that it takes a mini</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29495"><authors>Wiley,Keyser Cragg,C A,M J Demetsky</authors><title>Final report: simulation analysis of route diversion strategies for freeway incident management</title><venue>VTRC 95-R11, Traffic Research Advisory Committee, FHWA, USDOT</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Wiley and Keyser Cragg, C. A., and M. J. Demetsky. 1995 Final report: simulation analysis of route diversion strategies for freeway incident management, VTRC 95-R11, Traffic Research Advisory Committee, FHWA, USDOT.</raw></citation><citation id="29496"><authors>MK Centennial</authors><title>Final report: I-25 corridor incident management – Pueblo area</title><year>1996</year><raw>MK Centennial. 1996. Final report: I-25 corridor incident management – Pueblo area.</raw><contexts><context>t is now possible to answer questions on the importance of accurate spatial data in transportation modeling. This effort supplements the Pueblo Area: I-25 Corridor, Incident Management Plan (IMP) (MK Centennial, 1996). Particular attention is paid to queuing and spill-back from incident-caused congestion and the impact on access to alternate routes. The incident severity-level criteria are improved by including c</context><context>d impact upstream links in under 5 minutes. This congestion blocks two upstream alternate route accesses. Furthermore, emergency managers estimate that it takes a minimum of 14 minutes to respond (MK Centennial, 1996). By the time responders are on the scene, their primary resources for rerouting traffic, the two closest alternate routes, are already blocked. Simulation must be conducted with more comprehensive d</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29497"><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation (CDOT, Barton-Ashman Assoc., Inc</title><year>1994</year><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation (CDOT, Barton-Ashman Assoc., Inc.). 1994. Pueblo County regional transportation plan, April.</raw></citation><citation id="29498"><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation. 1997 Intersection Traffic Volume and Turn Movement Counts</title><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1997 Intersection Traffic Volume and Turn Movement Counts, September – December.</raw></citation><citation id="29499"><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation</title><venue>I-25 SB</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>block.</pages><volume>2900</volume><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1997. NU-METRICS traffic analyzer study, I-25 SB, 2900 block.</raw></citation><citation id="29500"><authors>of Transportation</authors><title>Pueblo urban area – transportation plan supplement</title><year>1995</year><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1995. Pueblo urban area – transportation plan supplement.</raw><contexts><context>vening (PM) rush-hours (approximately 8:00am-9:00am, 12:00n1:00pm, and 5:00pm-6:00pm). The time-periods are not consistent between daily samplings. Limited O-D data is available (Pueblo Department of Transportation, 1995). For all primary origin points in the study sub-area, total demand load is derived from the existing count data during the calibration process. Signal timing plans for the five signal groups are sup</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29501"><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation</title><year>1997</year><pages>204--206</pages><volume>181</volume><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1997. W4IKS signal timing plan tables, 181, 183, 204-206.</raw></citation><citation id="29502"><authors>F D Shepard</authors><venue>Incident Management Program in Virginia, Virginia Transportation Research Council</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1988</year><raw>Shepard, F. D. 1988. Incident Management Program in Virginia, Virginia Transportation Research Council.</raw><contexts><context>ortation incident management decisions. 1 INTRODUCTION Numerous traffic studies exist for large metropolitan regions that utilize simulation and include congestion analysis (Craig and Demetsky, 1995, Shepard, 1988 Southworth, 1995). These are the foundation for traffic incident and congestion management planning efforts for those areas. While such an incident management plan also exists for the Interstate 25 h</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29503"><authors>F Southworth</authors><title>A technical review of urban land use – transportation models as tools for evaluating vehicle travel reduction strategies</title><year>1995</year><raw>Southworth, F. 1995. A technical review of urban land use – transportation models as tools for evaluating vehicle travel reduction strategies, Oak Ridge National Laboratory for USDOE.</raw><contexts><context>ent management decisions. 1 INTRODUCTION Numerous traffic studies exist for large metropolitan regions that utilize simulation and include congestion analysis (Craig and Demetsky, 1995, Shepard, 1988 Southworth, 1995). These are the foundation for traffic incident and congestion management planning efforts for those areas. While such an incident management plan also exists for the Interstate 25 highway corridor t</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29504"><authors>M Van Aerde</authors><title>Integration Release 2: User’s Guide – Volumes I</title><venue>County of Pueblo, Colorado, GIS Program Manager, TIGER</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pubAddress>II, III, MVA. Kingston, ON</pubAddress><raw>Van Aerde, M. 1995. Integration Release 2: User’s Guide – Volumes I, II, III, MVA. Kingston, ON, 1995 Wiley, R. B. 1996. County of Pueblo, Colorado, GIS Program Manager, TIGER data projection and adjustment to gps controlled planimetric data.</raw></citation><citation id="29505"><authors>R B Wiley</authors><title>Discrete event simulation and geographic information systems in verification/validation of transportation system incident management planning</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Colorado, Pueblo, Colorado</pubAddress><tech>Masters thesis</tech><raw>Wiley, R. B. 1998. Discrete event simulation and geographic information systems in verification/validation of transportation system incident management planning, Masters thesis, Applied Science and Engineering Technology Department, University of Southern Colorado, Pueblo, Colorado.</raw><contexts><context>5 highway corridor through Pueblo, Colorado, the supporting studies do not. The accuracy of a roadway network’s spatial component is of critical importance to simulation-based transportation studies (Wiley, 1998). When modeling intersections (nodes) and road sections (links), vehicle travel times and potential queue sizes are directly dependent on accurate node locations and link lengths. A typical data sour</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29506"><authors>K E Wunderlich</authors><venue>Mitretek Systems, Sr. ITS Research Engineer, Personal communication</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><raw>Wunderlich, K. E., Ph.D. 1996. Mitretek Systems, Sr. ITS Research Engineer, Personal communication.</raw><contexts><context>. The realms of application are typically differentiated with microscopic models serving signalized roadway links and macroscopic models used in freeway or transit corridor modeling (Van Aerde, 1995, Wunderlich, 1996). The package is similar to general discrete simulation software in that entities or vehicles are generated randomly and routes are dynamically assigned. The generated entity inter-arrival rate is li</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29507"><authors>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES ROY B WILEY</authors><title>is a Senior Industrial and Systems Engineer with the Advanced Technology Division of RMC, Inc. of Pueblo, CO. He specializes in operations research and systems analysis with an emphasis on telecommunications system and transportation system simulations. Previously, he was Program Manager for the Geographic</title><venue>Information System Program for the County of Pueblo, Colorado. He received a B.S. in Range and Forest Management from Colorado State University in 1976, and an M.S. in Industrial and Systems Engineering from the University of Southern Colorado in</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES ROY B. WILEY is a Senior Industrial and Systems Engineer with the Advanced Technology Division of RMC, Inc. of Pueblo, CO. He specializes in operations research and systems analysis with an emphasis on telecommunications system and transportation system simulations. Previously, he was Program Manager for the Geographic Information System Program for the County of Pueblo, Colorado. He received a B.S. in Range and Forest Management from Colorado State University in 1976, and an M.S. in Industrial and Systems Engineering from the University of Southern Colorado in 1998.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc98papers/148.PDF</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>PDF</fileType><sha1>004b306c83f07f074746ac271120ac3cf1ebc018</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>