<document id="10.1.1.1.1566"><clusterid>1424</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Discrete Event Simulation Experiments And Geographic Information Systems In Congestion Management Planning</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">A regional transportation system and the movement of large traffic volumes through it, are characteristic of stochastic systems. The standard traffic management or transportation planning approach uses a slice in time view of the system. Static, mean values of system variables are used for the basis of incident-caused, congestion management decisions. By reason of the highly variable nature of transportation systems, discrete event simulation is used in the planning process. The simulation model is highly dependent on the spatial accuracy of real world coordinates of nodes and the lengths of the roadway network links. Link travel times, queue spill back and turn lane queue size are directly related to the magnitude of incident-caused congestion, and the roadway system&apos;s ability to recover from it. The incorporation of accurate Geographic Information System (GIS) data with a powerful transportation simulation software package and properly designed data collection and analysis techniques are invaluable in support of transportation incident management decisions.</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1998</year><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="2362239"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Roy Brooks Wiley</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">RMC, Inc.</affil><order>1</order></author><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Thomas Keyser</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author><author id="2362240"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">White Dove Court</name><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Pueblo, CO 81001-1871, U.S.A.</address><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29493"><clusterid>1425</clusterid><authors>CDOT</authors><title>Sites 5320000 and 10240000: monthly traffic volume report for</title><year>1996</year><pages>03--01</pages><raw>CDOT. 1996, 1997. Sites 5320000 and 10240000: monthly traffic volume report for 03/01/96-05/31/96, 10/01/9710/31/97.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29494"><clusterid>1426</clusterid><authors>Dan Centa</authors><title>Traffic Engineer, City of Pueblo, Personal communication</title><year>1996</year><raw>Centa, Dan. 1996. Traffic Engineer, City of Pueblo, Personal communication.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29495"><clusterid>1427</clusterid><authors>Wiley,Keyser Cragg,C A,M J Demetsky</authors><title>Final report: simulation analysis of route diversion strategies for freeway incident management</title><venue>VTRC 95-R11, Traffic Research Advisory Committee, FHWA, USDOT</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Wiley and Keyser Cragg, C. A., and M. J. Demetsky. 1995 Final report: simulation analysis of route diversion strategies for freeway incident management, VTRC 95-R11, Traffic Research Advisory Committee, FHWA, USDOT.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29496"><clusterid>1428</clusterid><authors>MK Centennial</authors><title>Final report: I-25 corridor incident management – Pueblo area</title><year>1996</year><raw>MK Centennial. 1996. Final report: I-25 corridor incident management – Pueblo area.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29497"><clusterid>1429</clusterid><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation (CDOT, Barton-Ashman Assoc., Inc</title><year>1994</year><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation (CDOT, Barton-Ashman Assoc., Inc.). 1994. Pueblo County regional transportation plan, April.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29498"><clusterid>1430</clusterid><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation. 1997 Intersection Traffic Volume and Turn Movement Counts</title><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1997 Intersection Traffic Volume and Turn Movement Counts, September – December.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29499"><clusterid>1431</clusterid><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation</title><venue>I-25 SB</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>block.</pages><volume>2900</volume><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1997. NU-METRICS traffic analyzer study, I-25 SB, 2900 block.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29500"><clusterid>1432</clusterid><authors>of Transportation</authors><title>Pueblo urban area – transportation plan supplement</title><year>1995</year><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1995. Pueblo urban area – transportation plan supplement.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29501"><clusterid>1431</clusterid><authors>Pueblo Dept</authors><title>of Transportation</title><year>1997</year><pages>204--206</pages><volume>181</volume><raw>Pueblo Dept. of Transportation. 1997. W4IKS signal timing plan tables, 181, 183, 204-206.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29502"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>F D Shepard</authors><venue>Incident Management Program in Virginia, Virginia Transportation Research Council</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1988</year><raw>Shepard, F. D. 1988. Incident Management Program in Virginia, Virginia Transportation Research Council.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29503"><clusterid>1433</clusterid><authors>F Southworth</authors><title>A technical review of urban land use – transportation models as tools for evaluating vehicle travel reduction strategies</title><year>1995</year><raw>Southworth, F. 1995. A technical review of urban land use – transportation models as tools for evaluating vehicle travel reduction strategies, Oak Ridge National Laboratory for USDOE.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29504"><clusterid>1434</clusterid><authors>M Van Aerde</authors><title>Integration Release 2: User’s Guide – Volumes I</title><venue>County of Pueblo, Colorado, GIS Program Manager, TIGER</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pubAddress>II, III, MVA. Kingston, ON</pubAddress><raw>Van Aerde, M. 1995. Integration Release 2: User’s Guide – Volumes I, II, III, MVA. Kingston, ON, 1995 Wiley, R. B. 1996. County of Pueblo, Colorado, GIS Program Manager, TIGER data projection and adjustment to gps controlled planimetric data.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29505"><clusterid>1435</clusterid><authors>R B Wiley</authors><title>Discrete event simulation and geographic information systems in verification/validation of transportation system incident management planning</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Colorado, Pueblo, Colorado</pubAddress><tech>Masters thesis</tech><raw>Wiley, R. B. 1998. Discrete event simulation and geographic information systems in verification/validation of transportation system incident management planning, Masters thesis, Applied Science and Engineering Technology Department, University of Southern Colorado, Pueblo, Colorado.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29506"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>K E Wunderlich</authors><venue>Mitretek Systems, Sr. ITS Research Engineer, Personal communication</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><raw>Wunderlich, K. E., Ph.D. 1996. Mitretek Systems, Sr. ITS Research Engineer, Personal communication.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation><citation id="29507"><clusterid>1436</clusterid><authors>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES ROY B WILEY</authors><title>is a Senior Industrial and Systems Engineer with the Advanced Technology Division of RMC, Inc. of Pueblo, CO. He specializes in operations research and systems analysis with an emphasis on telecommunications system and transportation system simulations. P</title><venue>Information System Program for the County of Pueblo, Colorado. He received a B.S. in Range and Forest Management from Colorado State University in 1976, and an M.S. in Industrial and Systems Engineering from the University of Southern Colorado in</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES ROY B. WILEY is a Senior Industrial and Systems Engineer with the Advanced Technology Division of RMC, Inc. of Pueblo, CO. He specializes in operations research and systems analysis with an emphasis on telecommunications system and transportation system simulations. Previously, he was Program Manager for the Geographic Information System Program for the County of Pueblo, Colorado. He received a B.S. in Range and Forest Management from Colorado State University in 1976, and an M.S. in Industrial and Systems Engineering from the University of Southern Colorado in 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1566</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc98papers/148.PDF</url></urls></fileInfo></document>