<document id="10.1.1.1.1513"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Reducing the Computational Load of Energy Evaluations for Protein Folding</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Predicting the native conformation using computational protein models requires a large num-ber of energy evaluations even with simplified models such as hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) models. Clearly, energy evaluations constitute a significant portion of computational time. We hypothesize that given the structured nature of algorithms that search for candidate conforma-tions such as stochastic methods, energy evaluation computations can be cached and reused, thus saving computational time and effort. In this paper, we present a caching approach and apply it to 2D triangular HP lattice model. We provide theoretical analysis and prediction of the expected savings from caching as applied this model. We conduct experiments using a so-phisticated evolutionary algorithm that contains elements of local search, memetic algorithms, diversity replacement, etc. in order to verify our hypothesis and demonstrate a significant level 1 of savings in computational effort and time that caching can provide.</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1242">protein folding</keyword><keyword id="1243">triangular lattice</keyword><keyword id="1244">HP energy model</keyword><keyword id="1245">caching</keyword><keyword id="1246">reuse</keyword><keyword id="1247">evolutionary</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4191"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Eunice E. Santos</name><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">santos@cs.vt.edu</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4192"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Eugene Santos</name><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">eugene@cse.uconn.edu</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28426"><authors>R Agarwala,S Batzoglou,V Dancik,S Decatur,M Farach,S Hannenhali,S Muthukrishnan,S Skiena</authors><title>Local rules for protein folding on a triangular lattice and generalized hydrophobicity in the HP model</title><venue>Journal of Computational Biology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>4--2</pages><raw>R. Agarwala, S. Batzoglou, V. Dancik, S. Decatur, M. Farach, S. Hannenhali, S. Muthukrishnan, and S. Skiena. Local rules for protein folding on a triangular lattice and generalized hydrophobicity in the HP model. Journal of Computational Biology, 4(2):275-296, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>ain growth algorithm[4], fast protein folding approximating algorithms [7], and genetic algorithm(s) [12]. However, it has been noted that square or 90-degree angles have serious issues and drawbacks [1], including the particularly serious parity constraint, i.e. any pair of amino acids which are an odd-distance apart from each other can never lie on adjacent square lattice points. 4sDue to this, tri</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28427"><authors>B Berger,T Leighton</authors><title>Protein folding in the hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) model is NP</title><venue>Journal of Computational Biology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>27--40</pages><volume>5</volume><raw>B. Berger, T. Leighton. Protein folding in the hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) model is NPcomplete. Journal of Computational Biology, 5(1), 27-40, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>he simplified models suffer from computational intractability in the worst case. For example, optimizing the simple 2-D square lattice hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) [6] has been shown to be NPComplete [2]. In the past several years, numerous algorithms and techniques have been proposed and explored for quickly determining native conformations based on models such as the HP models. Methods such as gene</context><context> a 2D-lattice. The standard assumption has been that the lattice is square in structure. Under this assumption, it has been proven that protein folding on the two- dimensional HP model is NP-complete [2, 5]. Several methods have been presented to try to solve this problem, such as the chain growth algorithm[4], fast protein folding approximating algorithms [7], and genetic algorithm(s) [12]. However, it</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28428"><authors>B P Blackburne,J D Hirst</authors><title>Evolution of Functional model Proteins</title><venue>Journal of Chemical Physics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><pages>1934--1942</pages><volume>115</volume><raw>B.P. Blackburne and J.D. Hirst. Evolution of Functional model Proteins. Journal of Chemical Physics, 115(4), 1934-1942, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>ice validated the prediction. In this paper, we further explore the effectiveness of partial fitness evaluation caching. In particular, we consider triangular lattices (also called Honeybee lattices) [3] which are much harder protein conformation optimization problems even in the 2D case. The degrees of freedom (6 directions for 2D) impose more computational requirements given the larger conformation</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28429"><authors>E Bornberg-Bauer</authors><title>Simple folding model for hp lattice proteins</title><venue>In Proceedings of Bioinformatics German Conference on Bioinformatics GCB ’96</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>125--36</pages><raw>E. Bornberg-Bauer. Simple folding model for hp lattice proteins. In Proceedings of Bioinformatics German Conference on Bioinformatics GCB ’96, 125-36, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>on, it has been proven that protein folding on the two- dimensional HP model is NP-complete [2, 5]. Several methods have been presented to try to solve this problem, such as the chain growth algorithm[4], fast protein folding approximating algorithms [7], and genetic algorithm(s) [12]. However, it has been noted that square or 90-degree angles have serious issues and drawbacks [1], including the part</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28430"><authors>P Crescenzi,D Goldman,C Piccolboni,M Yannakanis</authors><title>On the complexity of protein folding</title><venue>Journal of Computational Biology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>5--3</pages><raw>P. Crescenzi, D. Goldman, C. Piccolboni, M. Yannakanis. On the complexity of protein folding. Journal of Computational Biology 5(3):423-465, 1998.</raw><contexts><context> a 2D-lattice. The standard assumption has been that the lattice is square in structure. Under this assumption, it has been proven that protein folding on the two- dimensional HP model is NP-complete [2, 5]. Several methods have been presented to try to solve this problem, such as the chain growth algorithm[4], fast protein folding approximating algorithms [7], and genetic algorithm(s) [12]. However, it</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28431"><authors>K A Dill,S Bomberg,K Yue,K M Fiebig,D P Yee,P D Thomas,H S Chan</authors><title>Principles of protein folding: A perspective from simple exact models. Protein Sci 4</title><year>1995</year><pages>561--602</pages><raw>K.A. Dill, S. Bomberg, K. Yue, K.M. Fiebig, D.P. Yee, P.D. Thomas, H.S. Chan. Principles of protein folding: A perspective from simple exact models. Protein Sci 4, 561-602. 1995.</raw><contexts><context>computational protein models, even the simplified models suffer from computational intractability in the worst case. For example, optimizing the simple 2-D square lattice hydrophobic-hydrophilic (HP) [6] has been shown to be NPComplete [2]. In the past several years, numerous algorithms and techniques have been proposed and explored for quickly determining native conformations based on models such as</context><context>help to solve a large number of pharmaceutical and biotechnological problems. Therefore, several models have been presented for the protein folding problem. One of these is the well-known 2D-HP model [6]. The algorithms we presented here are all based on 2D-HP model, that is: (1) all the type of amino acids are represented by a set A={H,P}, (2) protein instances are represented by a binary sequence, </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28432"><authors>W E Hart,S Istrail</authors><title>Fast protein folding in the hydrophobic-bydrophilic model within three-eighths of optimal</title><venue>In Proceedings of Twenty-seventh Annual ACM Symposium on Theory of Computing(STOC95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>157--68</pages><raw>Hart, W. E., and Istrail, S. Fast protein folding in the hydrophobic-bydrophilic model within three-eighths of optimal. In Proceedings of Twenty-seventh Annual ACM Symposium on Theory of Computing(STOC95), 157-68, 1995.</raw><contexts><context>two- dimensional HP model is NP-complete [2, 5]. Several methods have been presented to try to solve this problem, such as the chain growth algorithm[4], fast protein folding approximating algorithms [7], and genetic algorithm(s) [12]. However, it has been noted that square or 90-degree angles have serious issues and drawbacks [1], including the particularly serious parity constraint, i.e. any pair o</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28433"><authors>N Krasnogor,B Blackburnem,J D Hirst,E K Burke</authors><title>Multimeme Algorithms for Protein Structure Prediction</title><venue>in Proceedings of Parallel Problem Solving From Nature, 2002, Lecture</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>N. Krasnogor, B. Blackburnem, J.D. Hirst, E.K. Burke. Multimeme Algorithms for Protein Structure Prediction in Proceedings of Parallel Problem Solving From Nature, 2002, Lecture</raw><contexts><context>, numerous algorithms and techniques have been proposed and explored for quickly determining native conformations based on models such as the HP models. Methods such as genetic and memetic algorithms [8], tabu search [9], and ant colony optimization [11] use approximation and randomized search in an effort to find good solutions in a reasonable amount of time. The fundamental nature of such approache</context><context>cause of the extra difficulty, simple genetic algorithms (GA) and evolutionary approaches have a difficult time solving 2D triangular lattice HP problems. As researchers have empirically demonstrated [8], more sophisticated optimization techniques such as hybrid local/global search, multi- meme GAs, scatter/gather searching, etc. must be employed in a variety of ways to improve diversity of the searc</context><context>is to compute the computational effort saved through caching. We implemented both versions in C++ on a Pentium IV 2GHz machine with 1G RAM running Linux. The testbed proteins we employ are drawn from [8] for triangular 2D-HP and from [10] which have yet to be computed in triangular 2D-HP. Table 5.1 contains the HPs used in our experiments. We note again that our goal in this experiment is to determin</context><context> n/a -17 30 PHHHPHHHPPPHPHHPHHPPHPHHHHPHPPHHHHHPHP HHPPHHP 45 n/a -36 31 HPHHHPHHHPPHHPHPHHPHHHPHPHPHHPPHHHPPHP HPPPPHPPHPPHHPPHPPH 57 n/a -38 Table 5.1. HP Testbed Proteins. Protein ID 1-20 are from [8]. Protein ID21-31 are from [10]. 16sAbsolute Energy Improvement 1.80 1.60 1.40 1.20 1.00 0.80 0.60 0.40 0.20 0.00 1 4 7 10 13 16 19 Protein Id # 22 25 28 31 Fig. 5.2. Average absolute energy value imp</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://excalibur.brc.uconn.edu/Papers/Conference/bibe04-submit.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>aac3c03cb67d0956f5c0602ef5af96b0eb933264</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>