<document id="10.1.1.1.1562"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">PARTITION SAMPLING FOR ACTIVE VIDEO DATABASE ANNOTATION</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Annotating a video-database requires an intensive human effort that is time consuming and error prone. However this task is mandatory to bridge the gap between low-level video features and the semantic content. We propose a partition sampling active learning method to minimize human effort in labeling. Formally, active learning is a process where new unlabeled samples are iteratively selected and presented to teachers. The major problem is then to find the best selection function that maximizes the knowledge gain acquired from new samples. In contrast with existing active learning approaches, we focus on the selection of multiple samples. We propose to select samples such that their contribution to the knowledge gain is complementary and optimal. Hence, at each iteration we ensure to maximize the knowledge gain. Our method offers many advantages; among them the possibility to share the annotation effort among several teachers. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4351"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Fabrice Souvannavong</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2229, route des crêtes; 06904 Sophia-Antipolis- France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Fabrice.Souvannavong @eurecom.fr</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4352"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Bernard Merialdo</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2229, route des crêtes; 06904 Sophia-Antipolis- France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Bernard.Merialdo @eurecom.fr</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4353"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Benoît Huet</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2229, route des crêtes; 06904 Sophia-Antipolis- France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Benoit.Huet)@eurecom.fr</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29321"><title>Reference removed for double blind reviewing</title><raw>Reference removed for double blind reviewing.</raw><contexts><context> It is composed of 40,000 annotated shots from news sequences [6]. Shots are described by HS color histograms and Gabor’s energies of their key frame. We use Latent Semantic Analysis, as described in [1], to capture local information, remove noise and emphasize information occurrence in frames. We draw the same conclusions. However the benefit over the extended greedy-like sampling is not as importan</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29322"><authors>Tsuhan Chen Cha Zhang</authors><title>An active learning framework for content-based information retrieval</title><venue>In IEEE Transactions on Multimedia</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>260--268</pages><volume>4</volume><raw>Tsuhan Chen Cha Zhang. An active learning framework for content-based information retrieval. In IEEE Transactions on Multimedia, volume 4, pages 260–268, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>hers proposed selection methods, such as query by committee [5] or uncertainty sampling [4]. Applications of active learning techniques are now emerging in the field of multimedia databasesannotation [2, 9]. In the following section we propose a new uncertainty sampling strategy, called partition sampling, that allows to select multiple samples as opposed to classical approaches. 3. PROPOSED APPROACH 3.</context><context>tion that close elements are similar. Thus the knowledge of one sample should induce the knowledge of its neighbors. This is implicitly used in the greedy-like active learning and it is emphasized in [2], where they proposed to weight the selection function value of a sample with an estimation of its probability density function to increase learning speed. However most ambiguous points are likely to </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29323"><authors>Shih-Fu Chang,W Chen,H J Meng,H Sundaram,Di Zhong</authors><title>A fully automated content-based video search engine supporting spatiotemporal queries</title><venue>In IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>602--615</pages><volume>8</volume><raw>Shih-Fu Chang, W. Chen, H.J. Meng, H. Sundaram, and Di Zhong. A fully automated content-based video search engine supporting spatiotemporal queries. In IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, volume 8, pages 602– 615, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>ithout the expensive human intervention to archive and annotate contents. Many researchers are currently investigating methods to automatically analyze, organize, index and retrieve video information [3, 7]. This effort is further stressed by the emerging Mpeg-7 standard that provides a rich and common description tool of multimedia contents. It is also encouraged by Video-TREC which aims at developing </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29324"><authors>Micahel I Jordan David A Cohn</authors><title>Zoubin Ghahramani. Active learning with statistical models</title><venue>Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><volume>4</volume><raw>Micahel I. Jordan David A. Cohn, Zoubin Ghahramani. Active learning with statistical models. Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research, 4:129–145, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>be selected from a unlabeled set. This approach, called selective sampling, is the most common, and many researchers proposed selection methods, such as query by committee [5] or uncertainty sampling [4]. Applications of active learning techniques are now emerging in the field of multimedia databasesannotation [2, 9]. In the following section we propose a new uncertainty sampling strategy, called par</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29325"><authors>Yoav Freund,H Sebastian Seung,Eli Shamir,Naftali Tishby</authors><title>Selective sampling using the query by committee algorithm</title><venue>Machine Learning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><volume>28</volume><raw>Yoav Freund, H. Sebastian Seung, Eli Shamir, and Naftali Tishby. Selective sampling using the query by committee algorithm. Machine Learning, 28:133–168, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>isting digit. They can also be selected from a unlabeled set. This approach, called selective sampling, is the most common, and many researchers proposed selection methods, such as query by committee [5] or uncertainty sampling [4]. Applications of active learning techniques are now emerging in the field of multimedia databasesannotation [2, 9]. In the following section we propose a new uncertainty s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29326"><authors>Ching-Yung Lin,Belle L Tseng,John R Smith</authors><title>Video collaborative annotation forum: Establishing ground-truth labels on large multimedia datasets</title><venue>In Proceedings of the TRECVID 2003 Workshop</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>Ching-Yung Lin, Belle L. Tseng, and John R. Smith. Video collaborative annotation forum: Establishing ground-truth labels on large multimedia datasets. In Proceedings of the TRECVID 2003 Workshop, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>rounds to find optimal elements since we do expect teachers to have a rest between rounds. Figure (2) presents results on a real database. It is composed of 40,000 annotated shots from news sequences [6]. Shots are described by HS color histograms and Gabor’s energies of their key frame. We use Latent Semantic Analysis, as described in [1], to capture local information, remove noise and emphasize inf</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29327"><authors>M R Naphade,T Kristjansson,B Frey,T S Huang</authors><title>Probabilistic multimedia objects (multijects): a novel approach to video indexing and retrieval</title><venue>In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>536--540</pages><volume>3</volume><raw>M.R. Naphade, T. Kristjansson, B. Frey, and T.S. Huang. Probabilistic multimedia objects (multijects): a novel approach to video indexing and retrieval. In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing, volume 3, pages 536–540, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>ithout the expensive human intervention to archive and annotate contents. Many researchers are currently investigating methods to automatically analyze, organize, index and retrieve video information [3, 7]. This effort is further stressed by the emerging Mpeg-7 standard that provides a rich and common description tool of multimedia contents. It is also encouraged by Video-TREC which aims at developing </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29328"><authors>Kamal Nigam,Andrew K McCallum,Sebastian Thrun,Tom M Mitchell</authors><title>Text classification from labeled and unlabeled documents using EM</title><venue>Machine Learning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>13--4</pages><volume>39</volume><raw>Kamal Nigam, Andrew K. McCallum, Sebastian Thrun, and Tom M. Mitchell. Text classification from labeled and unlabeled documents using EM. Machine Learning, 39(2/3):103– 134, 2000.</raw><contexts><context>Two approaches were proposed to this problem, semi-supervised and active learning. On one hand, a semi-supervised learner combines a small set of labeled samples with a large set of unlabeled samples [8]. The latter set does not provide any direct information but their distribution can be used to boost the performance of the classifier. On the other hand, an active learner starts from a very small nu</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29329"><authors>Alexander Hauptmann Rong Yan,Jie Yang</authors><title>Automatically labeling video data using multi-class active learning</title><venue>In IEEE International Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Alexander Hauptmann Rong Yan, Jie Yang. Automatically labeling video data using multi-class active learning. In IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision. Error rate Error rate 0.06 0.05 0.04 0.03 0.02 0.01 0.06 0.05 0.04 0.03 0.02 0.01 (x1,000) Training size (a) unique selection at each round Random Greedy−Like Training size (b) pool selection at each round Random Extended G−L Partition Sampling</raw><contexts><context>hers proposed selection methods, such as query by committee [5] or uncertainty sampling [4]. Applications of active learning techniques are now emerging in the field of multimedia databasesannotation [2, 9]. In the following section we propose a new uncertainty sampling strategy, called partition sampling, that allows to select multiple samples as opposed to classical approaches. 3. PROPOSED APPROACH 3.</context><context>∑EY|X[C( fL(x),y)] − EY |X[C( fL +(x),y)] (4) P To learn the hypothesis f L +(.) of equation (2) for each possible query sample S is now the major problem to compute the estimated error reduction. In [9], the authors first assume that all losses for any x ∈ P\L have an equal influence. Hence, the sum over P is reduced over S. Then they can neglect C( f L +(x),y) over C( fL(x),y) since the new learner</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.eurecom.fr/~huet/papers/wiamis04.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>f4ac3cc22a7f7a5c80d35cd740968e5e50d74b12</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>