<document id="10.1.1.1.1583"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">ABSTRACT AGENT-BASED MODELING AND SIMULATION IN CONSTRUCTION</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Agent-based Modeling and Simulation (ABMS) is a relatively new development that has found extensive use in areas such as social sciences, economics, biology, ecology etc. Can ABMS be effectively used in finding answers to complex construction systems? The focus of this paper is to provide some answers to this question. Initial experimentation is conducted to understand the advantages of using ABMS either in isolation or in combination with traditional simulation methodologies. The paper provides a summary of this experimentation, conclusions and sets the agenda for future research in this area. 1 CONSTRUCTION SIMULATION Construction researchers and practitioners have used various techniques for studying complex construction systems. These techniques include the basic networking techniques like CPM and PERT, queuing models, productivity models like method productivity delay model (Adrian 1976), operations research tools like linear programming, game theory, simulation, and industrial planning techniques like line of balance method. The advent of simulation methods in construction, occurred in the form of introduction of simple networking concepts, as a modeling framework for studying construction operations. The earliest of these methods was the so-called &amp;quot;link node&amp;quot; model adapted by Teicholz (1963). After that Halpin (1973) developed the CYCLONE format at the University of Illinois. CYCLONE has become the basis for a number of construction simulation systems. CYCLONE simplified the</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4399"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">S. Chick</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4400"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">P. J. Sánchez</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4401"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. Ferrin</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4402"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. J. Morrice</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4403"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Anil Sawhney</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Temp, AZ 85287-0204, U.S.A.</address><order>5</order></author><author id="4404"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Howard Bashford</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Temp, AZ 85287-0204, U.S.A.</address><order>6</order></author><author id="4405"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Del E. Webb</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Temp, AZ 85287-0204, U.S.A.</address><order>7</order></author><author id="4406"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Ajith Rao Mulky</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">; Troy, NY 12180, U.S.A.</address><order>8</order></author><author id="4407"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Kenneth Walsh</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">5500 Campanile Drive; San Diego, CA 92182, U.S.A.</address><order>9</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29724"><authors>S M AbouRizk,J Y Ruwanpura,K C Er,S Fernando</authors><title>Special Purpose Simulation Template for Utility Tunnel</title><venue>Construction”, Proceedings of the 1999 Winter Simulation Conference, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>948--955</pages><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>AbouRizk, S. M., Ruwanpura, J. Y., Er, K. C., and Fernando, S. 1999. “Special Purpose Simulation Template for Utility Tunnel Construction”, Proceedings of the 1999 Winter Simulation Conference, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Piscataway, New Jersey, 948-955.</raw><contexts><context>mulation initiatives have been launched. Simphony developed at the University of Alberta provides an advanced simulation environment specially tailored for construction researchers and practitioners (AbouRizk et al. 1999, Hajjar and AbouRizk 1999). STROBOSCOPE developed at the University of Michigan and now housed at Virginia Tech is another notable development that has mustered a strong following amongst constructio</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29725"><authors>J J Adrian,L T Boyer</authors><title>Modeling Method - Productivity</title><venue>Journal of Construction Division, ASCE</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1976</year><pages>157--168</pages><volume>102</volume><raw>Adrian J.J. and Boyer L.T. 1976. &amp;quot;Modeling Method - Productivity&amp;quot;, Journal of Construction Division, ASCE, 102(C01), 157-168.</raw></citation><citation id="29726"><authors>R Axelrod</authors><title>The Complexity of Cooperation: Agent-Based Models of Competition and Collaboration</title><year>1998</year><publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher><pubAddress>Princeton, N.J</pubAddress><raw>Axelrod, R. 1998. “The Complexity of Cooperation: Agent-Based Models of Competition and Collaboration”, Princeton University Press, Princeton, N.J.</raw><contexts><context>sciences, ecology, economics, political science and marketing and sales (Bonabeau 2002). In this approach each system is modeled as a collection of autonomous decision-making entities (Bonabeau 2002, Axelrod 1998, Axtell 1999, Sanchez and Lucas 2002). These agents sense and stochastically respond to conditions in their local environments, mimicking complex large-scale system behavior (Sanchez and Lucas 2002).</context><context> computational power of computers. Researchers can thus explore dynamics out of the reach of pure mathematical methods at the system level, and discover the fundamental rules driving system behavior (Axelrod 1998, Bonabeau 2002). 3 ABMS IN CONSTRUCTION Construction discipline is deeply entrenched in tradition and history. Researchers and practitioners alike are of the view point that there is “central control</context><context>arp. Paint Service Trim Flooring Final Clean Finish Figure 2: Simplified Residential Precedence MapsThe intention of the work presented here being illustrative rather than duplicative of the process (Axelrod 1998), only the first three stages (foundation through rough-in of the building services) were modeled. Thus, there were three different trade contractor agent types, one each for the foundation, framing,</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29727"><authors>R Axtell</authors><title>Why Agents? On the Varied Motivations for Agent Computing</title><venue>The University of Chicago</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>15--16</pages><raw>Axtell, R. 1999. “Why Agents? On the Varied Motivations for Agent Computing in the Social Science”, Proceedings of the Workshop on Agent Simulation: Applications, Models, and Tools October 15-16, 1999, The University of Chicago.</raw><contexts><context>ogy, economics, political science and marketing and sales (Bonabeau 2002). In this approach each system is modeled as a collection of autonomous decision-making entities (Bonabeau 2002, Axelrod 1998, Axtell 1999, Sanchez and Lucas 2002). These agents sense and stochastically respond to conditions in their local environments, mimicking complex large-scale system behavior (Sanchez and Lucas 2002). Each agent i</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29728"><authors>H H Bashford,A Sawhney,K D Walsh,K Kot</authors><title>2003. “Implications of Even-Flow Production Methodology for the U.S. Housing Industry”, Journal of Construction Engineering and Management (pending publication</title><raw>Bashford, H.H., A. Sawhney, K.D. Walsh, and K. Kot. 2003. “Implications of Even-Flow Production Methodology for the U.S. Housing Industry”, Journal of Construction Engineering and Management (pending publication).</raw></citation><citation id="29729"><authors>E Bonabeau</authors><title>Agent-based Modeling: Methods and Techniques for Simulating Human</title><venue>Systems”, PNAS, May</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><volume>14</volume><raw>Bonabeau, E. 2002. “Agent-based Modeling: Methods and Techniques for Simulating Human Systems”, PNAS, May 14, 2002, vol. 99 suppl. 3.</raw></citation><citation id="29730"><authors>D Y Chang,R I Carr</authors><title>RESQUE: A Resource Oriented Simulation System for Multiple Resource Constrained Processes</title><venue>Proceedings of the PMI Seminar/Symposium</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1987</year><pages>4--19</pages><pubAddress>Milwaukee, Wisconsin</pubAddress><raw>Chang, D. Y. and Carr, R. I. 1987. &amp;quot;RESQUE: A Resource Oriented Simulation System for Multiple Resource Constrained Processes&amp;quot;, Proceedings of the PMI Seminar/Symposium, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 4-19.</raw><contexts><context> interactive interface. Touran (1981) focused on automated real time data acquisition and its integration with INSIGHT. Work at the University of Michigan under Carr led to the development of RESQUE (Chang and Carr, 1987) which is also CYCLONE based with advanced resource handling capabilities. Ioannou (1989) developed UM-CYCLONE for advanced construction process modeling. More recently advanced construction simulati</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29731"><authors>V Colella,E Klopfer,M Resnick</authors><title>Adventures in Modeling: Exploring Complex Dynamic Systems with Starlogo”, Teacher’s</title><year>2001</year><publisher>College Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York, NY</pubAddress><raw>Colella, V.,E. Klopfer, and M. Resnick, 2001. “Adventures in Modeling: Exploring Complex Dynamic Systems with Starlogo”, Teacher’s College Press, New York, NY.</raw><contexts><context>me significantly. 4 CONSTRUCTION APPLICATION To consider the effectiveness of the agent-based methodology, a residential subdivision was modeled using the agent-based simulation environment StarLogo (Colella et al. 2001, education.mit.edu/starlogo/). StarLogo is a simple agent-based environment in which observer and agent rules can be programmed to allow predefined agents to interact Sawhney, Bashford, Walsh, and Mu</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29732"><authors>P Davidsson</authors><title>Multi Agent Simulation: Beyond Social Simulation”, Editors</title><venue>MABS 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>97--107</pages><raw>Davidsson, P., 2000. “Multi Agent Simulation: Beyond Social Simulation”, Editors S. Moss and P. Davidson: MABS 2000, pp. 97-107, 2000.</raw><contexts><context> this technique a new development; while others simply deem it as a natural extension of existing paradigms such as parallel and distributed discrete-event simulation, and object-oriented simulation (Davidsson 2000). ABMS has been used in a variety of fields including social sciences, ecology, economics, political science and marketing and sales (Bonabeau 2002). In this approach each system is modeled as a coll</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29733"><authors>Bashford Sawhney,Walsh,Mulky Flin,R Mearns,K O’Connor,P,R Bryden</authors><title>Measuring safety climate: Identifying the common features”, Safety Sci</title><year>2000</year><pages>177--192</pages><volume>34</volume><raw>Sawhney, Bashford, Walsh, and Mulky Flin, R., Mearns, K., O’Connor, P., and Bryden, R. 2000. “Measuring safety climate: Identifying the common features”, Safety Sci., 34, 177-192.</raw></citation><citation id="29734"><authors>D Hajjar,S M AbouRizk</authors><title>Simphony: An Environment for Building Special Purpose Construction Simulation Tools</title><venue>Proceedings of the 1999 Winter Simulation Conference, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Piscataway</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Hajjar, D. and AbouRizk, S. M. 1999. “Simphony: An Environment for Building Special Purpose Construction Simulation Tools”, Proceedings of the 1999 Winter Simulation Conference, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, Piscataway, New Jersey.</raw><contexts><context>ave been launched. Simphony developed at the University of Alberta provides an advanced simulation environment specially tailored for construction researchers and practitioners (AbouRizk et al. 1999, Hajjar and AbouRizk 1999). STROBOSCOPE developed at the University of Michigan and now housed at Virginia Tech is another notable development that has mustered a strong following amongst construction researchers (Martinez 19</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29735"><authors>D W Halpin,M Kueckmann</authors><venue>Lean Construction and Simulation”, in 2000 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pubAddress>Orlando, Florida</pubAddress><raw>Halpin D. W. and Kueckmann, M. 2002. “Lean Construction and Simulation”, in 2000 Winter Simulation Conference: December 2000. Orlando, Florida.</raw></citation><citation id="29736"><authors>D W Halpin</authors><title>An Investigation of the Use of Simulation Networks for Modeling Construction Operations&amp;quot;, Ph.D. thesis presented to the University of Illinois, at Urbana-Champaign, Illinois, in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy</title><year>1973</year><raw>Halpin, D. W. 1973. &amp;quot;An Investigation of the Use of Simulation Networks for Modeling Construction Operations&amp;quot;, Ph.D. thesis presented to the University of Illinois, at Urbana-Champaign, Illinois, in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy.</raw></citation><citation id="29737"><authors>G Howell</authors><title>White Paper. Berkeley/Stanford CE&amp;M Research Workshop, Available online at www.ce. berkeley.edu/~tommelein/CEMworkshop/Howell.pdf &lt;Last visited December 30</title><year>1999</year><raw>Howell, G. 1999. White Paper. Berkeley/Stanford CE&amp;M Research Workshop, Available online at www.ce. berkeley.edu/~tommelein/CEMworkshop/Howell.pdf &lt;Last visited December 30, 2002&gt;.</raw><contexts><context>lained based on the agent-based concept. At a micro-level, onsite activities seem to show more “organic” control as compared to the much subscribed central and coordinated control (Walsh et al. 2003, Howell 1999). Systems that show these kinds of behaviors are amenable to the use of agent-based modeling and simulation based inquiry. However, much research needs to be conducted in this field. The construction</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29738"><authors>G A Howell,H G Ballard</authors><title>Managing Uncertainty</title><venue>in the Piping Process”, Research Report 47-13, Constr. Industry Inst</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pages>pp.</pages><pubAddress>Austin, Texas</pubAddress><volume>103</volume><raw>Howell, G.A., and H.G. Ballard. 1996. “Managing Uncertainty in the Piping Process”, Research Report 47-13, Constr. Industry Inst., Austin, Texas, 103 pp.</raw><contexts><context> for the subdivision, and the utilization of the crews. The effect of the variability has been noted previously, both via direct observation and analysis (Bashford et al. 2003; Tommelein et al. 2002; Howell and Ballard 1996). One objective of the simulation effort was to see if the agent-based approach could effectively illustrate these same behaviors. In fact, the model performed extremely well in this regard. Figure 3</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29739"><authors>P G Ioannou</authors><title>UM-CYCLONE user’s guide</title><year>1989</year><raw>Ioannou, P. G. 1989. UM-CYCLONE user’s guide, Dept. of Civil Engineering, Univ. of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Mich.</raw></citation><citation id="29740"><authors>K Kim,B C Paulson</authors><title>Agent-Based Compensatory Negotiation Methodology to Facilitate Distributed Coordination of Project Schedule Changes</title><venue>Journal of Computing in Civil Engineering</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><pages>10--18</pages><volume>17</volume><raw>Kim, K., and B.C. Paulson. 2003. “Agent-Based Compensatory Negotiation Methodology to Facilitate Distributed Coordination of Project Schedule Changes”, Journal of Computing in Civil Engineering 17, No. 1 (Jan), 10-18.</raw><contexts><context>on based inquiry. However, much research needs to be conducted in this field. The construction project is routinely described as a setting in which constant change is a rule rather than an exception (Kim and Paulson 2003), and much of the construction management literature is dedicated to change management. Changes to the project plan occur due to design changes, unexpected delays or interruptions in the supply chain</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29741"><authors>J F Luch,D W Halpin</authors><title>Analysis of Construction Operations Using Microcomputers</title><venue>Journal of the Construction Division, ASCE</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1981</year><pages>1--129</pages><volume>108</volume><raw>Luch J. F., and Halpin D.W. 1981. &amp;quot;Analysis of Construction Operations Using Microcomputers&amp;quot;, Journal of the Construction Division, ASCE Vol. 108 No. CO1:129-145.</raw></citation><citation id="29742"><authors>J C Martinez</authors><title>STROBOSCOPE: State and Resource Based Simulation of Construction Processes</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1996</year><pubAddress>Michigan</pubAddress><tech>Ph.D. Dissertation</tech><raw>Martinez, J. C. 1996, &amp;quot;STROBOSCOPE: State and Resource Based Simulation of Construction Processes&amp;quot;, Ph.D. Dissertation, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>ouRizk 1999). STROBOSCOPE developed at the University of Michigan and now housed at Virginia Tech is another notable development that has mustered a strong following amongst construction researchers (Martinez 1996, Martinez and Ioannou 1999). Numerous other smaller scale initiatives can also been found in literature. Tommelein et al. (1998) and Halpin and Kueckmann (2002) recently expanded the use of construct</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29743"><authors>J C Martinez,P G Ioannou</authors><title>General Purpose Systems For Effective Construction Simulation</title><venue>Journal of Construction Engineering and Management, American Society of Civil Engineers</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><volume>125</volume><raw>Martinez, J.C. and P.G. Ioannou. 1999. &amp;quot;General Purpose Systems For Effective Construction Simulation&amp;quot;, Journal of Construction Engineering and Management, American Society of Civil Engineers, (125)4, JulyAugust 1999.</raw><contexts><context>TROBOSCOPE developed at the University of Michigan and now housed at Virginia Tech is another notable development that has mustered a strong following amongst construction researchers (Martinez 1996, Martinez and Ioannou 1999). Numerous other smaller scale initiatives can also been found in literature. Tommelein et al. (1998) and Halpin and Kueckmann (2002) recently expanded the use of construction simulation into areas p</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29744"><authors>S Mohamed</authors><title>Safety Climate in Construction Site Environments</title><venue>Journal of Construction Engineering and Management</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>375--384</pages><volume>128</volume><raw>Mohamed, S. 2002. “Safety Climate in Construction Site Environments”, Journal of Construction Engineering and Management, 128(5), 375-384.</raw></citation><citation id="29745"><authors>Boyd C Paulson</authors><title>Interactive Graphics for Simulating Construction Operations</title><venue>Journal of the Construction Division</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1987</year><pages>104--1</pages><raw>Paulson, Boyd C., Jr. 1987. &amp;quot;Interactive Graphics for Simulating Construction Operations&amp;quot;, Journal of the Construction Division, ASCE, 104(1):69-76.</raw></citation><citation id="29746"><authors>S Sanchez,T Lucas</authors><title>Exploring the world of Agent-Based Simulations: Simple Models, Complex Analyses</title><venue>Proceedings of the 2002 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><editors>E.Yücesan, C. H. Chen, J.L. Snowdon, and J.M. Charnes, eds</editors><raw>Sanchez, S., and Lucas, T., 2002. “Exploring the world of Agent-Based Simulations: Simple Models, Complex Analyses”, Proceedings of the 2002 Winter Simulation Conference E.Yücesan, C. H. Chen, J.L. Snowdon, and J.M. Charnes, eds.</raw><contexts><context>n which a simulation experiment is constructed around a set of autonomous “agents” that interact with each other and their underlying environment to mimic the real-world scenario that they replicate (Sanchez and Lucas 2002). ABMS tends to closely resemble how physical, biological, and social systems work in their natural form (Sawhney 2002, Walsh et al. 2003). Some consider this technique a new development; while other</context><context>s, political science and marketing and sales (Bonabeau 2002). In this approach each system is modeled as a collection of autonomous decision-making entities (Bonabeau 2002, Axelrod 1998, Axtell 1999, Sanchez and Lucas 2002). These agents sense and stochastically respond to conditions in their local environments, mimicking complex large-scale system behavior (Sanchez and Lucas 2002). Each agent individually assesses its</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29747"><authors>A Sawhney</authors><title>Investigating the use of Agent-Based Modeling and Simulation Methodology</title><venue>Del E. Webb School of Construction, Arizona State University</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Sawhney, A. 2002. “Investigating the use of Agent-Based Modeling and Simulation Methodology in Construction”, Internal Report, Del E. Webb School of Construction, Arizona State University.</raw></citation><citation id="29748"><authors>A Sawhney,H Deshpande</authors><title>2000.“JavaBeans-Based Framework For Construction Simulation</title><venue>in 2000 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pubAddress>Orlando, Florida</pubAddress><raw>Sawhney, A. and Deshpande, H. 2000.“JavaBeans-Based Framework For Construction Simulation”, in 2000 Winter Simulation Conference: December 2000. Orlando, Florida.</raw></citation><citation id="29749"><authors>P Teicholz</authors><title>A Simulation Approach to the selection of Construction Equipment</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1963</year><tech>Technical Report No. 26</tech><raw>Teicholz, P. 1963. &amp;quot;A Simulation Approach to the selection of Construction Equipment&amp;quot;, Technical Report No. 26, The Construction Institute, Stanford University.</raw></citation><citation id="29750"><authors>I D Tommelein</authors><title>Pull-driven Scheduling for Pipe Spool Installation</title><venue>Journal of Construction Engineering and Management</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>279--288</pages><volume>124</volume><raw>Tommelein, I.D. 1998. “Pull-driven Scheduling for Pipe Spool Installation”, Journal of Construction Engineering and Management, 124(4), 279-288.</raw></citation><citation id="29751"><authors>A Touran</authors><title>Construction Operations Data Acquisition and Processing Via Time-Lapse Photography Interfaced to a Microcomputer</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1981</year><tech>Ph.D. Dissertation</tech><raw>Touran, A. 1981. &amp;quot;Construction Operations Data Acquisition and Processing Via Time-Lapse Photography Interfaced to a Microcomputer&amp;quot;, Ph.D. Dissertation, School of Civil Engineering, Stanford University, Stanford CA.</raw></citation><citation id="29752"><authors>K D Walsh,J C Hershauer,T A Walsh,I D Tommelein,A Sawhney</authors><title>Lead Time Reduction via Pre-Positioning of Inventory</title><venue>in an Industrial Construction Supply Chain”, Proceedings, Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>8--11</pages><pubAddress>San Diego, CA</pubAddress><raw>Walsh, K.D., Hershauer, J.C., Walsh, T.A., Tommelein, I.D., and Sawhney, A. 2002. “Lead Time Reduction via Pre-Positioning of Inventory in an Industrial Construction Supply Chain”, Proceedings, Winter Simulation Conference, San Diego, CA, Dec. 8-11, 2002, 1737-1744.</raw><contexts><context> simulation. The common trend has been the heavy use of discrete event approach in construction simulation. Construction simulation has primarily been conducted using discrete event simulation tools (Walsh et al. 2002). This work makes a departure from this well traveled path in that it explores the application of ABMS in construction—as a standalone tool or in combination with discrete event simulation. 2 AGENT-B</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29753"><authors>K Walsh,A Sawhney,H Bashford</authors><title>Agentbased Modeling and Simulation</title><venue>in Construction”, Proceedings, Agent-Based Simulation 4</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>28--30</pages><pubAddress>Montpellier, France</pubAddress><raw>Walsh, K., Sawhney, A., and Bashford, H. 2003. “Agentbased Modeling and Simulation in Construction”, Proceedings, Agent-Based Simulation 4, Montpellier, France, April 28-30, 2003.</raw></citation><citation id="29754"><authors>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES</authors><title>ANIL SAWHNEY received his Bachelor of Civil Engineering degree from India in 1987 and a Master of Building Engineering and Management degree from School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi in 1990. He completed his Ph.D. studies at the University of Alberta in</title><venue>Arizona State University. His</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES ANIL SAWHNEY received his Bachelor of Civil Engineering degree from India in 1987 and a Master of Building Engineering and Management degree from School of Planning and Architecture, New Delhi in 1990. He completed his Ph.D. studies at the University of Alberta in June 1994. He is currently working as an Associate Professor in the Del E Webb School of Construction at Arizona State University. His research interests are mainly focused on construction simulation techniques, residential construction and use of computers in construction education. His email address is &lt;anil.sawhney@asu.edu&gt;.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc03papers/195.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>84706f015f744c60aaa34a4c0e60221f176116f5</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>