<document id="10.1.1.1.1534"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A SIMULATION STUDY OF AN AUTOMOTIVE FOUNDRY PLANT MANUFACTURING ENGINE BLOCKS</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">This paper discusses the initial efforts to implement simulation modeling as a visual management and analysis tool at an automotive foundry plant manufacturing engine blocks. The foundry process was modeled using Pro Model to identify bottlenecks and evaluate machine performance, cycle times and production data (total parts, rejects, throughput, products/hr) essential for efficient production control. Results from the current system identified assembly machine work area as the bottleneck (although utilization was greater than 95 % for two assembly machines) resulting in high work-in-process (WIP) inventory level, low resource and machine utilization. Based on these results, optimum numbers were identified through use of scenarios by varying the number of assembly machines and processing</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4270"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">E. Yücesan</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4271"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">C. -h. Chen</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4272"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. L. Snowdon</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4273"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">J. M. Charnes</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4274"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Sang D. Choi</name><order>5</order></author><author id="4275"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Anil R. Kumar</name><order>6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28782"><authors>R B Chase,N J Aquilano,F R Jacobs</authors><venue>Operations Management for Competitive Advantage (9 th Ed.). McGraw-Hill/Irwin</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pubAddress>New York, NY</pubAddress><raw>Chase, R.B., Aquilano, N.J., and Jacobs, F.R. 2001. Operations Management for Competitive Advantage (9 th Ed.). McGraw-Hill/Irwin, New York, NY.</raw><contexts><context>t Western Michigan University Kalamazoo, MI 49008-5061, U.S.A. Survival of any industry in today’s competitive market place depends on response time, production cost and flexibility in manufacturing (Chase et al. 2001). Automotive foundries are no exception to this rule. Hence strategies to increase throughput while reducing production costs are being implemented. One efficient strategy to reduce production costs </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28783"><authors>C R Harrell,K Tumay</authors><title>ProModel PC TUTOTIAL</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>Harrell, C.R. and Tumay, K. 1990. ProModel PC TUTOTIAL. In Proceedings of the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference, O. Balci, R.P. Sadowski, R.E. Nance (Eds.), 128–131.</raw><contexts><context>Kumar, and Houshyar based simulation tool for modeling all types of manufacturing systems ranging from small job shops and machining cells to large mass production and flexible manufacturing systems (Harrell and Tumay 1990). ProModel provides a visual representation of the various physical components of the systems and links them through routing and processing statements. ProModel also includes more than 20 statistical</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28784"><authors>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES SANG D CHOI</authors><title>holds a BSIE</title><year>1996</year><raw>AUTHOR BIOGRAPHIES SANG D. CHOI holds a BSIE (1996) from Kwan-Dong University and a MSIE (1999) from Wichita State University. He is currently a Ph.D. candidate in the Industrial and Manufacturing Engineering Department at Western Michigan University in Kalamazoo. His research interests are in occupational ergonomics and work/process design. He is a member of HFES and IIE. His email address is &lt;s9choi@wmich.edu&gt;.</raw></citation><citation id="28785"><authors>ANIL R KUMAR</authors><title>holds a Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering (1997) from University of Pune, India and a MSIE (2001) from Wichita State University. He is pursuing a doctorial degree at</title><raw>ANIL R. KUMAR holds a Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering (1997) from University of Pune, India and a MSIE (2001) from Wichita State University. He is pursuing a doctorial degree at Western Michigan University in Kalamazoo. He is currently working in the Human Performance Institute as a graduate assistant. His email address is &lt;a1kumar@wmich.edu&gt;.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc02papers/138.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>1a90622bed1f9a9cb0aa15dbc6e531f4b886f4ad</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>