<document id="10.1.1.1.1572"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Working Papers 49 (2001), 172–175 Vowels in infant- and adult-directed speech</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">F1 and F2 frequencies of the vowels /i/, /a / and /u / were measured in speech directed to an infant and to adults. The vowels were taken from content words as well as function words. The results showed that the vowel triangles in speech to the infant were expanded compared to those in speech to adults, but only in the content words. For function words, the opposite pattern was found: adults produced more expanded vowels in adult-directed speech than in infant-directed speech. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4372"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Joost Van De Weijer</name><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">vdweijer@ling.lu.se</email><order>1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29582"><authors>A Cutler</authors><title>Phonological cues to open- and closed-class words in the processing of spoken sentences</title><venue>Journal of Psycholinguistic Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>109--131</pages><volume>22</volume><raw>Cutler, A. 1993. Phonological cues to open- and closed-class words in the processing of spoken sentences. Journal of Psycholinguistic Research, 22, 109-131.</raw><contexts><context>Kuhl et al. (1997) can also be applied to function words. Although there are only few function word types, a large part of everyday speech, probably even a majority, consists of function word tokens (Cutler 1993). In other words, a great part of the vowels that infants actually hear are produced in function words, and not in content words. In order to address this question, I compared the F1 and F2 frequenci</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29583"><authors>P Kuhl,J Andruski,I Chistovich,L Chistovich,E Kozhevnikova,V Ryskina,E Stolyarova,U Sundberg</authors><title>Cross-language analysis of phonetic units in language addressed to infants</title><venue>Science</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>684--686</pages><volume>277</volume><raw>Kuhl, P., Andruski, J., Chistovich, I., Chistovich, L., Kozhevnikova, E., Ryskina, V., Stolyarova, E., Sundberg U., &amp; Lacerda, F. 1997. Cross-language analysis of phonetic units in language addressed to infants. Science, 277, 684-686.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ling.lu.se/conference/fonetik2001/proceedings/bidrag44.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>dbccdef30262fc86a6ba145d817fcb7eb9b099de</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>