<document id="10.1.1.1.1518"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Peer-to-Peer Human-Robot Interaction for Space Exploration</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">NASA has embarked on a long-term program to develop human-robot systems for sustained, affordable space exploration. To support this mission, we are working to improve human-robot interaction and performance on planetary surfaces. Rather than building robots that function as glorified tools, our focus is to enable humans and robots to work as partners and peers. In this paper, we describe our approach, which includes contextual dialogue, cognitive modeling, and metrics-based field testing.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4209"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Terrence Fong</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Moffett Field, CA 94035 USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">terry @.arc.nasa.gov</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4210"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Illah Nourbakhsh</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Moffett Field, CA 94035 USA</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">illah   @.arc.nasa.gov</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28555"><authors>N Cabrol</authors><title>Proceedings of the Astronaut-Rover interaction post Silver Lake field test debriefing: results, lessons learned, and directions for future human exploration of planetary surfaces</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1999</year><tech>Technical Report NP-2004-01-334HQ</tech><raw>Cabrol, N. 1999. Proceedings of the Astronaut-Rover interaction post Silver Lake field test debriefing: results, lessons learned, and directions for future human exploration of planetary surfaces. Technical Report NP-2004-01-334HQ, NASA Ames Research Center, Moffett Field, CA.</raw><contexts><context>used on developing human and robotic systems for planetary surfaces. Scant attention, however, has been paid to joint human-robot teams. Such teams, however, are attractive for numerous applications (Cabrol 1999; Huntsberger, Rodriguez, and Schenker 2000; Jones and Rock 2002). Robots could support longduration excursions by scouting, by surveying, and by carrying equipment. Robots could assist in site prepar</context><context>ar that we need to understand how such systems can best be used. A first step in this direction was taken in 1999, when NASA ARC and JSC conducted the “Astronaut-Rover Interaction Field Test” (ASRO) (Cabrol 1999). ASRO identified several operational scenarios in which EVA crewmembers and rovers can interact in a safe, productive manner. The study, however, focused only on surface exploration scenarios (i.e.,</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28556"><authors>T Fong,D Kaber,M Lewis,J Scholtz,A Schultz,A Steinfeld</authors><title>Common metrics for human-robot interaction. in submission</title><year>2004</year><raw>Fong, T., Kaber, D., Lewis, M., Scholtz, J., Schultz, A., and Steinfeld, A. 2004. Common metrics for human-robot interaction. in submission.</raw><contexts><context> for understanding how well humans and robots are able to work together. Thus, we intend to use a variety of metrics and critical incident analysis to characterize and assess human-robot performance (Fong et al. 2004; Scholtz et al. 2004). To evaluate system performance, one metric we will examine is fan out, which measures how many robots can be effectively controlled by a human (Goodrich and Olsen 2003). To ass</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28557"><authors>T Fong,C Thorpe,C Baur</authors><title>Multi-robot remote driving with collaborative control</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><volume>50</volume><raw>Fong, T., Thorpe, C., and Baur, C. 2003. Multi-robot remote driving with collaborative control. IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics 50(4).</raw></citation><citation id="28558"><authors>T Fong</authors><title>Collaborative control: a robot-centric model for vehicle teleoperation</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><pages>01--34</pages><pubAddress>Pittsburgh, PA</pubAddress><tech>Ph.D. Dissertation</tech><raw>Fong, T. 2001. Collaborative control: a robot-centric model for vehicle teleoperation. Ph.D. Dissertation, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA. CMU-RI-TR-01-34.</raw></citation><citation id="28559"><authors>M Goodrich,D Olsen</authors><title>Seven principles of efficient human robot interaction</title><venue>In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man and Cybernetics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>3943--3948</pages><raw>Goodrich, M., and Olsen, D. 2003. Seven principles of efficient human robot interaction. In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man and Cybernetics, 3943–3948.</raw><contexts><context>ot performance (Fong et al. 2004; Scholtz et al. 2004). To evaluate system performance, one metric we will examine is fan out, which measures how many robots can be effectively controlled by a human (Goodrich and Olsen 2003). To assess operator performance, we will use the NASA-Task Load IndeX (NASA-TLX) (Hart and Staveland 1988) and will measure the level of situational awareness (Scholtz 2003). To evaluate robot perfo</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28560"><authors>R Hansen,K Ford</authors><title>A human centered vision of Mars exploration</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2004</year><tech>Technical Report NAG9-1386</tech><raw>Hansen, R., and Ford, K. 2004. A human centered vision of Mars exploration. Technical Report NAG9-1386, Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, University of West Florida.</raw><contexts><context>cantly over the next few decades, a viable strategy is for humans to perform higherorder cognitive and perception functions while robots perform reactive, precise, and physically demanding functions (Hansen and Ford 2004). Of course, choosing the optimum distribution of responsibilities between human and robots is a difficult problem that must be addressed (Proud, Hard, and Mrozinski 2003; Rodriguez and Weisbin 2003)</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28561"><authors>S Hart,L Staveland</authors><title>Development of NASATLX (Task Load Index): results of empirical and theoretical research</title><year>1988</year><editors>In Hancock, P., and Meshkati, N., eds., Human Mental Workload</editors><publisher>North-Holland Elsevier Science</publisher><raw>Hart, S., and Staveland, L. 1988. Development of NASATLX (Task Load Index): results of empirical and theoretical research. In Hancock, P., and Meshkati, N., eds., Human Mental Workload. North-Holland Elsevier Science.</raw><contexts><context>examine is fan out, which measures how many robots can be effectively controlled by a human (Goodrich and Olsen 2003). To assess operator performance, we will use the NASA-Task Load IndeX (NASA-TLX) (Hart and Staveland 1988) and will measure the level of situational awareness (Scholtz 2003). To evaluate robot performance, one metric we will apply is self-awareness (i.e., how well a robot can report on its current health</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28562"><authors>T Huntsberger,G Rodriguez,P Schenker</authors><title>Robotics challenges for robotic and human Mars exploration</title><venue>In Proc. Robotics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>Huntsberger, T., Rodriguez, G., and Schenker, P. 2000. Robotics challenges for robotic and human Mars exploration. In Proc. Robotics.</raw></citation><citation id="28563"><authors>H Jones,S Rock</authors><title>Dialogue-based human-robot interaction for space construction teams</title><venue>In Proc. IEEE Aerospace Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>Jones, H., and Rock, S. 2002. Dialogue-based human-robot interaction for space construction teams. In Proc. IEEE Aerospace Conference.</raw><contexts><context>ry surfaces. Scant attention, however, has been paid to joint human-robot teams. Such teams, however, are attractive for numerous applications (Cabrol 1999; Huntsberger, Rodriguez, and Schenker 2000; Jones and Rock 2002). Robots could support longduration excursions by scouting, by surveying, and by carrying equipment. Robots could assist in site preparation, sample collection and transport, as well as provide conti</context><context>ral is crucial to future space exploration. In particular, we contend that humans and robots must be able to: (1) communicate clearly about their goals, abilities, plans, and achievements (Fong 2001; Jones and Rock 2002); (2) collaborate to solve problems, especially when situations exceed autonomous capabilities (Fong 2001); and (3) interact via multiple modalities (dialogue, gestures, etc), both locally and remote</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28564"><authors>D McFarlane</authors><title>Coordinating the interruption of people in human-computer interaction</title><venue>In Proc. HCI Interact</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>McFarlane, D. 1990. Coordinating the interruption of people in human-computer interaction. In Proc. HCI Interact.</raw><contexts><context>human interaction. Moreover, interruption is problematic because humans have cognitive limitations that restrict their ability to work during interruptions and to resume previously interrupted tasks (McFarlane 1990). Computational Cognitive Models In order to take the best possible advantage of the particular skills of humans and of robots in mixed-initiative teams, itsis important that robots be able to reason</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28565"><title>The vision for space exploration</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><pubAddress>NASA, Washington, DC</pubAddress><tech>Technical Report NP-2004-01-334-HQ</tech><raw>NASA. 2004. The vision for space exploration. Technical Report NP-2004-01-334-HQ, NASA, Washington, DC.</raw></citation><citation id="28566"><authors>R Proud,J Hard,R Mrozinski</authors><title>Methods for determining the level of autonomy to design into a human spaceflight vehicle: a function specific approach</title><venue>In Proc. NIST Performance Metrics for Intelligent Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Proud, R., Hard, J., and Mrozinski, R. 2003. Methods for determining the level of autonomy to design into a human spaceflight vehicle: a function specific approach. In Proc. NIST Performance Metrics for Intelligent Systems.</raw></citation><citation id="28567"><authors>G Rodriguez,C Weisbin</authors><title>A new method to evaluate human-robot system performance. Autonomous Robots 14(2):165–178</title><year>2003</year><raw>Rodriguez, G., and Weisbin, C. 2003. A new method to evaluate human-robot system performance. Autonomous Robots 14(2):165–178.</raw><contexts><context>tions (Hansen and Ford 2004). Of course, choosing the optimum distribution of responsibilities between human and robots is a difficult problem that must be addressed (Proud, Hard, and Mrozinski 2003; Rodriguez and Weisbin 2003). However, since robots will not be 100% self-sufficient (certainly not before 2020), situations will continue to arise in which the robot fails and a human needs to intervene (e.g., via teleoperatio</context><context>at can benefit from human-robot teams. In addition, a significant issue, which needs to be addressed, is how to decide which human and robotic assets are most appropriate for a given task or mission (Rodriguez and Weisbin 2003). Often it is possible to perform tasks with robots or humans or both, but we need to understand (especially in quantitative terms) the consequences of different allocation strategies. In particular</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28568"><authors>J Scholtz,J Young,J Drury,H Yanco</authors><title>Evaluation of human-robot interaction awareness in search and rescue</title><venue>In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><raw>Scholtz, J., Young, J., Drury, J., and Yanco, H. 2004. Evaluation of human-robot interaction awareness in search and rescue. In Proc. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation.</raw><contexts><context> how well humans and robots are able to work together. Thus, we intend to use a variety of metrics and critical incident analysis to characterize and assess human-robot performance (Fong et al. 2004; Scholtz et al. 2004). To evaluate system performance, one metric we will examine is fan out, which measures how many robots can be effectively controlled by a human (Goodrich and Olsen 2003). To assess operator performa</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28569"><authors>J Scholtz</authors><title>Theory and evaluation of human robot interactions</title><venue>In Proc. Hawaii International Conference on System Science 36</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Scholtz, J. 2003. Theory and evaluation of human robot interactions. In Proc. Hawaii International Conference on System Science 36.</raw></citation><citation id="28570"><authors>B Smith,S Tyler</authors><title>The design and application of MIDAS: a constructive simulation for human-system analysis</title><venue>In Proc. Simulation Technology and Training (SIMTECT</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Smith, B., and Tyler, S. 1997. The design and application of MIDAS: a constructive simulation for human-system analysis. In Proc. Simulation Technology and Training (SIMTECT).</raw><contexts><context>AS) to robotics. MIDAS consists of an agentbased operator model (modules represent cognitive and sensor-motor functions) and models of the proximal (displays, controls, etc.) and remote environments (Smith and Tyler 1997). It has been extensively used for human performance modeling and for predicting human-system effectiveness. As such, we believe MIDAS would be useful for improving HRI design, coordination, and dial</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28571"><authors>D Sofge,D Perzanowski,M Skubic,M Bugajska,J Trafton,N Cassimatis,D Brock,W Adams,A Schultz</authors><title>Cognitive tools for humanoid robots in space</title><venue>In Proc. IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><raw>Sofge, D., Perzanowski, D., Skubic, M., Bugajska, M., Trafton, J., Cassimatis, N., Brock, D., Adams, W., and Schultz, A. 2004. Cognitive tools for humanoid robots in space. In Proc. IFAC Symposium on Automatic Control in Aerospace.</raw><contexts><context> take someone else’s perspective, is critical to collaboration, and is therefore essential for robots collaborating with humans. Thus, we intend to use models of human perspective taking, such as in (Sofge et al. 2004), to improve HRI in situations where humans and robots are working side-by-side. Moreover, we are interested in using cognitive architectures for modeling behavioral outcomes in HRI. That is, we seek</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ri.cmu.edu/pub_files/pub4/fong_terrence_w_2004_1/fong_terrence_w_2004_1.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>bb44bfce19166763a0c858e32ca405b54761a879</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>