<document id="10.1.1.1.1578"><clusterid>1566</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Retrospective Digital Image Fusion of</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">ion. In 5 patients, additional pancreatic tumors or distant metastases only suspected during PET scanning were confirmed. Image fusion improved the sensitivity of malignancy detection from 76.6% (CT) and 84.4% (PET) to 89.1% (image fusion). Compared with CT alone, image fusion increased the sensitivity of detecting tissue infiltration to 68.2%, but at the cost of decreased specificity. Conclusion: The most important supplementary finding supplied by image fusion is a more precise correlation with focal tracer hot spots in PET. Image fusion improved the sensitivity of differentiating between benign and malignant pancreatic lesions with no significant change in specificity. All image modalities failed to stage lymph node involvement.  Key Words: PET; CT, spiral; image manipulation or reconstruction; pancreas; computer applications, detection  J Nucl Med 2004; 45:1279--1286  With  an incidence rate of 10 cases per 100,000 people per year, cancer of the pancreas is the third most common ma</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2004</year><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Multidetector Ct And</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29651"><clusterid>1567</clusterid><authors>D Malka,P Hammel,F Maire</authors><title>et al. Risk of pancreatic adenocarcinoma in chronic pancreatitis. Gut</title><pages>2002--51</pages><raw>Malka D, Hammel P, Maire F, et al. Risk of pancreatic adenocarcinoma in chronic pancreatitis. Gut. 2002;51:849–852.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29652"><clusterid>1568</clusterid><authors>Fuhrman GM</authors><title>Charnsangavej C, Abbruzzese JL, et al. Thin-section contrastenhanced computed tomography accurately predicts the resectability of malignant pancreatic neoplasms. Am J Surg</title><year>1994</year><raw>Fuhrman GM, Charnsangavej C, Abbruzzese JL, et al. Thin-section contrastenhanced computed tomography accurately predicts the resectability of malignant pancreatic neoplasms. Am J Surg. 1994;167:104–111.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29653"><clusterid>1569</clusterid><authors>N Hosten</authors><title>Lemke AJ, Wiedenmann B, Bohmig M, Rosewicz S. Combined imaging techniques for pancreatic cancer. Lancet</title><pages>2000--356</pages><raw>Hosten N, Lemke AJ, Wiedenmann B, Bohmig M, Rosewicz S. Combined imaging techniques for pancreatic cancer. Lancet. 2000;356:909–910.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29654"><clusterid>1570</clusterid><authors>T Higashi,T Saga,Y Nakamoto</authors><title>et al. Relationship between retention index</title><venue>in dual-phase 18 F-FDG PET, and hexokinase-II and glucose transporter-1 expression in pancreatic cancer. J Nucl Med</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>2002--43</pages><raw>Higashi T, Saga T, Nakamoto Y, et al. Relationship between retention index in dual-phase 18 F-FDG PET, and hexokinase-II and glucose transporter-1 expression in pancreatic cancer. J Nucl Med. 2002;43:173–180.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29655"><clusterid>1571</clusterid><authors>T Rohlfing,West JB,J Beier</authors><title>Liebig T, Taschner CA, Thomale UW. Registration of functional and anatomical MRI: accuracy assessment and application in navigated neurosurgery. Comput Aided Surg</title><pages>2000--5</pages><raw>Rohlfing T, West JB, Beier J, Liebig T, Taschner CA, Thomale UW. Registration of functional and anatomical MRI: accuracy assessment and application in navigated neurosurgery. Comput Aided Surg. 2000;5:414–425.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29656"><clusterid>1572</clusterid><authors>C Studholme,D Hill,D Hawkes</authors><title>An overlap invariant entropy measure of 3D medical image alignment. Pattern Recognit</title><year>1999</year><raw>Studholme C, Hill D, Hawkes D. An overlap invariant entropy measure of 3D medical image alignment. Pattern Recognit. 1999;32:71–86.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29657"><clusterid>1573</clusterid><authors>Lu DS,Reber HA,Krasny RM,Kadell BM,J Sayre</authors><title>Local staging of pancreatic cancer: criteria for unresectability of major vessels as revealed by pancreaticphase, thin-section helical CT. AJR</title><year>1997</year><raw>Lu DS, Reber HA, Krasny RM, Kadell BM, Sayre J. Local staging of pancreatic cancer: criteria for unresectability of major vessels as revealed by pancreaticphase, thin-section helical CT. AJR. 1997;168:1439–1443.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29658"><clusterid>1574</clusterid><authors>Moossa AR,Gamagami RA</authors><title>Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic neoplasms. Surg Clin North Am</title><year>1995</year><raw>Moossa AR, Gamagami RA. Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic neoplasms. Surg Clin North Am. 1995;75:871–890.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29659"><clusterid>1575</clusterid><authors>V Raptopoulos,Steer</authors><title>ML, Sheiman RG, Vrachliotis TG, Gougoutas CA, Movson JS. The use of helical CT and CT angiography to predict vascular involvement from pancreatic cancer: correlation with findings at surgery. AJR</title><year>1997</year><raw>Raptopoulos V, Steer ML, Sheiman RG, Vrachliotis TG, Gougoutas CA, Movson JS. The use of helical CT and CT angiography to predict vascular involvement from pancreatic cancer: correlation with findings at surgery. AJR. 1997;168:971–977.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29660"><clusterid>1576</clusterid><authors>Richter GM,C Wunsch,B Schneider</authors><title>et al. Hydro-CT in detection and staging of pancreatic carcinoma [in</title><year>1998</year><raw>Richter GM, Wunsch C, Schneider B, et al. Hydro-CT in detection and staging of pancreatic carcinoma [in German]. Radiologe. 1998;38:279–286.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29661"><clusterid>1577</clusterid><authors>Ell PJ</authors><title>von Schulthess GK. PET/CT: a new road map</title><venue>Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2002;29:719–720. 1286 THE JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MEDICINE</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2004</year><volume>45</volume><raw>Ell PJ, von Schulthess GK. PET/CT: a new road map. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2002;29:719–720. 1286 THE JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MEDICINE Vol. 45 No. 8 August 2004</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29662"><clusterid>1578</clusterid><authors>Jager PL</authors><title>Slart RH, Corstens FH, Hoekstra OS, Teule JJ, Oyen WJ. PET-CT: a matter of opinion? Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging</title><pages>2003--30</pages><raw>Jager PL, Slart RH, Corstens FH, Hoekstra OS, Teule JJ, Oyen WJ. PET-CT: a matter of opinion? Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2003;30:470–471.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29663"><clusterid>1579</clusterid><authors>Schaffler GJ</authors><title>Groell R, Schoellnast H, et al. Digital image fusion of CT and PET data sets: clinical value in abdominal/pelvic malignancies</title><venue>J Comput Assist Tomogr</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><volume>2000</volume><raw>Schaffler GJ, Groell R, Schoellnast H, et al. Digital image fusion of CT and PET data sets: clinical value in abdominal/pelvic malignancies. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 2000;24:644–647.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29664"><clusterid>1580</clusterid><authors>V Mongioj,A Brusa,G Loi</authors><title>et al. Accuracy evaluation of fusion of CT, MR, and SPECT images using commercially available software packages</title><venue>SRS PLATO and IFS). Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Mongioj V, Brusa A, Loi G, et al. Accuracy evaluation of fusion of CT, MR, and SPECT images using commercially available software packages (SRS PLATO and IFS). Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 1999;43:227–234.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29665"><clusterid>1581</clusterid><authors>J West,Fitzpatrick JM,Wang MY</authors><title>et al. Comparison and evaluation of retrospective intermodality brain image registration techniques. J Comput Assist Tomogr</title><year>1997</year><raw>West J, Fitzpatrick JM, Wang MY, et al. Comparison and evaluation of retrospective intermodality brain image registration techniques. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 1997;21:554–566.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29666"><clusterid>1582</clusterid><authors>W Schima,R Fugger,E Schober</authors><title>et al. Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic cancer: comparison of mangafodipir trisodium-enhanced MR imaging and contrast-enhanced helical hydro-CT. AJR</title><pages>2002--179</pages><raw>Schima W, Fugger R, Schober E, et al. Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic cancer: comparison of mangafodipir trisodium-enhanced MR imaging and contrast-enhanced helical hydro-CT. AJR. 2002;179:717–724.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29667"><clusterid>1583</clusterid><authors>Hill DL,Batchelor PG,M Holden,Hawkes DJ</authors><title>Medical image registration. Phys Med Biol</title><pages>2001--46</pages><raw>Hill DL, Batchelor PG, Holden M, Hawkes DJ. Medical image registration. Phys Med Biol. 2001;46:R1–R45.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29668"><clusterid>1659</clusterid><authors></authors><title>CR Jr. Nonrigid image registration in shared-memory multiprocessor environments with application to brains, breasts, and bees</title><venue>IEEE Trans Inf Technol Biomed</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>2003--7</pages><editors>Rohlfing T, Maurer</editors><raw>Rohlfing T, Maurer CR Jr. Nonrigid image registration in shared-memory multiprocessor environments with application to brains, breasts, and bees. IEEE Trans Inf Technol Biomed. 2003;7:16–25.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29669"><clusterid>1584</clusterid><authors>O Graf,Boland GW,Warshaw AL</authors><title>Fernandez-del-Castillo C, Hahn PF, Mueller PR. Arterial versus portal venous helical CT for revealing pancreatic adenocarcinoma: conspicuity of tumor and critical vascular anatomy. AJR</title><year>1997</year><raw>Graf O, Boland GW, Warshaw AL, Fernandez-del-Castillo C, Hahn PF, Mueller PR. Arterial versus portal venous helical CT for revealing pancreatic adenocarcinoma: conspicuity of tumor and critical vascular anatomy. AJR. 1997;169:119–123.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29670"><clusterid>1585</clusterid><authors>U Baum</authors><title>Lell M, Nomayr A, et al. Multiplanar spiral CT in the diagnosis of pancreatic tumors [in</title><year>1999</year><raw>Baum U, Lell M, Nomayr A, et al. Multiplanar spiral CT in the diagnosis of pancreatic tumors [in German]. Radiologe. 1999;39:958–964.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29671"><clusterid>1586</clusterid><authors>W Schima</authors><title>Ba-Ssalamah A. Radiologic staging of liver and pancreatic malignancies [in</title><year>1999</year><raw>Schima W, Ba-Ssalamah A. Radiologic staging of liver and pancreatic malignancies [in German]. Radiologe. 1999;39:568–577.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29672"><clusterid>1587</clusterid><authors>Richter GM,C Simon,V Hoffmann</authors><title>et al. Hydrospiral CT of the pancreas in thin section technique [in</title><year>1996</year><raw>Richter GM, Simon C, Hoffmann V, et al. Hydrospiral CT of the pancreas in thin section technique [in German]. Radiologe. 1996;36:397–405.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29673"><clusterid>1588</clusterid><authors>C Catalano,A Laghi,F Fraioli</authors><title>et al. Pancreatic carcinoma: the role of highresolution multislice spiral CT in the diagnosis and assessment of resectability. Eur Radiol</title><pages>2003--13</pages><raw>Catalano C, Laghi A, Fraioli F, et al. Pancreatic carcinoma: the role of highresolution multislice spiral CT in the diagnosis and assessment of resectability. Eur Radiol. 2003;13:149–156.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29674"><clusterid>1589</clusterid><authors>Robinson PJ,Sheridan MB</authors><title>Pancreatitis: computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging. Eur Radiol</title><pages>2000--10</pages><raw>Robinson PJ, Sheridan MB. Pancreatitis: computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging. Eur Radiol. 2000;10:401–408.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29675"><clusterid>1590</clusterid><authors>H Taoka,E Hauptmann,Traverso LW,Barnett MJ,Sarr MG,Reber HA</authors><title>How accurate is helical computed tomography for clinical staging of pancreatic cancer? Am J Surg</title><year>1999</year><raw>Taoka H, Hauptmann E, Traverso LW, Barnett MJ, Sarr MG, Reber HA. How accurate is helical computed tomography for clinical staging of pancreatic cancer? Am J Surg. 1999;177:428–432.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29676"><clusterid>1591</clusterid><authors>Freeny PC,Traverso LW,Ryan JA</authors><title>Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic adenocarcinoma with dynamic computed tomography. Am J Surg</title><year>1993</year><raw>Freeny PC, Traverso LW, Ryan JA. Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic adenocarcinoma with dynamic computed tomography. Am J Surg. 1993;165:600–606.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29677"><clusterid>1592</clusterid><authors>N Hosten,R Kreissig,R Puls</authors><title>et al. Fusion of CT and PET data: methods and clinical relevance for planning laser-induced thermotherapy of liver metastases [in German]. Rofo Fortschr Geb Rontgenstr Neuen Bildgeb Verfahr</title><pages>2000--172</pages><raw>Hosten N, Kreissig R, Puls R, et al. Fusion of CT and PET data: methods and clinical relevance for planning laser-induced thermotherapy of liver metastases [in German]. Rofo Fortschr Geb Rontgenstr Neuen Bildgeb Verfahr. 2000;172:630–635.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29678"><clusterid>1593</clusterid><authors>H Furukawa,T Kosuge,K Mukai</authors><title>et al. Helical computed tomography in the diagnosis of portal vein invasion by pancreatic head carcinoma: usefulness for selecting surgical procedures and predicting the outcome. Arch Surg</title><year>1998</year><raw>Furukawa H, Kosuge T, Mukai K, et al. Helical computed tomography in the diagnosis of portal vein invasion by pancreatic head carcinoma: usefulness for selecting surgical procedures and predicting the outcome. Arch Surg. 1998;133:61–</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29679"><clusterid>1594</clusterid><authors>Bluemke DA,Cameron JL</authors><title>Hruban RH, et al. Potentially resectable pancreatic adenocarcinoma: spiral CT assessment with surgical and pathologic correlation. Radiology</title><year>1995</year><raw>Bluemke DA, Cameron JL, Hruban RH, et al. Potentially resectable pancreatic adenocarcinoma: spiral CT assessment with surgical and pathologic correlation. Radiology. 1995;197:381–385.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29680"><clusterid>1595</clusterid><authors>Warshaw AL,Gu ZY,J Wittenberg,Waltman AC</authors><title>Preoperative staging and assessment of resectability of pancreatic cancer. Arch Surg</title><year>1990</year><raw>Warshaw AL, Gu ZY, Wittenberg J, Waltman AC. Preoperative staging and assessment of resectability of pancreatic cancer. Arch Surg. 1990;125:230–233.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29681"><clusterid>1596</clusterid><authors>Ross CB,Sharp KW,Kaufman AJ,T Andrews,Williams LF</authors><title>Efficacy of computerized tomography in the preoperative staging of pancreatic carcinoma. Am Surg</title><year>1988</year><raw>Ross CB, Sharp KW, Kaufman AJ, Andrews T, Williams LF. Efficacy of computerized tomography in the preoperative staging of pancreatic carcinoma. Am Surg. 1988;54:221–226.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29682"><clusterid>1673</clusterid><authors></authors><title>fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography in the differential diagnosis of pancreatic carcinoma: a report of 106 cases. Eur J Nucl Med</title><year>1997</year><editors>Zimny M, Bares R, Fass J, et al. Fluorine-18</editors><raw>Zimny M, Bares R, Fass J, et al. Fluorine-18 fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography in the differential diagnosis of pancreatic carcinoma: a report of 106 cases. Eur J Nucl Med. 1997;24:678–682.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29683"><clusterid>1597</clusterid><authors>P Berberat,H Friess,M Kashiwagi,Beger HG,Buchler MW</authors><title>Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic cancer by positron emission tomography</title><venue>World J Surg</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Berberat P, Friess H, Kashiwagi M, Beger HG, Buchler MW. Diagnosis and staging of pancreatic cancer by positron emission tomography. World J Surg. 1999;23:882–887.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29684"><clusterid>1598</clusterid><authors>R Bares,P Klever,S Hauptmann</authors><title>F-18 fluorodeoxyglucose PET in vivo evaluation of pancreatic glucose metabolism for detection of pancreatic cancer. Radiology</title><year>1994</year><raw>Bares R, Klever P, Hauptmann S, et al. F-18 fluorodeoxyglucose PET in vivo evaluation of pancreatic glucose metabolism for detection of pancreatic cancer. Radiology. 1994;192:79–86.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29685"><clusterid>1599</clusterid><authors>M Lonneux</authors><title>Borbath I, Bol A, et al. Attenuation correction in whole-body FDG oncological studies: the role of statistical reconstruction. Eur J Nucl Med</title><year>1999</year><raw>Lonneux M, Borbath I, Bol A, et al. Attenuation correction in whole-body FDG oncological studies: the role of statistical reconstruction. Eur J Nucl Med. 1999;26:591–598.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29686"><clusterid>1600</clusterid><authors>R Bares</authors><title>Dohmen BM, Cremerius U, Fass J, Teusch M, Bull U. Results of positron emission tomography with fluorine-18 labeled fluorodeoxyglucose in differential diagnosis and staging of pancreatic carcinoma [in</title><year>1996</year><raw>Bares R, Dohmen BM, Cremerius U, Fass J, Teusch M, Bull U. Results of positron emission tomography with fluorine-18 labeled fluorodeoxyglucose in differential diagnosis and staging of pancreatic carcinoma [in German]. Radiologe. 1996;36:435–440.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation><citation id="29687"><clusterid>1601</clusterid><authors>R Bares,P Klever,D Hellwig</authors><title>Pancreatic cancer detected by positron emission tomography with 18 F-labelled deoxyglucose: method and first results. Nucl Med Commun</title><year>1993</year><raw>Bares R, Klever P, Hellwig D, et al. Pancreatic cancer detected by positron emission tomography with 18 F-labelled deoxyglucose: method and first results. Nucl Med Commun. 1993;14:596–601.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1578</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://igl.stanford.edu/~torsten/references/./2004-lemke-jnm-CT_PET_fusion_pancreas.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>