<document id="10.1.1.1.1609"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">An Analytical Model of Adaptive Wormhole Routing with Time-out</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Several studies have shown that the performance advantages of adaptive routing over deterministic routing are reduced when the traffic contains strong degree of communication locality. This paper proposes a new analytical model of an adaptive routing algorithm proposed by Duato in [Dua94]. The main feature of this algorithm is the use of a time-out selection function for assigning virtual channels. This has the advantage of reducing virtual channels multiplexing to improve the network performance, especially, in the presence of communication locality. Simulation experiments reveal that the proposed model predicts message latency with a good degree of accuracy under different traffic conditions. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4470"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">A. Khonsari</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Glasgow, G12 8QQ, U.K.</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">mohamed@dcs.gla.ac.uk</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4471"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">H. Sarbazi-azad</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Glasgow, G12 8QQ, U.K.</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">ak @dcs.gla.ac.uk</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4472"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">M. Ould-khaoua</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Glasgow, G12 8QQ, U.K.</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">hsa @dcs.gla.ac.uk</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30176"><authors>A Agarwal</authors><title>Limits on interconnection network performance</title><venue>IEEE TPDS</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>398--412</pages><volume>2</volume><raw>A. Agarwal, Limits on interconnection network performance, IEEE TPDS, vol. 2, pp.398-412, 1991.</raw></citation><citation id="30177"><authors>E Anderson,J Brooks,C Grassl,S Scott</authors><venue>Performance of the Cray T3E multiprocessor, Proc. Supercomputing Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>E. Anderson, J. Brooks, C. Grassl, S. Scott, Performance of the Cray T3E multiprocessor, Proc. Supercomputing Conference, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>formance is achieved when class a and b contains (V-1) and one virtual channels, respectively. The first multicomputers and routers that use adaptive routing have recently been reported. The Cray T3E [And97] and Reliable Router [Dal94] are two examples of practical systems that have adopted Duato’s adaptive routing algorithm. Duato [Dua93, Dua97] has performed an extensive evaluation of his adaptive rout</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30178"><authors>Y Boura,C R Das,T M Jacob</authors><title>A performance model for adaptive routing</title><venue>in hypercubes, Proc. Int. Workshop Parallel Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>11--16</pages><pubAddress>Bangalore, India</pubAddress><raw>Y. Boura, C.R. Das, T.M. Jacob, A performance model for adaptive routing in hypercubes, Proc. Int. Workshop Parallel Processing, Bangalore, India, pp. 11-16, 1994.</raw><contexts><context>nsion still to be visited are busy. If P l denotes the probability that l virtual channels are busy, the probability of blocking at adaptive and deterministic channel are respectively approximated by [Bou94] Pai , j d ⎛ = ⎜ P ⎜ ⎝ V V P + ( V −1 V V −1) ⎞ ⎟ ⎟ ⎠ ( i− j+ 1) P = P (9) The probability P l ) 0 ( ≤ l ≤ V that l virtual channels at a given physical channel are busy can be determined using a Mark</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30179"><authors>B Ciciani,M Colajanni,C Paolucci</authors><title>An accurate model for the performance analysis of deterministic wormhole routing</title><venue>Proc. Int. Parallel Processing Symposium</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>353--359</pages><raw>B. Ciciani, M. Colajanni and C. Paolucci, An accurate model for the performance analysis of deterministic wormhole routing, Proc. Int. Parallel Processing Symposium, pp. 353-359, 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="30180"><authors>D J Daley</authors><title>General customer impatience in the queue GI/G/1</title><venue>J. of Applied Probability</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1965</year><pages>186--205</pages><volume>2</volume><raw>D.J. Daley, General customer impatience in the queue GI/G/1, J. of Applied Probability, vol. 2, pp. 186-205, 1965.</raw></citation><citation id="30181"><authors>W J Dally</authors><title>Performance analysis of k-ary n-cubes interconnection networks</title><venue>IEEE TC</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><pages>775--785</pages><volume>39</volume><raw>W.J. Dally, Performance analysis of k-ary n-cubes interconnection networks, IEEE TC, 39(6), pp. 775-785, 1990.</raw><contexts><context>, iPSC/2 [Nug88] and SGI Origin 2000 [Lau97] are examples of commercial systems that are based on the hypercube. Existing multicomputers [And97, Fil97, Lau97, Van94] have widely used wormhole routing [Dal90]. This is due to its low buffering requirement, and more importantly it makes latency independent of the message distance under light traffic loads. In wormhole routing, a message is divided into flit</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30182"><authors>W J Dally</authors><title>Virtual channel flow control</title><venue>IEEE TPDS</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1942</year><pages>pp.</pages><volume>3</volume><raw>W.J. Dally, Virtual channel flow control, IEEE TPDS, vol. 3, no. 2, pp. 194205, 1992.</raw><contexts><context>ions on the way messages visit the virtual channels; a virtual channel has its own flit queue, but shares the bandwidth of the physical channel with other virtual channels in a timemultiplexed manner [Dal92]. A typical example of a deadlock-free routing widely used in practice is deterministic routing where messages visit dimensions in a predefined order. Deterministic routing has been popular in multico</context><context> given queue by a factor, V V , representing the average degree of V virtual channels multiplexing, that takes place at a physical channel. The factor V V can be estimated using the following formula [Dal92] V V ∑ l= 0 V = V l ∑ l= 0 2 lP P l l (18)swhere P l ) 0 ( ≤ l ≤ V is the probability that l virtual channels at a given physical channel are busy (and is computed using equation 10). In the event of </context></contexts></citation><citation id="30183"><authors>W J Dally</authors><title>et al, The reliable router: A reliable and high-performance communication substrate for parallel computers</title><venue>Proc. 1 st workshop Parallel Computers, Routing &amp; communication, in K. Bolding and L. Snyder (Eds.), LNCS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pages>241--255</pages><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><raw>W.J. Dally et al, The reliable router: A reliable and high-performance communication substrate for parallel computers, Proc. 1 st workshop Parallel Computers, Routing &amp; communication, in K. Bolding and L. Snyder (Eds.), LNCS, Springer-Verlag, pp. 241-255, 1994.</raw><contexts><context>ass a and b contains (V-1) and one virtual channels, respectively. The first multicomputers and routers that use adaptive routing have recently been reported. The Cray T3E [And97] and Reliable Router [Dal94] are two examples of practical systems that have adopted Duato’s adaptive routing algorithm. Duato [Dua93, Dua97] has performed an extensive evaluation of his adaptive routing algorithm on the hypercu</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30184"><authors>J T Draper,J Ghosh</authors><title>A comprehensive analytical model for wormhole routing in multicomputer systems</title><venue>J. Parallel &amp; Distributed Computing</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>202--214</pages><volume>32</volume><raw>J.T. Draper and J. Ghosh, A comprehensive analytical model for wormhole routing in multicomputer systems, J. Parallel &amp; Distributed Computing, vol. 32, pp. 202-214, 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="30185"><authors>J Duato</authors><title>A new theory of deadlock-free adaptive routing in wormhole routing networks</title><venue>IEEE Trans. Parallel &amp; Distributed Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>1320--1331</pages><volume>4</volume><raw>J. Duato, A new theory of deadlock-free adaptive routing in wormhole routing networks, IEEE Trans. Parallel &amp; Distributed Systems 4(12), pp. 1320-1331, 1993.</raw><contexts><context>ir proposed algorithms require only one extra virtual channel per physical channel, compared to deterministic routing, allowing for an efficient router implementation. For instance, Duato’s algorithm [Dua93] divides the virtual channels associated with each physical channel into two classes: a and b. At each routing step, a message visits adaptively any available virtual channel from class a. If all the </context><context>re forced to share the bandwidth of the physical channels. To reduce the effects of virtual channels multiplexing, Duato [Dua94] has introduced to his original adaptive routing algorithm described in [Dua93] a time-out mechanism when selecting a particular class of virtual channels. When a message is blocked upon reaching a given router, it waits for a fixed time period for one of the virtual channels be</context><context>mance before they can be widely adopted in commercial multicomputers. Except from the models suggested in [Bou94, Oul99] for the simple version of Duato’s algorithm (i.e., with no time-out mechanism) [Dua93], there has not been any model proposed in the literature for any other adaptive routing algorithms, e.g. that of [Dua94, Lin93, Su93]. As a result, most existing studies [Lin93, Su93], including Duat</context><context>erwise, it suffers time-out, and as a result the message has to wait for the deterministic virtual channel corresponding to the lowest dimension still to be crossed according to deterministic routing [Dua93]. It is assumed that the probability of time-out at a given channel is independent of the subsequent channels. 2.3 The Communication Model Even though the proposed model can deal with different traffi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30186"><authors>J Duato</authors><title>Improving the efficiency of virtual channels with time-dependent selection functions, Future Generation Computer Systems 10(10</title><year>1994</year><pages>45--58</pages><raw>J. Duato, Improving the efficiency of virtual channels with time-dependent selection functions, Future Generation Computer Systems 10(10), pp. 45-58, 1994.</raw><contexts><context>r deterministic routing are reduced when the traffic contains strong degree of communication locality. This paper proposes a new analytical model of an adaptive routing algorithm proposed by Duato in [Dua94]. The main feature of this algorithm is the use of a time-out selection function for assigning virtual channels. This has the advantage of reducing virtual channels multiplexing to improve the network</context><context>formance levels are achieved compared to deterministic routing when the traffic was uniform. However, adaptive routing performed poorly when the traffic exhibited strong communication locality. Duato [Dua94] has attributed this performance degradation in the presence of communication locality to the overhead associated with virtual channels multiplexing. When traffic is local, messages make a few hops to</context><context>xing of virtual channels causes an increase in message latency since messages are forced to share the bandwidth of the physical channels. To reduce the effects of virtual channels multiplexing, Duato [Dua94] has introduced to his original adaptive routing algorithm described in [Dua93] a time-out mechanism when selecting a particular class of virtual channels. When a message is blocked upon reaching a gi</context><context>rtual channels belonging to class a that brings it closer to its destination. If it does not succeed, it waits for a virtual channel belonging to class b. Using the time-out mechanism as suggested in [Dua94] reduces the overhead due to virtual channelssmultiplexing. Simulation experiments reported in [Dua94] have confirmed that the new resulting adaptive routing algorithm leads to good performance improv</context><context>sed in the literature for any other adaptive routing algorithms, e.g. that of [Dua94, Lin93, Su93]. As a result, most existing studies [Lin93, Su93], including Duato’s study of the time-out mechanism [Dua94], have resorted to software simulation to evaluate the performance merits of adaptive routing algorithms. This paper presents a new analytical model to calculate the message latency in wormhole-routed</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30187"><authors>J Duato,S Yalamanchili,L Ni</authors><title>Interconnection Networks: An Engineering Approach</title><year>1997</year><publisher>IEEE CS Press</publisher><raw>J. Duato, S. Yalamanchili and L. Ni, Interconnection Networks: An Engineering Approach (IEEE CS Press, 1997).</raw></citation><citation id="30188"><authors>M Fillo,S W Keckler,W J Dally,N P Carter,A Chang,Y Gurevich,W S Lee</authors><title>The M-Machine multicomputer, Int</title><venue>Journal of Parallel Programming</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>183--212</pages><volume>25</volume><raw>M. Fillo, S.W. Keckler, W.J. Dally, N.P. Carter, A. Chang, Y. Gurevich, W.S. Lee, The M-Machine multicomputer, Int. Journal of Parallel Programming, 25(3), pp. 183-212, 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="30189"><authors>P C Hu,L Kleinrock</authors><title>A queueing model for wormhole routing with timeout</title><venue>Proc. 4th Int. Conf. on Computer Communications and Networks</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>584--593</pages><raw>P. C. Hu, L. Kleinrock, A queueing model for wormhole routing with timeout, Proc. 4th Int. Conf. on Computer Communications and Networks, pp. 584-593, 1995.</raw></citation><citation id="30190"><authors>J Kim,C R Das</authors><title>Hypercube communication delay with wormhole routing</title><venue>IEEE TC</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>806--814</pages><volume>43</volume><raw>J. Kim and C.R. Das, Hypercube communication delay with wormhole routing, IEEE TC 43(7), pp. 806-814, 1994. latency latency</raw></citation><citation id="30191"><authors>L Kleinrock</authors><title>Queueing Systems: Theory, vol.1</title><year>1975</year><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>L. Kleinrock, Queueing Systems: Theory, vol.1, John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, 1975.</raw><contexts><context>tual channel at the lowest dimension is calculated by Ptrλ c . Modelling the deterministic channel as an M/M/1 queue, with a mean arrival rate P λ and service time S , yields the mean waiting time as [Kle75] tr c w d = 1 S P λ S tr c ( 1 − P λ S) tr c Now, averaging over the waiting times seen by a message at one of the adaptive virtual channels (given equation 12) and at the deterministic virtual channe</context><context>elling the local queue in the source node as an M/M/1 queue with a mean arrival rate λ g / V and mean service time S yields the mean waiting time, w s , experienced by a message in the source node as [Kle75] λg S w = V s (17) 1 ⎛ λg ⎞ ⎜ ⎟ ⎜ 1− S S ⎟ ⎝ V ⎠ Having determined the mean network latency, S (given by equation 7), and the mean waiting time in the source node, w s (given by equation 17), we need </context></contexts></citation><citation id="30192"><authors>X Lin,P K Mckinley,L M Lin</authors><title>The message flow model for routing in wormhole-routed networks</title><venue>Proc. International Conference on Parallel Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>294--297</pages><raw>X. Lin, P.K. Mckinley and L.M. Lin, The message flow model for routing in wormhole-routed networks, Proc. International Conference on Parallel Processing, pp. 294-297, 1993.</raw></citation><citation id="30193"><authors>J Laudon,D Lenoski</authors><title>The SGI Origin: a ccNUMA highly scalable server</title><venue>Proc. ACM/IEEE 24th Int. Symp. Computer Architecture</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>241--251</pages><raw>J. Laudon, D. Lenoski, The SGI Origin: a ccNUMA highly scalable server, Proc. ACM/IEEE 24th Int. Symp. Computer Architecture, pp. 241-251, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>lar networks for practical multicomputers due to its desirable properties, including regularity, symmetry, low diameter and high connectivity. The iPSC/860 [Van94], iPSC/2 [Nug88] and SGI Origin 2000 [Lau97] are examples of commercial systems that are based on the hypercube. Existing multicomputers [And97, Fil97, Lau97, Van94] have widely used wormhole routing [Dal90]. This is due to its low buffering re</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30194"><venue>N-Cube Company, NCUBE-2 Processor Manual</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1990</year><raw>N-Cube Company, NCUBE-2 Processor Manual, 1990.</raw></citation><citation id="30195"><authors>L Ni,P K McKinley</authors><title>A survey of wormhole routing techniques in direct networks</title><venue>IEEE Computer</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>62--76</pages><volume>26</volume><raw>L. Ni, P.K. McKinley, A survey of wormhole routing techniques in direct networks, IEEE Computer 26(2), pp. 62-76, 1993.</raw></citation><citation id="30196"><authors>S F Nugent</authors><title>The iPSC/2 direct-connect communication technology</title><venue>Proc. Conf. Hypercube Concurrent Computers &amp; Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1988</year><pages>51--60</pages><volume>1</volume><raw>S.F. Nugent, The iPSC/2 direct-connect communication technology, Proc. Conf. Hypercube Concurrent Computers &amp; Applications (1), pp. 51-60, 1988.</raw><contexts><context>as been one of the most popular networks for practical multicomputers due to its desirable properties, including regularity, symmetry, low diameter and high connectivity. The iPSC/860 [Van94], iPSC/2 [Nug88] and SGI Origin 2000 [Lau97] are examples of commercial systems that are based on the hypercube. Existing multicomputers [And97, Fil97, Lau97, Van94] have widely used wormhole routing [Dal90]. This is</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30197"><authors>M Ould-Khaoua</authors><title>A performance model for Duato’s fully adaptive routing algorithm in k-ary n-cubes</title><venue>IEEE Trans. Computers</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><pages>1--8</pages><volume>48</volume><raw>M. Ould-Khaoua, A performance model for Duato’s fully adaptive routing algorithm in k-ary n-cubes, IEEE Trans. Computers 48(12), pp. 1-8, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>ever, due to the fact that the traffic rates are equal across the network channels, and due to the symmetry of the hypercube, a message sees the same mean waiting time across all the visited channels [Oul99]. A message is blocked at a channel when all the adaptive virtual channels of the remaining dimensions to be visited and also the deterministic virtual channels of the lowest dimension still to be vis</context><context> λg (11) n Due to the symmetry of the hypercube topology and uniformity of traffic on network channels, the mean service time seen by a message at each channel is the same across all network channels [Oul99] and can be approximated by the mean network latency, S (equation 7). Treating the adaptive virtual channels as an M/M/1 queue of impatient customers with deterministic time-out, and with the mean arr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30198"><authors>D A Reed,R M Fujitomo</authors><title>Multicomputer networks: Message based parallel processing</title><year>1987</year><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><raw>D.A. Reed, R.M. Fujitomo, Multicomputer networks: Message based parallel processing, MIT Press, 1987.</raw><contexts><context>d to different distributions (1)sfor message destinations, and consequently to different mean message distances. The following analysis uses the decreasing probability routing distribution defined in [Ree87] as a model of communication locality (it is worth noting that our modelling approach presented here can be equally apply to the other models discussed in [Ree87]). In this model, the probability, p i</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30199"><authors>C Su,K G Shin</authors><title>Adaptive deadlock-free routing in multicomputers using one extra channel</title><venue>Proc. International Conference on Parallel Processing</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>175--182</pages><raw>C. Su and K.G. Shin, Adaptive deadlock-free routing in multicomputers using one extra channel, Proc. International Conference on Parallel Processing, pp. 175-182, 1993.</raw></citation><citation id="30200"><authors>H C Tijms</authors><title>Stochastic modelling and analysis: A computational approach</title><raw>H.C. Tijms, Stochastic modelling and analysis: A computational approach</raw><contexts><context>ence time [Dal65, Tij86]; customers that do not receive service within a fixed time period, τ , leave the system. We have found that using M/M/1 queues with deterministic impatient time, suggested in [Tij86], enable us to obtain a simple and practical model that exhibits a reasonable degree of accuracy in predicting message latency (as will be shown later in Section 3). To derive the mean waiting time an</context><context>erministic time-out, and with the mean arrival rate λ c and service time S , yields the mean waiting time and probability of suffering timeout seen by a message at an adaptive virtual channel as (see [Tij86] for more details) w a = 2 λ S ⎛ S ⎞ c − ⎜ + λc Sτ ⎟e ( 1 − λc S) ⎜ cS ⎟ ⎝1 − λ ⎠ ⎛ −( 1− ⎜ 2 2 S ( 1 − Pt ) ⎜1 − λc S e ⎜ ⎝ 1− λ S e −( 1−λc S) τ S −( 1−λc S) τ Sa λc S) τ a ⎞ ⎟ ⎟ ⎟ ⎠ − Pτ t (12) ( 1</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30201"><authors>B Vanvoorst,S Seidel,E Barscz</authors><title>Workload of an iPSC/860, Proc.Scalable High-Performance Computing Conf</title><year>1994</year><pages>221--228</pages><raw>B. Vanvoorst, S. Seidel, E. Barscz, Workload of an iPSC/860, Proc.Scalable High-Performance Computing Conf., pp. 221-228, 1994. a) simulation model latency b) simulation model latency</raw><contexts><context> The hypercube has been one of the most popular networks for practical multicomputers due to its desirable properties, including regularity, symmetry, low diameter and high connectivity. The iPSC/860 [Van94], iPSC/2 [Nug88] and SGI Origin 2000 [Lau97] are examples of commercial systems that are based on the hypercube. Existing multicomputers [And97, Fil97, Lau97, Van94] have widely used wormhole routing </context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.comp.leeds.ac.uk/ukpew01/proceedings/khonsari.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>734b75508422c4635ce855e97b35ee626da41326</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>