<document id="10.1.1.1.1585"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Inferring White Matter Geometry from Diffusion Tensor MRI: Application to Connectivity Mapping</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract. We introduce a novel approach to the cerebral white matter connectivity mapping from diffusion tensor MRI. DT-MRI is the unique non-invasive technique capable of probing and quantifying the anisotropic diffusion of water molecules in biological tissues. We address the problem of consistent neural fibers reconstruction in areas of complex diffusion profiles with potentially multiple fibers orientations. Our method relies on a global modelization of the acquired MRI volume as a Riemannian manifold M and proceeds in 4 majors steps: First, we establish the link between Brownian motion and diffusion MRI by using the Laplace-Beltrami operator on M. We then expose how the sole knowledge of the diffusion properties of water molecules on M is sufficient to infer its geometry. There exists a direct mapping between the diffusion tensor and the metric of M. Next, having access to that metric, we propose a novel level set formulation scheme to approximate the distance function related to a radial Brownian motion on M. Finally, a rigorous numerical scheme using the exponential map is derived to estimate the geodesics of M, seen as the diffusion paths of water molecules. Numerical experimentations conducted on synthetic and real diffusion MRI datasets illustrate the potentialities of this global approach. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4409"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Christophe Lenglet</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Odyssée Lab, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">clenglet@sophia.inria.fr</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4410"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Rachid Deriche</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Odyssée Lab, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">der@sophia.inria.fr</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4411"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Olivier Faugeras</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Odyssée Lab, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">faugeras@sophia.inria.fr</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29763"><authors>D L Bihan,E Breton,D Lallemand,P Grenier,E Cabanis,Laval-Jeantet</authors><title>M.: MR imaging of intravoxel incoherent motions: Application to diffusion and perfusion in neurologic disorders. Radiology</title><year>1986</year><pages>401--407</pages><raw>Bihan, D.L., Breton, E., Lallemand, D., Grenier, P., Cabanis, E., Laval-Jeantet, M.: MR imaging of intravoxel incoherent motions: Application to diffusion and perfusion in neurologic disorders. Radiology (1986) 401–407</raw><contexts><context>synthetic and real diffusion MRI datasets illustrate the potentialities of this global approach. 1 Introduction Diffusion imaging is a magnetic resonance imaging technique introduced in the mid 1980s [1], [2] which provides a very sensitive probe of biological tissues architecture. Although this method suffered, in its very first years, from severe technical constraints such as acquisition time or mo</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29764"><authors>K Merboldt,W Hanicke,J Frahm</authors><title>Self-diffusion nmr imaging using stimulated echoes</title><venue>J. Magn. Reson</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1985</year><pages>479--486</pages><volume>64</volume><raw>Merboldt, K., Hanicke, W., Frahm, J.: Self-diffusion nmr imaging using stimulated echoes. J. Magn. Reson. 64 (1985) 479–486</raw><contexts><context>etic and real diffusion MRI datasets illustrate the potentialities of this global approach. 1 Introduction Diffusion imaging is a magnetic resonance imaging technique introduced in the mid 1980s [1], [2] which provides a very sensitive probe of biological tissues architecture. Although this method suffered, in its very first years, from severe technical constraints such as acquisition time or motion </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29765"><authors>N Selden,D Gitelman,N Salamon-Murayama,T Parrish,Mesulam</authors><title>M.: Trajectories of cholinergic pathways within the cerebral hemispheres of the human brain. Brain 121</title><year>1998</year><publisher>Faugeras</publisher><volume>2249</volume><raw>Selden, N., Gitelman, D., Salamon-Murayama, N., Parrish, T., Mesulam, M.: Trajectories of cholinergic pathways within the cerebral hemispheres of the human brain. Brain 121 (1998) 2249–2257 12 C. Lenglet, R. Deriche, O. Faugeras</raw><contexts><context>ities such as ultrafast echo-planar methods. In order to understand the neural fibers bundle architecture, anatomists used to perform cerebral dissection, strychnine or chemical markers neuronography [3]. As of today, diffusion MRI is the unique non-invasive technique capable of probing and quantifying the anisotropic diffusion of water molecules in tissues like brain or muscles. As we will see in th</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29766"><authors>P Basser,J Mattiello,LeBihan</authors><title>D.: Estimation of the effective self-diffusion tensor from the NMR spin echo</title><venue>Journal of Magnetic Resonance B</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>247--254</pages><raw>Basser, P., Mattiello, J., LeBihan, D.: Estimation of the effective self-diffusion tensor from the NMR spin echo. Journal of Magnetic Resonance B (1994) 247–254</raw><contexts><context>umber of sampling directions (at least 6, up to several hundreds) provides an exquisite insight into the local orientation of fibers and is known as diffusion-weighted imaging. In 1994, Basser et al. [4] proposed the model, now widely used, of the diffusion tensor featuring an analytic means to precisely describe the three-dimensional nature of anisotropy in tissues. Numerous works have already addre</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29767"><authors>D Tschumperlé,Deriche</authors><title>R.: Variational frameworks for DT-MRI estimation, regularization and visualization</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Tschumperlé, D., Deriche, R.: Variational frameworks for DT-MRI estimation, regularization and visualization. In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003)</raw><contexts><context>scribe the three-dimensional nature of anisotropy in tissues. Numerous works have already addressed the problem of the estimation and regularization of these tensor fields. References can be found in [5], [6], [7], [8], [9]. Motivated by the potentially dramatic improvements that knowledge of anatomical connectivity would bring into the understanding of functional coupling between cortical regions [1</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29768"><authors>C Chefd’hotel,D Tschumperlé,R Deriche,Faugeras</authors><title>O.: Constrained flows on matrix-valued functions : application to diffusion tensor regularization</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ECCV. (2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Chefd’hotel, C., Tschumperlé, D., Deriche, R., Faugeras, O.: Constrained flows on matrix-valued functions : application to diffusion tensor regularization. In: Proceedings of ECCV. (2002)</raw><contexts><context>e the three-dimensional nature of anisotropy in tissues. Numerous works have already addressed the problem of the estimation and regularization of these tensor fields. References can be found in [5], [6], [7], [8], [9]. Motivated by the potentially dramatic improvements that knowledge of anatomical connectivity would bring into the understanding of functional coupling between cortical regions [10], t</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29769"><authors>O Coulon,D Alexander,Arridge</authors><title>S.: A regularization scheme for diffusion tensor magnetic resonance images</title><venue>In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Coulon, O., Alexander, D., Arridge, S.: A regularization scheme for diffusion tensor magnetic resonance images. In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2001)</raw><contexts><context> three-dimensional nature of anisotropy in tissues. Numerous works have already addressed the problem of the estimation and regularization of these tensor fields. References can be found in [5], [6], [7], [8], [9]. Motivated by the potentially dramatic improvements that knowledge of anatomical connectivity would bring into the understanding of functional coupling between cortical regions [10], the st</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29770"><authors>C Westin,S Maier,H Mamata,A Nabavi,F Jolesz,Kikinis</authors><title>R.: Processing and visualization for diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Medical Image Analysis. Volume 6. (2002) 93–108</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Westin, C., Maier, S., Mamata, H., Nabavi, A., Jolesz, F., Kikinis, R.: Processing and visualization for diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of Medical Image Analysis. Volume 6. (2002) 93–108</raw><contexts><context>e-dimensional nature of anisotropy in tissues. Numerous works have already addressed the problem of the estimation and regularization of these tensor fields. References can be found in [5], [6], [7], [8], [9]. Motivated by the potentially dramatic improvements that knowledge of anatomical connectivity would bring into the understanding of functional coupling between cortical regions [10], the study o</context><context>ts our capacity to resolve multiple fibers orientations since local tractography becomes unstable when crossing artificially isotropic regions characterized by a planar or spherical diffusion profile [8]. On the other side, new diffusion imaging methods have been recently introduced in an attempt to better describe the complexity of water motion but at the cost of increased acquisition times. This is</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29771"><authors>Z Wang,B Vemuri,Y Chen,Mareci</authors><title>T.: Simultaneous smoothing and estimation of the tensor field from diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of CVPR Volume I</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>461--466</pages><raw>Wang, Z., Vemuri, B., Chen, Y., Mareci, T.: Simultaneous smoothing and estimation of the tensor field from diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of CVPR Volume I., (2003) 461–466</raw><contexts><context>ensional nature of anisotropy in tissues. Numerous works have already addressed the problem of the estimation and regularization of these tensor fields. References can be found in [5], [6], [7], [8], [9]. Motivated by the potentially dramatic improvements that knowledge of anatomical connectivity would bring into the understanding of functional coupling between cortical regions [10], the study of neu</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29772"><authors>M Guye,G J Parkera,M Symms,P Boulby,C Wheeler-Kingshott,A SalekHaddadi,G Barker,J Duncana</authors><title>Combined functional MRI and tractography to demonstrate the connectivity of the human primary motor cortex in vivo. NeuroImage 19</title><year>2003</year><pages>1349--1360</pages><raw>Guye, M., Parkera, G.J., Symms, M., Boulby, P., Wheeler-Kingshott, C., SalekHaddadi, A., Barker, G., Duncana, J.: Combined functional MRI and tractography to demonstrate the connectivity of the human primary motor cortex in vivo. NeuroImage 19 (2003) 1349–1360</raw><contexts><context>5], [6], [7], [8], [9]. Motivated by the potentially dramatic improvements that knowledge of anatomical connectivity would bring into the understanding of functional coupling between cortical regions [10], the study of neurodegenerative diseases, neurosurgery planning or tumor growth quantification, various methods have been proposed to tackle the issue of cerebral connectivity mapping. Local approach</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29773"><authors>S Mori,B Crain,V Chacko,Zijl</authors><title>P.V.: Three-dimensional tracking of axonal projections in the brain by magnetic resonance imaging. Annals of Neurology 45</title><year>1999</year><pages>265--269</pages><raw>Mori, S., Crain, B., Chacko, V., Zijl, P.V.: Three-dimensional tracking of axonal projections in the brain by magnetic resonance imaging. Annals of Neurology 45 (1999) 265–269</raw><contexts><context>s, neurosurgery planning or tumor growth quantification, various methods have been proposed to tackle the issue of cerebral connectivity mapping. Local approaches based on line propagation techniques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29774"><authors>L Zhukov,Barr</authors><title>A.: Oriented tensor reconstruction: Tracing neural pathways from diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Visualization. (2002) 387–394</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Zhukov, L., Barr, A.: Oriented tensor reconstruction: Tracing neural pathways from diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of Visualization. (2002) 387–394</raw><contexts><context>rosurgery planning or tumor growth quantification, various methods have been proposed to tackle the issue of cerebral connectivity mapping. Local approaches based on line propagation techniques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29775"><authors>M Lazar,D Weinstein,J Tsuruda,K Hasan,K Arfanakis,M Meyerand,B Badie,H Rowley,Field V Haughton,A Alexander</authors><title>A.: White matter tractography using diffusion tensor deflection. In: Human Brain Mapping. Volume 18</title><year>2003</year><pages>306--321</pages><raw>Lazar, M., Weinstein, D., Tsuruda, J., Hasan, K., Arfanakis, K., Meyerand, M., Badie, B., Rowley, H., V.Haughton, Field, A., Alexander, A.: White matter tractography using diffusion tensor deflection. In: Human Brain Mapping. Volume 18. (2003) 306–321</raw><contexts><context> line propagation techniques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limi</context><context>methods which only produce macroscopically satisfying results. With trilinear interpolation of the tensor field and a 4 th order Runge Kutta integration scheme, we used the advection-diffusion method [13] and obtained the results on figure 1. Our global approach is actually more concerned to resolve local ambiguities due to isotropic tensors. We consider synthetic and real data 1 to quantify the quali</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29776"><authors>P Basser,S Pajevic,C Pierpaoli,Duda</authors><title>vivo fiber tractography using DT-MRI data</title><pages>625--632</pages><editors>J., Aldroubi, A.: In</editors><volume>44</volume><raw>Basser, P., Pajevic, S., Pierpaoli, C., Duda, J., Aldroubi, A.: In vivo fiber tractography using DT-MRI data. Magn. Res. Med. 44 (2000) 625–632</raw><contexts><context>propagation techniques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29777"><authors>B Vemuri,Y Chen,M Rao,T McGraw,T Mareci,Wang</authors><title>Z.: Fiber tract mapping from diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of VLSM. (2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Vemuri, B., Chen, Y., Rao, M., McGraw, T., Mareci, T., Wang, Z.: Fiber tract mapping from diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of VLSM. (2001)</raw><contexts><context>ation techniques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation, they</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29778"><authors>J Campbell,K Siddiqi,B Vemuri,Pike</authors><title>G.: A geometric flow for white matter fibre tract reconstruction</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 505–508</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Campbell, J., Siddiqi, K., Vemuri, B., Pike, G.: A geometric flow for white matter fibre tract reconstruction. In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 505–508</raw><contexts><context>techniques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation, they enabl</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29779"><authors>D Tuch</authors><title>Mapping cortical connectivity with diffusion MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 392–394</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Tuch, D.: Mapping cortical connectivity with diffusion MRI. In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 392–394</raw><contexts><context>ques [11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation, they enable us t</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29780"><authors>P Hagmann,J Thiran,L Jonasson,P Vandergheynst,S Clarke,P Maeder,Meuli</authors><title>R.: DTI mapping of human brain connectivity: Statistical fiber tracking and virtual dissection. NeuroImage 19</title><year>2003</year><pages>545--554</pages><raw>Hagmann, P., Thiran, J., Jonasson, L., Vandergheynst, P., Clarke, S., Maeder, P., Meuli, R.: DTI mapping of human brain connectivity: Statistical fiber tracking and virtual dissection. NeuroImage 19 (2003) 545–554</raw><contexts><context>11], [12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation, they enable us to gene</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29781"><authors>M Bjornemo,A Brun,R Kikinis,Westin</authors><title>C.: Regularized stochastic white matter tractography using diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of MICCAI. (2002) 435–442</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Bjornemo, M., Brun, A., Kikinis, R., Westin, C.: Regularized stochastic white matter tractography using diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of MICCAI. (2002) 435–442</raw><contexts><context>12] provide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation, they enable us to generate r</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29782"><authors>G Parker,Alexander</authors><title>D.: Probabilistic monte carlo based mapping of cerebral connections utilising whole-brain crossing fibre information</title><venue>In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2003) 684–695</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Parker, G., Alexander, D.: Probabilistic monte carlo based mapping of cerebral connections utilising whole-brain crossing fibre information. In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2003) 684–695</raw><contexts><context>ovide fast algorithms and have been augmented to incorporate some natural constraints such as regularity, stochastic behavior and even local non-Gaussianity ([13], [14], [15], [16], [17], [18], [19], [20]). All these efforts aim to overcome the intrinsic ambiguity of the diffusion tensor related to white matter partial volume effects. Bearing in mind this limitation, they enable us to generate relativ</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29783"><title>angular resolution diffusion imaging reveals intravoxel white matter fiber heterogeneity</title><pages>577--582</pages><editors>Tuch, D., Reese, T., Wiegell, M., Makris, N., Belliveau, J., Wedeen, V.: High</editors><volume>48</volume><raw>Tuch, D., Reese, T., Wiegell, M., Makris, N., Belliveau, J., Wedeen, V.: High angular resolution diffusion imaging reveals intravoxel white matter fiber heterogeneity. Magn. Res. Med. 48 (2002) 577–582</raw><contexts><context>have been recently introduced in an attempt to better describe the complexity of water motion but at the cost of increased acquisition times. This is a case of high angular diffusion weighted imaging [21], [22] where the variance of the signal could give important information on the multimodal aspect of diffusion. Diffusion Spectrum Imaging [23], [24] provides, at each voxel, an estimation of the prob</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29784"><authors>L Frank</authors><title>Characterization of anisotropy in high angular resolution diffusionweighted MRI</title><venue>Magn. Res. Med</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>1083--1099</pages><volume>47</volume><raw>Frank, L.: Characterization of anisotropy in high angular resolution diffusionweighted MRI. Magn. Res. Med 47 (2002) 1083–1099</raw><contexts><context>een recently introduced in an attempt to better describe the complexity of water motion but at the cost of increased acquisition times. This is a case of high angular diffusion weighted imaging [21], [22] where the variance of the signal could give important information on the multimodal aspect of diffusion. Diffusion Spectrum Imaging [23], [24] provides, at each voxel, an estimation of the probabilit</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29785"><authors>D Tuch,M Wiegell,T Reese,J Belliveau,Weeden</authors><title>V.: Measuring corticocortical connectivity matrices with diffusion spectrum imaging</title><venue>In: Int. Soc. Magn. Reson. Med. Volume 9. (2001) 502  White Matter Geometry from DT-MRI 13</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Tuch, D., Wiegell, M., Reese, T., Belliveau, J., Weeden, V.: Measuring corticocortical connectivity matrices with diffusion spectrum imaging. In: Int. Soc. Magn. Reson. Med. Volume 9. (2001) 502 Inferring White Matter Geometry from DT-MRI 13</raw><contexts><context>his is a case of high angular diffusion weighted imaging [21], [22] where the variance of the signal could give important information on the multimodal aspect of diffusion. Diffusion Spectrum Imaging [23], [24] provides, at each voxel, an estimation of the probability density function of water molecules and has been shown to be a particularly accurate means to access the whole complexity of the diffus</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29786"><authors>C Lin,V Weeden,J Chen,C Yao,Tseng</authors><title>W.I.: Validation of diffusion spectrum magnetic resonance imaging with manganese-enhanced rat optic tracts and ex vivo phantoms. NeuroImage 19</title><year>2003</year><pages>482--495</pages><raw>Lin, C., Weeden, V., Chen, J., Yao, C., Tseng, W.I.: Validation of diffusion spectrum magnetic resonance imaging with manganese-enhanced rat optic tracts and ex vivo phantoms. NeuroImage 19 (2003) 482–495</raw><contexts><context> a case of high angular diffusion weighted imaging [21], [22] where the variance of the signal could give important information on the multimodal aspect of diffusion. Diffusion Spectrum Imaging [23], [24] provides, at each voxel, an estimation of the probability density function of water molecules and has been shown to be a particularly accurate means to access the whole complexity of the diffusion pr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29787"><authors>R Bammer,M Auer,S Keeling,Augustin</authors><title>Diffusion tensor imaging using single-shot sense-EPI</title><pages>128--136</pages><editors>M., Stables, L., Prokesch, R., Stollberger, R., Moseley, M., Fazekas, F</editors><volume>48</volume><raw>Bammer, R., Auer, M., Keeling, S., Augustin, M., Stables, L., Prokesch, R., Stollberger, R., Moseley, M., Fazekas, F.: Diffusion tensor imaging using single-shot sense-EPI. Magn. Res. Med. 48 (2002) 128–136</raw><contexts><context>er molecules and has been shown to be a particularly accurate means to access the whole complexity of the diffusion process in biological tissues. In favor of these promising modalities, parallel MRI [25] will reduce the acquisition time in a near future and thus permit high resolution imaging. More global algorithms such as [26] have been proposed to better handle the situations of false planar or sp</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29788"><authors>J F Mangin,C Poupon,Y Cointepas,D Rivière,D Papadopoulos-Orfanos,C A Clark,J Régis,Bihan</authors><title>D.L.: A framework based on spin glass models for the inference of anatomical connectivity from diffusion-weighted MR data</title><venue>NMR in Biomedicine 15</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>481--492</pages><raw>Mangin, J.F., Poupon, C., Cointepas, Y., Rivière, D., Papadopoulos-Orfanos, D., Clark, C.A., Régis, J., Bihan, D.L.: A framework based on spin glass models for the inference of anatomical connectivity from diffusion-weighted MR data. NMR in Biomedicine 15 (2002) 481–492</raw><contexts><context>biological tissues. In favor of these promising modalities, parallel MRI [25] will reduce the acquisition time in a near future and thus permit high resolution imaging. More global algorithms such as [26] have been proposed to better handle the situations of false planar or spherical tensors (with fibers crossings) and to propose some sort of likelihood of connection. In [27], the authors make use of </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29789"><authors>G Parker,C Wheeler-Kingshott,Barker</authors><title>G.: Estimating distributed anatomical connectivity using fast marching methods and diffusion tensor imaging. Trans. Med. Imaging 21</title><year>2002</year><pages>505--512</pages><raw>Parker, G., Wheeler-Kingshott, C., Barker, G.: Estimating distributed anatomical connectivity using fast marching methods and diffusion tensor imaging. Trans. Med. Imaging 21 (2002) 505–512</raw><contexts><context>global algorithms such as [26] have been proposed to better handle the situations of false planar or spherical tensors (with fibers crossings) and to propose some sort of likelihood of connection. In [27], the authors make use of the major eigenvector field and in [28] the full diffusion tensor provides the metric of a Riemannian manifold but this was not exploited to propose intrinsic schemes.sInferr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29790"><authors>L O’Donnell,S Haker,Westin</authors><title>C.: New approaches to estimation of white matter connectivity in diffusion tensor MRI: Elliptic PDEs and geodesics in a tensor-warped space</title><venue>In: Proceedings of MICCAI</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>459--466</pages><raw>O’Donnell, L., Haker, S., Westin, C.: New approaches to estimation of white matter connectivity in diffusion tensor MRI: Elliptic PDEs and geodesics in a tensor-warped space. In: Proceedings of MICCAI. (2002) 459–466.</raw><contexts><context>e the situations of false planar or spherical tensors (with fibers crossings) and to propose some sort of likelihood of connection. In [27], the authors make use of the major eigenvector field and in [28] the full diffusion tensor provides the metric of a Riemannian manifold but this was not exploited to propose intrinsic schemes.sInferring White Matter Geometry from DT-MRI 3 We derive a novel approac</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29791"><authors>N Ikeda,Watanabe</authors><venue>S.: Stochastic Differential Equations and Diffusion Processes. North-Holland Mathematical Library</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1989</year><raw>Ikeda, N., Watanabe, S.: Stochastic Differential Equations and Diffusion Processes. North-Holland Mathematical Library (1989)</raw><contexts><context>tal solution associated with L (solution of equation 2). On manifolds, constructing this solution is a tough task, but for our problem, we only need to characterize L. Further details can be found in [29]. We denote by V d = C([0, ∞[→ R d ) the set of d-dimensional continuous functions and by B(V d ) the topological σ-algebra on V d . Then, Definition 1. A d-dimensional continuous process X is a V d -</context><context>inition D(L)) and on the Brownian motion Xt, it is possible to define an L-diffusion process on a Riemannian manifold M from the d-dimensional stochastic process Xt. We refer the interested reader to [29]. We focus, as in [32], on the case of a diffusion process with time-independent infinitesimal generator L, assumed to be smooth and non-degenerate elliptic. We introduce ∆M the Laplace-Beltrami diffe</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29792"><authors>A Einstein</authors><title>Investigations on the Theory of the Brownian Movement. Dover Pubns</title><year>1956</year><raw>Einstein, A.: Investigations on the Theory of the Brownian Movement. Dover Pubns (1956)</raw><contexts><context>= ∇.(D∇C) = LC (2) In anisotropic cerebral tissues, water molecules motion varies in direction depending on obstacles such as axonal membranes. The positive definite order-2 tensor D has been related [30] to the root mean square of the diffusion distance by D = 1 6t 〈(x − x0)(x − x0) T 〉 (〈.〉 denotes an ensemble average). This is directly related to the minimal fundamental solution of equation 2 for a</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29793"><authors>N Sochen,R Deriche,Lopez-Perez</authors><title>L.: The beltrami flow over implicit manifolds</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Sochen, N., Deriche, R., Lopez-Perez, L.: The beltrami flow over implicit manifolds. In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003)</raw><contexts><context>ounterparts when moving from linear spaces, such as R d , to Riemannian manifolds. Explicit derivation of p is non-trivial in that case and the Laplace-Beltrami operator, well known in image analysis [31], will be of particular importance to define L.sInferring White Matter Geometry from DT-MRI 5 3 White Matter as a Riemannian Manifold 3.1 Geometry of a Manifold from Diffusion Processes We now want to</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29794"><authors>de Lara</authors><title>M.: Geometric and symmetry properties of a nondegenerate diffusion process. An. of Probability 23</title><year>1995</year><pages>1557--1604</pages><raw>de Lara, M.: Geometric and symmetry properties of a nondegenerate diffusion process. An. of Probability 23 (1995) 1557–1604</raw><contexts><context>he Brownian motion Xt, it is possible to define an L-diffusion process on a Riemannian manifold M from the d-dimensional stochastic process Xt. We refer the interested reader to [29]. We focus, as in [32], on the case of a diffusion process with time-independent infinitesimal generator L, assumed to be smooth and non-degenerate elliptic. We introduce ∆M the Laplace-Beltrami differential operator such </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29795"><authors>M Liao</authors><title>Symmetry groups of markov processes</title><venue>Anal. of Prob</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1992</year><pages>563--578</pages><volume>20</volume><raw>Liao, M.: Symmetry groups of markov processes. Anal. of Prob. 20 (1992) 563–578</raw><contexts><context>ols of the metric {gij}. ∆M is second order, strictly elliptic. At that point of our analysis, it turns out that constructing the infinitesimal generator L of our diffusion process boils down to (see [33]): Definition 3. The operator L is said to be an intrinsic Laplacian generating a Brownian motion on M if L = 1 2 ∆M . Thus, for a smooth and non-degenerate elliptic differential operator on M of the </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29796"><authors>E Hsu</authors><title>Stochastic Analysis on Manifolds. Volume 38</title><venue>of Graduate Studies in Mathematics. AMS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>Hsu, E.: Stochastic Analysis on Manifolds. Volume 38 of Graduate Studies in Mathematics. AMS (2001)</raw><contexts><context>ibers in the white matter) as the characteristics lines of the differential operator L we can easily extend the concept of radial process for that type of stochastic motion on a Riemannian manifold M [34]. Let us fix a reference point x0 ∈ M and let r(x) = φ(x0, x) be the Riemannian distance between x and x0. Then we define the radial process rt = r(Xt). The function r : M → R + has a well behaved sin</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29797"><authors>C Mantegazza,Mennucci</authors><title>A.: Hamilton–jacobi equations and distance functions on Riemannian manifolds</title><venue>App. Math. and Optim</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>1--25</pages><volume>47</volume><raw>Mantegazza, C., Mennucci, A.: Hamilton–jacobi equations and distance functions on Riemannian manifolds. App. Math. and Optim. 47 (2002) 1–25</raw><contexts><context> G = {gij} the metric tensor, this writes √ v T Gv. Then, by setting H(x, p) = |p| − 1, we will work on the following theorem (for details on viscosity solutions on a Riemannian manifold, we refer to [35]) Theorem 1. The distance function φ is the unique viscosity solution of the Hamilton-Jacobi problem � |gradφ| = 1 in M \ K (3) φ(x) = 0 when x ∈ K in the class of bounded uniformly continuous functio</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29798"><authors>S Osher</authors><title>A level set formulation for the solution of the dirichlet problem for a hamilton-Jacobi equations</title><venue>SIAM Journal on Mathematical Analysis</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>1145--1152</pages><volume>24</volume><raw>Osher, S.: A level set formulation for the solution of the dirichlet problem for a hamilton-Jacobi equations. SIAM Journal on Mathematical Analysis 24 (1993) 1145–1152</raw><contexts><context>ue function of the minimum arrival time problem. This will enable us to solve equation 3 as a dynamic problem and thus to take advantage of the great flexibility of Level Set methods. On the basis of [36], [37], [38] and [39], we reformulate equation 3 by considering φ as the zero level set of a function ψ and requiring that the evolution of ψ generates φ so that ψ(x, t) = 0 ⇔ t = φ(x) (4) Osher ([36]</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29799"><authors>J Sethian</authors><title>Level Set Methods</title><year>1996</year><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>Sethian, J.: Level Set Methods. Cambridge University Press (1996)</raw><contexts><context>ction of the minimum arrival time problem. This will enable us to solve equation 3 as a dynamic problem and thus to take advantage of the great flexibility of Level Set methods. On the basis of [36], [37], [38] and [39], we reformulate equation 3 by considering φ as the zero level set of a function ψ and requiring that the evolution of ψ generates φ so that ψ(x, t) = 0 ⇔ t = φ(x) (4) Osher ([36]) show</context><context>ne so that it satisfies the usual jump and entropy conditions and converges towards the unique viscosity solution of interest. References can be found in [40]. On the basis of the Engquist-Osher flux [37] and the approach by Kimmel-Amir-Bruckstein for level set distance computation on 2D manifolds [41], we propose the following numerical flux for our quadratic Hamiltonian dψ T G −1 dψ: |gradψ| 2 = 3� </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29800"><authors>Y H Tsai,Y Giga,Osher</authors><title>S.: A level set approach for computing discontinuous solutions of Hamilton–Jacobi equations</title><venue>Math. Comput</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><pages>159--181</pages><volume>72</volume><raw>Tsai, Y.H., Giga, Y., Osher, S.: A level set approach for computing discontinuous solutions of Hamilton–Jacobi equations. Math. Comput. 72 (2003) 159–181</raw><contexts><context>of the minimum arrival time problem. This will enable us to solve equation 3 as a dynamic problem and thus to take advantage of the great flexibility of Level Set methods. On the basis of [36], [37], [38] and [39], we reformulate equation 3 by considering φ as the zero level set of a function ψ and requiring that the evolution of ψ generates φ so that ψ(x, t) = 0 ⇔ t = φ(x) (4) Osher ([36]) showed by </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29801"><authors>Y Chen,Y Giga,Goto</authors><title>S.: Uniqueness and existence of viscosity solutions of generalized mean curvature flow equations</title><venue>Journal on Differential Geometry</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>749--786</pages><volume>33</volume><raw>Chen, Y., Giga, Y., Goto, S.: Uniqueness and existence of viscosity solutions of generalized mean curvature flow equations. Journal on Differential Geometry 33 (1991) 749–786</raw><contexts><context>nimum arrival time problem. This will enable us to solve equation 3 as a dynamic problem and thus to take advantage of the great flexibility of Level Set methods. On the basis of [36], [37], [38] and [39], we reformulate equation 3 by considering φ as the zero level set of a function ψ and requiring that the evolution of ψ generates φ so that ψ(x, t) = 0 ⇔ t = φ(x) (4) Osher ([36]) showed by using The</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29802"><authors>R LeVeque</authors><title>Numerical methods for conservation laws</title><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Birkhäuser, Basel</pubAddress><raw>LeVeque, R.: Numerical methods for conservation laws. Birkhäuser, Basel (1992)</raw><contexts><context>ux |gradψ| 2 and that is consistent and monotone so that it satisfies the usual jump and entropy conditions and converges towards the unique viscosity solution of interest. References can be found in [40]. On the basis of the Engquist-Osher flux [37] and the approach by Kimmel-Amir-Bruckstein for level set distance computation on 2D manifolds [41], we propose the following numerical flux for our quadr</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29803"><authors>R Kimmel,A Amir,Bruckstein</authors><title>A.: Finding shortest paths on surfaces using level set propagation</title><venue>Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><pages>635--640</pages><volume>17</volume><raw>Kimmel, R., Amir, A., Bruckstein, A.: Finding shortest paths on surfaces using level set propagation. Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence 17 (1995) 635–640</raw><contexts><context>osity solution of interest. References can be found in [40]. On the basis of the Engquist-Osher flux [37] and the approach by Kimmel-Amir-Bruckstein for level set distance computation on 2D manifolds [41], we propose the following numerical flux for our quadratic Hamiltonian dψ T G −1 dψ: |gradψ| 2 = 3� i=1 g ii (max(D − xi ψ, 0)2 + min(D + xi ψ, 0)2 ) + 3� g ij minmod(D + xiψ, D− xiψ)minmod(D+ xj ψ, </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29804"><authors>X Liu,S Osher,Chan</authors><title>T.: Weighted essentially non oscillatory schemes</title><venue>J. Comput. Phys</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>200--212</pages><volume>115</volume><raw>Liu, X., Osher, S., Chan, T.: Weighted essentially non oscillatory schemes. J. Comput. Phys. 115 (1994) 200–212</raw><contexts><context>ion has also been done by using WENO schemes in order to increase the accuracy of the method. They consist of a convex combination of nth (we take n = 5) order polynomial approximation of derivatives [42]. A classical narrow band implementation is used to speed up the computations. 4.3 Numerical Scheme for the Geodesics Estimation We finally derive an intrinsic method for geodesics computation in orde</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>ftp://ftp-sop.inria.fr/odyssee/Publications/2004/lenglet-deriche-etal:04.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>a41ff44ddba48ce46b6d78033bca40c9a471f5e9</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>