<document id="10.1.1.1.1538"><clusterid>839</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Complex Systems Modeling</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">This paper addresses the simulation of the dynamics of complex systems by using hierarchical graph and multi-agent system. A complex system is composed of numerous interacting parts that can be described recursively. First we summarize the hierarchical aspect of the complex system. We then present a description of hierarchical graph as a data structure for structural modeling in parallel with dynamics simulation by agents. This method can be used by physiological modelers, ecological modelers, etc as well as in other domains that are considered as complex systems. An example issued from physiology will illustrate this approach.</abstract><year src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2003</year><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Christophe Lecerf Thi</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28851"><clusterid>840</clusterid><authors>A Aiello</authors><title>Environnement Orienté Objet de Modélisation et de Simulation à Evénements Discrets de Systèmes Complexes</title><venue>U.F.R. Sciences et Techniques, L’UNIVERSITE DE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>14--1</pages><pubAddress>CORSE</pubAddress><raw>Aiello, A. (1997). Environnement Orienté Objet de Modélisation et de Simulation à Evénements Discrets de Systèmes Complexes. U.F.R. Sciences et Techniques, L’UNIVERSITE DE CORSE: 141.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28852"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>J S C,Barry L Nelson,David M Nicol</authors><venue>Discrete-Event System Simulation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><raw>Jerry Banks (Editor), J. S. C., Barry L. Nelson, David M. Nicol (2000). Discrete-Event System Simulation, Prentice Hall.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28853"><clusterid>841</clusterid><authors>G A Chauvet</authors><title>Hierarchical functional organization of formal biological systems: a dynamical approach. I. An increase of complexity by self-association increases the domain of stability of a biological system</title><venue>Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>425--444</pages><volume>339</volume><raw>Chauvet G.A., (1993a). Hierarchical functional organization of formal biological systems: a dynamical approach. I. An increase of complexity by self-association increases the domain of stability of a biological system. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences, 339, 425-444.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28854"><clusterid>841</clusterid><authors>G A Chauvet</authors><title>Hierarchical functional organization of formal biological systems: a dynamical approach. II.The concept of nonsymmetry leads to a criterion of evolution deduced from an optimum principle of the (O-FBS) sub-system</title><venue>Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>445--461</pages><volume>339</volume><raw>Chauvet G.A., (1993b). Hierarchical functional organization of formal biological systems: a dynamical approach. II.The concept of nonsymmetry leads to a criterion of evolution deduced from an optimum principle of the (O-FBS) sub-system, Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences, 339, 445-461.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28855"><clusterid>841</clusterid><authors>G A Chauvet</authors><title>Hierarchical functional organization of formal biological systems: a dynamical approach. III. The concept of nonlocality leads to a field theory describing the dynamics at each level of organization of the (D-FBS) sub-system</title><venue>Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>463--481</pages><volume>339</volume><raw>Chauvet G.A., (1993c). Hierarchical functional organization of formal biological systems: a dynamical approach. III. The concept of nonlocality leads to a field theory describing the dynamics at each level of organization of the (D-FBS) sub-system, Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences, 339, 463-481.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28856"><clusterid>842</clusterid><authors>A G Chauvet</authors><title>Theoretical systems in Biology: Hierarchical and Functional Integration. Volume II: Tissues and Organs</title><year>1996</year><pubAddress>Oxford: Pergamon, II</pubAddress><raw>A.G. Chauvet, Theoretical systems in Biology: Hierarchical and Functional Integration. Volume II: Tissues and Organs, Oxford: Pergamon, II , 1996</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28857"><clusterid>842</clusterid><authors>A G Chauvet</authors><title>Theoretical systems in Biology: Hierarchical and Functional Integration. Volume III: Organization and regulation</title><venue>Pergamon, III</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><pubAddress>Oxford</pubAddress><raw>A.G. Chauvet, Theoretical systems in Biology: Hierarchical and Functional Integration. Volume III: Organization and regulation, Oxford: Pergamon, III , 1996</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28858"><clusterid>843</clusterid><authors>A G Chauvet</authors><title>S-propagators: a formalism for the hierarchical organization of physiological systems. Application to the nervous and the respiratory system</title><venue>Inter Journal of General Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><pages>1--53</pages><volume>28</volume><raw>A.G. Chauvet, S-propagators: a formalism for the hierarchical organization of physiological systems. Application to the nervous and the respiratory system, Inter Journal of General Systems, 28 (1)53-96, 1999</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28859"><clusterid>844</clusterid><authors>K M Chandy,J Misra</authors><title>Distributed Simulation: A case study in Design and Verification of Distributed Programs</title><venue>IEEE Transactions of Software Engineering</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1979</year><pages>440--452</pages><volume>5</volume><raw>Chandy K.M., Misra J. (1979). Distributed Simulation: A case study in Design and Verification of Distributed Programs, IEEE Transactions of Software Engineering, SE-5(5), 440-452.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28860"><clusterid>845</clusterid><authors>H Van Dyke Parunak,R S,Rick L Riolo</authors><title>Agent-Based Modeling vs. Equation-Based Modeling: A Case Study and Users’ Guide</title><venue>Proceedings of Multi-agent systems and Agent-based Simulation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>H. Van Dyke Parunak, R. S., Rick L. Riolo (1998). Agent-Based Modeling vs. Equation-Based Modeling: A Case Study and Users’ Guide. Proceedings of Multi-agent systems and Agent-based Simulation, Springer.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28861"><clusterid>846</clusterid><authors>G Engels,A S</authors><title>Encapsulated Hierarchical Graphs, Graph Types, and Meta Types</title><year>1995</year><raw>G. Engels, A.S. (1995). Encapsulated Hierarchical Graphs, Graph Types, and Meta Types.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28862"><clusterid>847</clusterid><authors>J V Helden,A Naim,R Mancuso,M Eldridge,L Wernisch,D Gilbert,S J Wodak</authors><title>Representing and analysing molecular and cellular function in the computer , Biol Chem</title><year>2000</year><pages>381--9</pages><raw>Helden J.V., Naim A., Mancuso R.,Eldridge M., Wernisch L., Gilbert D. and Wodak S.J. (2000), Representing and analysing molecular and cellular function in the computer , Biol Chem 381(9-10), 921-35.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28863"><clusterid>848</clusterid><authors>N R Jennings</authors><title>An Agent-based Approach for Building Complex Software Systems</title><venue>ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>35--41</pages><volume>44</volume><raw>Jennings, N. R. An Agent-based Approach for Building Complex Software Systems. ACM 44(4): 35-41.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28864"><clusterid>95</clusterid><authors>A M Law,W D Kelton</authors><title>Simulation, modeling and analysis</title><venue>3 rd ed., MacGraw Hill Intl series</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>Law A.M., Kelton W.D., (1994). Simulation, modeling and analysis, 3 rd ed., MacGraw Hill Intl series.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28865"><clusterid>849</clusterid><authors>C Lecerf,M Bui</authors><title>Modeling physiological function: parallels with distributed processing</title><year>2001</year><publisher>Eurosim</publisher><raw>C. Lecerf, M. Bui. (2001). Modeling physiological function: parallels with distributed processing. Eurosim.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28866"><clusterid>850</clusterid><authors>J Rickel</authors><title>Automated modeling of complex systems to answer prediction question</title><venue>Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>201--260</pages><volume>93</volume><raw>Rickel, J. (1997). Automated modeling of complex systems to answer prediction question. Artificial Intelligence 93: 201-260.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28867"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>R Thomas,R D’Ari</authors><venue>Biological Feedback, CRC Press, Boca Raton</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1990</year><raw>Thomas R., D’Ari R. (1990). Biological Feedback, CRC Press, Boca Raton Florida. Thomas R., (1996).</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28868"><clusterid>851</clusterid><authors>A M Uhrmacher,B Schattenberg</authors><title>Agent in discrete event simulation</title><venue>10TH European Simulation Symposium ‘Simulation in Industry - Simulation Technology: Science and Art’ (ESS’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>129--136</pages><publisher>Publications</publisher><pubAddress>Nottingham, SCS</pubAddress><raw>A. M. Uhrmacher, B. Schattenberg (1998). Agent in discrete event simulation. 10TH European Simulation Symposium ‘Simulation in Industry - Simulation Technology: Science and Art’ (ESS’98), Nottingham, SCS Publications, 129-136.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28869"><clusterid>845</clusterid><authors>H Van Dyke Parunak,R S,Rick L Riolo</authors><title>Agent-Based Modeling vs. Equation-Based Modeling: A Case Study and Users’ Guide</title><venue>Proceedings of Multi-agent systems and Agent-based Simulation</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>H. Van Dyke Parunak, R. S., Rick L. Riolo (1998). Agent-Based Modeling vs. Equation-Based Modeling: A Case Study and Users’ Guide. Proceedings of Multi-agent systems and Agent-based Simulation, Springer.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation><citation id="28870"><clusterid>852</clusterid><authors>M J Wooldridge N R Jennings</authors><title>Intelligent Agents: Theory and Practice</title><venue>The Knowledge Engineering Review</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><pages>115--152</pages><volume>10</volume><raw>M. J. Wooldridge N. R. Jennings. (1995). Intelligent Agents: Theory and Practice. The Knowledge Engineering Review. 10(2). 115-152.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1538</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://e-ifi.org/rivf/2003/proceedings/p93-98.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>