<document id="10.1.1.1.1608"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">in today’s Internet, and Multiprotocol Label Switching</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Differentiated Services (DiffServ) is scalable for deployment</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4468"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Raymond Law</name><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">rlaw@vt.edu</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4469"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Srihari Raghavan</name><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">srihari@vt.edu</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="30162"><authors>B Davie,Y Rekhter</authors><venue>MPLS Technology and Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><pubAddress>San Francisco, CA</pubAddress><raw>B. Davie, and Y. Rekhter, MPLS Technology and Applications, Morgan Kaufmann, San Francisco, CA, 2000</raw><contexts><context>ith the packet, which is used to specify queuing, scheduling, and drop precedence [3]. There are three defined PHBs: (i) Best effort, (ii) Assured Forwarding (AF), and (iii) Expedited Forwarding (EF) [1]. A PHB group is a set of PHBs that must maintain the order of packets in microflows [5]. A Behavior Aggregate (BA) is an aggregate of microflows with the same DSCP [3]. At the ingress node in a DiffS</context><context>price and higher performance. They also offer traffic engineering, resulting in better utilization of network resources such as link capacity as well as the ability to adapt to node and link failures [1]. To deploy MPLS in an IP network, the Shim label header [4] is inserted between the link layer and network layer headers. The Label field identifies the Forwarding Equivalence Class (FEC), which is a</context><context>Entry (NHLFE), in the same manner (i.e. over the same path with the same forwarding treatment). The EXP field can be used to select the appropriate PHB for the packet. MPLS consists of two components [1]. The conventional routing protocol uses the FEC-to-NHLFE mapping (FTN) to forward unlabeled packets. The label binding and distribution uses the Label-to-NHLFE mapping (ILM) to forward labeled packet</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30163"><authors>U Black</authors><title>MPLS and Label Switching Networks</title><venue>Upper Saddle River, NJ, 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher><raw>U. Black, MPLS and Label Switching Networks, Prentice Hall, Upper Saddle River, NJ, 2001</raw><contexts><context>croflows [5]. A Behavior Aggregate (BA) is an aggregate of microflows with the same DSCP [3]. At the ingress node in a DiffServ domain, the DSCP value is determined based on multifield classification [2] of the incoming packet. At the interior nodes, the PHB is determined from the DSCP and appropriate QoS treatment is applied to the packet. At the egress node, the packet is routed to the next hop in </context></contexts></citation><citation id="30164"><authors>S Blake</authors><title>et al, An Architecture for Differentiated Services, RFC 2475</title><year>1998</year><raw>S. Blake et al, An Architecture for Differentiated Services, RFC 2475, December 1998</raw><contexts><context>Simulator (ns-2) [10] to show the fast rerouting feature of MPLS and how it solves the problem of link failures in a DiffServ network. 2 Backgrounds [Raymond Law] 2.1 Differentiated Services DiffServ [3] provides scalable and “better than best-effort” QoS. DiffServ routers is stateless and do not keep track of individual microflows, making it scalable to be deployed in the Internet. The DiffServ Code</context><context>t (DSCP) in the Differentiated Services (DS) field of the IP header identifies the Per Hop Behavior (PHB) associated with the packet, which is used to specify queuing, scheduling, and drop precedence [3]. There are three defined PHBs: (i) Best effort, (ii) Assured Forwarding (AF), and (iii) Expedited Forwarding (EF) [1]. A PHB group is a set of PHBs that must maintain the order of packets in microflo</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30165"><authors>E Rosen,A Viswanathan,R Callon</authors><venue>Multiprotocol Label Switching Architecture, RFC 3031</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>E. Rosen, A. Viswanathan, and R. Callon, Multiprotocol Label Switching Architecture, RFC 3031, January 2001</raw><contexts><context>d at the boundary nodes to ensure the traffic streams conform to the traffic conditioning agreement (TCA) between two domains [2]. 2.2 Multiprotocol Label Switching MPLS Label Switching Routers (LSR) [4] provide fast packet forwarding compared to routers, with lower price and higher performance. They also offer traffic engineering, resulting in better utilization of network resources such as link cap</context><context>col uses the FEC-to-NHLFE mapping (FTN) to forward unlabeled packets. The label binding and distribution uses the Label-to-NHLFE mapping (ILM) to forward labeled packets. A Label Switching Path (LSP) [4] is set up as follows. The ingress LSR sends a Label Request message toward the egress LSR, which sends back a Label Mapping message back to the ingress LSR [1]. During the propagation of these label </context><context>m to forward labeled packets through a MPLS domain. The ingress LSR pushes a label to a packetsand the egress LSR pops a label from a packet. Intermediate LSRs perform both a label pop and label push [4]. 3 DiffServ + MPLS [Raymond Law] There are two basic problems for MPLS support of DiffServ. First, the DSCP is carried in the IP header, but the LSRs only examine the label header. Second, the DSCP h</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30166"><authors>D Grossman</authors><title>New Terminology for DiffServ</title><venue>IETF Internet Draft</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><volume>04</volume><raw>D. Grossman, New Terminology for DiffServ, IETF Internet Draft, draft-ietf-DiffServ-new-terms-04.txt, March 2001</raw><contexts><context>here are three defined PHBs: (i) Best effort, (ii) Assured Forwarding (AF), and (iii) Expedited Forwarding (EF) [1]. A PHB group is a set of PHBs that must maintain the order of packets in microflows [5]. A Behavior Aggregate (BA) is an aggregate of microflows with the same DSCP [3]. At the ingress node in a DiffServ domain, the DSCP value is determined based on multifield classification [2] of the i</context><context>ed PHBs) [6]. 3.6 Label-Only-Inferred-PSC LSP (L-LSP) Packets in a microflow must maintain the same order from the ingress LSR to the egress LSR, so they belong to the same PHB Scheduling Class (PSC) [5], which is a PHB group such that the order of packets in the group must be preserved, and are placed in a common queue. The set of BAs whose order must be maintained during transmission constitutes an</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30167"><authors>F Faucheur</authors><title>et al</title><venue>MPLS Support of Differentiated Services, IETF Internet Draft, draft-ietf-mpls-diff-ext-08.txt</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>F. Faucheur et al, MPLS Support of Differentiated Services, IETF Internet Draft, draft-ietf-mpls-diff-ext-08.txt, February 2001</raw><contexts><context>r technologies such as IP, ATM, and Frame Relay. MPLS support for DiffServ over IP is discussed in this paper. Information regarding MPLS support for DiffServ over ATM and Frame Relay can be found in [6]. This paper first explains the concepts behind DiffServ, MPLS, and DiffServ + MPLS. It then presents results from an event-driven simulation using Network Simulator (ns-2) [10] to show the fast rerou</context><context>to the ingress LSR [1]. During the propagation of these label messages, all LSRs on this path use these label information to set up their ILMs so that packets can be forwarded using the label headers [6]. MPLS uses the label swapping mechanism to forward labeled packets through a MPLS domain. The ingress LSR pushes a label to a packetsand the egress LSR pops a label from a packet. Intermediate LSRs p</context><context>of DiffServ. First, the DSCP is carried in the IP header, but the LSRs only examine the label header. Second, the DSCP has 6 bits but the EXP field has only 3 bits. There are two solutions defined in [6] to remedy these two problems: (i) EXP-InferredPSC LSP (E-LSP), and (ii) Label-Only-Inferred-PSC LSP (LLSP). The LSR DiffServ label switching behavior, as discussed below, has four stages which are de</context><context>an be either preconfigured or explicitly signaled during the E-LSP establishment. The LSR determines the PHB to be applied to the incoming packet by looking up the EXP field in the EXP-to-PHB mapping [6]. For L-LSP, the EXP-to-PHB mapping is a function of the PSC carried on the L-LSP, and is set up during the LLSP establishment. Therefore, the PSC (i.e. queuing and scheduling) is already known to the</context><context> DiffServ LSR may perform marking, policing, and shaping on the incoming traffic streams, potentially changing the outgoing PHBs associated with non-conforming packets in the incoming traffic streams [6]. Thus, the incoming and outgoing PHB may be different. If no traffic conditioning is performed, the incoming and outgoing PHB are identical. 3.3 Label Forwarding Each DiffServ LSR must know the DiffS</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30168"><authors>Differentiated IETF</authors><title>Services (DiffServ), http://www.ietf.org/html.charters/DiffServ-charter.html (current 29</title><year>2001</year><raw>IETF, Differentiated Services (DiffServ), http://www.ietf.org/html.charters/DiffServ-charter.html (current 29 Apr. 2001).</raw><contexts><context>nal procedures of E-LSP and L-LSP. This was followed by some simulation results to underline the need of DiffServ + MPLS based on MPLS-based rerouting. Currently, only unicast operation is defined in [7], while multicast communication requires further study. Use of the EXP field to support Explicit Congestion Notification (ECN) together with DiffServ is also under development. Finally, there is not a</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30169"><authors>IETF</authors><title>Multiprotocol Label Swtiching (mpls), http:// www.ietf.org/html.charters/mpls-charter.html (current 29</title><year>2001</year><raw>IETF, Multiprotocol Label Swtiching (mpls), http:// www.ietf.org/html.charters/mpls-charter.html (current 29 Apr. 2001)</raw></citation><citation id="30170"><authors>“The Ns-2</authors><title>Network Simulator – ns-2”, http://www. isi.edu/nsnam/ns/ (current 29</title><year>2001</year><raw>Ns-2, “The Network Simulator – ns-2”, http://www. isi.edu/nsnam/ns/ (current 29 Apr. 2001)</raw></citation><citation id="30171"><authors>F L</authors><title>Faucheur et al</title><venue>MPLS Support of Differentiated Services”, draft-ietf-mpls-diff-ext-09</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>F. L. Faucheur et al., “MPLS Support of Differentiated Services”, draft-ietf-mpls-diff-ext-09, Apr. 2001.</raw><contexts><context>e Relay can be found in [6]. This paper first explains the concepts behind DiffServ, MPLS, and DiffServ + MPLS. It then presents results from an event-driven simulation using Network Simulator (ns-2) [10] to show the fast rerouting feature of MPLS and how it solves the problem of link failures in a DiffServ network. 2 Backgrounds [Raymond Law] 2.1 Differentiated Services DiffServ [3] provides scalable</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30172"><authors>S Murphy</authors><title>The ns MPLS/DiffServ patch”, http://www. teltec.dcu.ie/~murphys/ns-work/mpls-DiffServ/ (current 29</title><year>2001</year><raw>S. Murphy, “The ns MPLS/DiffServ patch”, http://www. teltec.dcu.ie/~murphys/ns-work/mpls-DiffServ/ (current 29 Apr 2001)</raw><contexts><context>reason for MPLS and DiffServ integration, but will not be dealt with here. The environment consists of ns-2 network simulation software in Linux operating system. Two ns-2 patches, the DiffServ patch [11] and the MPLS patch [12] were applied to execute the simulations. 4.2 Simulation Setup and Details Figure 4.1 below shows the topology that was used in the simulation.sFigure 4.1. Simulation Topology </context></contexts></citation><citation id="30173"><authors>G Ahn</authors><title>MPLS Network Simulator”, http://www.raonet. com/introduction.shtml (current 29</title><year>2001</year><raw>G. Ahn, “MPLS Network Simulator”, http://www.raonet. com/introduction.shtml (current 29 Apr 2001)</raw><contexts><context>Serv integration, but will not be dealt with here. The environment consists of ns-2 network simulation software in Linux operating system. Two ns-2 patches, the DiffServ patch [11] and the MPLS patch [12] were applied to execute the simulations. 4.2 Simulation Setup and Details Figure 4.1 below shows the topology that was used in the simulation.sFigure 4.1. Simulation Topology [13] The red-colored nod</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30174"><authors>D Haskin</authors><title>A Method for Setting an Alternative Label Switched Paths to Handle Fast Reroute”, draft-haskinmpls-fast-reroute-05</title><year>2001</year><raw>D. Haskin, “A Method for Setting an Alternative Label Switched Paths to Handle Fast Reroute”, draft-haskinmpls-fast-reroute-05, May 2001.</raw><contexts><context> and the MPLS patch [12] were applied to execute the simulations. 4.2 Simulation Setup and Details Figure 4.1 below shows the topology that was used in the simulation.sFigure 4.1. Simulation Topology [13] The red-colored nodes represent MPLS LSRs, while the nodes, 0,1, and 2 represent source nodes. Node 12 acts as the destination node. Node 0 is the origin node for the User Datagram Protocol (UDP) tra</context><context>th received at the destination node 12 from both the TCP and UDP sources. The fifth and final stage introduces MPLS in these networks and uses an MPLSbased fast rerouting algorithm proposed by Haskin [13]. This fast rerouting scheme helps DiffServ networks by allowing continuous data flow even in the presence of link failures in the networks. 4.3 Simulation Results The simulation results are in the fo</context></contexts></citation><citation id="30175"><authors>K Nichols</authors><title>An Opinionated View of the Current State of IP DiffServ”, ftp://ftp-eng.cisco.com/ftp/kmngroup/docs/kmn_ucbmm.pdf (current 29</title><year>2001</year><raw>K. Nichols, “An Opinionated View of the Current State of IP DiffServ”, ftp://ftp-eng.cisco.com/ftp/kmngroup/docs/kmn_ucbmm.pdf (current 29 Apr 2001).</raw><contexts><context>the research opportunities on the topic of DiffServ + MPLS. Future work should concentrate on simulations with more realistic topologies and different TCP sources like HTTP web traffic as observed in [14]. MPLS-based traffic engineering is another important advantage to DiffServ. Similar experiments can be done to highlight these advantages. Acknowledgement We would like to acknowledge Dr. L. A. DaSil</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ee.vt.edu/~ldasilva/6504/diffserv_mpls_report_final.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>51dfdd25bfe07d93ce6f6b7d9974b63c19fd22da</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>