<document id="10.1.1.1.1586"><clusterid>1718</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Efficient Reasoning with Range and Domain Constraints</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">We show how a tableaux algorithm for   that include range and domain axioms, prove that the extended algorithm is still a decision   concepts w.r.t. such a role box, and show how support for range and domian axioms can be exploited in order to add a new form of absorption optimisation called role absorption. We illustrate the effectiveness of the optimised algorithm by analysing the perfomance of our FaCT++  implementation when classifying terminologies derived from realistic ontologies. 1 </abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2004</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In Proc. of the 2004 Description Logic Workshop (DL 2004</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">41--50</pages><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4313870"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Dmitry Tsarkov</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Department of Computer Science; The University of Manchester</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Manchester, UK</address><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4313871"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Ian Horrocks</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Department of Computer Science; The University of Manchester</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Manchester, UK</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">tsarkov|horrocks@cs.man.ac.uk</email><order src="null">2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29805"><clusterid>1719</clusterid><authors>S Bechhofer,I Horrocks,C Goble,R Stevens</authors><title>OilEd: a reason-able ontology editor for the semantic web</title><venue>In Proc. of the Joint German/Austrian Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (KI 2001), number 2174 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>396--408</pages><publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher><raw>S. Bechhofer, I. Horrocks, C. Goble, and R. Stevens. OilEd: a reason-able ontology editor for the semantic web. In Proc. of the Joint German/Austrian Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (KI 2001), number 2174 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, pages 396–408. Springer-Verlag, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29806"><clusterid>1720</clusterid><authors>Mike Dean,Dan Connolly,Frank van Harmelen,James Hendler,Ian Horrocks,Deborah L McGuinness,Peter F Patel-Schneider,Lynn Andrea Stein</authors><title>OWL web on language 1.0 reference. W3C Proposed Recommendation, 15 December 2003. Available athttp://www.w3.org/TR/owl-ref</title><raw>Mike Dean, Dan Connolly, Frank van Harmelen, James Hendler, Ian Horrocks, Deborah L. McGuinness, Peter F. Patel-Schneider, and Lynn Andrea Stein. OWL web ontology language 1.0 reference. W3C Proposed Recommendation, 15 December 2003. Available athttp://www.w3.org/TR/owl-ref/.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29807"><clusterid>1721</clusterid><authors>D Fensel,F van Harmelen,I Horrocks,D McGuinness,P F Patel-Schneider</authors><title>OIL: An ontology infrastructure for the semantic web</title><venue>IEEE Intelligent Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--1</pages><volume>16</volume><raw>D. Fensel, F. van Harmelen, I. Horrocks, D. McGuinness, and P. F. Patel-Schneider. OIL: An ontology infrastructure for the semantic web. IEEE Intelligent Systems, 16(2):38–45, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29808"><clusterid>1722</clusterid><authors>Volker Haarslev,Ralf Möller</authors><title>High performance reasoning with very large knowledge bases: A practical case study</title><venue>In Proc. of the 17th Int. Joint Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>161--168</pages><raw>Volker Haarslev and Ralf Möller. High performance reasoning with very large knowledge bases: A practical case study. In Proc. of the 17th Int. Joint Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI 2001), pages 161–168, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29809"><clusterid>1723</clusterid><authors>RACER</authors><title>system description</title><venue>In Proc. of the Int. Joint Conf. on Automated Reasoning (IJCAR 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>701--705</pages><publisher>Springer</publisher><volume>2083</volume><raw>Volker Haarslev and Ralf Möller. RACER system description. In Proc. of the Int. Joint Conf. on Automated Reasoning (IJCAR 2001), volume 2083 of Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, pages 701–705. Springer, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29810"><clusterid>1724</clusterid><authors>I Horrocks</authors><title>Implementation and optimisation techniques</title><venue>The Description Logic Handbook: Theory, Implementation, and Applications</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>306--346</pages><editors>In Franz Baader, Diego Calvanese, Deborah McGuinness, Daniele Nardi, and Peter F. Patel-Schneider, editors</editors><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>I. Horrocks. Implementation and optimisation techniques. In Franz Baader, Diego Calvanese, Deborah McGuinness, Daniele Nardi, and Peter F. Patel-Schneider, editors, The Description Logic Handbook: Theory, Implementation, and Applications, pages 306– 346. Cambridge University Press, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29811"><clusterid>1725</clusterid><authors>Ian Horrocks</authors><title>Using an expressive description logic: FaCT or fiction</title><venue>In Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>636--647</pages><raw>Ian Horrocks. Using an expressive description logic: FaCT or fiction? In Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR’98), pages 636–647, 1998.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29812"><clusterid>1726</clusterid><authors>Ian Horrocks,Peter F Patel-Schneider,Frank van Harmelen</authors><title>Reviewing the design of DAML+OIL: An ontology language for the semantic web</title><venue>In Proc. of the 18th Nat. Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>792--797</pages><publisher>AAAI Press</publisher><raw>Ian Horrocks, Peter F. Patel-Schneider, and Frank van Harmelen. Reviewing the design of DAML+OIL: An ontology language for the semantic web. In Proc. of the 18th Nat. Conf. on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2002), pages 792–797. AAAI Press, 2002.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29813"><clusterid>1727</clusterid><authors>Ian Horrocks,Ulrike Sattler,Stephan Tobies</authors><title>Practical reasoning for expressive description logics</title><venue>Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Logic for Programming and Automated Reasoning (LPAR’99), number 1705 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>161--180</pages><editors>In Harald Ganzinger, David McAllester, and Andrei Voronkov, editors</editors><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>Ian Horrocks, Ulrike Sattler, and Stephan Tobies. Practical reasoning for expressive description logics. In Harald Ganzinger, David McAllester, and Andrei Voronkov, editors, Proc. of the 6th Int. Conf. on Logic for Programming and Automated Reasoning (LPAR’99), number 1705 in Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, pages 161–180. Springer, 1999.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29814"><clusterid>1728</clusterid><authors>Ian Horrocks,Stephan Tobies</authors><title>Reasoning with axioms: Theory and practice</title><venue>In Proc. of the 7th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>285--296</pages><raw>Ian Horrocks and Stephan Tobies. Reasoning with axioms: Theory and practice. In Proc. of the 7th Int. Conf. on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR 2000), pages 285–296, 2000.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29815"><clusterid>1729</clusterid><authors>N F Noy,M Sintek,S Decker,M Crubezy,R W Fergerson,M A Musen</authors><title>Creating semantic web contents with Protégé-2000</title><venue>IEEE Intelligent Systems</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>200--1</pages><volume>16</volume><raw>N. F. Noy, M. Sintek, S. Decker, M. Crubezy, R. W. Fergerson, and M. A. Musen. Creating semantic web contents with Protégé-2000. IEEE Intelligent Systems, 16(2):60– 71, 2001.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation><citation id="29816"><clusterid>1809</clusterid><authors></authors><title>A semantic infosphere</title><venue>Proc. of the 2003 International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC 2003), number 2870 in Lecture Notes in Computer Science</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>882--896</pages><editors>Michael Uschold, Peter Clark, Fred Dickey, Casey Fung, Sonia Smith, Stephen Uczekaj Michael Wilke, Sean Bechhofer, and Ian Horrocks</editors><publisher>Springer</publisher><raw>Michael Uschold, Peter Clark, Fred Dickey, Casey Fung, Sonia Smith, Stephen Uczekaj Michael Wilke, Sean Bechhofer, and Ian Horrocks. A semantic infosphere. In Dieter Fensel, Katia Sycara, and John Mylopoulos, editors, Proc. of the 2003 International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC 2003), number 2870 in Lecture Notes in Computer Science, pages 882–896. Springer, 2003.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1586</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://sunsite.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/Publications/CEUR-WS//Vol-104/05Tsarkow-final.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>