<document id="10.1.1.1.1523"><clusterid>620</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Classification And Regression Trees, Cart - A User Manual For Identifying Indicators Of Vulnerability To Famine And Chronic Food Insecurity</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">ue, the Netherlands, Norway, the Philippines, the Rockefeller Foundation, the Rural Industries Research and Development Corporation (Australia), South Africa, the Southern African Development Bank, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, the United Nations Children&apos;s Fund, the United States, and the World Bank. CLASSIFIC ATION AND REGRESSION TREES, CART^TM  A USER MANUAL FOR IDENTIFYING INDIC A TORS OF VULNERABILITY TO FAMINE AND CHRONIC FOOD INSECURITY YISEHAC YOHANNES PATRICK WEBB MICROCOMPUTERS IN POLICY RESEARCH   INTERNATIONAL FOOD POLICY RESEARCH INSTITUTE  CART is a registered trademark of California Statistical Software, Inc. Copyright 1999 by the International Food Policy Research Institute 2033 K Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20006-1002 U.S.A. Library of Congress Cataloging-in-Publication Data available Yohannes, Yisehac Classification and Regression Trees, Cart^TM : A User Manual for Identifying Indicators of Vulnerability to Famine and Chronic Food Insecurity / Yise</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1248">FAMINE AND CHRONIC FOOD INSECURITY YISE HAC YO HAN NES</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4231"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Auser Manualfor</name><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4232"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Yisehac Yohannes</name><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4233"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Patrick Webb</name><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28621"><clusterid>621</clusterid><authors>D A Bloch,M R Segal</authors><title>Empiri cal com pari son of approaches of form ing strata: Using clas si fi ca tion trees to adjust for covari ates. Jour nal of the Ameri can Sta tis ti cal Asso cia tion 84 (408): 897–905</title><year>1989</year><raw>Bloch, D. A., and M. R. Segal. 1989. Empiri cal com pari son of approaches of form ing strata: Using clas si fi ca tion trees to adjust for covari ates. Jour nal of the Ameri can Sta tis ti cal Asso cia tion 84 (408): 897–905.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28622"><clusterid>622</clusterid><authors>Bor ton,J,J Sho ham</authors><title>Map ping vul ner abil ity to food in se cu - rity: Ten ta tive guide lines for WFP coun try of fices. Lon don: Re lief and De vel op ment In sti tute</title><year>1991</year><raw>Bor ton, J., and J. Sho ham. 1991. Map ping vul ner abil ity to food in se cu - rity: Ten ta tive guide lines for WFP coun try of fices. Lon don: Re lief and De vel op ment In sti tute.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28623"><clusterid>623</clusterid><authors>Brei man,J H Fried man L,R A Ol shen,C J Stone</authors><title>Classification and re gres sion trees. Mon terey</title><year>1984</year><publisher>Wadsworth, Inc</publisher><pubAddress>Calif., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Brei man, L., J. H. Fried man, R. A. Ol shen, and C. J. Stone. 1984. Classification and re gres sion trees. Mon terey, Calif., U.S.A.: Wadsworth, Inc.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28624"><clusterid>624</clusterid><authors>Cur rey,B</authors><title>Map ping of ar eas li able to fam ine in Bang la desh. Ph.D. the sis (un pub lished). Ge og ra phy De part ment, Uni ver sity of Ha waii, Hono lulu, Ha waii</title><year>1978</year><pubAddress>U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Cur rey, B. 1978. Map ping of ar eas li able to fam ine in Bang la desh. Ph.D. the sis (un pub lished). Ge og ra phy De part ment, Uni ver sity of Ha waii, Hono lulu, Ha waii, U.S.A.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28625"><clusterid>625</clusterid><authors>Cut ler,B</authors><title>Map ping risks of po ten tial food cri ses in Ethio pia. A re port to the Food Pol icy and Nu tri tion Di vi sion of the Food and Ag ri cul tural Or gani za tion of the United Na tions. Ad dis Ababa. Pho to copy</title><year>1986</year><raw>Cut ler, B. 1986. Map ping risks of po ten tial food cri ses in Ethio pia. A re port to the Food Pol icy and Nu tri tion Di vi sion of the Food and Ag ri cul tural Or gani za tion of the United Na tions. Ad dis Ababa. Pho to copy.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28626"><clusterid>626</clusterid><authors>Down ing,T E</authors><title>Assess ing socio eco nomic vul ner abil ity to fam ine: Frame works, con cepts, and appli ca tions. Work ing Paper No. 2. Arling ton</title><year>1990</year><pubAddress>Va., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Down ing, T. E. 1990. Assess ing socio eco nomic vul ner abil ity to fam ine: Frame works, con cepts, and appli ca tions. Work ing Paper No. 2. Arling ton, Va., U.S.A.: Fam ine Early Warn ing Sys tem Pro ject, Tulane Uni ver sity/Pragma Cor po ra tion.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28627"><clusterid>642</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Re gions/vul ner able groups in FEWS meth od ol ogy</title><year>1993</year><raw>———. 1993. Re gions/vul ner able groups in FEWS meth od ol ogy.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28628"><clusterid>627</clusterid><authors>Memo ran</authors><title>dum for USAID FEWS Pro ject</title><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Rome</pubAddress><volume>2</volume><raw>Memo ran dum for USAID FEWS Pro ject, Rosslyn, Va., U.S.A. FAO (Food and Ag ri cul ture Or gani za tion of the United Na tions). 1998. Guide lines for na tional food in se cu rity and vul ner abil ity in for ma - tion and map ping sys tems (FIVIMS): Back ground and prin ci ples. Re port to the Com mit tee on World Food Se cu rity, Twenty- Fourth Ses sion, Rome, 2–5 June. FAO, Rome.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28629"><clusterid>628</clusterid><authors>FEWS</authors><title>ine Early Warn ing Sys tem Pro ject</title><year>1993</year><raw>FEWS (Fam ine Early Warn ing Sys tem Pro ject). 1993. Vul ner abil ity assess ment. Report pre pared for the United States Agency for Inter na tional Devel op ment’s Bureau for Africa, Office of Analy sis Research and Tech ni cal Serv ices. Wash ing ton, D.C.: Tulane Uni - ver sity/Pragma Cor po ra tion.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28630"><clusterid>629</clusterid><authors>Frank en berger,T</authors><title>ca tors and data col lec tion meth ods for as sess ing house hold food se cu rity. In House hold food se cu rity: Con cepts, in di ca tors</title><year>1992</year><editors>In di</editors><raw>Frank en berger, T. 1992. In di ca tors and data col lec tion meth ods for as sess ing house hold food se cu rity. In House hold food se cu rity: Con cepts, in di ca tors, and meth ods, ed. S. Max well and T. Frank - en berger. Rome: United Na tions Chil drens Fund/In ter na tional Fund for Ag ri cul tural De vel op ment.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28631"><clusterid>630</clusterid><authors>Fryd man,E I Alt man H,D-L Kao</authors><title>In tro duc ing re cur sive par ti tion ing for fi nan cial clas si fi ca tion: The case of fi nan cial dis - tress. Jour nal of Fi nance</title><year>1985</year><pages>269--291</pages><volume>40</volume><raw>Fryd man, H., E. I. Alt man, and D.-L. Kao. 1985. In tro duc ing re cur sive par ti tion ing for fi nan cial clas si fi ca tion: The case of fi nan cial dis - tress. Jour nal of Fi nance 40 (1): 269–291.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28632"><clusterid>631</clusterid><authors>Hutchin son,P Gil ruth C,R Hay,S Marsh,C Lee</authors><title>Geo - graphic in for ma tion sys tems ap pli ca tions in crop as sess ment and fam ine early warn ing. Re port for the Food and Ag ri cul ture Or gani - za tion of the United Na tions. Uni ver sity of Ari zona, Tuc son</title><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Ariz., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Hutchin son, C., P. Gil ruth, R. Hay, S. Marsh, and C. Lee. 1992. Geo - graphic in for ma tion sys tems ap pli ca tions in crop as sess ment and fam ine early warn ing. Re port for the Food and Ag ri cul ture Or gani - za tion of the United Na tions. Uni ver sity of Ari zona, Tuc son, Ariz., U.S.A.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28633"><clusterid>632</clusterid><authors>G V Kass</authors><title>An ex plora tory tech nique for in ves ti gat ing large quan ti ties of cate gori cal data. Ap plied Sta tis tics 29</title><year>1980</year><pages>119--127</pages><volume>2</volume><raw>Kass, G. V. 1980. An ex plora tory tech nique for in ves ti gat ing large quan ti ties of cate gori cal data. Ap plied Sta tis tics 29 (2): 119–127.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28634"><clusterid>633</clusterid><authors>Mad dala,G S</authors><title>Lim ited de pend ent and quali ta tive vari ables in econo met rics. Cam bridge: Cam bridge Uni ver sity</title><year>1983</year><publisher>Press</publisher><raw>Mad dala, G. S. 1983. Lim ited de pend ent and quali ta tive vari ables in econo met rics. Cam bridge: Cam bridge Uni ver sity Press.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28635"><clusterid>634</clusterid><authors>Ma rais,M L,J M Pa tell,M A Wolf son</authors><title>The ex peri men tal de sign of clas si fi ca tion mod els: An ap pli ca tion of re cur sive par ti - tion ing and boot strap ping to com mer cial bank loan clas si fi ca tions</title><year>1985</year><raw>Ma rais, M. L., J. M. Pa tell, and M. A. Wolf son. 1985. The ex peri men tal de sign of clas si fi ca tion mod els: An ap pli ca tion of re cur sive par ti - tion ing and boot strap ping to com mer cial bank loan clas si fi ca tions.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28636"><clusterid>651</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Jour nal of Ac count ing Re search 22 (Sup ple ment</title><year>1984</year><pages>87--114</pages><raw>Jour nal of Ac count ing Re search 22 (Sup ple ment 1984): 87–114.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28637"><clusterid>635</clusterid><authors>Max well,S</authors><title>Food inse cu rity in North Sudan. IDS Dis cus sion Paper 262. Brigh ton, U.K.: Insti tute of Devel op ment Stud ies, Uni - ver sity of Sus sex</title><year>1989</year><raw>Max well, S. 1989. Food inse cu rity in North Sudan. IDS Dis cus sion Paper 262. Brigh ton, U.K.: Insti tute of Devel op ment Stud ies, Uni - ver sity of Sus sex.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28638"><clusterid>636</clusterid><authors>Mor gan,J N,R C</authors><title>Mes sen ger. 1973. THAID: A se quen tial search pro gram for the analy sis of nomi nal scale de pend ent vari ables. Tech ni cal re port. In sti tute for So cial Re search, Uni ver sity of Michi - gan, Ann Ar</title><pubAddress>bor, Mich., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Mor gan, J. N., and R. C. Mes sen ger. 1973. THAID: A se quen tial search pro gram for the analy sis of nomi nal scale de pend ent vari ables. Tech ni cal re port. In sti tute for So cial Re search, Uni ver sity of Michi - gan, Ann Ar bor, Mich., U.S.A.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28639"><clusterid>637</clusterid><authors>Mor gan,J N,J A Son quist</authors><title>Prob lems in the analy sis of sur vey data, and a pro posal. Jour nal of Ameri can Sta tis ti cal As so - cia tion 58</title><year>1963</year><pages>415--434</pages><raw>Mor gan, J. N., and J. A. Son quist. 1963. Prob lems in the analy sis of sur vey data, and a pro posal. Jour nal of Ameri can Sta tis ti cal As so - cia tion 58: 415–434.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28640"><clusterid>638</clusterid><authors>Ri ely,F</authors><title>Vul ner abil ity analy sis in the FEWS proj ect. Re port to the United States Agency for In ter na tional De vel op ment. Tu lane Uni ver sity, New Or leans</title><year>1993</year><pubAddress>La., U.S.A</pubAddress><raw>Ri ely, F. 1993. Vul ner abil ity analy sis in the FEWS proj ect. Re port to the United States Agency for In ter na tional De vel op ment. Tu lane Uni ver sity, New Or leans, La., U.S.A. Pho to copy.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28641"><clusterid>639</clusterid><authors>Sea man,J Holt J,P Al len</authors><title>A new ap proach to vul nerabil ity map ping for ar eas at risk of food cri sis</title><venue>In terim re port on the Risk- Mapping Pro ject. Save the Chil dren Fund (UK), Lon</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><raw>Sea man, J., J. Holt, and P. Al len. 1993. A new ap proach to vul nerabil ity map ping for ar eas at risk of food cri sis. In terim re port on the Risk- Mapping Pro ject. Save the Chil dren Fund (UK), Lon don. Pho to copy.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28642"><clusterid>640</clusterid><authors>Sey oum,E Rich ard son S,P Webb,F Ri ely,Y Yo</authors><title>han nes</title><year>1995</year><raw>Sey oum, S., E. Rich ard son, P. Webb, F. Ri ely, and Y. Yo han nes. 1995. Ana lyz ing and map ping food in se cu rity: An ex plora tory “CART” meth od ol ogy ap plied to Ethio pia. Fi nal re port to the United States Agency for In ter na tional De vel op ment. In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute, Wash ing ton, D.C. Pho to copy.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28643"><clusterid>641</clusterid><authors>Srini vasan,V,Y H Kim</authors><title>Credit grant ing: A com para tive analy sis of clas si fi ca tion pro ce dures. Jour nal of Fi nance</title><year>1987</year><pages>665--683</pages><volume>42</volume><raw>Srini vasan, V., and Y. H. Kim. 1987. Credit grant ing: A com para tive analy sis of clas si fi ca tion pro ce dures. Jour nal of Fi nance 42 (3): 665–683.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28644"><clusterid>642</clusterid><authors>Ste in berg,D,P Colla</authors><title>CART: Tree- structured non para met - ric data analy sis</title><year>1995</year><pubAddress>San Di ego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal</pubAddress><raw>Ste in berg, D., and P. Colla. 1995. CART: Tree- structured non para met - ric data analy sis. San Di ego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal ford Sys tems.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28645"><clusterid>643</clusterid><authors>Ste in berg,P Colla D,K Mar tin</authors><title>CART—Clas si fi ca tion and regres sion trees: Sup ple men tary man ual for Win dows</title><year>1998</year><pubAddress>San Diego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal</pubAddress><raw>Ste in berg, D., P. Colla, and K. Mar tin. 1998. CART—Clas si fi ca tion and regres sion trees: Sup ple men tary man ual for Win dows. San Diego, Calif., U.S.A.: Sal ford Sys tems.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28646"><clusterid>644</clusterid><authors>T Teklu,J von Braun,E Zaki</authors><title>Drought and fam ine re la - tion ships in Su dan: Pol icy im pli ca tions. Re search Re port 88. Wash - ing ton, D.C.: In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute</title><year>1991</year><raw>Teklu, T., J. von Braun, and E. Zaki. 1991. Drought and fam ine re la - tion ships in Su dan: Pol icy im pli ca tions. Re search Re port 88. Wash - ing ton, D.C.: In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28647"><clusterid>645</clusterid><authors>P Webb,J von Braun</authors><title>Fam ine and food se cu rity in Ethio - pia: Les sons for Af rica. Lon don</title><year>1994</year><publisher>John Wiley</publisher><raw>Webb, P., and J. von Braun. 1994. Fam ine and food se cu rity in Ethio - pia: Les sons for Af rica. Lon don: John Wiley.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28648"><clusterid>646</clusterid><authors>P Webb,J von Braun,Y Yo</authors><title>han nes</title><year>1992</year><raw>Webb, P., J. von Braun, and Y. Yo han nes. 1992. Fam ine in Ethio pia: Pol icy im pli ca tions of cop ing fail ure at na tional and house hold lev els. Re search Re port 92. Wash ing ton, D.C.: In ter na tional Food Pol icy Re search In sti tute.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28649"><clusterid>647</clusterid><authors>P Webb,E Rich ard son,S Sey oum,Y Yohan nes</authors><title>Vul ner - abil ity map ping and geo graphi cal tar get ing: An explora tory method applied to Ethio pia. Inter na tional Food Pol icy Research Insti tute, Wash ing ton, D.C. Pho to copy</title><year>1994</year><raw>Webb, P., E. Rich ard son, S. Sey oum, and Y. Yohan nes. 1994. Vul ner - abil ity map ping and geo graphi cal tar get ing: An explora tory method applied to Ethio pia. Inter na tional Food Pol icy Research Insti tute, Wash ing ton, D.C. Pho to copy.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation><citation id="28650"><clusterid>648</clusterid><authors>Wil liams,M A,H de Silva,M F Koehn,S I Orn stein</authors><title>Why did so many sav ings and loans go bank rupt? Eco nom ics Let ters (36): 61–66</title><year>1991</year><raw>Wil liams, M. A., H. de Silva, M. F. Koehn, and S. I. Orn stein. 1991. Why did so many sav ings and loans go bank rupt? Eco nom ics Let ters (36): 61–66.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1523</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.ifpri.org/pubs/microcom/micro3.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>