<document id="10.1.1.1.1582"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">ABSTRACT EFFICIENT ANALYSIS OF RARE EVENTS ASSOCIATED WITH INDIVIDUAL BUFFERS</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Over the last decade, importance sampling has been a popular technique for the efficient estimation of rare event probabilities. This paper presents an approach for applying balanced likelihood ratio importance sampling to the problem of quantifying the probability that the content of the second buffer in a two node tandem Jackson network reaches some high level before it becomes empty. Heuristic importance sampling distributions are derived that can be used to estimate this overflow probability in cases where the first buffer capacity is finite or infinite. The proposed importance sampling distributions differ from previous balanced likelihood ratio methods in that they are specified as functions of the contents of the buffers. Empirical results indicate that the relative errors of these importance sampling estimators is bounded independent of the buffer size when the second server is the bottleneck and is bounded linearly in the buffer size otherwise. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4393"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">S. Chick</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4394"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">P. J. Sánchez</name><order>2</order></author><author id="4395"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. Ferrin</name><order>3</order></author><author id="4396"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">D. J. Morrice</name><order>4</order></author><author id="4397"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">In A Tandem</name><order>5</order></author><author id="4398"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Jackson Network</name><order>6</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29720"><authors>C Alexopoulos,B C Shultes</authors><title>The balanced likelihood ratio method for estimating performance measures of highly reliable systems</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><editors>ed. D. J</editors><raw>Alexopoulos, C. and B. C. Shultes. 1998. The balanced likelihood ratio method for estimating performance measures of highly reliable systems. In Proceedings of the 1998 Winter Simulation Conference, ed. D. J.</raw><contexts><context>ss-entropy optimization approach to estimate the overflow probability in three stages by approximating an optimal tilting parameter. The balanced likelihood ratio approach to importance sampling (see Alexopoulos and Shultes 1998, 2001) was developed for analyzing system performance in fault-tolerant repairable systems. This approach has been used to derive importance sampling estimators for limiting system unavailability and</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29721"><authors>C Alexopoulos,B C Shultes</authors><title>Estimating reliability measures for highly dependable systems, using balanced likelihood ratios</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Reliability</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><pages>265--280</pages><volume>50</volume><raw>Alexopoulos, C. and B. C. Shultes. 2001. Estimating reliability measures for highly dependable systems, using balanced likelihood ratios. IEEE Transactions on Reliability 50 (3): 265-280.</raw><contexts><context>The proposed importance sampling method is based on the balanced likelihood ratio approach. This approach was originally proposed to estimate the reliability of fault-tolerant repairable systems (see Alexopoulos and Shultes 2001) and was later adapted to estimate system overflow probabilities in tandem-Jackson networks (see Shultes 2002). A key feature of this approach is that likelihood ratios associated with regenerative c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29722"><authors>S Asmussen,R Y Rubinstein</authors><title>Steady state rare events simulation in queueing models and its complexity properties</title><venue>In Advances in Queueing: Theory, Methods and Open</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><pages>429--462</pages><editors>problems, ed. J. H. Dhashalow</editors><publisher>CRC Press</publisher><pubAddress>Boca Raton, Florida</pubAddress><raw>Asmussen, S., and R.Y. Rubinstein. 1995. Steady state rare events simulation in queueing models and its complexity properties. In Advances in Queueing: Theory, Methods and Open problems, ed. J. H. Dhashalow, CRC Press, Boca Raton, Florida, 429-462.</raw><contexts><context>eliability, particularly the time until one of these events occurs. Importance sampling is gaining popularity as an efficient method for analyzing rare events in queueing and reliability systems (see Asmussen and Rubinstein 1995, Heidelberger 1995). The application of importance sampling involves simulating the model using an auxiliary distribution designed to make the system experience rare events of Ramya Dhamodaran Bruce </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29723"><authors>P T De Boer,D P Kroese,R Y Rubinstein</authors><title>Estimating buffer overflows in three stages using crossentropy</title><year>2002</year><raw>De Boer, P. T., D. P. Kroese, and R. Y. Rubinstein. 2002. Estimating buffer overflows in three stages using crossentropy.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc03papers/062.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>def289ad3edccc385a016e1968156e807b89590a</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>