<document id="10.1.1.1.1585"><clusterid>1677</clusterid><title src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Inferring White Matter Geometry from Diffusion Tensor MRI: Application to Connectivity Mapping</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">We introduce a novel approach to the cerebral white matter  connectivity mapping from di#usion tensor MRI. DT-MRI is the  unique non-invasive technique capable of probing and quantifying the  anisotropic di#usion of water molecules in biological tissues. We address  the problem of consistent neural fibers reconstruction in areas of complex  di#usion profiles with potentially multiple fibers orientations. Our  method relies on a global modelization of the acquired MRI volume as a  Riemannian manifold M and proceeds in 4 majors steps: First, we establish  the link between Brownian motion and di#usion MRI by using the  Laplace-Beltrami operator on M . We then expose how the sole knowledge  of the di#usion properties of water molecules on M is su#cient to  infer its geometry. There exists a direct mapping between the di#usion  tensor and the metric of M . Next, having access to that metric, we propose  a novel level set formulation scheme to approximate the distance  function related to a radial Brownian motion on M . Finally, a rigorous  numerical scheme using the exponential map is derived to estimate the  geodesics of M , seen as the di#usion paths of water molecules. Numerical  experimentations conducted on synthetic and real di#usion MRI datasets  illustrate the potentialities of this global approach.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2004</year><venue src="INFERENCE">in Lecture Notes in Computer Science, T. Pajdla and</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">127--140</pages><volume src="INFERENCE">2004</volume><publisher src="INFERENCE">Springer</publisher><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4313849"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Christophe Lenglet</name><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Odyssée Lab, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">clenglet@sophia.inria.fr</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4313850"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> Rachid Deriche</name><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Odyssée Lab, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">der@sophia.inria.fr</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4313851"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Olivier Faugeras</name><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Odyssée Lab, INRIA Sophia-Antipolis, France</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">faugeras@sophia.inria.fr</email><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29763"><clusterid>1678</clusterid><authors>D L Bihan,E Breton,D Lallemand,P Grenier,E Cabanis,Laval-Jeantet</authors><title>M.: MR imaging of intravoxel incoherent motions: Application to diffusion and perfusion in neurologic disorders. Radiology</title><year>1986</year><pages>401--407</pages><raw>Bihan, D.L., Breton, E., Lallemand, D., Grenier, P., Cabanis, E., Laval-Jeantet, M.: MR imaging of intravoxel incoherent motions: Application to diffusion and perfusion in neurologic disorders. Radiology (1986) 401–407</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29764"><clusterid>1679</clusterid><authors>K Merboldt,W Hanicke,J Frahm</authors><title>Self-diffusion nmr imaging using stimulated echoes</title><venue>J. Magn. Reson</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1985</year><pages>479--486</pages><volume>64</volume><raw>Merboldt, K., Hanicke, W., Frahm, J.: Self-diffusion nmr imaging using stimulated echoes. J. Magn. Reson. 64 (1985) 479–486</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29765"><clusterid>1680</clusterid><authors>N Selden,D Gitelman,N Salamon-Murayama,T Parrish,Mesulam</authors><title>M.: Trajectories of cholinergic pathways within the cerebral hemispheres of the human brain. Brain 121</title><year>1998</year><publisher>Faugeras</publisher><volume>2249</volume><raw>Selden, N., Gitelman, D., Salamon-Murayama, N., Parrish, T., Mesulam, M.: Trajectories of cholinergic pathways within the cerebral hemispheres of the human brain. Brain 121 (1998) 2249–2257 12 C. Lenglet, R. Deriche, O. Faugeras</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29766"><clusterid>1681</clusterid><authors>P Basser,J Mattiello,LeBihan</authors><title>D.: Estimation of the effective self-diffusion tensor from the NMR spin echo</title><venue>Journal of Magnetic Resonance B</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>247--254</pages><raw>Basser, P., Mattiello, J., LeBihan, D.: Estimation of the effective self-diffusion tensor from the NMR spin echo. Journal of Magnetic Resonance B (1994) 247–254</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29767"><clusterid>1682</clusterid><authors>D Tschumperlé,Deriche</authors><title>R.: Variational frameworks for DT-MRI estimation, regularization and visualization</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Tschumperlé, D., Deriche, R.: Variational frameworks for DT-MRI estimation, regularization and visualization. In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29768"><clusterid>1683</clusterid><authors>C Chefd’hotel,D Tschumperlé,R Deriche,Faugeras</authors><title>O.: Constrained flows on matrix-valued functions : application to diffusion tensor regularization</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ECCV. (2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Chefd’hotel, C., Tschumperlé, D., Deriche, R., Faugeras, O.: Constrained flows on matrix-valued functions : application to diffusion tensor regularization. In: Proceedings of ECCV. (2002)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29769"><clusterid>1684</clusterid><authors>O Coulon,D Alexander,Arridge</authors><title>S.: A regularization scheme for diffusion tensor magnetic resonance images</title><venue>In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Coulon, O., Alexander, D., Arridge, S.: A regularization scheme for diffusion tensor magnetic resonance images. In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2001)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29770"><clusterid>1685</clusterid><authors>C Westin,S Maier,H Mamata,A Nabavi,F Jolesz,Kikinis</authors><title>R.: Processing and visualization for diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Medical Image Analysis. Volume 6. (2002) 93–108</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Westin, C., Maier, S., Mamata, H., Nabavi, A., Jolesz, F., Kikinis, R.: Processing and visualization for diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of Medical Image Analysis. Volume 6. (2002) 93–108</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29771"><clusterid>1686</clusterid><authors>Z Wang,B Vemuri,Y Chen,Mareci</authors><title>T.: Simultaneous smoothing and estimation of the tensor field from diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of CVPR Volume I</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pages>461--466</pages><raw>Wang, Z., Vemuri, B., Chen, Y., Mareci, T.: Simultaneous smoothing and estimation of the tensor field from diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of CVPR Volume I., (2003) 461–466</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29772"><clusterid>1687</clusterid><authors>M Guye,G J Parkera,M Symms,P Boulby,C Wheeler-Kingshott,A SalekHaddadi,G Barker,J Duncana</authors><title>Combined functional MRI and tractography to demonstrate the connectivity of the human primary motor cortex in vivo. NeuroImage 19</title><year>2003</year><pages>1349--1360</pages><raw>Guye, M., Parkera, G.J., Symms, M., Boulby, P., Wheeler-Kingshott, C., SalekHaddadi, A., Barker, G., Duncana, J.: Combined functional MRI and tractography to demonstrate the connectivity of the human primary motor cortex in vivo. NeuroImage 19 (2003) 1349–1360</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29773"><clusterid>1688</clusterid><authors>S Mori,B Crain,V Chacko,Zijl</authors><title>P.V.: Three-dimensional tracking of axonal projections in the brain by magnetic resonance imaging. Annals of Neurology 45</title><year>1999</year><pages>265--269</pages><raw>Mori, S., Crain, B., Chacko, V., Zijl, P.V.: Three-dimensional tracking of axonal projections in the brain by magnetic resonance imaging. Annals of Neurology 45 (1999) 265–269</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29774"><clusterid>1689</clusterid><authors>L Zhukov,Barr</authors><title>A.: Oriented tensor reconstruction: Tracing neural pathways from diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of Visualization. (2002) 387–394</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Zhukov, L., Barr, A.: Oriented tensor reconstruction: Tracing neural pathways from diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of Visualization. (2002) 387–394</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29775"><clusterid>1690</clusterid><authors>M Lazar,D Weinstein,J Tsuruda,K Hasan,K Arfanakis,M Meyerand,B Badie,H Rowley,Field V Haughton,A Alexander</authors><title>A.: White matter tractography using diffusion tensor deflection. In: Human Brain Mapping. Volume 18</title><year>2003</year><pages>306--321</pages><raw>Lazar, M., Weinstein, D., Tsuruda, J., Hasan, K., Arfanakis, K., Meyerand, M., Badie, B., Rowley, H., V.Haughton, Field, A., Alexander, A.: White matter tractography using diffusion tensor deflection. In: Human Brain Mapping. Volume 18. (2003) 306–321</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29776"><clusterid>1691</clusterid><authors>P Basser,S Pajevic,C Pierpaoli,Duda</authors><title>vivo fiber tractography using DT-MRI data</title><pages>625--632</pages><editors>J., Aldroubi, A.: In</editors><volume>44</volume><raw>Basser, P., Pajevic, S., Pierpaoli, C., Duda, J., Aldroubi, A.: In vivo fiber tractography using DT-MRI data. Magn. Res. Med. 44 (2000) 625–632</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29777"><clusterid>1692</clusterid><authors>B Vemuri,Y Chen,M Rao,T McGraw,T Mareci,Wang</authors><title>Z.: Fiber tract mapping from diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of VLSM. (2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Vemuri, B., Chen, Y., Rao, M., McGraw, T., Mareci, T., Wang, Z.: Fiber tract mapping from diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of VLSM. (2001)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29778"><clusterid>1693</clusterid><authors>J Campbell,K Siddiqi,B Vemuri,Pike</authors><title>G.: A geometric flow for white matter fibre tract reconstruction</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 505–508</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Campbell, J., Siddiqi, K., Vemuri, B., Pike, G.: A geometric flow for white matter fibre tract reconstruction. In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 505–508</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29779"><clusterid>1694</clusterid><authors>D Tuch</authors><title>Mapping cortical connectivity with diffusion MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 392–394</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Tuch, D.: Mapping cortical connectivity with diffusion MRI. In: Proceedings of ISBI. (2002) 392–394</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29780"><clusterid>1695</clusterid><authors>P Hagmann,J Thiran,L Jonasson,P Vandergheynst,S Clarke,P Maeder,Meuli</authors><title>R.: DTI mapping of human brain connectivity: Statistical fiber tracking and virtual dissection. NeuroImage 19</title><year>2003</year><pages>545--554</pages><raw>Hagmann, P., Thiran, J., Jonasson, L., Vandergheynst, P., Clarke, S., Maeder, P., Meuli, R.: DTI mapping of human brain connectivity: Statistical fiber tracking and virtual dissection. NeuroImage 19 (2003) 545–554</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29781"><clusterid>1696</clusterid><authors>M Bjornemo,A Brun,R Kikinis,Westin</authors><title>C.: Regularized stochastic white matter tractography using diffusion tensor MRI</title><venue>In: Proceedings of MICCAI. (2002) 435–442</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Bjornemo, M., Brun, A., Kikinis, R., Westin, C.: Regularized stochastic white matter tractography using diffusion tensor MRI. In: Proceedings of MICCAI. (2002) 435–442</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29782"><clusterid>1697</clusterid><authors>G Parker,Alexander</authors><title>D.: Probabilistic monte carlo based mapping of cerebral connections utilising whole-brain crossing fibre information</title><venue>In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2003) 684–695</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Parker, G., Alexander, D.: Probabilistic monte carlo based mapping of cerebral connections utilising whole-brain crossing fibre information. In: Proceedings of IPMI. (2003) 684–695</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29783"><clusterid>1776</clusterid><authors></authors><title>angular resolution diffusion imaging reveals intravoxel white matter fiber heterogeneity</title><pages>577--582</pages><editors>Tuch, D., Reese, T., Wiegell, M., Makris, N., Belliveau, J., Wedeen, V.: High</editors><volume>48</volume><raw>Tuch, D., Reese, T., Wiegell, M., Makris, N., Belliveau, J., Wedeen, V.: High angular resolution diffusion imaging reveals intravoxel white matter fiber heterogeneity. Magn. Res. Med. 48 (2002) 577–582</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29784"><clusterid>1698</clusterid><authors>L Frank</authors><title>Characterization of anisotropy in high angular resolution diffusionweighted MRI</title><venue>Magn. Res. Med</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>1083--1099</pages><volume>47</volume><raw>Frank, L.: Characterization of anisotropy in high angular resolution diffusionweighted MRI. Magn. Res. Med 47 (2002) 1083–1099</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29785"><clusterid>1699</clusterid><authors>D Tuch,M Wiegell,T Reese,J Belliveau,Weeden</authors><title>V.: Measuring corticocortical connectivity matrices with diffusion spectrum imaging</title><venue>In: Int. Soc. Magn. Reson. Med. Volume 9. (2001) 502  White Matter Geometry from DT-MRI 13</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Tuch, D., Wiegell, M., Reese, T., Belliveau, J., Weeden, V.: Measuring corticocortical connectivity matrices with diffusion spectrum imaging. In: Int. Soc. Magn. Reson. Med. Volume 9. (2001) 502 Inferring White Matter Geometry from DT-MRI 13</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29786"><clusterid>1700</clusterid><authors>C Lin,V Weeden,J Chen,C Yao,Tseng</authors><title>W.I.: Validation of diffusion spectrum magnetic resonance imaging with manganese-enhanced rat optic tracts and ex vivo phantoms. NeuroImage 19</title><year>2003</year><pages>482--495</pages><raw>Lin, C., Weeden, V., Chen, J., Yao, C., Tseng, W.I.: Validation of diffusion spectrum magnetic resonance imaging with manganese-enhanced rat optic tracts and ex vivo phantoms. NeuroImage 19 (2003) 482–495</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29787"><clusterid>1701</clusterid><authors>R Bammer,M Auer,S Keeling,Augustin</authors><title>Diffusion tensor imaging using single-shot sense-EPI</title><pages>128--136</pages><editors>M., Stables, L., Prokesch, R., Stollberger, R., Moseley, M., Fazekas, F</editors><volume>48</volume><raw>Bammer, R., Auer, M., Keeling, S., Augustin, M., Stables, L., Prokesch, R., Stollberger, R., Moseley, M., Fazekas, F.: Diffusion tensor imaging using single-shot sense-EPI. Magn. Res. Med. 48 (2002) 128–136</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29788"><clusterid>1702</clusterid><authors>J F Mangin,C Poupon,Y Cointepas,D Rivière,D Papadopoulos-Orfanos,C A Clark,J Régis,Bihan</authors><title>D.L.: A framework based on spin glass models for the inference of anatomical connectivity from diffusion-weighted MR data</title><venue>NMR in Biomedicine 15</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>481--492</pages><raw>Mangin, J.F., Poupon, C., Cointepas, Y., Rivière, D., Papadopoulos-Orfanos, D., Clark, C.A., Régis, J., Bihan, D.L.: A framework based on spin glass models for the inference of anatomical connectivity from diffusion-weighted MR data. NMR in Biomedicine 15 (2002) 481–492</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29789"><clusterid>1703</clusterid><authors>G Parker,C Wheeler-Kingshott,Barker</authors><title>G.: Estimating distributed anatomical connectivity using fast marching methods and diffusion tensor imaging. Trans. Med. Imaging 21</title><year>2002</year><pages>505--512</pages><raw>Parker, G., Wheeler-Kingshott, C., Barker, G.: Estimating distributed anatomical connectivity using fast marching methods and diffusion tensor imaging. Trans. Med. Imaging 21 (2002) 505–512</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29790"><clusterid>1704</clusterid><authors>L O’Donnell,S Haker,Westin</authors><title>C.: New approaches to estimation of white matter connectivity in diffusion tensor MRI: Elliptic PDEs and geodesics in a tensor-warped space</title><venue>In: Proceedings of MICCAI</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>459--466</pages><raw>O’Donnell, L., Haker, S., Westin, C.: New approaches to estimation of white matter connectivity in diffusion tensor MRI: Elliptic PDEs and geodesics in a tensor-warped space. In: Proceedings of MICCAI. (2002) 459–466.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29791"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>N Ikeda,Watanabe</authors><venue>S.: Stochastic Differential Equations and Diffusion Processes. North-Holland Mathematical Library</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1989</year><raw>Ikeda, N., Watanabe, S.: Stochastic Differential Equations and Diffusion Processes. North-Holland Mathematical Library (1989)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29792"><clusterid>1705</clusterid><authors>A Einstein</authors><title>Investigations on the Theory of the Brownian Movement. Dover Pubns</title><year>1956</year><raw>Einstein, A.: Investigations on the Theory of the Brownian Movement. Dover Pubns (1956)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29793"><clusterid>1706</clusterid><authors>N Sochen,R Deriche,Lopez-Perez</authors><title>L.: The beltrami flow over implicit manifolds</title><venue>In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Sochen, N., Deriche, R., Lopez-Perez, L.: The beltrami flow over implicit manifolds. In: Proceedings of ICCV. (2003)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29794"><clusterid>1707</clusterid><authors>de Lara</authors><title>M.: Geometric and symmetry properties of a nondegenerate diffusion process. An. of Probability 23</title><year>1995</year><pages>1557--1604</pages><raw>de Lara, M.: Geometric and symmetry properties of a nondegenerate diffusion process. An. of Probability 23 (1995) 1557–1604</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29795"><clusterid>1708</clusterid><authors>M Liao</authors><title>Symmetry groups of markov processes</title><venue>Anal. of Prob</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1992</year><pages>563--578</pages><volume>20</volume><raw>Liao, M.: Symmetry groups of markov processes. Anal. of Prob. 20 (1992) 563–578</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29796"><clusterid>1709</clusterid><authors>E Hsu</authors><title>Stochastic Analysis on Manifolds. Volume 38</title><venue>of Graduate Studies in Mathematics. AMS</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>Hsu, E.: Stochastic Analysis on Manifolds. Volume 38 of Graduate Studies in Mathematics. AMS (2001)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29797"><clusterid>1710</clusterid><authors>C Mantegazza,Mennucci</authors><title>A.: Hamilton–jacobi equations and distance functions on Riemannian manifolds</title><venue>App. Math. and Optim</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>1--25</pages><volume>47</volume><raw>Mantegazza, C., Mennucci, A.: Hamilton–jacobi equations and distance functions on Riemannian manifolds. App. Math. and Optim. 47 (2002) 1–25</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29798"><clusterid>1711</clusterid><authors>S Osher</authors><title>A level set formulation for the solution of the dirichlet problem for a hamilton-Jacobi equations</title><venue>SIAM Journal on Mathematical Analysis</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1993</year><pages>1145--1152</pages><volume>24</volume><raw>Osher, S.: A level set formulation for the solution of the dirichlet problem for a hamilton-Jacobi equations. SIAM Journal on Mathematical Analysis 24 (1993) 1145–1152</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29799"><clusterid>1712</clusterid><authors>J Sethian</authors><title>Level Set Methods</title><year>1996</year><publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher><raw>Sethian, J.: Level Set Methods. Cambridge University Press (1996)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29800"><clusterid>1713</clusterid><authors>Y H Tsai,Y Giga,Osher</authors><title>S.: A level set approach for computing discontinuous solutions of Hamilton–Jacobi equations</title><venue>Math. Comput</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><pages>159--181</pages><volume>72</volume><raw>Tsai, Y.H., Giga, Y., Osher, S.: A level set approach for computing discontinuous solutions of Hamilton–Jacobi equations. Math. Comput. 72 (2003) 159–181</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29801"><clusterid>1714</clusterid><authors>Y Chen,Y Giga,Goto</authors><title>S.: Uniqueness and existence of viscosity solutions of generalized mean curvature flow equations</title><venue>Journal on Differential Geometry</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>749--786</pages><volume>33</volume><raw>Chen, Y., Giga, Y., Goto, S.: Uniqueness and existence of viscosity solutions of generalized mean curvature flow equations. Journal on Differential Geometry 33 (1991) 749–786</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29802"><clusterid>1715</clusterid><authors>R LeVeque</authors><title>Numerical methods for conservation laws</title><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Birkhäuser, Basel</pubAddress><raw>LeVeque, R.: Numerical methods for conservation laws. Birkhäuser, Basel (1992)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29803"><clusterid>1716</clusterid><authors>R Kimmel,A Amir,Bruckstein</authors><title>A.: Finding shortest paths on surfaces using level set propagation</title><venue>Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><pages>635--640</pages><volume>17</volume><raw>Kimmel, R., Amir, A., Bruckstein, A.: Finding shortest paths on surfaces using level set propagation. Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence 17 (1995) 635–640</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation><citation id="29804"><clusterid>1717</clusterid><authors>X Liu,S Osher,Chan</authors><title>T.: Weighted essentially non oscillatory schemes</title><venue>J. Comput. Phys</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>200--212</pages><volume>115</volume><raw>Liu, X., Osher, S., Chan, T.: Weighted essentially non oscillatory schemes. J. Comput. Phys. 115 (1994) 200–212</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1585</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>ftp://ftp-sop.inria.fr/odyssee/Publications/2004/lenglet-deriche-etal:04.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>