<document id="10.1.1.1.1512"><clusterid>480</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">SIS-PRUEBA A tool for rapid prototyping and testing of Speech Recognition user interfaces in Telefónica Móviles España</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">SIS PRUEBA is a software tool to integrate usability and user-centred design principles in the development process of services within Telefónica Móviles España (TME), the largest mobile telecommunications operator in Spain. The successful deployment of complex services, from both users ' and developer's points of view, require of a high degree of integration of a User Centered methodology with the design, development and usability tests in all the phases of the life cycle of services. An important example is Telefónica Móviles Portal de Voz (Voice Portal), a service providing information retrieval on a large number of issues using the voice or DTMF commands. With this objective, the purpose of SIS PRUEBA is to provide a single tool to integrate the characteristics of the unified processes of development (UP) with techniques of rapid prototyping like part of the usability methodology. Main benefits of SIS PRUEBA are: Definition and management of assigned components to usability projects (services, functionalities, use cases, types of users and use contexts). Creation of measurement libraries (questions, formats of answers and questionnaires). Allows for the quick production of batteries of usability trials by means of different experimental designs. Management of user panels for trials Administration of usability trials in supports of &amp;quot;paper and pencil &amp;quot; and/or remote (Internet). Emulation of voice interfaces on flow charts in design time. Keywords User-centered design, prototyping and model based design, software development methodology</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4186"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Pedro Concejero Cerezo</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">Telefónica Investigación y Desarrollo,</affil><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">pedro.concejero@tid.es</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4187"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Juan José</name><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4188"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Rodríguez Soler</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Emilio Vargas, 6, E-28043 MADRID ESPAÑA</address><order src="null">3</order></author><author id="4189"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Daniel Tapias Merino</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Serrano Galvache, 12, E-28033 MADRID</address><order src="null">4</order></author><author id="4190"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Telefónica Móviles España</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Serrano Galvache, 12, E-28033 MADRID</address><order src="null">5</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28422"><clusterid>481</clusterid><authors>I Jacobson,J Rumbaugh</authors><title>El proceso unificado de desarrollo de software</title><year>2000</year><publisher>Addison Wesley</publisher><raw>Jacobson, I; Rumbaugh, J. (2000). El proceso unificado de desarrollo de software. Addison Wesley</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1512</paperid></citation><citation id="28423"><clusterid>482</clusterid><authors>ISO</authors><title>Ergonomic requirements for office work with visual display terminals (VDT’s). Geneva: International Standards Organization. addition to functional parameters, at the same time allowing tests of early prototypes. - Improve the efficiency of the whole devel</title><year>1988</year><raw>ISO 9241 (1988): Ergonomic requirements for office work with visual display terminals (VDT’s). Geneva: International Standards Organization. addition to functional parameters, at the same time allowing tests of early prototypes. - Improve the efficiency of the whole development process and the final quality of the product as delivered to the market.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1512</paperid></citation><citation id="28424"><clusterid>483</clusterid><authors>ISO</authors><title>Human-centred design processes for interactive systems</title><venue>Geneva: International Standards Organization</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>ISO -13407 (1999): Human-centred design processes for interactive systems. Geneva: International Standards Organization.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1512</paperid></citation><citation id="28425"><clusterid>484</clusterid><authors>S Zahran</authors><title>Software Process Improvement, Practical Guidelines for Business Success</title><year>1998</year><pages>0--201</pages><publisher>Addison Wesley, ISBN</publisher><raw>Zahran, S. (1998). Software Process Improvement, Practical Guidelines for Business Success. Addison Wesley, ISBN 0-201-17782-X</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1512</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><url>http://sunsite.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/Publications/CEUR-WS//Vol-103/concejero-et-al.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>bf07dfed6c9588f7237543549bdb0fd47d2ca8fa</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>