<document id="10.1.1.1.1536"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">proofs</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1254">KEY WORDS</keyword><keyword id="1255">Grid computing</keyword><keyword id="1256">distributed computing</keyword><keyword id="1257">heterogeneous network computing</keyword><keyword id="1258">client--server</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4278"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Dorian C. Arnold</name><order>1</order></author><author id="4279"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Jack Dongarra</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">; Computer Science Department,; WI 53706, U.S.A.; Computer Science and Engineering Department, University of California,; San Diego, La Jolla, CA 92093-0114, U.S.A.; Computer Science Department, University of Tennessee,; Knoxville, TN 37923-3450, U.S.A</address><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28795"><title>The Grid, Blueprint for a New Computing Infrastructure</title><year>1998</year><editors>Foster I, Kesselman C (eds</editors><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><pubAddress>San Mateo, CA</pubAddress><raw>Foster I, Kesselman C (eds.). The Grid, Blueprint for a New Computing Infrastructure. Morgan Kaufmann: San Mateo, CA, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>e early 1990s, the distributed computing domain has been a hot-bed of research as scientists explored techniques to expand the boundaries of scientific computing. In this era, the term Grid computing [1] was coined to describe a fabric, analogous to the electrical power grid, that would uniformly and seamlessly channel computational services to clients who `plug in' to the Grid. The NetSolve system, </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28796"><authors>D Arnold,S Agrawal,S Blackford,J Dongarra,M Miller,K Sagi,Z Shi,S Vahdiyar</authors><title>User's guide to NetSolve V1.4</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2001</year><tech>Technical Report UT-CS-01-467</tech><raw>Arnold D, Agrawal S, Blackford S, Dongarra J, Miller M, Sagi K, Shi Z, Vahdiyar S. User's guide to NetSolve V1.4. Technical Report UT-CS-01-467, Computer Science Department, University of Tennessee, July 2001.</raw><contexts><context> goal of this article is to highlight the research accomplishments of the NetSolve system; additional low-level details including complete usage instructions can be found in the NetSolve User's Guide [2]. 10 THE NetSolve SYSTEM This section offers a high-level overview of the NetSolve system discussing, in turn, architectural, implementation and managerial issues. The architecture An instance of a Ne</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28797"><venue>Sun Microsystems Inc. External Data Representation Standard RFC 1014</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1987</year><pages>2--5</pages><raw>Sun Microsystems Inc. External Data Representation Standard RFC 1014, June 1987. 25</raw><contexts><context>tiates each communication session, during which computer hosts determine whether they understand the same 35 data format (endianness, data sizes, etc.). When an incompatibility is detected, Sun's XDR [3] protocol is used to encode local data to a globally-understood format, allowing each host to decode from this Copyright # 2002 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Concurrency Computat.: Pract. Exper. 2002; 14:1-</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28798"><authors>Neuman BC,T Ts'o</authors><title>Kerberos: An authentication service for computer networks</title><venue>IEEE Communications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>32--9</pages><raw>Neuman BC, Ts'o T. Kerberos: An authentication service for computer networks. IEEE Communications 1994; 32(9):33--</raw><contexts><context>to install system components and, once installed, one can easily donate services to the community at large. However, for those that require a more controlled system, NetSolve incorporates Kerberos V5 [4] protocols to allow for client--server authentication and access control (discussed in the access control mechanisms section). 5 Administrative issues A NetSolve pool will most naturally consist of in</context><context>ive information. In the latest version of NetSolve, we have introduced the ability to generate access control lists which are used to grant and deny access to the NetSolve servers. We use Kerberos V5 [4] services to add this functionality to NetSolve, as it is one of the most trusted and popular infrastructures for authentication 30 services. Using Kerberos, the `administrator' of the server identifi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28799"><title>IBM LoadLeveler for AIX</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2000</year><tech>Technical Report SA22-7311-01</tech><raw>IBM LoadLeveler for AIX. Technical Report SA22-7311-01, April 2000. http://www.rs6000.ibm.com/doc link/en US/a doc lib/sp32/LoadL/lllv2mst.html.</raw><contexts><context>ist of independent workstations or workstation clusters. We do support the use of supercomputer class machines (MPPs and SMPs) as servers, but we do not interface to batch schedulers like LoadLeveler [5] or PBS [6]. Instead, on these classes of machines parallel jobs are launched in an interactive manner. However, the reader should note the existence of 10 an interface to the Globus infrastructure (s</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28800"><venue>The Math Works Inc. Using MATLAB Version 5. The Math Works Inc</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><raw>The Math Works Inc. Using MATLAB Version 5. The Math Works Inc., 1992.</raw><contexts><context>tsolve nb('wait',request); (a) (b) Figure 2. Examples of calling NetSolve from within the Matlab environment in blocking (a) and non-blocking (b) fashions. currently supports APIs for both the Matlab [7] and Mathematica [8] environments. NetSolve enhances these environments by expanding the numerical functions available to the environment and allowing for increased performance by executing code remot</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28801"><authors>S Wolfram</authors><title>The Mathematica Book (3rd edn</title><venue>Wolfram Median Inc. and Cambridge</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1996</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><raw>Wolfram S. The Mathematica Book (3rd edn). Wolfram Median Inc. and Cambridge University Press, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>uest); (a) (b) Figure 2. Examples of calling NetSolve from within the Matlab environment in blocking (a) and non-blocking (b) fashions. currently supports APIs for both the Matlab [7] and Mathematica [8] environments. NetSolve enhances these environments by expanding the numerical functions available to the environment and allowing for increased performance by executing code remotely on more efficien</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28802"><authors>I Foster,C Kesselman</authors><title>Globus: A metacomputing infrastructure toolkit</title><venue>International Journal of Supercomputer Applications</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Foster I, Kesselman C. Globus: A metacomputing infrastructure toolkit. International Journal of Supercomputer Applications 1997; 11(2):115--128.</raw><contexts><context>urces (GRID) Figure 4. Proxy architecture. behalf of the client means that different proxies can negotiate for different types of services. So far, we have implemented proxies to negotiate for Globus [9] services and, of course, the standard NetSolve services. Future work may include integrating other systems like Condor [10] or Legion [11] in a similar fashion; however, a primary motivation of the N</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28803"><authors>M Litzkow,M Livny</authors><title>Mutka M. Condor---a hunter of idle workstations</title><venue>Proceedings of the 8th International Conference 35 of Distributed Computing Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>104--111</pages><pubAddress>San Jose, CA</pubAddress><raw>Litzkow M, Livny M, Mutka M. Condor---a hunter of idle workstations. Proceedings of the 8th International Conference 35 of Distributed Computing Systems, San Jose, CA, June 1998; 104--111.</raw><contexts><context>pes of services. So far, we have implemented proxies to negotiate for Globus [9] services and, of course, the standard NetSolve services. Future work may include integrating other systems like Condor [10] or Legion [11] in a similar fashion; however, a primary motivation of the NetSolve proxy architecture was to make it feasible and easy for parties not affiliated with the NetSolve project 5 to enable</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28804"><authors>P</authors><title>A synopsis of the Legion Project</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1994</year><tech>Technical Report CS-94-20</tech><raw>Grimshaw A, Wulf W, French J, Weaver A, Reynolds Jr. P. A synopsis of the Legion Project. Technical Report CS-94-20, Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia, 1994.</raw><contexts><context>. So far, we have implemented proxies to negotiate for Globus [9] services and, of course, the standard NetSolve services. Future work may include integrating other systems like Condor [10] or Legion [11] in a similar fashion; however, a primary motivation of the NetSolve proxy architecture was to make it feasible and easy for parties not affiliated with the NetSolve project 5 to enable these types of</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28805"><authors>Arnold DC,D Bachmann,J Dongarra</authors><title>Request sequencing: Optimizing communication for the Grid. Euro-Par 2000--- Parallel Processing</title><year>2000</year><pages>4--0</pages><editors>Bode A, Ludwig T, Karl W, Wismuller R (eds</editors><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>Berlin</pubAddress><raw>Arnold DC, Bachmann D, Dongarra J. Request sequencing: Optimizing communication for the Grid. Euro-Par 2000--- Parallel Processing, Bode A, Ludwig T, Karl W, Wismuller R (eds.). Springer: Berlin, 2000; 1213--1222. 40</raw><contexts><context> the overhead of the DAG construction and make sequencing worthwhile. Figure 5(b) shows the reduced data flow between client and server components that occurs when the sequencing mode is employed. In [12], this interface is discussed and some experimental results are given that were achieved using 20 this data persistence technique. The results support our theories that this is a very good way to opti</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28806"><authors>M Beck,T Moore</authors><title>The Internet2 Distributed Storage Infrastructure Project: An architecture for internet content channels. Computer Networking and ISDN Systems</title><year>1998</year><pages>30--22</pages><raw>Beck M, Moore T. The Internet2 Distributed Storage Infrastructure Project: An architecture for internet content channels. Computer Networking and ISDN Systems 1998; 30(22/23):2141--2148.</raw><contexts><context>y to optimize the use of Grid resources, especially when bandwidth is of the essence, data sets are very large, or both. Distributed storage infrastructures A distributed storage infrastructure (DSI) [13] is a technology that allows a program to manage data stored remotely. The Internet backplane protocol (IBP) [14] is an example DSI that has been 25 incorporated into NetSolve in an effort to logistic</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28807"><authors>J Plank,M Beck,W Elwasif,T Moore,M Swany,R Wolski</authors><venue>IBP---the Internet Backplane Protocol: Storage in the network. NetStore '99: Network Storage Symposium</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Seattle, WA</pubAddress><raw>Plank J, Beck M, Elwasif W, Moore T, Swany M, Wolski R. IBP---the Internet Backplane Protocol: Storage in the network. NetStore '99: Network Storage Symposium, Seattle, WA, October 1999.</raw><contexts><context>r both. Distributed storage infrastructures A distributed storage infrastructure (DSI) [13] is a technology that allows a program to manage data stored remotely. The Internet backplane protocol (IBP) [14] is an example DSI that has been 25 incorporated into NetSolve in an effort to logistically store data in storage depots convenient to Copyright # 2002 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Concurrency Computat.: P</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28808"><authors>A Chervenak,I Foster,C Kesselman,C Salisbury</authors><title>Tuecke S. The Data Grid: Towards an Architecture for the Distributed 45 Management and Analysis of Large Scientific Datasets</title><raw>Chervenak A, Foster I, Kesselman C, Salisbury C, Tuecke S. The Data Grid: Towards an Architecture for the Distributed 45 Management and Analysis of Large Scientific Datasets.</raw><contexts><context>em to leverage DSI storage without modifying the standard NetSolve functions for computational requests. A complete taxonomy on the state of the art in DSIs and Data Grid technologies can be found in [15], which also gives full details regarding NetSolve's DSI integration efforts. Task farming 10 This interface addresses applications that have simple task-parallel structures but require a large number</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28809"><authors>H Casanova,M Kim,Plank JS,J Dongarra</authors><title>Adaptive scheduling for task farming with Grid middleware. The International Journal of Supercomputer Applications and High Performance Computing 1999; 13:231--240. Copyright # 2002</title><venue>Concurrency Computat.: Pract. Exper. 2002; 14:1--23 Uncorrected proofs July 11, 2002 Marked proof Ref: CPE678/24683e Sheet number 23 NetSolve INNOVATIONS 23</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher><raw>Casanova H, Kim M, Plank JS, Dongarra J. Adaptive scheduling for task farming with Grid middleware. The International Journal of Supercomputer Applications and High Performance Computing 1999; 13:231--240. Copyright # 2002 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Concurrency Computat.: Pract. Exper. 2002; 14:1--23 Uncorrected proofs July 11, 2002 Marked proof Ref: CPE678/24683e Sheet number 23 NetSolve INNOVATIONS 23</raw><contexts><context>tions it is to be expected that the availability and load of resources within the server pool will change dynamically. The design and validation of the NetSolve task farming interface is presented in [16]. This article also presents a preliminary adaptive scheduling algorithm for task farming. The initial task farming work in NetSolve has lead to a larger development and integration effort as part of </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28810"><authors>H Casanova,G Obertelli,F Berman,R Wolski</authors><title>The AppLeS Parameter Sweep Template: User-level middleware for the Grid</title><venue>Proceedings of SuperComputing 2000 (SC'00</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>Casanova H, Obertelli G, Berman F, Wolski R. The AppLeS Parameter Sweep Template: User-level middleware for the Grid. Proceedings of SuperComputing 2000 (SC'00), November 2000.</raw><contexts><context>ticle also presents a preliminary adaptive scheduling algorithm for task farming. The initial task farming work in NetSolve has lead to a larger development and integration effort as part of the APST [17] project 25 (see the section on data persistence). Transparent algorithm selection Through NetSolve, users are given access to complex algorithms that solve a variety of types of problems, one instanc</context><context> design. Several scheduling heuristics were studied in [35] and experimental results using NetSolve on a wide-area testbed for running large MCell simulations with those heuristics can be 15 found in [17]. Nuclear engineering The goal of this project is to develop a prototype environment for the Collaborative Environment for Nuclear Technology Software (CENTS). CENTS aims to lay the foundation for a W</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28811"><authors>S Balay,Gropp WD,Smith BF</authors><venue>Modern Software Tools in Scientific Computing.Birkhauser</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>163--202</pages><pubAddress>Basel</pubAddress><raw>Balay S, Gropp WD, Smith BF. Modern Software Tools in Scientific Computing.Birkhauser: Basel, 1997; 163--202.</raw><contexts><context>ng on the characteristics of the matrix being solved, some perform poorly and others not at all. NetSolve 30 has incorporated a large number of solver algorithms from a variety of packages like PETSc [18] and Aztec [19]. We have further created an interface that allows the user to generically call a `LinearSolve' routine which transparently analyzes the input matrix and determines which algorithm to u</context><context>ty, NetSolve has integrated a variety of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available for a large number of pla</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28812"><authors>Hutchinson SA,Shadid JN</authors><title>Tuminaro RS. Aztec User's Guide: Version 1.1</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1995</year><pages>5</pages><tech>Technical Report SAND95-1559</tech><raw>Hutchinson SA, Shadid JN, Tuminaro RS. Aztec User's Guide: Version 1.1. Technical Report SAND95-1559, Sandia National Laboratories, 1995. 5</raw><contexts><context>cteristics of the matrix being solved, some perform poorly and others not at all. NetSolve 30 has incorporated a large number of solver algorithms from a variety of packages like PETSc [18] and Aztec [19]. We have further created an interface that allows the user to generically call a `LinearSolve' routine which transparently analyzes the input matrix and determines which algorithm to use based on inp</context><context> has integrated a variety of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available for a large number of platforms and a</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28813"><authors>Arnold DC,S Blackford,J Dongarra</authors><title>Eijkhout V, Xu T. Seamless access to adaptive solver algorithms</title><venue>Proceedings of the 16th IMACS World Congress 2000 on Scientific Computation, Applied Mathematics and Simulation, August 2000; Session 172, paper 6. http://imacs2000.epfl.ch/Abstracts/RechAbstSess.asp</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Arnold DC, Blackford S, Dongarra J, Eijkhout V, Xu T. Seamless access to adaptive solver algorithms. Proceedings of the 16th IMACS World Congress 2000 on Scientific Computation, Applied Mathematics and Simulation, August 2000; Session 172, paper 6. http://imacs2000.epfl.ch/Abstracts/RechAbstSess.asp.</raw><contexts><context>rix features like size, shape, sparsity, symmetry and bandwidth dimensions, and decides which of the available solver packages is most appropriate to 35 correctly and efficiently solve the system. In [20], this interface and the heuristics and decisions that are involved in the algorithm selection process are discussed. This interface allows the non-expert user to properly and efficiently use solver a</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28814"><authors>D Kincaid,C Lawson,R Hanson,F Krogh</authors><title>Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms for Fortran Usage</title><year>1979</year><pages>5--308</pages><raw>Kincaid D, Lawson C, Hanson R, Krogh F. Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms for Fortran Usage 1979; 5:308--325.</raw></citation><citation id="28815"><authors>S Hammarling,J Dongarra,Du Croz J,R Hanson</authors><title>An Extended Set of Fortran Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms</title><year>1988</year><raw>Hammarling S, Dongarra J, Du Croz J, Hanson R. An Extended Set of Fortran Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms 1988; 14(1):1--32.</raw></citation><citation id="28816"><authors>I Duff,J Dongarra,Du</authors><title>Croz J, Hammarling S. A Set of Level 3 Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms</title><year>1990</year><raw>Duff I, Dongarra J, Du Croz J, Hammarling S. A Set of Level 3 Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms 1990; 16(1):1--17.</raw></citation><citation id="28817"><authors>E Anderson,Z Bai,C Bischof,S Blackford,J Demmel</authors><venue>McKenney A, Sorensen D. LAPACK User's Guide (3rd edn). Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Philadelphia, PA</pubAddress><volume>15</volume><raw>Anderson E, Bai Z, Bischof C, Blackford S, Demmel J, Dongarra J, Du Croz J, Greenbaum A, Hammarling S, 15 McKenney A, Sorensen D. LAPACK User's Guide (3rd edn). Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics: Philadelphia, PA, 1999.</raw><contexts><context> scientific services Using the PDF facility, NetSolve has integrated a variety of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these package</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28818"><authors>Blackford LS,J Choi,A Cleary</authors><title>D'Azevedo E</title><venue>Demmel J, Dhillon I, Dongarra J, Hammarling S, Henry G, Petitet A, Stanley K, Walker D, Whaley RC. ScaLAPACK User's Guide. Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pubAddress>Philadelphia, PA</pubAddress><volume>20</volume><raw>Blackford LS, Choi J, Cleary A, D'Azevedo E, Demmel J, Dhillon I, Dongarra J, Hammarling S, Henry G, Petitet A, Stanley K, Walker D, Whaley RC. ScaLAPACK User's Guide. Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics: Philadelphia, PA, 1997. 20</raw><contexts><context>ices Using the PDF facility, NetSolve has integrated a variety of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28819"><authors>D Young,D Kincaid,J Respess,R Grimes</authors><title>Itpack 2c: A Fortran package for solving large sparse linear systems by adaptive accelerated iterative method</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1996</year><tech>Technical Report</tech><raw>Young D, Kincaid D, Respess J, Grimes R. Itpack 2c: A Fortran package for solving large sparse linear systems by adaptive accelerated iterative method. Technical Report, 1996.</raw><contexts><context>e PDF facility, NetSolve has integrated a variety of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available for a large n</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28820"><authors>Duff IS</authors><title>Erisman AM, Reid JK. Direct Methods for Sparse Matices</title><year>1986</year><pubAddress>Clarendon Press: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>Duff IS, Erisman AM, Reid JK. Direct Methods for Sparse Matices. Clarendon Press: Oxford, 1986.</raw><contexts><context>ated a variety of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available for a large number of platforms and are freely d</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28821"><authors>X Li</authors><title>Sparse Gaussian elimination on high performance computers</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1996</year><pages>2--5</pages><tech>PhD Thesis</tech><raw>Li X. Sparse Gaussian elimination on high performance computers. PhD Thesis, Computer Science Department, University of California at Berkeley, 1996. 25</raw><contexts><context> of scientific packages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available for a large number of platforms and are freely distributed. Th</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28822"><authors>R Lehoucq,D Sorensen,C Yang</authors><title>ARPACK User's Guide (1st edn</title><venue>Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Philadelphia, PA</pubAddress><raw>Lehoucq R, Sorensen D, Yang C. ARPACK User's Guide (1st edn). Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics: Philadelphia, PA, 1998.</raw><contexts><context>ackages. These PDFs 10 are distributed with the current implementation of NetSolve: BLAS [22--24], LAPACK [25], ScaLAPACK [26], ItPack [27], PETSc [18], AZTEC [19], MA28 [28], SuperLU [29] and ARPACK [30]. When efficient, we include the actual numerical library with NetSolve; in the other cases, these packages are available for a large number of platforms and are freely distributed. The server/service</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28823"><authors>Arnold DC,S Browne,J Dongarra,G Fagg,K Moore</authors><title>Secure remote access to numerical software and computational hardware. DoD High-Performance Computing Modernization Program Users Group Conference</title><year>2000</year><pages>00--30</pages><raw>Arnold DC, Browne S, Dongarra J, Fagg G, Moore K. Secure remote access to numerical software and computational hardware. DoD High-Performance Computing Modernization Program Users Group Conference, June 2000. http://www.hpcmo.hpc.mil/Htdocs/UGC/UGC00. 30</raw><contexts><context>s being employed. Demand for more sophisticated security services is being evaluated to determine future work in this direction. More details about the current security implementation can be found in [31]. 5 Network Weather Service (NWS) CPU sensors NetSolve servers must be able to attain and report information regarding their CPU load so that the agent can determine which servers represent the best c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28824"><authors>R Wolski</authors><title>Dynamically forecasting network performance using the Network Weather Service</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>1996</year><tech>Technical Report TR-CS96494</tech><raw>Wolski R. Dynamically forecasting network performance using the Network Weather Service. Technical Report TR-CS96494, University of California at San Diego, October 1996.</raw><contexts><context>and report information regarding their CPU load so that the agent can determine which servers represent the best choice to service a request. The CPU load manager performs this task; however, the NWS [32] is a Grid service utility with a component, the CPU sensor, that does this as well. The following section discusses our integration of NWS forecasters 10 and motivates our use of the NWS CPU sensors </context><context>rror' is reported. 30 NWS forecasters When allocating resources, the agent's main goals is to choose the best-suited computational server for each incoming request We have employed the use of the NWS [32] to help us gather the information necessary to make these decisions. The NetSolve agent calls upon the services of NWS forecasters to predict future availability of server hosts based upon previously</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28825"><authors>Arnold DC,W Lee,J Dongarra,M Wheeler</authors><title>Providing infrastructure and interface to high-performance applications in a distributed setting</title><venue>High Performance Computing 2000, Tentner A (ed.). Society for Computer Simulation International, 2000; 248--253. 35</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Arnold DC, Lee W, Dongarra J, Wheeler M. Providing infrastructure and interface to high-performance applications in a distributed setting. High Performance Computing 2000, Tentner A (ed.). Society for Computer Simulation International, 2000; 248--253. 35</raw><contexts><context>IPARS system (Figure 8) allows users to access IPARS (including postprocessing of the output to create animated images that exhibit the variations of concentration, pressure, etc. of relevant fluids) [33]. The interface is primarily used from handy machines like laptop computers to run real-time simulations on clusters of workstations that allow for much quicker execution. IPARS 15 runs primarily on L</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28826"><venue>AppLeS Parameter Sweep Template (APST) Web</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><pages>page. http://grail.sdsc.edu/projects/apst</pages><raw>AppLeS Parameter Sweep Template (APST) Web page. http://grail.sdsc.edu/projects/apst [2001].</raw><contexts><context>ge of MCell input data requirements to minimize execution turn-around time. In this 10 context, NetSolve is used as part of a user-level middleware project, the AppLeS Parameter Sweep Template (APST) [34], developed at the University of California, San Diego. The use of NetSolve isolates the scheduler from the resource-management details and allows researchers to focus on the scheduler design. Several</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28827"><authors>H Casanova,A Legrand,D Zagorodnov,F Berman</authors><title>Heuristics for scheduling parameter sweep applications in Grid environments. Proceedings of the 9th Heterogeneous Computing Workshop (HCW'00), 2000. Copyright # 2002</title><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher><raw>Casanova H, Legrand A, Zagorodnov D, Berman F. Heuristics for scheduling parameter sweep applications in Grid environments. Proceedings of the 9th Heterogeneous Computing Workshop (HCW'00), 2000. Copyright # 2002 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Concurrency Computat.: Pract. Exper. 2002; 14:1--23 Annotations from cpe678.pdf Page 22 Annotation 1 Au: refs [10] and [14] Please give publisher details. Annotation 2 Au: ref. [15] Is this reference a book? Please give year and publisher. Page 23 Annotation 1 Au: refs [17], [21] and [35] Please give publisher details. Annotation 2 Au: ref. [21] Is this reference a book? Please give publisher details. Annotation 3 Au: ref. [27] Which institution?</raw><contexts><context>rnia, San Diego. The use of NetSolve isolates the scheduler from the resource-management details and allows researchers to focus on the scheduler design. Several scheduling heuristics were studied in [35] and experimental results using NetSolve on a wide-area testbed for running large MCell simulations with those heuristics can be 15 found in [17]. Nuclear engineering The goal of this project is to de</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://icl.cs.utk.edu/news_pub/submissions/cpe678.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>*LEGACY*</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>e58d19a74afb777392750467701d49dee505e5fd</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>