<document id="10.1.1.1.1531"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract Automatic Construction of Navigable Concept Networks Characterizing Text Databases</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">In this paper we present a comprehensive approach to conceptual structuring and intelligent navigation of text databases. Given any collection of texts, we first automatically extract a set of index terms describing each text. Next, we use a particular lattice conceptual clustering method to build a network of clustered texts whose nodes are described using the index terms. We argue that the resulting network supports an hybrid navigational approach to text retrieval- implemented into an actual user interface- that combines browsing potentials with good retrieval performance. We present the results of an experiment on subject searching where this approach outperformed a conventional Boolean retrieval system. 1.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4255"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Claudio Carpineto</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Italy</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">carpinet @fub.it</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4256"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Giovanni Romano</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Italy</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">romano@fub.it</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4257"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Fondazione Ugo Bordoni</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Italy</address><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28742"><authors>R Barletta,W Mark</authors><title>Explanation-Based Indexing of Cases</title><venue>Proceedings of AAAI-88, St</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1988</year><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><pubAddress>Paul, Minnesota</pubAddress><raw>Barletta, R., Mark, W. (1988). Explanation-Based Indexing of Cases. Proceedings of AAAI-88, St. Paul, Minnesota, Morgan Kaufmann.</raw><contexts><context>nt of each text. Basically, there are two kinds of approaches. In the AI-based approach, natural language processing techniques (Sowa, 1984; Srihari and Burhans, 1994) or machine learning techniques (Barletta and Mark, 1988; Baudin et al, 1994) can be used to build or refine an internal representation of each text. Although most of these methods can produce deep conceptual indices, they can only work in restricted envir</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28743"><authors>C Baudin,B Pell,S Kedar</authors><title>Incremental Acquisition of Conceptual Indices for Multimedia Design Documentation</title><venue>Proceedings of the AAAI-94 Workshop on Indexing and Reuse in Multimedia Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pubAddress>Seattle, Washington</pubAddress><raw>Baudin, C., Pell, B., Kedar, S. (1994). Incremental Acquisition of Conceptual Indices for Multimedia Design Documentation. Proceedings of the AAAI-94 Workshop on Indexing and Reuse in Multimedia Systems, Seattle, Washington.</raw><contexts><context>y, there are two kinds of approaches. In the AI-based approach, natural language processing techniques (Sowa, 1984; Srihari and Burhans, 1994) or machine learning techniques (Barletta and Mark, 1988; Baudin et al, 1994) can be used to build or refine an internal representation of each text. Although most of these methods can produce deep conceptual indices, they can only work in restricted environments and usually </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28744"><authors>M Bowman,P Danzig,U Manber</authors><title>Scalable Internet Resource Discovery: Research Problems and Approaches</title><venue>Communications of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>98--114</pages><volume>37</volume><raw>Bowman, M., Danzig, P., Manber, U., &amp; Schwartz, F. (1994). Scalable Internet Resource Discovery: Research Problems and Approaches. Communications of the ACM, 37, 8, pp. 98-114.</raw><contexts><context>sort of structure and then let the user navigate through it. In fact, the organizing/navigating paradigm is becoming very popular (Thompson and Croft, 1989; Maarek et al, 1991; Lucarella et al, 1993; Bowman et al, 1994). One main problem of this approach is creating the atomic pieces of information and linking them, which usually requires subjective and time-consuming decisions. We argue that conceptual clustering </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28745"><authors>C Carpineto</authors><title>GALOIS: An order-theoretic approach to conceptual clustering</title><venue>Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Machine Learning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>33--40</pages><publisher>Kaufmann</publisher><pubAddress>Amherst, MA:Morgan</pubAddress><raw>Carpineto, C., &amp; Romano, G. (1993). GALOIS: An order-theoretic approach to conceptual clustering. Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Machine Learning (pp. 33-40), Amherst, MA:Morgan Kaufmann.</raw></citation><citation id="28746"><authors>C Carpineto</authors><title>A lattice conceptual clustering system and its application to browsing retrieval</title><year>1994</year><raw>Carpineto, C., &amp; Romano, G. (1994a). A lattice conceptual clustering system and its application to browsing retrieval. Submitted to Machine Learning.</raw></citation><citation id="28747"><authors>C Carpineto</authors><title>Dynamically bounding browsable retrieval spaces: an application to Galois lattices</title><venue>In Proceedings of RIAO 94: Intelligent Multimedia Information Retrieval Systems and Management(pp. 520-533</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>Carpineto, C., &amp; Romano, G. (1994b). Dynamically bounding browsable retrieval spaces: an application to Galois lattices. In Proceedings of RIAO 94: Intelligent Multimedia Information Retrieval Systems and Management(pp. 520-533), New York.</raw></citation><citation id="28748"><authors>C Carpineto</authors><title>ULYSSES: A lattice-based multiple interaction strategy retrieval interface. To appear</title><venue>in Proceedings of EWHCI'95: 5th East-West Human Computer Interaction Conference, Moscow</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Carpineto, C., &amp; Romano, G. (1995). ULYSSES: A lattice-based multiple interaction strategy retrieval interface. To appear in Proceedings of EWHCI'95: 5th East-West Human Computer Interaction Conference, Moscow .</raw></citation><citation id="28749"><authors>H Chen,P Hsu,R Orwig,L Hoopes,J Nunamaker</authors><title>Automatic concept classification of text from electronic meeting</title><venue>Communications of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1994</year><pages>57--73</pages><volume>37</volume><raw>Chen, H., Hsu, P., Orwig, R., Hoopes, L., Nunamaker, J. (1994). Automatic concept classification of text from electronic meeting. Communications of the ACM, 37, 10, pp. 57-73.</raw><contexts><context> generality and efficiency. For instance, we could use vocabulary normalization tools such as synonym list and thesarus associations, or using adjacent words to form term-phrases (Maarek et al, 1991; Chen et al, 1994). We have to emphasize, however, that it has been often reported that in many practical situations the use of more elaborated systems than single-word term extraction did not result in significant pe</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28750"><authors>D Crouch,C Crouch</authors><title>The use of cluster hierarchies in hypertext information retrieval</title><venue>Proceedings of the ACM Hypertext '89 Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1989</year><pages>225--237</pages><publisher>ACM</publisher><pubAddress>Pittsburgh, PA</pubAddress><raw>Crouch, D., Crouch, C., &amp; Andreas, G. (1989). The use of cluster hierarchies in hypertext information retrieval. Proceedings of the ACM Hypertext '89 Conference (pp. 225-237), Pittsburgh, PA: ACM.</raw></citation><citation id="28751"><authors>G Furnas</authors><title>Generalized fisheye views</title><venue>Proceedings of the Human Factors in Computing Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1986</year><pages>16--23</pages><publisher>North</publisher><pubAddress>Holland</pubAddress><raw>Furnas, G. (1986). Generalized fisheye views. Proceedings of the Human Factors in Computing Systems (pp.16-23). North Holland.</raw><contexts><context>e interface on top of GALOIS, named ULYSSES 2 . The first problem in the design of the interface is the visualization of the search space. We adopted an approach similar to generalized fish-eye view (Furnas, 1986), in which there is a current focus of interest and the adjacent nodes are displayed with decreasing level of detail as we move away from the focus. As the lattice is typically too large to fit on a </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28752"><authors>D Karp,Y Schabes,M Zaidel,D Egedi</authors><title>A freely available wide coverage morphological analyzer for English</title><venue>Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING '92</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1992</year><pubAddress>Nantes, France</pubAddress><raw>Karp, D., Schabes, Y., Zaidel, M., Egedi, D. (1992). A freely available wide coverage morphological analyzer for English. Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING '92), Nantes, France.</raw><contexts><context>dual words occurring in a text collection, ignoring punctuation and case. 2. Word stemming We reduce each word to word-stem form. This is done by using a very large morphological lexicon for English (Karp et al, 1992) that contains the standard inflections for nouns (singular, plural, singular genitive, plural genitive), verbs (infinitive, third person singular, past tense, past participle, progressive form), adj</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28753"><authors>D Lucarella,S Parisotto,A Zanzi</authors><title>MORE: Multimedia Object Retrieval Environment</title><venue>Proceedings of the Fifth ACM Conference on Hypertext</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pages>39--50</pages><pubAddress>Seattle, WA</pubAddress><raw>Lucarella, D., Parisotto, S., Zanzi, A. (1993). MORE: Multimedia Object Retrieval Environment. Proceedings of the Fifth ACM Conference on Hypertext (pp. 39-50). Seattle, WA.</raw><contexts><context> information into some sort of structure and then let the user navigate through it. In fact, the organizing/navigating paradigm is becoming very popular (Thompson and Croft, 1989; Maarek et al, 1991; Lucarella et al, 1993; Bowman et al, 1994). One main problem of this approach is creating the atomic pieces of information and linking them, which usually requires subjective and time-consuming decisions. We argue that co</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28754"><authors>Y Maarek,D Berry</authors><title>An Information Retrieval Approach For Automatically Constructing Software Libraries</title><venue>IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>800--813</pages><volume>17</volume><raw>Maarek, Y., Berry, D., &amp; Kaiser, G. (1991). An Information Retrieval Approach For Automatically Constructing Software Libraries. IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering, 17, 8, 800-813.</raw></citation><citation id="28755"><authors>C Mellish</authors><title>The description identification problem</title><venue>Artificial Intelligence</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>151--168</pages><volume>52</volume><raw>Mellish, C. (1991). The description identification problem. Artificial Intelligence, 52, 2, 151-168.</raw><contexts><context> constraint are expressed as inequality relations between the description of any admissible class c and some conjunction of terms c1. In our framework, which is logically similar to that proposed in (Mellish, 1991), there are four types of constraints (i.e., c &gt; c1, c &lt; c1, c ¬ &gt; c1, c ¬ &lt; c1); each constraint produces a simple graphical partition of the search space, and possesses a meaningful interpretation </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28756"><authors>R Michalski,R Stepp</authors><title>Learning from observation: Conceptual clustering</title><venue>In</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1983</year><publisher>Tioga Publishing</publisher><pubAddress>Palo Alto, CA</pubAddress><volume>1</volume><raw>Michalski, R., Stepp, R. (1983). Learning from observation: Conceptual clustering. In R. Michalski, J. Carbonell, T. Mitchell (Eds.), Machine Learning: An Artificial Intelligence Approach (Vol. 1). Palo Alto, CA: Tioga Publishing.</raw></citation><citation id="28757"><authors>G Salton</authors><title>Automatic Text Processing: The transformation, Analysis and Retrieval of Information by Computer</title><year>1989</year><publisher>Addison Wesley</publisher><raw>Salton, G. (1989). Automatic Text Processing: The transformation, Analysis and Retrieval of Information by Computer. Addison Wesley.</raw><contexts><context>of the weigthing functions that have been proposed tend to favor terms occurring with relatively high frequencies in some individual documents, but with a relatively low overall collection frequency (Salton, 1989). We use the Signal-Noise Ratio method, which has an information theory basis; the signal of term k for a collection of n documents is defined as follows SIGNAL k = log 2 (TOTFREQ k ) − NOISE k NOISE</context><context>, however, that it has been often reported that in many practical situations the use of more elaborated systems than single-word term extraction did not result in significant performance improvement (Salton, 1989). Computationally, the indexing module works fairly well. We organized the lexicon into a digital search tree, or trie, and represented all other information (stop-words, weights, etc.) into the same</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28758"><authors>J Sowa</authors><venue>Conceptual Structures: Information Processing in Mind and Machine, Addison-Wesley</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1984</year><raw>Sowa, J. (1984). Conceptual Structures: Information Processing in Mind and Machine, Addison-Wesley, 1984.</raw><contexts><context>a conceptual representation of a text database is to identify the content of each text. Basically, there are two kinds of approaches. In the AI-based approach, natural language processing techniques (Sowa, 1984; Srihari and Burhans, 1994) or machine learning techniques (Barletta and Mark, 1988; Baudin et al, 1994) can be used to build or refine an internal representation of each text. Although most of these</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28759"><authors>R Srihari,D Burhans</authors><title>Visual Semantics: Extracting Visual Information from Text Accompanying Pictures</title><venue>Proceedings of AAAI-94</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><publisher>AAAI Press</publisher><pubAddress>Seattle, Washington</pubAddress><raw>Srihari, R., Burhans, D. (1994). Visual Semantics: Extracting Visual Information from Text Accompanying Pictures. Proceedings of AAAI-94, Seattle, Washington, AAAI Press.</raw><contexts><context> representation of a text database is to identify the content of each text. Basically, there are two kinds of approaches. In the AI-based approach, natural language processing techniques (Sowa, 1984; Srihari and Burhans, 1994) or machine learning techniques (Barletta and Mark, 1988; Baudin et al, 1994) can be used to build or refine an internal representation of each text. Although most of these methods can produce deep c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28760"><authors>R Thompson</authors><title>Support for browsing in an intelligent text retrieval system</title><venue>International Journal of Man-machine Studies</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1989</year><pages>639--668</pages><volume>30</volume><raw>Thompson, R., &amp; Croft, B. (1989). Support for browsing in an intelligent text retrieval system. International Journal of Man-machine Studies, 30, 639-668.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://search.fub.it/claudio/pdf/AIIA1995.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>337b8fbbd31b23f5c070d283aab54cf4c2eef510</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>