<document id="10.1.1.1.1556"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Netview: Application Software for Constructing and Visually Exploring Phylogenetic Networks</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Reconstructing evolutionary history of a group of species is a major task in biological study. Many methods exist for reconstructing such history, or phylogeny, but most of them are based on an assumption that evolution of given gene family can be represented as a tree. However some families of genes may have alternative historical structure that cannot be represented as a tree. Such history can</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1268">phylogenetic network</keyword><keyword id="1269">neighbor-joining method</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4336"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Kirill Kryukov</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Graduate University for Advanced Studies, Mishima 411-8540, Japan</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">kkryukov@lab.nig.ac.jp</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4337"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Naruya Saitou</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Graduate University for Advanced Studies, Mishima 411-8540, Japan</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">nsaitou@genes.nig.ac.jp</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29252"><authors>N Saitou,M Nei</authors><title>The neighbor-joining method: a new method for reconstructing phylogenetic trees, Molecular Biology and Evolution</title><year>1987</year><pages>4--406</pages><raw>Saitou, N. and Nei, M., The neighbor-joining method: a new method for reconstructing phylogenetic trees, Molecular Biology and Evolution, 4:406–425, 1987.</raw><contexts><context>veloped a program Netview, which enables constructing phylogenetic network based on the sequence data. 2 Netview Netview uses following approach to construct a network: First, it constructs a NJ-tree [1] for provided set of sequences, using nucleotide difference distance matrix (Fig. 1). Then every nucleotide site position of sequence data is analyzed to check if it is compatible with the NJ-tree con</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29253"><authors>N Saitou,F-I Yamamoto</authors><title>Evolution of primate ABO blood group genes and their homologous genes, Molecular Biology and Evolution</title><year>1997</year><raw>Saitou, N. and Yamamoto, F.-I., Evolution of primate ABO blood group genes and their homologous genes, Molecular Biology and Evolution, 14(4):399–411, 1997.</raw><contexts><context>rns (designated with binary characters) that are present in the sequence data. Partitions 1-5, 7, and 8 are compatible with the NJ tree, while partitions 6, 9, 10 are not. (Example sequences are from [2]) Figure 2: Example phylogenetic network, produced with Netview. Partition no. 6 was chosen. Netview is written in C and has it’s source will be open. Currently only a windows version exists, but it i</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://hc.ims.u-tokyo.ac.jp/JSBi/journal/GIW03/GIW03SS06.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>83b5aaa85c01bf0034b9b41ab3be1b1a85df9ffb</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>