<document id="10.1.1.1.1560"><clusterid>1219</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">Automatic Topic Identification Using Ontology Hierarchy</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract. This paper proposes a method of using ontology hierarchy in automatic topic identification. The fundamental idea behind this work is to exploit an ontology hierarchical structure in order to find a topic of a text. The keywords which are extracted from a given text will be mapped onto their corresponding concepts in the ontology. By optimizing the corresponding concepts, we will pick a single node among the concepts nodes which we believe is the topic of the target text. However, a limited vocabulary problem is encountered while mapping the keywords onto their corresponding concepts. This situation forces us to extend the ontology by enriching each of its concepts with new concepts using the external linguistics knowledge-base (WordNet). Our intuition of a high number keywords mapped onto the ontology concepts is that our topic identification technique can perform at its best. 1</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2001</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In the Proc. of the 2 nd International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics (CICLing-2001</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">444--453</pages><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4313639"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Sabrina Tiun</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">1</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">UTMK, P.Pengajian Sains Komputer, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800; Pulau Pinang, Malaysia</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">sab@cs.usm.my</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="4313640"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Rosni Abdullah</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">1</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">UTMK, P.Pengajian Sains Komputer, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800; Pulau Pinang, Malaysia</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">rosni@cs.usm.my</email><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="4313641"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Tang Enya Kong</name><affil src="SVM HeaderParse 0.2">1</affil><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">UTMK, P.Pengajian Sains Komputer, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800; Pulau Pinang, Malaysia</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">enyakong@cs.usm.my</email><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29289"><clusterid>1220</clusterid><authors>S Banerjee,V O Mittal</authors><title>On the Use of Linguistics Ontologies for Acessing Distributed Digital Libraries</title><venue>Proceeding of the First Annual Conference on Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>Banerjee, S., Mittal, V.O.: On the Use of Linguistics Ontologies for Acessing Distributed Digital Libraries. Proceeding of the First Annual Conference on Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries (1994)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29290"><clusterid>1221</clusterid><authors>S Chakrabarti,B Dom,Indyk</authors><title>P.: Enhanced Hypertext Categorization Using Hyperlinks</title><venue>ACM SIGMIND</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Seattle, Washington</pubAddress><raw>Chakrabarti, S., Dom, B., Indyk, P.: Enhanced Hypertext Categorization Using Hyperlinks. ACM SIGMIND, Seattle, Washington (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29291"><clusterid>1222</clusterid><authors>C Chekuri,M H Goldwasser,P Raghavan,Upfal</authors><title>E.: Web Search Using Automated Classification</title><venue>Poster at the Sixth International World Wide Web Conference (WWW6</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Chekuri, C., Goldwasser, M.H, Raghavan, P., Upfal, E.: Web Search Using Automated Classification. Poster at the Sixth International World Wide Web Conference (WWW6) (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29292"><clusterid>1223</clusterid><authors>D’ Alessio,D Murray,K Schiaffino,R Kreshenbaum</authors><title>A.: Hierarchical Text Categorization. Proceeding RIAO2000</title><year>2000</year><raw>D’ Alessio, D., Murray, K., Schiaffino, R., Kreshenbaum, A.: Hierarchical Text Categorization. Proceeding RIAO2000 (2000)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29293"><clusterid>1224</clusterid><authors>D’ Alessio,D Murray,K Schiaffino,R Kreshenbaum</authors><title>A.: The effect of Topological Structure on Hierarchical Text Categorization</title><venue>Proceeding of the Sixth Workshop on Very Large Corpora, COLLING ACL ’98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>D’ Alessio, D., Murray, K., Schiaffino, R., Kreshenbaum, A.: The effect of Topological Structure on Hierarchical Text Categorization. Proceeding of the Sixth Workshop on Very Large Corpora, COLLING ACL ’98 (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29294"><clusterid>1225</clusterid><authors>A Gelbukh,G Sidorov,Guzman</authors><title>A.: A Method of Describing Document Contents through Topic Selection</title><venue>In Proc. of International Symposium on String Processing and Information Retrieval, Cancun, Mexico. Library of Congress 99-64139, IEEE Computer</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><publisher>Society Press</publisher><raw>Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman, A.: A Method of Describing Document Contents through Topic Selection. In Proc. of International Symposium on String Processing and Information Retrieval, Cancun, Mexico. Library of Congress 99-64139, IEEE Computer Society Press (1999)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29295"><clusterid>1226</clusterid><authors>A Gelbukh,G Sidorov,Guzman</authors><title>A.: Use of a Weighted Topic Hierarchy for Document Classification</title><venue>In Václav Matoušek et al (eds.): Text, Speech and Dialogue in Poc. 2 nd International Workshop. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, No.92, ISBN 3-54066494-7, Springer-Verlag., Czech Republic</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>130--135</pages><raw>Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman, A.: Use of a Weighted Topic Hierarchy for Document Classification. In Václav Matoušek et al (eds.): Text, Speech and Dialogue in Poc. 2 nd International Workshop. Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence, No.92, ISBN 3-54066494-7, Springer-Verlag., Czech Republic (1999) 130-135</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29296"><clusterid>1227</clusterid><authors>A Gelbukh,G Sidorov,Guzman</authors><title>A.,: Text Categorization Using a Hierarchical Topic Dictionary</title><venue>Proc. Text Mining Workshop at 16th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI’99</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Stockholm, Sweden</pubAddress><raw>Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman, A.,: Text Categorization Using a Hierarchical Topic Dictionary. Proc. Text Mining Workshop at 16th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI’99), Stockholm, Sweden (1999)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29297"><clusterid>1228</clusterid><authors>N Gövert,M Lalmas,Fuhr</authors><title>N.: A Probabilistic Description-Oriented Approach for Categorizing Web Document</title><venue>Proceeding of the Eighth International Conference on Information Knowledge Management</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>475--482</pages><pubAddress>Kansas City, MO USA</pubAddress><raw>Gövert, N., Lalmas, M., Fuhr, N.: A Probabilistic Description-Oriented Approach for Categorizing Web Document. Proceeding of the Eighth International Conference on Information Knowledge Management, Kansas City, MO USA (1999) 475-482</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29298"><clusterid>1229</clusterid><authors>R Greiner,A Grove,Schuurmans</authors><title>D.: On learning hierarchical Classifications</title><year>1997</year><raw>Greiner, R., Grove, A, Schuurmans, D.: On learning hierarchical Classifications (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29299"><clusterid>1230</clusterid><authors>M Grobelnik,Mladenic</authors><title>D.: Fast Categorization</title><venue>In Proceedings of Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery Data Mining</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>Grobelnik, M., Mladenic, D.: Fast Categorization. In Proceedings of Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery Data Mining (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29300"><clusterid>1231</clusterid><authors>A Guzman</authors><title>Finding the Main Themes in a Spanish Document. Journal Expert Systems with Application</title><year>1998</year><pages>139--148</pages><raw>Guzman, A.: Finding the Main Themes in a Spanish Document. Journal Expert Systems with Application (1998) 139-148</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29301"><clusterid>1232</clusterid><authors>E Hoenkamp</authors><title>Spotting Ontological Lacunae through Spectrum Analysis Of Retrieved Documents</title><venue>13 th European Conference On Artificial Intelligent, ECAI98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Brighton, England</pubAddress><raw>Hoenkamp, E.: Spotting Ontological Lacunae through Spectrum Analysis Of Retrieved Documents. 13 th European Conference On Artificial Intelligent, ECAI98, Brighton, England (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29302"><clusterid>1233</clusterid><authors>D Koller,Sahami</authors><title>M.: Hierarchically Classifying Documents Using Very Few Words</title><venue>In the Proceeding of Machine Learning (ICML-97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><pages>170--176</pages><raw>Koller, D., Sahami, M.: Hierarchically Classifying Documents Using Very Few Words. In the Proceeding of Machine Learning (ICML-97) (1997) 170-176</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29303"><clusterid>1234</clusterid><authors>J Shin Lee</authors><title>D.: Multilevel Automatic Categorization for Webpages. The INET Proceeding ’98</title><year>1998</year><raw>Lee, J. Shin, D.: Multilevel Automatic Categorization for Webpages. The INET Proceeding ’98 (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29304"><clusterid>1235</clusterid><authors>C Y Lin,Hovy</authors><title>E.: Identifying Topics by Position</title><venue>In the Proceeding of The Workshop of Intelligent Scalable Text Summarization ’97</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Lin, C.Y, Hovy, E.: Identifying Topics by Position. In the Proceeding of The Workshop of Intelligent Scalable Text Summarization ’97 (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29305"><clusterid>1236</clusterid><authors>C Y Lin</authors><title>Knowledge-based Automatic Topic Identification</title><venue>In the Proceeding of The 33 rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics ’95</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Lin, C.Y: Knowledge-based Automatic Topic Identification. In the Proceeding of The 33 rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics ’95 (1995)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29306"><clusterid>1237</clusterid><authors>A McCallum,R Rosenfeld,T Mitchell,Y A Ng</authors><title>Improving Text Classification by Shrinkage in a Hierarchy of Classes</title><venue>Proceeding of the 15 th Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-98</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>McCallum, A., Rosenfeld, R., Mitchell, T., Ng, Y.A.: Improving Text Classification by Shrinkage in a Hierarchy of Classes. Proceeding of the 15 th Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-98) (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29307"><clusterid>1238</clusterid><authors>G A Miller,R Beckwith,C Fellbaum,D Gross,Miller</authors><title>K.: Introduction to WordNet</title><venue>An-Online Lexical Database. Five Papers on WordNet</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><raw>Miller, G.A, Beckwith, R., Fellbaum, C., Gross, D., Miller, K.: Introduction to WordNet: An-Online Lexical Database. Five Papers on WordNet (1993)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29308"><clusterid>1239</clusterid><authors>C Y Quek,Mitchell</authors><title>T: Classification of World Wide Web Documents. Seniors Honors Thesis</title><year>1998</year><raw>Quek, C.Y, Mitchell, T: Classification of World Wide Web Documents. Seniors Honors Thesis, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Melon University (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29309"><clusterid>1240</clusterid><authors>S Scott,S Matwin</authors><title>Text Classification using WordNet Hypernyms</title><venue>In the Proceeding of Workshop – Usage of WordNet in Natural Language Processing Systems</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Montreal, Canada</pubAddress><raw>Scott, S., Matwin, S.: Text Classification using WordNet Hypernyms. In the Proceeding of Workshop – Usage of WordNet in Natural Language Processing Systems, Montreal, Canada (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29310"><clusterid>0</clusterid><authors>Sense Tagger</authors><venue>UTMK Internal Paper. Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, Malaysia</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Sense Tagger. UTMK Internal Paper. Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, Malaysia (1999)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29311"><clusterid>404</clusterid><authors>S Soderland</authors><title>Learning to extract text-based information from World Wide Web</title><venue>In the Proceeding of the Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and DataMining</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Soderland, S.: Learning to extract text-based information from World Wide Web. In the Proceeding of the Third International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and DataMining (1997)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29312"><clusterid>1241</clusterid><authors>E M Voorhees</authors><title>On Expanding Query Vectors with Lexically Related Words</title><venue>Proceeding of the Second Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-2), NIST Special Publication</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1993</year><pubAddress>Gatherburg, Maryland</pubAddress><raw>Voorhees, E.M.: On Expanding Query Vectors with Lexically Related Words. Proceeding of the Second Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-2), NIST Special Publication, Gatherburg, Maryland (1993)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation><citation id="29313"><clusterid>1242</clusterid><authors>A S Weigned,E D Wiener,J O Pedersen</authors><title>Working Papers IS-98-22</title><venue>Of Business, New York University</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><raw>Weigned, A.S, Wiener, E.D, Pedersen, J.O.: Working Papers IS-98-22. Dept. of Info. System, Leonard N. Stern, School Of Business, New York University (1998)</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1560</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://utmk.cs.usm.my/pdf/CICLing01.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>