<document id="10.1.1.1.1549"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Adaptive Sampling for Environmental Robotics</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract — The capabilities and distributed nature of networked sensors are uniquely suited to the characterization of distributed phenomena in the natural environment. However, environmental characterization by fixed distributed sensors encounters challenges in complex environments. In this paper we describe Networked Infomechanical Systems (NIMS), a new distributed, robotic sensor methodology developed for applications including characterization of environmental structure and phenomena. NIMS exploits deployed infrastructure that provides the benefits of precise motion, aerial suspension, and low energy sustainable operations in complex environments. NIMS nodes may explore a three-dimensional environment and enable the deployment of sensor nodes at diverse locations and viewing perspectives. NIMS characterization of phenomena in a three dimensional space must now consider the selection of sensor sampling points</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4320"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Mohammad Rahimi</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">CA 90089</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">{mhr@cens.ucla.edu</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4321"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Richard Pon</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">CA 90089</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">rpon@ee.ucla.edu</email><order>2</order></author><author id="4322"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">William J. Kaiser</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">CA 90089</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">kaiser@ee.ucla.edu</email><order>3</order></author><author id="4323"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Gaurav S. Sukhatme</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">CA 90089</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">gaurav@pollux.usc.edu</email><order>4</order></author><author id="4324"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Deborah Estrin</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">CA 90089</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">mbs@ee.ucla.edu</email><order>5</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29112"><authors>G J Pottie,W J Kaiser</authors><title>Wireless Integrated Network Sensors</title><venue>Communications of the ACM</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><pages>51--58</pages><volume>43</volume><raw>Pottie, G.J., and Kaiser, W.J., “Wireless Integrated Network Sensors”, Communications of the ACM, vol. 43, pp. 51-58, 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29113"><authors>D Estrin,G J Pottie,M Srivastava</authors><title>Instrumenting the world with wireless sensor networks</title><venue>ICASSP 2001</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>7--11</pages><pubAddress>Salt Lake City</pubAddress><raw>Estrin, D., Pottie, G.J., Srivastava, M., “Instrumenting the world with wireless sensor networks”, ICASSP 2001, Salt Lake City, May 7-11,</raw></citation><citation id="29114"><authors>K Sohrabi,B Manriquez,G J Pottie</authors><title>Near ground wideband channel measurement in 800-1000 MHz</title><venue>IEEE VTC Spring</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>16--20</pages><pubAddress>Houston, TX</pubAddress><volume>99</volume><raw>Sohrabi, K., Manriquez, B., and Pottie, G.J., “Near ground wideband channel measurement in 800-1000 MHz&amp;quot;, IEEE VTC Spring '99, Houston, TX May 16-20, 1999.</raw><contexts><context>y motion for sustainable operation, 5) logistics capability with energy transport via the cable systems, and 6) node elevation for enhancing wireless link budget relative to surface-distributed nodes [4]. Finally, the need for high fidelity monitoring of large environments will require the simultaneous operation of multiple NIMS nodes that exploit the infrastructure for communication and coordination</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29115"><authors>M J Mataric,G S Sukhatme,D Ostergaard</authors><title>Multi-robot Task Allocation in Uncertain Environments”, Autonomous Robots</title><raw>Mataric,M.J., Sukhatme,G.S., and Ostergaard, D., “Multi-robot Task Allocation in Uncertain Environments”, Autonomous Robots (to appear).</raw><contexts><context> Finally, the need for high fidelity monitoring of large environments will require the simultaneous operation of multiple NIMS nodes that exploit the infrastructure for communication and coordination [5]. NIMS applications to environmental monitoring range from fundamental science objectives to public health and safety. Examples include natural environment monitoring with requirements for characteriz</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29116"><authors>C M P Ozanne,D Anhuf,S L Boulter,M Keller,R L Kitching,C Körner,F C Meinzer,A W Mitchell,T Nakashizuka,Silva Dias,P L Stork,N E Wright,S J Yoshimura,M</authors><title>Biodiversity meets the atmosphere: A global view of forest canopies</title><venue>Science</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2003</year><pages>183--186</pages><volume>301</volume><raw>Ozanne, C.M.P., Anhuf, D., Boulter, S.L., Keller, M., Kitching, R.L., Körner, C., Meinzer, F.C., Mitchell, A.W., Nakashizuka, T., Silva Dias, P.L., Stork, N.E., Wright, S.J., Yoshimura, M. (2003), “Biodiversity meets the atmosphere: A global view of forest canopies.”, Science, vol. 301, pp. 183-186, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>on of space- and time-dependent variables of temperature, water vapor concentration, and solar illumination within the complex environment is essential to the investigation of global change phenomena [6]. These variables must be sampled in a vast three-dimensional volume while both spatial and temporal variations are unknown and initially are unpredictable. Thus, while NIMS capabilities offer the abi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29117"><authors>S Thrun</authors><title>Robotics Mapping: A survey”, Exploring Artificial Intelligence in the New Millenium by</title><year>2002</year><publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><raw>S. Thrun, “Robotics Mapping: A survey”, Exploring Artificial Intelligence in the New Millenium by Lakemeyer, G. and Nebel, B. Morgan Kaufmann 2002.</raw></citation><citation id="29118"><authors>S Thrun,D Fox,W Burgard</authors><title>A probabilistic approach to concurrent mapping and localization for mobile robots</title><venue>Machine Learning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><pages>31--29</pages><volume>5</volume><raw>S. Thrun, D. Fox, and W. Burgard, “A probabilistic approach to concurrent mapping and localization for mobile robots”, Machine Learning, 31:29-53, 1998. also appeared in Autonomous Robots 5, 253271.</raw></citation><citation id="29119"><authors>A M Jazwinsky</authors><title>Stochastic Processes and Filtering Theory</title><year>1970</year><publisher>Academic</publisher><pubAddress>New York</pubAddress><raw>A.M. Jazwinsky. “Stochastic Processes and Filtering Theory” Academic, New York, 1970.</raw><contexts><context>ularly in the presence of dynamic environments. Robotic mapping algorithms have relied primarily on probabilistic as opposed to statistical approaches. These approaches range from the Bayesian filter [9] to Kalman filter [10], hidden Markov model [11], to Bayesian network. These methods apply to mapping unknown environments with known robotic localization or localization with known environments. The </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29120"><authors>R E Kalman</authors><title>A new approach to linear filtering and prediction problems”, Trans</title><venue>ASME, Journal of Basic Engineering,82:35–45</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1960</year><raw>R. E. Kalman. “A new approach to linear filtering and prediction problems”, Trans. ASME, Journal of Basic Engineering,82:35–45, 1960.</raw><contexts><context>e of dynamic environments. Robotic mapping algorithms have relied primarily on probabilistic as opposed to statistical approaches. These approaches range from the Bayesian filter [9] to Kalman filter [10], hidden Markov model [11], to Bayesian network. These methods apply to mapping unknown environments with known robotic localization or localization with known environments. The Simultaneous Localizat</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29121"><authors>L R Rabiner</authors><title>A tutorial on hidden markov models and selected applications in speech recognition</title><venue>In Proceedings of theIEEE. IEEE</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1989</year><volume>8825949</volume><raw>L. R. Rabiner. “A tutorial on hidden markov models and selected applications in speech recognition”, In Proceedings of theIEEE. IEEE, 1989. IEEE Log Number 8825949.</raw><contexts><context> Robotic mapping algorithms have relied primarily on probabilistic as opposed to statistical approaches. These approaches range from the Bayesian filter [9] to Kalman filter [10], hidden Markov model [11], to Bayesian network. These methods apply to mapping unknown environments with known robotic localization or localization with known environments. The Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) app</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29122"><authors>G Dissanayake,H Durrant-Whyte,T Bailey</authors><title>A computationally efficient solution to the simultaneous localisation and map building (SLAM) problem”, Working notes of ICRA’2000Workshop W4: Mobile Robot Navigation and Mapping,April</title><year>2000</year><raw>G. Dissanayake, H. Durrant-Whyte, and T. Bailey. “A computationally efficient solution to the simultaneous localisation and map building (SLAM) problem”, Working notes of ICRA’2000Workshop W4: Mobile Robot Navigation and Mapping,April 2000.</raw><contexts><context> localization or localization with known environments. The Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) approach is intended to achieve both mapping and localization without prior knowledge of either.[12] Geostatistics provides analysis methods for determination of spatial variation and interpolation of sampled data to obtain reconstructions (maps) of phenomena. These techniques have been long used in</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29123"><authors>M A Oliver,A L Kharyat</authors><title>Investigating the spatial variation of radon in soil geostatistically</title><venue>Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on GeoComputation Mary</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pages>2--8</pages><pubAddress>Washington College Fredericksburg, Virginia, USA</pubAddress><volume>25</volume><raw>M. A. Oliver, A. L. Kharyat. “Investigating the spatial variation of radon in soil geostatistically”, Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on GeoComputation Mary Washington College Fredericksburg, Virginia, USA 25 - 28 July 1999.</raw><contexts><context>for determination of spatial variation and interpolation of sampled data to obtain reconstructions (maps) of phenomena. These techniques have been long used in science disciplines such soil analysis, [13] weather mapping, [14] atmospheric science, [15] contamination studies, and geology. Also in the field of sensor networks, research has yielded methods for determination of spatio-temporal variable di</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29124"><authors>G Dubois,M Saisana,A Chaloulakou,N Spyrellis</authors><title>Spatial correlation analysis of nitrogen dioxide (NO2) concentrations in the area of Milan</title><venue>Italy”. Proceedings of the First Biennial Meeting of the International Modelling and Software Society, IEMSS’2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pages>536--541</pages><pubAddress>Lugano, Switzerland</pubAddress><volume>3</volume><raw>Dubois G., Saisana M., Chaloulakou A. and Spyrellis N. (2002). “Spatial correlation analysis of nitrogen dioxide (NO2) concentrations in the area of Milan, Italy”. Proceedings of the First Biennial Meeting of the International Modelling and Software Society, IEMSS’2002, June 2002, Lugano, Switzerland. A. E. Rizzoli &amp; A. J. Jakeman (Eds), Vol. 3., pp. 536-541.</raw><contexts><context>patial variation and interpolation of sampled data to obtain reconstructions (maps) of phenomena. These techniques have been long used in science disciplines such soil analysis, [13] weather mapping, [14] atmospheric science, [15] contamination studies, and geology. Also in the field of sensor networks, research has yielded methods for determination of spatio-temporal variable distribution and efficie</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29125"><authors>G Christakos,V M Vyas</authors><title>A composite space/time approach to studying ozone distribution over eastern United States”, Atmos</title><venue>Env</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1998</year><pages>2845--2857</pages><volume>32</volume><raw>Christakos, G., and V.M. Vyas, “A composite space/time approach to studying ozone distribution over eastern United States”, Atmos. Env., 32, 2845-2857, 1998</raw><contexts><context>polation of sampled data to obtain reconstructions (maps) of phenomena. These techniques have been long used in science disciplines such soil analysis, [13] weather mapping, [14] atmospheric science, [15] contamination studies, and geology. Also in the field of sensor networks, research has yielded methods for determination of spatio-temporal variable distribution and efficient field estimation for fi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29126"><authors>R Nowak,U</authors><title>Mitra,”Boundary Estimation in Sensor Networks: Theory and Methods</title><venue>2nd International Workshop on Information Processing in Sensor Networks</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pages>22--23</pages><pubAddress>Palo Alto, CA</pubAddress><raw>R. Nowak and U. Mitra,”Boundary Estimation in Sensor Networks: Theory and Methods”, , 2nd International Workshop on Information Processing in Sensor Networks, Palo Alto, CA, April 22-23, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>ies, and geology. Also in the field of sensor networks, research has yielded methods for determination of spatio-temporal variable distribution and efficient field estimation for fixed sensing points.[16,17] This NIMS investigation is focused on the problem of spatiotemporal sampling of dynamic and unpredictable environmental phenomena in three-dimensional spaces. This requires that sampling be responsiv</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29127"><authors>Deepak Ganesan,Sylvia Ratnasamy</authors><title>Hanbiao Wang and Deborah Estrin. “Coping with irregular spatio-temporal sampling</title><venue>in sensor networks”, 2nd Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-II</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>Deepak Ganesan, Sylvia Ratnasamy, Hanbiao Wang and Deborah Estrin. “Coping with irregular spatio-temporal sampling in sensor networks”, 2nd Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets-II), November 2003.</raw><contexts><context>ies, and geology. Also in the field of sensor networks, research has yielded methods for determination of spatio-temporal variable distribution and efficient field estimation for fixed sensing points.[16,17] This NIMS investigation is focused on the problem of spatiotemporal sampling of dynamic and unpredictable environmental phenomena in three-dimensional spaces. This requires that sampling be responsiv</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29128"><authors>W J Youden,A Mehlich</authors><title>Selection of efficient methods for soil sampling</title><venue>Contributions of the Boyce Thompson Institute of Plant Research</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1937</year><pages>59--72</pages><volume>9</volume><raw>Youden, W.J. and A. Mehlich, 1937. “Selection of efficient methods for soil sampling”. Contributions of the Boyce Thompson Institute of Plant Research, 9, pp. 59-72</raw></citation><citation id="29129"><authors>M A Oliver,R Webster</authors><title>1986 . “Combining nested and linear sampling for determining the scale and form of spatial variation of regionalized variables</title><venue>Geographical Analysis</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>227--242</pages><volume>18</volume><raw>Oliver, M.A., and R. Webster ,1986 . “Combining nested and linear sampling for determining the scale and form of spatial variation of regionalized variables”, Geographical Analysis, 18, pp. 227-242.</raw></citation><citation id="29130"><title>Cressie NAC.,1990, “The Origin of Kriging</title><venue>Mathematical Geology</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>239--252</pages><volume>22</volume><raw>Cressie NAC.,1990, “The Origin of Kriging” , Mathematical Geology, 22, p. 239-252.</raw><contexts><context>ling pixel at point i,j and Zˆ L ( i, j) is the average value of the leaf stratum that the pixel belongs to it. In practice a more sophisticated spatial mapping technique, for example, that of Kriging[20] may be readily used here leading to reduced estimation error in specific applications. D. Convergence Properties Convergence condition of this sampling algorithm depends on the spatial distribution o</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29131"><authors>N A C Cressie</authors><title>Fitting variogram models by weighted least squares”.Mathematical Geology</title><year>1985</year><pages>563--586</pages><volume>17</volume><raw>Cressie, N.A.C. 1985. “Fitting variogram models by weighted least squares”.Mathematical Geology, Vol. 17, pp. 563–586.</raw><contexts><context>ends on the spatial distribution of data. There are existing techniques for specification of sampling characteristics for environments. One such tool that has received much attention is the variogram [21]. The variogram reveals the randomness and structured aspects of the spatial dispersion of a given variable. The variogram is a plot of the average square difference between the values of a spatial va</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29132"><authors>Wind River</authors><title>Canopy Crane Reseach Facility</title><venue>http://depts.washington.edu/wrccrf</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Wind River Canopy Crane Reseach Facility , “http://depts.washington.edu/wrccrf/ ”</raw><contexts><context>etically Active Radiation (PAR) spectral band. In addition to local deployments near our facilities an experimental deployment has also been completed at the Wind River Canopy Crane Research Facility [22] near Carson, Washington, located in the Wind River Experimental Forest. The NIMS deployment included a complete system with NIMS sensor nodes (carrying both vertical and horizontal mobility), solar c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29133"><authors>P Chaudhuri,M-C Huang,W-Y Loh,R Yao</authors><title>Piecewise-polynomial regression trees”, Statistica Sinica</title><year>1994</year><pages>4--143</pages><raw>P. Chaudhuri, M.-C. Huang, W.-Y. Loh, and R. Yao, (1994). “Piecewise-polynomial regression trees”, Statistica Sinica,, 4,143-167.</raw><contexts><context>iple assets that may be properly distributed. • Using more accurate piecewise linear tree estimation of a phenomena. Estimation of leaf area can be replaced by higher order estimators at each stratum [23] to increase sampling efficiency especially as nonlinearly of the phenomena increases. • Finally, while the sampling method reported here relies on a proactive exploration of the environment (followed</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://cres.usc.edu/pubdb_html/files_upload/400.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>03258ad97a825e35c44f87f6ae5e704f3651b3f0</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>