<document id="10.1.1.1.1589"><clusterid>1757</clusterid><title src="INFERENCE">Biodiversity Informatics: The Challenge of Rapid Development, Large Databases, and Complex Data (keynote</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">There are high expectations in all sectors of society for immediate access to biological knowledge of all kinds. To fully exploit and manage the value of biological resources, society must have the intellectual tools to store, retrieve, collate, analyze, and synthesize organism-level and ecological scale information. However, it currently is difficult to discover, access, and use biodiversity data because of the long history of &quot;bottom-up&quot; evolution of scientific biodiversity information, the mismatch between the distribution of biodiversity itself and the distribution of the data about it, and, most importantly, the inherent complexity of biodiversity and ecological data. This stems from, among many factors, numerous data types, the nonexistence of a common underlying (binary) language, and the multiple perceptions of different researchers/data recorders across spatial or temporal distance or both. The challenge presented to the computer science and information technology community by the biodiversity and ecological information domain is worthy of all the time and talent that can be brought to bear, because the continued existence  of the species Homo sapiens depends upon  gaining an understanding of this spaceship Earth  and our fellow passengers upon it.</abstract><year src="INFERENCE">2000</year><venue src="INFERENCE">In Proceedings of 26th International Conference on Very Large Data Bases</venue><venType src="INFERENCE">CONFERENCE</venType><pages src="INFERENCE">729--732</pages><publisher src="INFERENCE">Morgan Kaufmann</publisher><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="7693733"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Meredith A. Lane</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Academy of Natural Sciences National Science Foundation CSIRO Entomology</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1900 Benjamin Franklin Pkwy 4201 Wilson Blvd GPO Box 1700; Philadelphia, PA 19103 Arlington, VA 20560 Canberra ACT 2601; USA; USA Australia</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">lane@ansp.org</email><order src="null">1</order></author><author id="7693734"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections"> James L. Edwards</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Academy of Natural Sciences National Science Foundation CSIRO Entomology</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1900 Benjamin Franklin Pkwy 4201 Wilson Blvd GPO Box 1700; Philadelphia, PA 19103 Arlington, VA 20560 Canberra ACT 2601; USA; USA Australia</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">jledward@nsf.gov</email><order src="null">2</order></author><author id="7693735"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Ebbe S. Nielsen</name><affil src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Academy of Natural Sciences National Science Foundation CSIRO Entomology</affil><address src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1900 Benjamin Franklin Pkwy 4201 Wilson Blvd GPO Box 1700; Philadelphia, PA 19103 Arlington, VA 20560 Canberra ACT 2601; USA; USA Australia</address><email src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">ebben@ento.csiro.au</email><order src="null">3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29842"><clusterid>1758</clusterid><authors>M A Lane</authors><title>Weaving a Web of Wealth: Biological Informatics for Industry, Science and Health. Report from the Australian Academy of Science</title><year>1999</year><pages>pp.</pages><pubAddress>Canberra, Australia</pubAddress><volume>40</volume><raw>Lane, M. A. 1999. Weaving a Web of Wealth: Biological Informatics for Industry, Science and Health. Report from the Australian Academy of Science, Canberra, Australia. 40 pp.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1589</paperid></citation><citation id="29843"><clusterid>1839</clusterid><authors></authors><title>President’s Committee of Advisors on Science and Technology Panel on Biodiversity and Ecosystems</title><year>1998</year><pages>pp.</pages><volume>96</volume><raw>President’s Committee of Advisors on Science and Technology Panel on Biodiversity and Ecosystems. 1998. Teaming With Life: Investing in Science to Understand and Use America’s Living Capital. 96 pp. http://www.whitehouse.gov/WH/EOP/OSTP/Environ ment/html/teamingcover.html</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1589</paperid></citation><citation id="29844"><clusterid>1759</clusterid><authors>Web</authors><title>site for the Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF) http://www.gbif.org</title><raw>Web site for the Global Biodiversity Information Facility (GBIF) http://www.gbif.org/</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1589</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.vldb.org/conf/2000/P729.pdf</url></urls></fileInfo></document>