<document id="10.1.1.1.1545"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">EPTD DISCUSSION PAPER NO. 83 HOW AGRICULTURAL RESEARCH AFFECTS URBAN POVERTY IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES: THE CASE OF CHINA</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">EPTD Discussion Papers contain preliminary material and research results, and are circulated prior to a full peer review in order to stimulate discussion and critical comment. It is expected that most Discussion Papers will eventually be published in some other form, and that their content may also be revised. This paper develops a framework to measure the impact of agricultural research on urban poverty. Increased investments in agricultural R&amp;D can lower food prices by increasing food production, and lower food prices benefit the urban poor because they often spend more than 60 % of their income on food. Application of the framework to China shows that these food price effects are large and that the benefits for the urban poor have been about as large as the benefits for the rural poor.</abstract><keywords><keyword id="1259">developing countries</keyword><keyword id="1260">China</keyword><keyword id="1261">agricultural research</keyword><keyword id="1262">urban</keyword><keyword id="1263">poverty i ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</keyword></keywords><authors><author id="4308"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Shenggen Fan</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2033 K Street, N.W.; Washington, D.C. 20006 U.S.A.</address><order>1</order></author><author id="4309"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Cheng Fang</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2033 K Street, N.W.; Washington, D.C. 20006 U.S.A.</address><order>2</order></author><author id="4310"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Xiaobo Zhang</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">2033 K Street, N.W.; Washington, D.C. 20006 U.S.A.</address><order>3</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="28965"><authors>M Akino,Y Hayami</authors><title>Efficiency and equity in public research: Rice breeding in Japan's economic development</title><venue>American Journal of Agricultural Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1975</year><pages>11--0</pages><volume>57</volume><raw>Akino, M. and Y. Hayami. 1975. Efficiency and equity in public research: Rice breeding in Japan's economic development. American Journal of Agricultural Economics 57(1): 110.</raw><contexts><context>ang, and Zhang 2000; Hazell and Haddad 2001). The links between agricultural research and food price benefits for consumers have also been quantified, using the consumer surplus as a welfare measure (Akino and Hayami 1975; Mellor 1975; Scobie and Posada 1978; and Pinstrup-Andersen 1979). But little work has been done on quantifying the impact of agricultural research on urban poverty reduction, despite the fact that r</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28966"><authors>J Alston,C Chan-Kang,M Marra,P Pardey,T Wyatt</authors><title>A meta-analysis of rates of return to agricultural</title><venue>R&amp;D, Ex Pede Herculem? Research Report 113, Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>Alston, J., C. Chan-Kang, M. Marra, P. Pardey, and T. Wyatt. 2000. A meta-analysis of rates of return to agricultural R&amp;D, Ex Pede Herculem? Research Report 113, Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw><contexts><context> COUNTRIES: THE CASE OF CHINA Shenggen Fan 1 , Cheng Fang, 2 and Xiaobo Zhang 3 1. INTRODUCTION Many studies have shown that investments in agricultural research can yield favorable economic returns (Alston et al. 2000), and contribute to significant reductions in rural poverty (Kerr and Kolavalli 1999; Fan, Hazell, and Thorat 2000; Fan, Zhang, and Zhang 2000; Hazell and Haddad 2001). The links between agricultural</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28967"><authors>J Alston,B Craig,P Pardey</authors><title>Dynamics in the creation and depreciation of knowledge, and the returns to research</title><venue>Environment and Production Technology Division Discussion Paper No. 35. Washington DC: International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>Alston, J., B. Craig, and P. Pardey. 1998. Dynamics in the creation and depreciation of knowledge, and the returns to research. Environment and Production Technology Division Discussion Paper No. 35. Washington DC: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw></citation><citation id="28968"><title>The Asian development bank and poverty reduction in China: Introduction</title><pages>2000--2000025</pages><raw>Asian Development Bank. 2000. The Asian development bank and poverty reduction in China: Introduction. http://www.adb.org/Documents/Speeches/2000/ms2000025.asp.</raw></citation><citation id="28969"><authors>R Davidson,J MacKinnon</authors><title>Estimation and inference in econometrics</title><year>1993</year><publisher>University Press</publisher><pubAddress>New York and London: Oxford</pubAddress><raw>Davidson, R. and J. MacKinnon. 1993. Estimation and inference in econometrics. New York and London: Oxford University Press.</raw></citation><citation id="28970"><authors>R E Evenson,P M Flores</authors><title>Social returns to rice research</title><venue>In Economic Consequences of the New Rice Technology. Los Banos, Philippines: International Rice Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1978</year><raw>Evenson, R. E., and P. M. Flores. 1978. Social returns to rice research. In Economic Consequences of the New Rice Technology. Los Banos, Philippines: International Rice Research Institute.</raw></citation><citation id="28971"><authors>Shenggen Fan</authors><title>Effects of technological change and institutional reform on production growth in Chinese agriculture</title><venue>American Journal of Agricultural Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1991</year><pages>266--275</pages><volume>73</volume><raw>Fan, Shenggen. 1991. Effects of technological change and institutional reform on production growth in Chinese agriculture. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, 73 (2): 266-275.</raw><contexts><context>s on agricultural production. Institutional changes and policy reforms have made important contributions to growth in agricultural and nonagricultural production and poverty reduction in rural China (Fan 1991, and Fan and Pardey 1997). We do not need to estimate these contributions for the purposes of this study, but in order to reduce possible estimation biases that may arise from neglecting them, we add</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28972"><title>Research investment and the economic returns to Chinese agricultural research</title><venue>Journal of Productivity Analysis</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><pages>9--2</pages><volume>14</volume><raw>Fan, Shenggen. 2000. Research investment and the economic returns to Chinese agricultural research. Journal of Productivity Analysis, 14 (92).</raw></citation><citation id="28973"><title>Government spending, agricultural growth and poverty in rural India</title><venue>American Journal of Agricultural Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1992</year><volume>82</volume><raw>Fan, Shenggen, Peter Hazell, and S. Thorat. 2000. Government spending, agricultural growth and poverty in rural India. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, 82 (4): Fan, Shenggen and Philip G. Pardey. 1992. Agricultural research in China: Its institutional development and impact. The Hague: International Service for National Agricultural Research.</raw><contexts><context> 45,669 0.56 10.34 5.24 0.44 1986-90 1,725 53,598 32,480 0.51 11.90 6.16 0.39 1991-94 2,099 61,876 33,886 0.54 14.29 6.14 0.39 1995-97 2,203 64,352 35,211 0.53 12.06 8.42 0.32 Sources: Fan and Pardey (1992), Fan and Pardey (1995), and State Statistical Bureau and State Science and Technology Commission (various years).sDuring the 1950s and 1960s, the number of researchers increased steadily. By 1973 the</context><context>research institutes. The research expenditures reported in this study include only those expenses used to directly support agricultural research. The data reported here were taken from Fan and Pardey (1992) and various publications from the Government Science and Technology Commission and the Government Statistical Bureau. Research expenditures and personnel numbers include those from research instituti</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28974"><authors>Shenggen Fan,P G Pardey</authors><title>Research, productivity, and output growth in Chinese agriculture</title><venue>Journal of Development Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1997</year><pages>115--137</pages><volume>53</volume><raw>Fan, Shenggen, and P. G. Pardey. 1997. Research, productivity, and output growth in Chinese agriculture. Journal of Development Economics, 53: 115-137.</raw><contexts><context>ral production. Institutional changes and policy reforms have made important contributions to growth in agricultural and nonagricultural production and poverty reduction in rural China (Fan 1991, and Fan and Pardey 1997). We do not need to estimate these contributions for the purposes of this study, but in order to reduce possible estimation biases that may arise from neglecting them, we added year and province dumm</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28975"><authors>Growth</authors><title>inequality, and poverty in rural China: The role of public investment</title><venue>Environment and Production Technology Division Discussion Paper No. 66. Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><raw>Fan, Shenggen, Linxiu Zhang, and Xiaobo Zhang. 2000. Growth, inequality, and poverty in rural China: The role of public investment. Environment and Production Technology Division Discussion Paper No. 66. Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw></citation><citation id="28976"><authors>W H Greene</authors><title>Econometric analysis</title><year>1993</year><publisher>Prentice-Hall, Inc</publisher><raw>Greene, W.H. 1993. Econometric analysis. Prentice-Hall, Inc.</raw><contexts><context>lag for R&amp;D expenditure. Various procedures have been suggested for determining the appropriate lag length. The adjusted R 2 and Akaike's Information Criteria (AIC) are often used by many economists (Greene 1993). In this report, we simply use the adjusted R 2 . Since the R 2 value estimated from a simultaneous equations system does not provide the correct information on the goodness of fit of the estimated </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28977"><authors>L Haddad,Marie T Ruel,James L Garret</authors><title>Are urban poverty and undernutrition growing? Some newly assembled evidence. Food Consumption and Nutrition Division Discussion Paper</title><venue>DC: International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Haddad, L., Marie T. Ruel, and James L. Garret. 1999. Are urban poverty and undernutrition growing? Some newly assembled evidence. Food Consumption and Nutrition Division Discussion Paper No. No. 63. Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw><contexts><context>been done on quantifying the impact of agricultural research on urban poverty reduction, despite the fact that rapid urbanization is increasing the incidence of urban poverty in developing countries (Haddad et al. 1999; Ravillion 2000). This paper is intended to help fill that gap, and reports on an econometric study of the links between past expenditures on agricultural research and urban poverty reduction in Chin</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28978"><authors>Peter Hazell,Lawrence Haddad</authors><title>Agricultural research and poverty reduction</title><year>2001</year><raw>Hazell, Peter, and Lawrence Haddad. 2001. Agricultural research and poverty reduction.</raw><contexts><context>an yield favorable economic returns (Alston et al. 2000), and contribute to significant reductions in rural poverty (Kerr and Kolavalli 1999; Fan, Hazell, and Thorat 2000; Fan, Zhang, and Zhang 2000; Hazell and Haddad 2001). The links between agricultural research and food price benefits for consumers have also been quantified, using the consumer surplus as a welfare measure (Akino and Hayami 1975; Mellor 1975; Scobie </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28979"><authors>Ravi Kanbur,Xiaobo Zhang</authors><title>Which regional inequality: Rural-urban or coast-inland? with Ravi Kanbur</title><venue>Journal of Comparative Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><pages>686--701</pages><volume>27</volume><raw>Kanbur, Ravi and Xiaobo Zhang, 1999. Which regional inequality: Rural-urban or coast-inland? with Ravi Kanbur, Journal of Comparative Economics, 27: 686-701.</raw></citation><citation id="28980"><authors>John Kerr,S Kolavalli</authors><title>Impact of agricultural research on poverty alleviation: Conceptual framework with illustrations from literature</title><venue>Environment and Production Technology Division Discussion Paper No. 56. Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>Kerr, John, and S. Kolavalli, 1999. Impact of agricultural research on poverty alleviation: Conceptual framework with illustrations from literature. Environment and Production Technology Division Discussion Paper No. 56. Washington, DC: International Food Policy Research Institute.</raw><contexts><context>1. INTRODUCTION Many studies have shown that investments in agricultural research can yield favorable economic returns (Alston et al. 2000), and contribute to significant reductions in rural poverty (Kerr and Kolavalli 1999; Fan, Hazell, and Thorat 2000; Fan, Zhang, and Zhang 2000; Hazell and Haddad 2001). The links between agricultural research and food price benefits for consumers have also been quantified, using the </context></contexts></citation><citation id="28981"><authors>Justin Yifu Lin</authors><title>Rural reforms and agricultural growth in China</title><venue>American Economic Review</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1992</year><pages>34--51</pages><volume>82</volume><raw>Lin, Justin Yifu. 1992. Rural reforms and agricultural growth in China. American Economic Review, 82 (1): 34-51.</raw></citation><citation id="28982"><authors>J W Mellor</authors><title>The impact of new agricultural technology on employment and income distribution--Concepts and policy</title><venue>Occasional Paper</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1975</year><pubAddress>Washington DC: USAID</pubAddress><volume>2</volume><raw>Mellor, J. W. 1975. The impact of new agricultural technology on employment and income distribution--Concepts and policy. Occasional Paper No. 2., Washington DC: USAID.</raw><contexts><context>zell and Haddad 2001). The links between agricultural research and food price benefits for consumers have also been quantified, using the consumer surplus as a welfare measure (Akino and Hayami 1975; Mellor 1975; Scobie and Posada 1978; and Pinstrup-Andersen 1979). But little work has been done on quantifying the impact of agricultural research on urban poverty reduction, despite the fact that rapid urbaniza</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28983"><authors>Per Pinstrup-Andersen</authors><title>Modern agricultural technology and income distribution: The market price effect</title><venue>European Review of Agricultural Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1979</year><pages>17--46</pages><volume>6</volume><raw>Pinstrup-Andersen, Per. 1979. Modern agricultural technology and income distribution: The market price effect. European Review of Agricultural Economics 6(1): 17-46.</raw><contexts><context>agricultural research and food price benefits for consumers have also been quantified, using the consumer surplus as a welfare measure (Akino and Hayami 1975; Mellor 1975; Scobie and Posada 1978; and Pinstrup-Andersen 1979). But little work has been done on quantifying the impact of agricultural research on urban poverty reduction, despite the fact that rapid urbanization is increasing the incidence of urban poverty in</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28984"><authors>M Ravillion</authors><title>On the urbanization of poverty. World Bank Discussion Paper</title><publisher>World Bank</publisher><pubAddress>Washington, DC</pubAddress><raw>Ravillion, M. 2000. On the urbanization of poverty. World Bank Discussion Paper. Washington, DC: World Bank.</raw></citation><citation id="28985"><authors>Grant Scobie,R Posada</authors><title>The impact of technological change on income distribution: The case of rice in Colombia</title><venue>American Journal of Agricultural Economics</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1978</year><pages>859--2</pages><volume>60</volume><raw>Scobie, Grant and R. Posada. 1978. The impact of technological change on income distribution: The case of rice in Colombia. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, 60(1): 8592.</raw><contexts><context>ad 2001). The links between agricultural research and food price benefits for consumers have also been quantified, using the consumer surplus as a welfare measure (Akino and Hayami 1975; Mellor 1975; Scobie and Posada 1978; and Pinstrup-Andersen 1979). But little work has been done on quantifying the impact of agricultural research on urban poverty reduction, despite the fact that rapid urbanization is increasing the i</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28986"><authors>Danis Tao Yang,Fang Cai</authors><title>The political economy of China’s rural-urban divide. Center for Research on Economic Development and Policy Reform Working Paper No</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2000</year><tech>62</tech><raw>Yang, Danis Tao, and Fang Cai. 2000. The political economy of China’s rural-urban divide. Center for Research on Economic Development and Policy Reform Working Paper No. 62, Palo Alto, Calif: Stanford University.</raw></citation><citation id="28987"><authors>Xiaobo Zhang</authors><title>Food Demand in China: A Case of Guangdong Province. Unpublished master thesis</title><year>1998</year><pubAddress>Ithaca, NY</pubAddress><raw>Zhang, Xiaobo (1998). Food Demand in China: A Case of Guangdong Province. Unpublished master thesis. Ithaca, NY: Cornell University.</raw></citation><citation id="28988"><authors>J Scherr,Peter B R Hazell</authors><venue>LIST OF EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 01 Sustainable Agricultural Development Strategies in Fragile Lands, by Sara</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>LIST OF EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 01 Sustainable Agricultural Development Strategies in Fragile Lands, by Sara J. Scherr and Peter B.R. Hazell, June 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="28989"><authors>W Rosegrant</authors><title>02 Confronting the Environmental Consequences of the Green Revolution</title><venue>in Asia, by Prabhu L. Pingali and Mark</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>02 Confronting the Environmental Consequences of the Green Revolution in Asia, by Prabhu L. Pingali and Mark W. Rosegrant, August 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="28990"><title>03 Infrastructure and Technology Constraints to Agricultural Development in the Humid and Subhumid Tropics of Africa, by Dunstan S.C</title><year>1994</year><pubAddress>Spencer</pubAddress><raw>03 Infrastructure and Technology Constraints to Agricultural Development in the Humid and Subhumid Tropics of Africa, by Dunstan S.C. Spencer, August 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="28991"><venue>04 Water Markets in Pakistan: Participation and Productivity, by Ruth Meinzen-Dick and Martha Sullins</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><raw>04 Water Markets in Pakistan: Participation and Productivity, by Ruth Meinzen-Dick and Martha Sullins, September 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="28992"><authors>Stephen A Vosti,Julie Witcover,Michael Lipton</authors><title>05 The Impact of Technical Change in Agriculture on Human Fertility: District-level Evidence From India, by</title><year>1994</year><raw>05 The Impact of Technical Change in Agriculture on Human Fertility: District-level Evidence From India, by Stephen A. Vosti, Julie Witcover, and Michael Lipton, October 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="28993"><title>06 Reforming Water Allocation Policy Through Markets in Tradable Water Rights: Lessons from</title><venue>by Mark W. Rosegrant and Renato Gazri S</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1994</year><pubAddress>Chile, Mexico, and California</pubAddress><raw>06 Reforming Water Allocation Policy Through Markets in Tradable Water Rights: Lessons from Chile, Mexico, and California, by Mark W. Rosegrant and Renato Gazri S, October 1994.</raw></citation><citation id="28994"><authors>Robert E Evenson</authors><title>07 Total Factor Productivity and Sources of Long-Term Growth</title><venue>in Indian Agriculture, by Mark W. Rosegrant and</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>07 Total Factor Productivity and Sources of Long-Term Growth in Indian Agriculture, by Mark W. Rosegrant and Robert E. Evenson, April 1995.</raw></citation><citation id="28995"><venue>08 Farm-Nonfarm Growth Linkages in Zambia, by Peter B.R. Hazell and Behjat Hoijati</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>08 Farm-Nonfarm Growth Linkages in Zambia, by Peter B.R. Hazell and Behjat Hoijati, April 1995.</raw><contexts><context> 0.44 1986-90 1,725 53,598 32,480 0.51 11.90 6.16 0.39 1991-94 2,099 61,876 33,886 0.54 14.29 6.14 0.39 1995-97 2,203 64,352 35,211 0.53 12.06 8.42 0.32 Sources: Fan and Pardey (1992), Fan and Pardey (1995), and State Statistical Bureau and State Science and Technology Commission (various years).sDuring the 1950s and 1960s, the number of researchers increased steadily. By 1973 there were about 10,000 sc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28996"><title>09 Livestock and Deforestation in Central America in the 1980s and 1990s: A Policy Perspective, by David Kaimowitz (Interamerican Institute for Cooperation on Agriculture</title><year>1995</year><raw>09 Livestock and Deforestation in Central America in the 1980s and 1990s: A Policy Perspective, by David Kaimowitz (Interamerican Institute for Cooperation on Agriculture), June 1995.</raw><contexts><context> 0.44 1986-90 1,725 53,598 32,480 0.51 11.90 6.16 0.39 1991-94 2,099 61,876 33,886 0.54 14.29 6.14 0.39 1995-97 2,203 64,352 35,211 0.53 12.06 8.42 0.32 Sources: Fan and Pardey (1992), Fan and Pardey (1995), and State Statistical Bureau and State Science and Technology Commission (various years).sDuring the 1950s and 1960s, the number of researchers increased steadily. By 1973 there were about 10,000 sc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28997"><authors>Siam,Ibrahim Soliman</authors><title>10 Effects of the Structural Adjustment Program on Agricultural Production and Resource Use in Egypt, by Peter B.R</title><venue>Hazell, Nicostrato Perez, Gamal</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1995</year><raw>10 Effects of the Structural Adjustment Program on Agricultural Production and Resource Use in Egypt, by Peter B.R. Hazell, Nicostrato Perez, Gamal Siam, and Ibrahim Soliman, August 1995.</raw></citation><citation id="28998"><title>11 Local Organizations for Natural Resource Management: Lessons from Theoretical and Empirical Literature, by Lise Nordvig Rasmussen and Ruth Meinzen-Dick</title><year>1995</year><raw>11 Local Organizations for Natural Resource Management: Lessons from Theoretical and Empirical Literature, by Lise Nordvig Rasmussen and Ruth Meinzen-Dick, August 1995.</raw><contexts><context> 0.44 1986-90 1,725 53,598 32,480 0.51 11.90 6.16 0.39 1991-94 2,099 61,876 33,886 0.54 14.29 6.14 0.39 1995-97 2,203 64,352 35,211 0.53 12.06 8.42 0.32 Sources: Fan and Pardey (1992), Fan and Pardey (1995), and State Statistical Bureau and State Science and Technology Commission (various years).sDuring the 1950s and 1960s, the number of researchers increased steadily. By 1973 there were about 10,000 sc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="28999"><authors>Mark W Rosegrant Ito,Mercedita C AgcaoiliSombilla</authors><title>12 Quality-Equivalent and Cost-Adjusted Measurement of International Competitiveness in Japanese Rice Markets, by Shoichi</title><year>1995</year><raw>12 Quality-Equivalent and Cost-Adjusted Measurement of International Competitiveness in Japanese Rice Markets, by Shoichi Ito, Mark W. Rosegrant, and Mercedita C. AgcaoiliSombilla, August 1995.</raw></citation><citation id="29000"><authors>Philip G Pardey</authors><venue>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 13 Role of Inputs, Institutions, and Technical Innovations in Stimulating Growth in Chinese Agriculture, by Shenggen Fan and</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 13 Role of Inputs, Institutions, and Technical Innovations in Stimulating Growth in Chinese Agriculture, by Shenggen Fan and Philip G. Pardey, September 1995.</raw></citation><citation id="29001"><venue>14 Investments in African Agricultural Research, by Philip G. Pardey, Johannes Roseboom, and Nienke Beintema</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>14 Investments in African Agricultural Research, by Philip G. Pardey, Johannes Roseboom, and Nienke Beintema, October 1995.</raw><contexts><context> 0.44 1986-90 1,725 53,598 32,480 0.51 11.90 6.16 0.39 1991-94 2,099 61,876 33,886 0.54 14.29 6.14 0.39 1995-97 2,203 64,352 35,211 0.53 12.06 8.42 0.32 Sources: Fan and Pardey (1992), Fan and Pardey (1995), and State Statistical Bureau and State Science and Technology Commission (various years).sDuring the 1950s and 1960s, the number of researchers increased steadily. By 1973 there were about 10,000 sc</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29002"><authors>B R Hazell,V N Misra,Behjat Hoijati</authors><title>15 Role of Terms of Trade in Indian Agricultural Growth: A National and State Level Analysis, by Peter</title><venue>16 Policies and Markets for Non-Timber Tree Products, by</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>15 Role of Terms of Trade in Indian Agricultural Growth: A National and State Level Analysis, by Peter B.R. Hazell, V.N. Misra, and Behjat Hoijati, December 1995. 16 Policies and Markets for Non-Timber Tree Products, by Peter A. Dewees and Sara J.</raw></citation><citation id="29003"><authors>Scherr</authors><year>1996</year><raw>Scherr, March 1996.</raw></citation><citation id="29004"><authors>John Kerr</authors><venue>Determinants of Farmers’ Indigenous Soil and Water Conservation Investments in India’s Semi-Arid Tropics, by John Pender and</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><volume>17</volume><raw>17 Determinants of Farmers’ Indigenous Soil and Water Conservation Investments in India’s Semi-Arid Tropics, by John Pender and John Kerr, August 1996.</raw></citation><citation id="29005"><authors>G Pardey,Julian M Alston,Jason E Christian,Shenggen Fan</authors><title>18 Summary of a Productive Partnership: The Benefits from U.S</title><venue>Participation in the CGIAR, by Philip</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><raw>18 Summary of a Productive Partnership: The Benefits from U.S. Participation in the CGIAR, by Philip G. Pardey, Julian M. Alston, Jason E. Christian, and Shenggen Fan, October 1996.</raw></citation><citation id="29006"><title>Crop Genetic Resource Policy: Towards a Research Agenda, by Brian D</title><year>19</year><pubAddress>Wright</pubAddress><raw>19 Crop Genetic Resource Policy: Towards a Research Agenda, by Brian D. Wright, October 1996.</raw></citation><citation id="29007"><authors>M Kerr</authors><title>Sustainable Development of Rainfed Agriculture in India, by</title><year>1996</year><publisher>John</publisher><volume>20</volume><raw>20 Sustainable Development of Rainfed Agriculture in India, by John M. Kerr, November 1996.</raw></citation><citation id="29008"><venue>Impact of Market and Population Pressure on Production, Incomes and Natural Resources in the Dryland Savannas of West Africa: Bioeconomic Modeling at the Village Level, by Bruno Barbier</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1996</year><volume>21</volume><raw>21 Impact of Market and Population Pressure on Production, Incomes and Natural Resources in the Dryland Savannas of West Africa: Bioeconomic Modeling at the Village Level, by Bruno Barbier, November 1996.</raw></citation><citation id="29009"><authors>Why</authors><title>Do Projections on China’s Future Food Supply and Demand Differ? by Shenggen Fan and Mercedita Agcaoili-Sombilla</title><year>1997</year><raw>22 Why Do Projections on China’s Future Food Supply and Demand Differ? by Shenggen Fan and Mercedita Agcaoili-Sombilla, March 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29010"><authors>Philip G Pardey</authors><title>23 Agroecological Aspects of Evaluating Agricultural RandD, by Stanley Wood and</title><year>1997</year><raw>23 Agroecological Aspects of Evaluating Agricultural RandD, by Stanley Wood and Philip G. Pardey, March 1997.</raw><contexts><context>uction. Institutional changes and policy reforms have made important contributions to growth in agricultural and nonagricultural production and poverty reduction in rural China (Fan 1991, and Fan and Pardey 1997). We do not need to estimate these contributions for the purposes of this study, but in order to reduce possible estimation biases that may arise from neglecting them, we added year and province dumm</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29011"><authors>Population Pressure,Land</authors><title>Tenure, and Tree Resource Management in Uganda, by Frank Place and Keijiro</title><year>1997</year><raw>24 Population Pressure, Land Tenure, and Tree Resource Management in Uganda, by Frank Place and Keijiro Otsuka, March 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29012"><authors>Should</authors><title>India Invest More in Less-favored Areas? by Shenggen Fan and</title><year>1997</year><raw>25 Should India Invest More in Less-favored Areas? by Shenggen Fan and Peter Hazell, April 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29013"><authors>Scott R Templeton,Sara J Scherr</authors><venue>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 26 Population Pressure and the Microeconomy of Land Management in Hills and Mountains of Developing Countries, by</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 26 Population Pressure and the Microeconomy of Land Management in Hills and Mountains of Developing Countries, by Scott R. Templeton and Sara J. Scherr, April 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29014"><authors>Population Land</authors><title>Tenure and Natural Resource Management: The Case of Customary Land Area in Malawi, by Frank Place and Keijiro</title><year>1997</year><raw>27 Population Land Tenure and Natural Resource Management: The Case of Customary Land Area in Malawi, by Frank Place and Keijiro Otsuka, April 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29015"><authors>Water</authors><title>Resources Development in Africa: A Review and Synthesis of Issues, Potentials, and Strategies for the Future, by Mark W. Rosegrant and Nicostrato</title><year>1997</year><raw>28 Water Resources Development in Africa: A Review and Synthesis of Issues, Potentials, and Strategies for the Future, by Mark W. Rosegrant and Nicostrato D. Perez, September 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29016"><authors>M Alston,Philip G Pardey,Vincent H Smith</authors><title>29 Financing Agricultural RandD in Rich Countries: What’s Happening and Why? by Julian</title><year>1997</year><raw>29 Financing Agricultural RandD in Rich Countries: What’s Happening and Why? by Julian M. Alston, Philip G. Pardey, and Vincent H. Smith, September 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29017"><authors>How</authors><title>Fast Have China’s Agricultural Production and Productivity Really Been Growing? by Shenggen Fan</title><year>1997</year><raw>30 How Fast Have China’s Agricultural Production and Productivity Really Been Growing? by Shenggen Fan, September 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29018"><authors>Does Land</authors><title>Tenure Insecurity Discourage Tree Planting? Evolution of Customary Land Tenure and Agroforestry management in Sumatra, by Keijiro</title><year>1997</year><raw>31 Does Land Tenure Insecurity Discourage Tree Planting? Evolution of Customary Land Tenure and Agroforestry management in Sumatra, by Keijiro Otsuka, S. Suyanto, and Thomas P. Tomich, December 1997.</raw></citation><citation id="29019"><authors>Bergeron</authors><title>32 Natural Resource Management in the Hillsides of Honduras: Bioeconomic Modeling at the Micro-Watershed Level, by Bruno Barbier and Gilles</title><year>1998</year><raw>32 Natural Resource Management in the Hillsides of Honduras: Bioeconomic Modeling at the Micro-Watershed Level, by Bruno Barbier and Gilles Bergeron, January 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29020"><authors>Government Spending,Growth</authors><title>Poverty: An Analysis of Interlinkages</title><venue>in Rural India, by Shenggen Fan, Peter Hazell, and Sukhadeo Thorat</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>33 Government Spending, Growth, and Poverty: An Analysis of Interlinkages in Rural India, by Shenggen Fan, Peter Hazell, and Sukhadeo Thorat, March 1998. Revised December 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29021"><title>34 Coalitions and the Organization of Multiple-Stakeholder Action: A Case Study</title><venue>of Agricultural Research and Extension in Rajasthan, India, by Ruth Alsop</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1998</year><raw>34 Coalitions and the Organization of Multiple-Stakeholder Action: A Case Study of Agricultural Research and Extension in Rajasthan, India, by Ruth Alsop, April 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29022"><authors>Julian Alston,Barbara Craig,Philip Pardey</authors><title>35 Dynamics in the Creation and Depreciation of Knowledge and the Returns to Research, by</title><year>1998</year><raw>35 Dynamics in the Creation and Depreciation of Knowledge and the Returns to Research, by Julian Alston, Barbara Craig, and Philip Pardey, July, 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29023"><authors>M Beintema,Philip G Pardey,Johannes Roseboom</authors><title>36 Educating Agricultural Researchers: A Review of the Role of African Universities, by Nienke</title><year>1998</year><raw>36 Educating Agricultural Researchers: A Review of the Role of African Universities, by Nienke M. Beintema, Philip G. Pardey, and Johannes Roseboom, August 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29024"><authors>Philip G Pardey Roseboom,Nienke M Beintema</authors><title>37 The Changing Organizational Basis of African Agricultural Research, by Johannes</title><year>1998</year><raw>37 The Changing Organizational Basis of African Agricultural Research, by Johannes Roseboom, Philip G. Pardey, and Nienke M. Beintema, November 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29025"><authors>Julian M Alston,Michele C Marra,Philip G Pardey,T J Wyatt</authors><title>38 Research Returns Redux: A Meta-Analysis of the Returns to Agricultural RandD, by</title><year>1998</year><raw>38 Research Returns Redux: A Meta-Analysis of the Returns to Agricultural RandD, by Julian M. Alston, Michele C. Marra, Philip G. Pardey, and T.J. Wyatt, November 1998.</raw></citation><citation id="29026"><venue>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 39 Technological Change, Technical and Allocative Efficiency in Chinese Agriculture: The Case of Rice Production in Jiangsu, by Shenggen Fan</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 39 Technological Change, Technical and Allocative Efficiency in Chinese Agriculture: The Case of Rice Production in Jiangsu, by Shenggen Fan, January 1999.</raw><contexts><context>trolled by state governments and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primar</context><context>gree d. In this report, we use PDLs of degree 2. In this case, we only need to estimate three instead of i+1 parameters for the lag distribution. For more detailed information on this 6 Alston et al. (1999) argue that research lag may be much longer than previously thought, perhaps even infinite. But this argument may be less relevant for most developing countries since their national agricultural resea</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29027"><title>40 The Substance of Interaction: Design and Policy Implications of NGO-Government</title><venue>Projects in India, by Ruth Alsop with Ved</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><pubAddress>Arya</pubAddress><raw>40 The Substance of Interaction: Design and Policy Implications of NGO-Government Projects in India, by Ruth Alsop with Ved Arya, January 1999.</raw><contexts><context>trolled by state governments and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primar</context><context>gree d. In this report, we use PDLs of degree 2. In this case, we only need to estimate three instead of i+1 parameters for the lag distribution. For more detailed information on this 6 Alston et al. (1999) argue that research lag may be much longer than previously thought, perhaps even infinite. But this argument may be less relevant for most developing countries since their national agricultural resea</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29028"><authors>Frank Place Pender,Simeon Ehui</authors><title>41 Strategies for Sustainable Agricultural Development in the East African Highlands, by</title><year>1999</year><publisher>John</publisher><raw>41 Strategies for Sustainable Agricultural Development in the East African Highlands, by John Pender, Frank Place, and Simeon Ehui, April 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29029"><title>42 Cost Aspects of African Agricultural Research, by Philip G</title><venue>Pardey, Johannes Roseboom, Nienke M. Beintema, and Connie Chan-Kang</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>1999</year><raw>42 Cost Aspects of African Agricultural Research, by Philip G. Pardey, Johannes Roseboom, Nienke M. Beintema, and Connie Chan-Kang, April 1999.</raw><contexts><context>trolled by state governments and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primar</context><context>gree d. In this report, we use PDLs of degree 2. In this case, we only need to estimate three instead of i+1 parameters for the lag distribution. For more detailed information on this 6 Alston et al. (1999) argue that research lag may be much longer than previously thought, perhaps even infinite. But this argument may be less relevant for most developing countries since their national agricultural resea</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29030"><authors>Peter Hazell</authors><title>43 Are Returns to Public Investment Lower in Less-favored Rural Areas? An Empirical Analysis of India, by Shenggen Fan and</title><year>1999</year><raw>43 Are Returns to Public Investment Lower in Less-favored Rural Areas? An Empirical Analysis of India, by Shenggen Fan and Peter Hazell, May 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29031"><authors>Kate Sebastian Wood,Freddy Nachtergaele,Daniel Nielsen,Aiguo Dai</authors><title>44 Spatial Aspects of the Design and Targeting of Agricultural Development Strategies, by Stanley</title><year>1999</year><raw>44 Spatial Aspects of the Design and Targeting of Agricultural Development Strategies, by Stanley Wood, Kate Sebastian, Freddy Nachtergaele, Daniel Nielsen, and Aiguo Dai, May 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29032"><authors>Sara J Scherr Pender,Guadalupe Durón</authors><title>45 Pathways of Development in the Hillsides of Honduras: Causes and Implications for Agricultural Production, Poverty, and Sustainable Resource Use, by</title><year>1999</year><publisher>John</publisher><raw>45 Pathways of Development in the Hillsides of Honduras: Causes and Implications for Agricultural Production, Poverty, and Sustainable Resource Use, by John Pender, Sara J. Scherr, and Guadalupe Durón, May 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29033"><authors>John Pender</authors><title>46 Determinants of Land Use Change: Evidence from a Community Study</title><venue>in Honduras, by Gilles Bergeron and</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>46 Determinants of Land Use Change: Evidence from a Community Study in Honduras, by Gilles Bergeron and John Pender, July 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29034"><authors>Ringler</authors><title>47 Impact on Food Security and Rural Development of Reallocating Water from Agriculture, by Mark W. Rosegrant and Claudia</title><year>1999</year><raw>47 Impact on Food Security and Rural Development of Reallocating Water from Agriculture, by Mark W. Rosegrant and Claudia Ringler, August 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29035"><title>48 Rural Population Growth, Agricultural Change and Natural Resource Management in Developing Countries: A Review of Hypotheses and Some Evidence from Honduras, by John Pender</title><year>1999</year><raw>48 Rural Population Growth, Agricultural Change and Natural Resource Management in Developing Countries: A Review of Hypotheses and Some Evidence from Honduras, by John Pender, August 1999.</raw><contexts><context>trolled by state governments and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primar</context><context>gree d. In this report, we use PDLs of degree 2. In this case, we only need to estimate three instead of i+1 parameters for the lag distribution. For more detailed information on this 6 Alston et al. (1999) argue that research lag may be much longer than previously thought, perhaps even infinite. But this argument may be less relevant for most developing countries since their national agricultural resea</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29036"><authors>Sara J Scherr</authors><title>49 Organizational Development and Natural Resource Management: Evidence from Central Honduras, by John Pender and</title><year>1999</year><raw>49 Organizational Development and Natural Resource Management: Evidence from Central Honduras, by John Pender and Sara J. Scherr, November 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29037"><authors>Fan</authors><title>50 Estimating Crop-Specific Production Technologies in Chinese Agriculture: A Generalized Maximum Entropy Approach, by Xiaobo Zhang and Shenggen</title><year>1999</year><raw>50 Estimating Crop-Specific Production Technologies in Chinese Agriculture: A Generalized Maximum Entropy Approach, by Xiaobo Zhang and Shenggen Fan, September 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29038"><authors>Brian D Wright</authors><title>51 Dynamic Implications of Patenting for Crop Genetic Resources, by Bonwoo Koo and</title><year>1999</year><raw>51 Dynamic Implications of Patenting for Crop Genetic Resources, by Bonwoo Koo and Brian D. Wright, October 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29039"><authors>Philip G Pardey,Bonwoo Koo,Brian D Wright,M Eric van Dusen,Bent Skovmand,Suketoshi Taba</authors><title>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 52 Costing the Ex Situ Conservation of Genetic Resources: Maize and Wheat at CIMMYT, by</title><year>1999</year><raw>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 52 Costing the Ex Situ Conservation of Genetic Resources: Maize and Wheat at CIMMYT, by Philip G. Pardey, Bonwoo Koo, Brian D. Wright, M. Eric van Dusen, Bent Skovmand, and Suketoshi Taba, October 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29040"><authors>Zhang,Sherman Robinson</authors><title>53 Past and Future Sources of Growth for China, by Shenggen Fan, Xiaobo</title><year>1999</year><raw>53 Past and Future Sources of Growth for China, by Shenggen Fan, Xiaobo Zhang, and Sherman Robinson, October 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29041"><authors>Brian D Wright</authors><title>54 The Timing of Evaluation of Genebank Accessions and the Effects of Biotechnology, by Bonwoo Koo and</title><year>1999</year><raw>54 The Timing of Evaluation of Genebank Accessions and the Effects of Biotechnology, by Bonwoo Koo and Brian D. Wright, October 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29042"><authors>New</authors><title>Approaches to Crop Yield Insurance in Developing Countries, by Jerry</title><year>1999</year><raw>55 New Approaches to Crop Yield Insurance in Developing Countries, by Jerry Skees, Peter Hazell, and Mario Miranda, November 1999.</raw></citation><citation id="29043"><title>56 Impact of Agricultural Research on Poverty Alleviation: Conceptual Framework with Illustrations from the Literature, by John Kerr and Shashi Kolavalli</title><year>1999</year><raw>56 Impact of Agricultural Research on Poverty Alleviation: Conceptual Framework with Illustrations from the Literature, by John Kerr and Shashi Kolavalli, December 1999.</raw><contexts><context>trolled by state governments and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primar</context><context>gree d. In this report, we use PDLs of degree 2. In this case, we only need to estimate three instead of i+1 parameters for the lag distribution. For more detailed information on this 6 Alston et al. (1999) argue that research lag may be much longer than previously thought, perhaps even infinite. But this argument may be less relevant for most developing countries since their national agricultural resea</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29044"><title>57 Could Futures Markets Help Growers Better Manage Coffee Price Risks in Costa Rica? by Peter Hazell</title><year>2000</year><raw>57 Could Futures Markets Help Growers Better Manage Coffee Price Risks in Costa Rica? by Peter Hazell, January 2000.</raw><contexts><context>ents and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primary school education, 8 ye</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29045"><authors>Urbanization Industrialization,Land</authors><title>Use in China, by Xiaobo</title><year>2000</year><raw>58 Industrialization, Urbanization, and Land Use in China, by Xiaobo Zhang, Tim Mount, and Richard Boisvert, January 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29046"><authors>Water</authors><title>Rights and Multiple Water Uses: Framework and Application to Kirindi Oya</title><venue>Irrigation System, Sri Lanka, by Ruth Meinzen-Dick and Margaretha</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>59 Water Rights and Multiple Water Uses: Framework and Application to Kirindi Oya Irrigation System, Sri Lanka, by Ruth Meinzen-Dick and Margaretha Bakker, March 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29047"><title>60 Community natural Resource Management: The Case of Woodlots</title><venue>in Northern Ethiopia, by Berhanu Gebremedhin, John Pender and Girmay Tesfaye</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>60 Community natural Resource Management: The Case of Woodlots in Northern Ethiopia, by Berhanu Gebremedhin, John Pender and Girmay Tesfaye, April 2000.</raw><contexts><context>ents and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primary school education, 8 ye</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29048"><title>61 What Affects Organization and Collective Action for Managing Resources? Evidence from Canal Irrigation Systems</title><venue>in India, by Ruth Meinzen-Dick, K.V. Raju, and Ashok Gulati</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>61 What Affects Organization and Collective Action for Managing Resources? Evidence from Canal Irrigation Systems in India, by Ruth Meinzen-Dick, K.V. Raju, and Ashok Gulati, June 2000.</raw><contexts><context>ents and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primary school education, 8 ye</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29049"><authors>Raymond J Venner</authors><title>62 The Effects of the U.S. Plant Variety Protection Act on Wheat Genetic Improvement, by Julian M. Alston and</title><year>2000</year><raw>62 The Effects of the U.S. Plant Variety Protection Act on Wheat Genetic Improvement, by Julian M. Alston and Raymond J. Venner, May 2000. 63 Integrated Economic-Hydrologic Water Modeling at the Basin Scale: The Maipo River Basin, by M. W. Rosegrant, C. Ringler, D.C. McKinney, X. Cai, A. Keller, and G.</raw></citation><citation id="29050"><authors>Donoso</authors><year>2000</year><raw>Donoso, May 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29051"><authors>Mark W Rosegrant Ringler,Michael S Paisner</authors><title>64 Irrigation and Water Resources in Latin America and he Caribbean: Challenges and Strategies, by Claudia</title><year>2000</year><raw>64 Irrigation and Water Resources in Latin America and he Caribbean: Challenges and Strategies, by Claudia Ringler, Mark W. Rosegrant, and Michael S. Paisner, June 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29052"><authors>John Pender</authors><title>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 65 The Role of Trees for Sustainable Management of Less-favored Lands: The Case of Eucalyptus in Ethiopia, by Pamela Jagger and</title><year>2000</year><raw>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 65 The Role of Trees for Sustainable Management of Less-favored Lands: The Case of Eucalyptus in Ethiopia, by Pamela Jagger and John Pender, June 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29053"><title>66 Growth and Poverty in Rural China: The Role of</title><venue>Public Investments, by Shenggen Fan, Linxiu Zhang, and Xiaobo Zhang</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>66 Growth and Poverty in Rural China: The Role of Public Investments, by Shenggen Fan, Linxiu Zhang, and Xiaobo Zhang, June 2000.</raw><contexts><context>ents and were allowed to vary by only a few percentage points across provinces. We therefore assume that price levels were the same for all provinces in 1984. Kanbur and Zhang (1999) and Yang and Cai (2000) have adopted similar methods to calculate real expenditure levels across regions.s12 years for a person who is illiterate and semi-illiterate, 5 years for a person with primary school education, 8 ye</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29054"><authors>Steve Vosti Carpentier,Julie Witcover</authors><title>67 Small-Scale Farms in the Western Brazilian Amazon: Can They Benefit from Carbon Trade? by Chantal</title><year>2000</year><raw>67 Small-Scale Farms in the Western Brazilian Amazon: Can They Benefit from Carbon Trade? by Chantal Carpentier, Steve Vosti, and Julie Witcover, September 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29055"><authors>P J George</authors><title>68 An Evaluation of Dryland Watershed Development Projects</title><venue>in India, by John Kerr, Ganesh Pangare, Vasudha Lokur Pangare, and</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>68 An Evaluation of Dryland Watershed Development Projects in India, by John Kerr, Ganesh Pangare, Vasudha Lokur Pangare, and P.J. George, October 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29056"><authors>Murray Fulton</authors><title>69 Consumption Effects of Genetic Modification: What If Consumers Are Right? by Konstantinos Giannakas and</title><year>2000</year><raw>69 Consumption Effects of Genetic Modification: What If Consumers Are Right? by Konstantinos Giannakas and Murray Fulton, November 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29057"><authors>G Pardey,Brian D Wright,Patricia Zambrano</authors><title>70 South-North Trade, Intellectual Property Jurisdictions, and Freedom to Operate in Agricultural Research on Staple Crops, by Eran Binenbaum</title><venue>Carol Nottenburg, Philip</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2000</year><raw>70 South-North Trade, Intellectual Property Jurisdictions, and Freedom to Operate in Agricultural Research on Staple Crops, by Eran Binenbaum, Carol Nottenburg, Philip G. Pardey, Brian D. Wright, and Patricia Zambrano, December 2000.</raw></citation><citation id="29058"><authors>Fan</authors><venue>71 Public Investment and Regional Inequality in Rural China, by Xiaobo Zhang and Shenggen</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>71 Public Investment and Regional Inequality in Rural China, by Xiaobo Zhang and Shenggen Fan, December 2000.</raw><contexts><context>(1997) show that research-induced technical change accounts for 20% of the growth in agricultural output since 1965. The rates of returns of this investment are also higher, ranging from 35 % to 90% (Fan 2000). 3. URBAN POVERTY Compared to rural poverty, urban poverty is small in China. Using a poverty line of $1.0 income per capita per day measured in 1985 purchasing power parity (or 1985 PPP dollar), th</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29059"><authors>Claudia Ringler Cai,Mark W Rosegrant</authors><title>72 Does Efficient Water Management Matter? Physical and Economic Efficiency of Water Use in the River Basin, by Ximing</title><year>2001</year><raw>72 Does Efficient Water Management Matter? Physical and Economic Efficiency of Water Use in the River Basin, by Ximing Cai, Claudia Ringler, and Mark W. Rosegrant, March 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29060"><authors>Dixon,Rafael Celis</authors><title>73 Monitoring Systems for Managing Natural Resources: Economics, Indicators and Environmental Externalities in a Costa Rican Watershed, by Peter Hazell, Ujjayant Chakravorty</title><year>2001</year><pubAddress>John</pubAddress><raw>73 Monitoring Systems for Managing Natural Resources: Economics, Indicators and Environmental Externalities in a Costa Rican Watershed, by Peter Hazell, Ujjayant Chakravorty, John Dixon, and Rafael Celis, March 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29061"><authors>Li</authors><title>74 Does Guanxi Matter to Nonfarm Employment? by Xiaobo Zhang and Guo</title><year>2001</year><raw>74 Does Guanxi Matter to Nonfarm Employment? by Xiaobo Zhang and Guo Li, June 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29062"><authors>Abdul Kamara McCarthy,Michael Kirk</authors><title>75 The Effect of Environmental Variability on Livestock and Land-Use Management: The Borana</title><year>2001</year><pubAddress>Plateau, Southern Ethiopia, by Nancy</pubAddress><raw>75 The Effect of Environmental Variability on Livestock and Land-Use Management: The Borana Plateau, Southern Ethiopia, by Nancy McCarthy, Abdul Kamara, and Michael Kirk, July 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29063"><authors>Market</authors><title>Imperfections and Land Productivity in the Ethiopian Highlands, by Stein</title><year>2001</year><raw>76 Market Imperfections and Land Productivity in the Ethiopian Highlands, by Stein Holden, Bekele Shiferaw, and John Pender, August 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29064"><title>77 Strategies for Sustainable Agricultural Development in the Ethiopian Highlands, by</title><venue>John Pender, Berhanu Gebremedhin, Samuel Benin, and Simeon Ehui</venue><venType>JOURNAL</venType><year>2001</year><raw>77 Strategies for Sustainable Agricultural Development in the Ethiopian Highlands, by John Pender, Berhanu Gebremedhin, Samuel Benin, and Simeon Ehui, August 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29065"><venue>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 78 Managing Droughts in the Low-Rainfall Areas of the Middle East and North Africa, by Peter Hazell, Peter Oram, and Nabil Chaherli</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>EPTD DISCUSSION PAPERS 78 Managing Droughts in the Low-Rainfall Areas of the Middle East and North Africa, by Peter Hazell, Peter Oram, and Nabil Chaherli, September 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29066"><authors>Philip G Pardey,Brian D Wright</authors><title>79 Accessing Other People’s Technology: Do Non-Profit Agencies Need It? How To Obtain It, by Carol Nottenburg</title><year>2001</year><raw>79 Accessing Other People’s Technology: Do Non-Profit Agencies Need It? How To Obtain It, by Carol Nottenburg, Philip G. Pardey, and Brian D. Wright, September 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29067"><title>80 The Economics of Intellectual Property Rights Under Imperfect Enforcement: Developing Countries</title><venue>Biotechnology, and the TRIPS Agreement, by Konstantinos Giannakas</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>80 The Economics of Intellectual Property Rights Under Imperfect Enforcement: Developing Countries, Biotechnology, and the TRIPS Agreement, by Konstantinos Giannakas, September 2001.</raw></citation><citation id="29068"><authors>Land</authors><title>Lease Markets and Agricultural Efficiency: Theory and Evidence from Ethiopia, by John Pender and Marcel Fafchamps</title><year>2001</year><raw>81 Land Lease Markets and Agricultural Efficiency: Theory and Evidence from Ethiopia, by John Pender and Marcel Fafchamps, October 2001.</raw></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ifpri.org/divs/eptd/dp/papers/eptdp83.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>94307fab8938c59aeb64e323974e6a1c9fa446d1</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>