<document id="10.1.1.1.1546"><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">ONTOLOGY-BASED QUERY REFINEMENT FOR MULTIMEDIA META OBJECTS</title><abstract src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Abstract: To enable efficient access to multimedia content, the media data has to be aug-mented by semantic metadata and functionality. The semantic representation has to be inte-grated with domain ontologies to fully exploit domain-specific knowledge. This knowledge can be used for refining ambiguous user queries by closing the conceptual gap between the user and the information to be retrieved. In our previous research, we have introduced Enhanced Multi-media Meta Objects (EMMOs) as a new approach for semantic multimedia meta modeling, as well as the query algebra EMMA, which is adequate and complete with regard to the EMMO model. This paper focuses on the refinement of EMMA queries by incorporating ontological knowledge. 1</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="4311"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Sonja Zillner</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Vienna, Austria</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">sonja.zillner@univie.ac.at</email><order>1</order></author><author id="4312"><name src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Werner Winiwarter</name><address src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Vienna, Austria</address><email src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">werner.winiwarter@univie.ac.at</email><order>2</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29069"><authors>J Ayars</authors><title>et al. Synchronized Multimedia Integration Language</title><venue>SMIL 2.0). W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2001</year><raw>J. Ayars et al. Synchronized Multimedia Integration Language (SMIL 2.0). W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), August 2001.</raw><contexts><context>aspect, as well as versioning support in a homogenous way, the EMMO model constitutes a unique approach to multimedia meta modeling. None of the standards for multimedia document models, such as SMIL [1] or SVG [7], and none of the standards for semantic media description, such as RDF [13] or Topic Maps [11], addresses all these aspects. Thus, none of the query languages for those standards can fulfi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29070"><authors>M Benari</authors><title>et al. Proposal for a Standard Ontology of Intertextualtiy</title><venue>Public Deliverable Version 2.0, CULTOS Consortium and Project Planning</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>M. Benari et al. Proposal for a Standard Ontology of Intertextualtiy. Public Deliverable Version 2.0, CULTOS Consortium and Project Planning, June 2003.</raw><contexts><context> relational concepts. Object concepts are used for labeling the nodes, relational concepts for labeling the associations within an EMMO’s graph structure. For example, the Ontology of Intertextuality [2], which was established within the CULTOS project, defines object concepts for describing media objects, e.g. the concepts Text or Performance, and relational concepts for describing relationships hol</context><context>abel of an association is changed to the inverse concept, then source and target entity have to be exchanged to keep the semantics intact. Figure 2 shows an extract of the Ontology of Intertextuality [2]. It describes a hierarchy of relational concepts and subconcepts. In addition, is specifies that the concept inspire is transitive, the concept similar audience is symmetric, and the concepts retell </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29071"><authors>D Bogachev</authors><title>TMPath – Revisited. Online Article, available under http://homepage.mac.com/dmitryv/ TopicMaps/TMPath/TMPathRevisited.html</title><year>2004</year><raw>D. Bogachev. TMPath – Revisited. Online Article, available under http://homepage.mac.com/dmitryv/ TopicMaps/TMPath/TMPathRevisited.html, 2004.</raw><contexts><context>orate ontology constructs, such as the transitivity or symmetry of relationships. The situation for query languages for Topic Maps is quite similar as for RDF. Approaches such as Tolog [10] or TMPath [3] provide means for graph navigation, but only Tolog addresses ontology integration by offering some very limited features, e.g. querying concept-subconcept relationships. Although there exist quite a </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29072"><authors>D Brickely,R Guha</authors><title>Resource Description Framework (RDF) Vocabulary Description Language 1.0</title><venue>RDF Schema. W3C Working Draft, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><raw>D. Brickely and R. Guha. Resource Description Framework (RDF) Vocabulary Description Language 1.0: RDF Schema. W3C Working Draft, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), April 2002.</raw><contexts><context>Existing query languages for RDF, such as RAL [9] or RQL [12], provide means to navigate the RDF graph structure and enable the integration of a very simple ontology structure described by RDF Schema [4]. However, they cannot deal with more elaborate ontology constructs, such as the transitivity or symmetry of relationships. The situation for query languages for Topic Maps is quite similar as for RDF</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29073"><authors>J Davies,R Weeks,U Krohn</authors><title>QuizRDF: Search technology for the Semantic Web</title><venue>In Proc. of the 37th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS’04), Big Island</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><pubAddress>Hawaii</pubAddress><raw>J. Davies, R. Weeks, and U. Krohn. QuizRDF: Search technology for the Semantic Web. In Proc. of the 37th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS’04), Big Island, Hawaii, 2004.</raw><contexts><context>on by offering some very limited features, e.g. querying concept-subconcept relationships. Although there exist quite a few approaches for ontology-based browsing of text collections, such as QuizRDF [5], Spectacle [8], or SESQ [16], none of those approaches is suitable for retrieving multimedia data or allows to refine user queries by drawing inferences from ontological knowledge. However, those app</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29074"><authors>D Fensel</authors><title>Ontologies: A Silver Bullet for Knowledge Management and Electronic Commerce</title><year>2001</year><publisher>Springer</publisher><pubAddress>Heidelberg</pubAddress><raw>D. Fensel. Ontologies: A Silver Bullet for Knowledge Management and Electronic Commerce. Springer, Heidelberg, 2001.</raw><contexts><context>lational Concepts By providing a shared and common understanding of a domain that can be communicated between people and applications systems, ontologies facilitate the sharing and reuse of knowledge [6]. An ontology suitable for the integration into the EMMO model has to distinguish between object concepts and relational concepts. Object concepts are used for labeling the nodes, relational concepts </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29075"><authors>J Ferraiolo,F Jun,D Jackson</authors><venue>Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) 1.1. W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><raw>J. Ferraiolo, F. Jun, and D. Jackson. Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) 1.1. W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), January 2003.</raw><contexts><context>well as versioning support in a homogenous way, the EMMO model constitutes a unique approach to multimedia meta modeling. None of the standards for multimedia document models, such as SMIL [1] or SVG [7], and none of the standards for semantic media description, such as RDF [13] or Topic Maps [11], addresses all these aspects. Thus, none of the query languages for those standards can fulfil all requi</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29076"><authors>C Flut</authors><title>et al. Spectacle</title><venue>In Towards the Semantic Web: Ontology-driven Knolwedge Managment</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pubAddress>West Sussex, UK</pubAddress><raw>C. Flut et al. Spectacle. In Towards the Semantic Web: Ontology-driven Knolwedge Managment, West Sussex, UK, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>some very limited features, e.g. querying concept-subconcept relationships. Although there exist quite a few approaches for ontology-based browsing of text collections, such as QuizRDF [5], Spectacle [8], or SESQ [16], none of those approaches is suitable for retrieving multimedia data or allows to refine user queries by drawing inferences from ontological knowledge. However, those approaches offer u</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29077"><authors>F Frasincar</authors><title>et al. RAL: An Algebra for Querying RDF</title><venue>In Proc. of the Third International Conference on Web Information Systems Engineering (WISE 2000</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pubAddress>Singapore</pubAddress><raw>F. Frasincar et al. RAL: An Algebra for Querying RDF. In Proc. of the Third International Conference on Web Information Systems Engineering (WISE 2000), Singapore, 2002.</raw><contexts><context> regarding whether they allow for navigation of the graph structure and whether the navigational access can be refined bysintegrating ontology knowledge. Existing query languages for RDF, such as RAL [9] or RQL [12], provide means to navigate the RDF graph structure and enable the integration of a very simple ontology structure described by RDF Schema [4]. However, they cannot deal with more elaborat</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29078"><authors>L Garshol</authors><title>Tolog 0.1. Ontopia</title><venType>TECHREPORT</venType><year>2003</year><tech>Technical Report, Ontopia</tech><raw>L. Garshol. Tolog 0.1. Ontopia Technical Report, Ontopia, 2003.</raw><contexts><context> with more elaborate ontology constructs, such as the transitivity or symmetry of relationships. The situation for query languages for Topic Maps is quite similar as for RDF. Approaches such as Tolog [10] or TMPath [3] provide means for graph navigation, but only Tolog addresses ontology integration by offering some very limited features, e.g. querying concept-subconcept relationships. Although there </context></contexts></citation><citation id="29079"><venue>ISO/IEC JTC 1/SC 34/WG 3. Information Technology – SGML Applications – Topic Maps. ISO/IEC International Standard 13250:2000, International Organization for Standardization/International Electrotechnical Commission (ISO/IEC</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><raw>ISO/IEC JTC 1/SC 34/WG 3. Information Technology – SGML Applications – Topic Maps. ISO/IEC International Standard 13250:2000, International Organization for Standardization/International Electrotechnical Commission (ISO/IEC), February 2000.</raw><contexts><context>o multimedia meta modeling. None of the standards for multimedia document models, such as SMIL [1] or SVG [7], and none of the standards for semantic media description, such as RDF [13] or Topic Maps [11], addresses all these aspects. Thus, none of the query languages for those standards can fulfil all requirements with respect to the expressiveness of a query language for EMMOs. However, valuable asp</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29080"><authors>G Karvounarakis</authors><title>et al. RQL: A Declarative Query Language for RDF</title><venue>In Proc. of the 11th International World Wide Web Conference (WWW 2002</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2002</year><pubAddress>Honolulu, Hawaii</pubAddress><raw>G. Karvounarakis et al. RQL: A Declarative Query Language for RDF. In Proc. of the 11th International World Wide Web Conference (WWW 2002), Honolulu, Hawaii, 2002.</raw><contexts><context>whether they allow for navigation of the graph structure and whether the navigational access can be refined bysintegrating ontology knowledge. Existing query languages for RDF, such as RAL [9] or RQL [12], provide means to navigate the RDF graph structure and enable the integration of a very simple ontology structure described by RDF Schema [4]. However, they cannot deal with more elaborate ontology c</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29081"><authors>O Lassila,R Swick</authors><title>Resource Description Framework (RDF) Model and Syntax Specification</title><venue>W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1999</year><raw>O. Lassila and R. Swick. Resource Description Framework (RDF) Model and Syntax Specification. W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), February 1999.</raw><contexts><context>a unique approach to multimedia meta modeling. None of the standards for multimedia document models, such as SMIL [1] or SVG [7], and none of the standards for semantic media description, such as RDF [13] or Topic Maps [11], addresses all these aspects. Thus, none of the query languages for those standards can fulfil all requirements with respect to the expressiveness of a query language for EMMOs. Ho</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29082"><authors>K Schellner,U Westermann,S Zillner,W Klas</authors><title>CULTOS: Towards a World-Wide Digital Collection of Exchangeable Units of Multimedia Content for Intertextual Studies</title><venue>In Proc. of the Conference on Distributed Multimedia Systems (DMS 2003</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pubAddress>Miami, Florida</pubAddress><raw>K. Schellner, U. Westermann, S. Zillner, and W. Klas. CULTOS: Towards a World-Wide Digital Collection of Exchangeable Units of Multimedia Content for Intertextual Studies . In Proc. of the Conference on Distributed Multimedia Systems (DMS 2003), Miami, Florida, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>multimedia content is to enhance multimedia resources by semantic metamodels and to integrate domain ontologies. To answer these challenges, we have developed Enhanced Multimedia Meta Objects (EMMOs) [14], a novel approach for semantic multimedia content modeling. EMMOs were created within the EU-project CULTOS to model InterTextualThreads (ITTs), i.e. complex knowledge structures used by the research</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29083"><authors>P Schneider,P Hayes,I Horrocks</authors><venue>OWL Web Ontology Language Semantics and Abstract Syntax. W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2004</year><raw>P. Schneider, P. Hayes, and I. Horrocks. OWL Web Ontology Language Semantics and Abstract Syntax. W3C Recommendation, World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), February 2004.</raw><contexts><context> for the performance evaluation of explicit and implicit query refinement. Regarding the ontology construction, we currently use Protege2000 to build the domain ontology, and import the resulting OWL [15] description into the EMMO environment. However, future work will also focus on the development of an ontology description language that is fully compatible with the EMMO model. This way we will be ab</context></contexts></citation><citation id="29084"><authors>Z Zhang</authors><title>An Ontology-based Method for Querying the Web Date</title><venue>In Proc. of the 17th International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications(AINA’03</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2003</year><pubAddress>Xi’an, China</pubAddress><raw>Z. Zhang et al. An Ontology-based Method for Querying the Web Date. In Proc. of the 17th International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications(AINA’03), Xi’an, China, 2003.</raw><contexts><context>ited features, e.g. querying concept-subconcept relationships. Although there exist quite a few approaches for ontology-based browsing of text collections, such as QuizRDF [5], Spectacle [8], or SESQ [16], none of those approaches is suitable for retrieving multimedia data or allows to refine user queries by drawing inferences from ontological knowledge. However, those approaches offer useful insights</context></contexts></citation></citations><fileInfo><url>http://www.ifs.univie.ac.at/~ww/iiwas04a.pdf</url><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><checkSums><checkSum><fileType>pdf</fileType><sha1>daa389736be825c7a9cc33a7e4ef31b9235676da</sha1></checkSum></checkSums></fileInfo></document>