<document id="10.1.1.1.1592"><clusterid>1808</clusterid><title src="SVM HeaderParse 0.1">Proceedings of the 2001 Winter Simulation Conference</title><abstract src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Proper education of a modeling and simulation professional meeting the extensive criteria imposed by the community poses significant challenges. In this paper, we explore the formation of a university-based education in modeling and simulation to meet the challenges. We examine the factors affecting the composition of a modeling and simulation course. Based on the anticipated consequences, we propose potential solutions.</abstract><keywords></keywords><authors><author id="null"><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">Peters Smith Medeiros</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">1</order></author><author id="4426"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">B. A. Peters</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">2</order></author><author id="4427"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">J. S. Smith</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">3</order></author><author id="4428"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">D. J. Medeiros</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">4</order></author><author id="4429"><clusterid>0</clusterid><name src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">M. W. Rohrer</name><order src="user correction - Legacy Corrections">5</order></author></authors><citations src="ParsCit 1.0"><citation id="29893"><clusterid>1809</clusterid><authors>R E Beckwith</authors><title>Survey of simulation education I: The perceived need. Handout for presentation at</title><venue>the ORSA/TIMS Joint Meeting</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1974</year><pubAddress>San Juan, PR</pubAddress><raw>Beckwith, R. E. 1974. Survey of simulation education I: The perceived need. Handout for presentation at the ORSA/TIMS Joint Meeting, San Juan, PR, October 18.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29894"><clusterid>1810</clusterid><authors>R E 1976a Beckwith</authors><title>Report on a simulation survey. Graduate</title><pubAddress>New Orleans, LA</pubAddress><raw>Beckwith, R. E. 1976a. Report on a simulation survey. Graduate School of Business Administration, Tulane University, New Orleans, LA, December.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29895"><clusterid>1811</clusterid><authors>R E Beckwith</authors><title>1976b. Letter of transmittal to members of the</title><venue>TIMS College on Simulation and Gaming, Graduate School of Business Administration, Tulane University</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><pubAddress>New Orleans, LA</pubAddress><raw>Beckwith, R. E. 1976b. Letter of transmittal to members of the TIMS College on Simulation and Gaming, Graduate School of Business Administration, Tulane University, New Orleans, LA, December.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29896"><clusterid>1812</clusterid><authors>R E Nance</authors><title>Simulation education: past reflections and future directions</title><venue>In Proceedings of the 2000 Winter Simulation Conference</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>2000</year><pages>1595--1601</pages><editors>ed. J. A. Joines, R. R. Barton, K. Kang, and P. A. Fishwick</editors><publisher>Piscataway</publisher><pubAddress>New Jersey</pubAddress><raw>Nance, R. E. 2000. Simulation education: past reflections and future directions. In Proceedings of the 2000 Winter Simulation Conference, ed. J. A. Joines, R. R. Barton, K. Kang, and P. A. Fishwick, 1595-1601. Piscataway, New Jersey: Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29897"><clusterid>1813</clusterid><authors>R E Nance,C M Overstreet</authors><title>A survey perspective on simulation course content, Presentation transparencies from Panel on the Teaching of Simulation</title><year>1976</year><raw>Nance, R. E. and C. M. Overstreet. 1976. A survey perspective on simulation course content, Presentation transparencies from Panel on the Teaching of Simulation.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29898"><clusterid>1814</clusterid><authors>R V Rogers</authors><title>Notes and commentaries from what makes a modeling and simulation professional? An invited workshop</title><year>1997</year><pages>11--13</pages><pubAddress>Orlando, FL</pubAddress><raw>Rogers, R. V. 1997a. Notes and commentaries from what makes a modeling and simulation professional? An invited workshop, Orlando, FL, February 11-13.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29899"><clusterid>1815</clusterid><authors>R V Rogers</authors><title>What makes a modeling and simulation professional?: The consensus from one workshop</title><year>1997</year><raw>Rogers, R. V. 1997b. What makes a modeling and simulation professional?: The consensus from one workshop.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29900"><clusterid>1898</clusterid><authors></authors><title>Nance is also Chairman of the Board of Orca Computer, Inc. He held a distinguished visiting honors professorship at the University of Central Florida for the spring semester</title><venue>the Imperial College of Science and Technology (UK). He has held a number of editorial positions and was the founding Editor-in-Chief of the ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation, 1990-1995. Currently, he is a member of the Editorial Board,</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1997</year><raw>Nance is also Chairman of the Board of Orca Computer, Inc. He held a distinguished visiting honors professorship at the University of Central Florida for the spring semester, 1997. Dr. Nance has held research appointments at the Naval Surface Weapons Center and at the Imperial College of Science and Technology (UK). He has held a number of editorial positions and was the founding Editor-in-Chief of the ACM Transactions on Modeling and Computer Simulation, 1990-1995. Currently, he is a member of the Editorial Board, Software Practitioner Series, Springer. He served as Program Chair for the 1990 Winter Simulation Conference.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation><citation id="29901"><clusterid>1816</clusterid><authors>Nance</authors><title>received a Distinguished Service Award from the TIMS College on Simulation in 1987</title><venue>In</venue><venType>CONFERENCE</venType><year>1995</year><raw>Dr. Nance received a Distinguished Service Award from the TIMS College on Simulation in 1987. In 1995 he was honored by an award for “Distinguished Service to SIGSIM and the Simulation Community” by the ACM Special Interest Group on Simulation. He was named an ACM Fellow in 1996. His e-mail and web addresses are &lt;nance@vt.edu&gt; and &lt;www.cs.vt.edu/info/ people/vitae/Nance.html&gt;.</raw><paperid>10.1.1.1.1592</paperid></citation></citations><fileInfo><crawldate>Nov 19, 2007</crawldate><repID>rep1</repID><conversionTrace>PDFLib TET</conversionTrace><urls><url>http://www.informs-cs.org/wsc01papers/214.PDF</url></urls></fileInfo></document>